<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Xtravirt on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/xtravirt/</link><description>Recent content in Xtravirt on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 21:09:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/xtravirt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#VMworld2015 – Days 3 and 4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-2015-days-3-and-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 21:09:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-2015-days-3-and-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="wednesday"&gt;Wednesday &lt;a class="anchor" href="#wednesday"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had lined up several sessions so I was quick to get along to my first session - Operational Remediation with vRealize Operations… Tying it All Together - #MGT5735. The session was excellent and gave a great overview and introduction to what is possible with remediation in vROps 6.1. Big thanks to Chima Njaka for this session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/10/CRRF3iyW8AA6yHx_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from a few other sessions I spent a lot of the afternoon in the VMUG lounge with my colleagues from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Xtravirt" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; @xtravirt
&lt;/a&gt; (see pic below) and meeting lots of other folk from the around the globe (this is what makes this conference so very great for me), putting faces to twitter handles for the first time and so on. Networking with your peers at an event such as this is incredibly valuable, educational and really enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My first VMworld..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/my-first-vmworld/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 12:38:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/my-first-vmworld/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/10/vmworld2014.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this was my first VMworld I am not ashamed to say I was really stoked about attending, many of my peers have attended in the past and were going to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I flew in on the Sunday evening so that I could register early on Monday for partner day, however I did miss the chance to attend what turned out to be a very popular and very full Rockstar event on the Sunday evening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>