<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Full Stack on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/full-stack/</link><description>Recent content in Full Stack on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 07:18:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/full-stack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 2- Full Stack monitoring with vRealize Operations Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/05/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-2-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 07:18:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/05/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-2-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;[&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-8035&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2017/03/logo.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; which vROps can provide by using various extensibility solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discussed the following use cases and demonstrated them in live environments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Use Case 1 - Full-Stack vSphere Monitoring. From application to Infrastructure.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Use Case 2 - Amazon RDS Workloads. Monitoring public cloud workloads with vROps.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Use Case 3 - vROps Extensibility. Metrics, Logs and Costing come together along with other 3rd party extensibility options.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Announcing Part 2 – #vROps Webinar series 2017 – “Full Stack” monitoring with vRealize Operations Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/announcing-part-2-vrops-webinar-series-2017-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 07:50:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/announcing-part-2-vrops-webinar-series-2017-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/03/logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;As promised, vROps Webinar Series 2017 is back with the second episode of the year. Last time around we looked closely into the features of vROps 6.5 and as stated during that webinar, we will now show you how you can unlock the full capabilities of vROps using the extensibility of the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have been following the Webinar Series, by now you have a complete visibility into the capabilities of vROps, when it comes to monitoring the vSphere infrastructure. While this infrastructure is important for the IaaS provider, what business cares about is Applications. The good news is that vROps provides you an extensible platform which can be leveraged to extend the product capability into any area where metrics exist. This could be at the layers of your Software Defined Datacenter such as Compute, Network &amp;amp; Storage, or in the Application Stack and it&amp;rsquo;s tiers such as App, Web and DB.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>