<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vcp on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcp/</link><description>Recent content in vcp on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMware Certified Professional - Data Center Virtualization 2021 Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/11/vmware-certified-professional-data-center-virtualization-2021-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/11/vmware-certified-professional-data-center-virtualization-2021-exam-experience/</guid><description>Having not sat any VMware exams recently (MSC exam not including) I had to update my VMware certification status and therefore sit the VCP exam.
The VCP-DCV 2021 certification validates candidate skills to implement, manage, and troubleshoot a vSphere infrastructure, using best practices to provide a powerful, flexible, and secure foundation for business agility that can accelerate the transformation to cloud computing.
The Exam The exam covers a broad spectrum of vSphere components as you would expect.</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2014: VCP NV Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 11:56:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/</guid><description>It is with great relief that I can announce I have passed my VCP NV (Network Virtualisation) having been caught out by the difficulty of the exam and failing previously.
Exam Preparation I was fortunate to attend a VMware internal bootcamp (roughly equivalent to the ICM course) for NSX and have had experience deploying production NSX environments, so that is by far the best preparation. As always, the exam blueprint is crucial, you *have* to know all areas covered there.</description></item></channel></rss>