<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vmworld2017 on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vmworld2017/</link><description>Recent content in Vmworld2017 on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 14:19:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vmworld2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Network and Security keynote and NSX-T Architecture Deep Dive #NET1863BE</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-network-and-security-keynote-and-nsx-t-architecture-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 14:19:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-network-and-security-keynote-and-nsx-t-architecture-deep-dive/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="transforming-networking-and-security-for-the-digital-era"&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Transforming Networking and Security for the Digital Era &lt;a class="anchor" href="#transforming-networking-and-security-for-the-digital-era"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wednesday morning I attended the Network and Security keynote which, if I&amp;rsquo;m honest, I found to be a bit boring. To be fair, it was probably aimed at business leaders and maybe not those that are technical. There were three customer stories, but I would have liked to have heard much more about the problems that NSX solved for them specifically, rather than being datacenter transformation/cloud journey stories that included NSX. For me, it felt like there was nothing new in the presentation that hadn&amp;rsquo;t been covered in the general sessions. I would have liked to have seen and heard a bit more what the NSBU&amp;rsquo;s leadership think is going to be big over the next 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Intro to NSX-T Architecture #NET1510BE and NSX-T and Kubernetes #NET1522BE</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-intro-to-nsx-t-architecture-net1510be-and-nsx-t-and-kubernetes-net1522be/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 11:23:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-intro-to-nsx-t-architecture-net1510be-and-nsx-t-and-kubernetes-net1522be/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be no surprise, given &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/the-next-big-thing/"&gt;my impending move to the VMware PSO NSX Practice&lt;/a&gt;, that this morning I&amp;rsquo;ve been focussing on NSX-T. The two sessions I attended were the Introduction to NSX-T Architecture and Integrating NSX-T with Kubernetes. In a weird twist of scheduling, the Kubernetes session was before the introduction session, but it worked out OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the Kubernetes session really enjoyable and really felt like the speakers delivered a great overview of the integration and how they work together. I was pleasantly surprised with how fami&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;liar a lot of the concepts were, coming from an NSX-v and vRealize Automation background. It&amp;rsquo;s similar, but different! This is something I can really get my teeth into.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Day One General Session</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-day-one-general-session/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 11:17:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-day-one-general-session/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was honoured to be asked to be part of VMware&amp;rsquo;s CrowdChat for the general sessions this year, the idea being to live-tweet the General Session as it progressed. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to embed the session from CrowdChat itself below, but it might be blocked by your browser for running unsafe scripts. You can also see the commentary on the &lt;a href="https://www.crowdchat.net/VMworldDayOne"&gt;Day One General Session here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[http://www.via-cc.at/057s1]&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: vSAN Specialist and VMware {Code} Hackathon</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-vsan-specialist-and-vmware-code-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 10:41:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-vsan-specialist-and-vmware-code-hackathon/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vmware-vsan-2017-specialist-exam"&gt;VMware vSAN 2017 Specialist Exam &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vmware-vsan-2017-specialist-exam"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I always like to take a discounted exam at VMworld, this year I opted for the VMware vSAN 2017 Specialist exam, which was released a few weeks ago. Having delivered quite a few vSAN based solutions over the last few years, I was fairly confident in the blueprint. I am pleased to say that I passed the exam with a score of 422, way higher than I expected! I thought the exam itself was fair, and covered and tested the basics of vSAN well. You definitely need to know the supported architectures and how storage policies effect and apply to the data on vSAN.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>