<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blogengine on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/blogengine/</link><description>Recent content in blogengine on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 10:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/blogengine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I&amp;rsquo;ve changed my blogging software from BlogEngine.Net to WordPress</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/07/why-ive-changed-my-bogging-software-from-blogengine-net-to-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 10:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/07/why-ive-changed-my-bogging-software-from-blogengine-net-to-wordpress/</guid><description>Up until now, I’ve been using BlogEngine.Net as my blogging platform, and up until now I’ve been relatively happy with using it. One of the major drivers for me as a “Microsoft” person was to use something that is based on Microsoft technology – BlogEngine.Net is based (as the name suggests) on the .Net framework. I’m much happier these days writing limited amounts of C#.Net than I am with PHP.</description></item><item><title>Commenting re-enabled!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/06/commenting-re-enabled/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 16:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/06/commenting-re-enabled/</guid><description>Shhhh, don&amp;rsquo;t tell the spam-bots, but after a blissful month of having broken the comments system and not having enough time to fix it, I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got round to doing it! Comments will now work without errors - and the spam-bots should have a hard time getting past reCaptcha too!
At some point I&amp;rsquo;ll update to 1.6.1, but for now, I&amp;rsquo;m glad it&amp;rsquo;s working again!</description></item><item><title>BlogEngine.Net 1.6 is released – and I’ve upgraded! Also migrated to IIS 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/blogengine-net-1-6-is-released-%E2%80%93-and-i%E2%80%99ve-upgraded-also-migrated-to-iis-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/blogengine-net-1-6-is-released-%E2%80%93-and-i%E2%80%99ve-upgraded-also-migrated-to-iis-7/</guid><description>I’ve just upgraded to BE.Net 1.6, and I thought I’d migrate to GoDaddy’s IIS 7 servers at the same time. The theory is that this would be a an easy migration and I’d have the weekend to iron out any bugs. Not so.
After testing on my local IIS 7 and working perfectly, I uploaded the updates to my live blog and hit the “Migrate to IIS 7” button, which promises it will be completed in 24h.</description></item><item><title>New look and feel, revised categories and a traffic milestone!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/04/new-look-and-feel-revised-categories-and-a-traffic-milestone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2009 11:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/04/new-look-and-feel-revised-categories-and-a-traffic-milestone/</guid><description>Just a quick note to mark the fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the look and feel of the blog - hopefully with a bit more space and cleaner lines. It&amp;rsquo;s still teething, so report any bugs you see! I&amp;rsquo;ve had a bit of a cleanup of the categories to remove some of the less &amp;ldquo;category&amp;rdquo; like ones - they were being a bit blurred with the tags.
Lastly, I&amp;rsquo;m really quite amazed to say that my blog is now well over 100 visitors a day on a weekday, so thank you for visiting!</description></item><item><title>Code syntax highlighting in BlogEngine.Net</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/code-syntax-highlighting-in-blogengine-net/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2008 09:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/code-syntax-highlighting-in-blogengine-net/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just added some code syntax highlighting to this blog using SyntaxHighlighter and a great how-to article by Scott Dougherty this means that any code I post should look like this:
public static string SayHello(string name){ return String.Format("Hello, {0}!", name);} There are a few bugs at the moment, one being that tiny_mce is stripping linebreaks from the code posting (just a minor one) and the theme somehow removes the line numbers, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll find a way around them…somehow.</description></item><item><title>Posting to BlogEngine using Windows Live Writer</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/posting-to-blogengine-using-windows-live-writer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2008 15:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/posting-to-blogengine-using-windows-live-writer/</guid><description>One of my unpublished gripes with the DotNetNuke blog was that it was a pain to make work with WLW. One of the cool things with BE.Net is that it does work with WLW, not only that but it works well. Setup was a breeze and within 2 minutes I&amp;rsquo;m now writing my first post, including tags and categories (hit F2 if you&amp;rsquo;re trying to do that in WLW).
Now this is cool!</description></item><item><title>Force BlogEngine.Net to update its cache after an import</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/force-blogengine-net-to-update-its-cache-after-an-import/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2008 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/force-blogengine-net-to-update-its-cache-after-an-import/</guid><description>Well my first real post on BlogEngine.Net is…about BlogEngine.Net!
After running the import program from my old DotNetNuke blog I found that the importer had worked, but that the blog entries had not shown up. This was because the cache that BE.Net uses for the XML data files. Since I&amp;rsquo;m on a shared hosting I couldn&amp;rsquo;t just run an IISReset.exe, so I obviously needed a work around, and here it is:</description></item><item><title>Lament for WordPress and a call for a .Net WordPress killer</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/lament-for-wordpress-and-a-call-for-a-net-wordpress-killer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 22:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/lament-for-wordpress-and-a-call-for-a-net-wordpress-killer/</guid><description>I miss WordPress. I miss the fact that it would save my work periodically, and that if my session timed out while the I was writing a blog, it would be there when I logged back in as an unpublished daft. I miss having my categorised posts. I miss having tags to tell me what I&amp;rsquo;ve written about. Even Google seems to prefer my old blog, old pages that don&amp;rsquo;t exist are returned where these ones sit in anonymity.</description></item></channel></rss>