<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vRealize Log Insight on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vrealize-log-insight/</link><description>Recent content in vRealize Log Insight on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:26:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vrealize-log-insight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Log Insight services not starting after cluster IP changes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/log-insight-services-not-starting-after-cluster-ip-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:26:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/log-insight-services-not-starting-after-cluster-ip-changes/</guid><description>I ran into this problem at a customer site where all the Log Insight nodes were changed due to some IP address conflicts. I think the problem occurred because the IP addresses were all changed and the VMs shut down, without time for the application to update the node IPs.
The symptoms:
The web interface was down, a netstat -ano | grep -i “443” showed the service was listening _service loginsight status|restart|stop|start _hung and then timed out on the Master node The loginsight service was not running on the Worker nodes /var/log/loginsight/runtime.</description></item><item><title>Creating a vRealize Log Insight 2.5 cluster with Integrated Load Balancing</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/02/creating-a-vrealize-log-insight-2-5-cluster-with-integrated-load-balancing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 15:36:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/02/creating-a-vrealize-log-insight-2-5-cluster-with-integrated-load-balancing/</guid><description>vRealize Log Insight 2.5 improves on the clustering in previous versions with an Integrated Load Balancer (ILB) which allows you to distribute load across your cluster of Log Insight instances without actually needing an external load balancer. The advantage of this over an external load balancer is that the source IP is maintained which allows for easier analysis.
The minimum number of nodes in a cluster is three, the first node becomes the Master node and the other two become Worker nodes.</description></item><item><title>Installing and Configuring vCenter Log Insight</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-and-configuring-vcenter-log-insight/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 13:32:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-and-configuring-vcenter-log-insight/</guid><description>With the release of vCenter Log Insight Public Beta (http://communities.vmware.com/community/vmtn/vcenter/vcenter-log-insight) I thought I’d strike while the iron is hot and run through the installation and configuration.
Deploying the OVF This is such a bread and butter task that it doesn’t require more than a few words – it’s definitely worth looking at the Sizing PDF before you deploy (VMware-vCenter-Log-Insight-1.0-Beta-Virtual-Appliance-Sizing.pdf) as it’s not small even for a test installation. If you’re using less than the recommended 8GB RAM there are additional steps to change the heap size for performance.</description></item></channel></rss>