<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Networking on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/category/networking/</link><description>Recent content in Networking on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 08:21:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/category/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cisco SG300 – Static route not showing, but already exists?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/cisco-sg300-static-route-not-showing-but-already-exists/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 08:21:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/cisco-sg300-static-route-not-showing-but-already-exists/</guid><description>OK, so recently I had been setting up NSX in my lab and I wanted to create some static routes on my SG300-20 so I could access the VMs that were on my NSX network.
I added the VLAN I wanted to use and added a VLAN interface. All good.
I went ahead and added the static route as shown below.
As you can see it was applied successfully.
However looking at the static routes I could not see the route I had just added.</description></item><item><title>NST-T 2.0 Lab Build: Logical Router Configuration</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/12/nst-t-2-0-lab-build-logical-router-config/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 14:48:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/12/nst-t-2-0-lab-build-logical-router-config/</guid><description>Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!
Lab Environment This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.</description></item><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: Transport Zones and Transport Nodes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/10/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-transport-zones-and-transport-nodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 21:17:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/10/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-transport-zones-and-transport-nodes/</guid><description>Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!
Lab Environment This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.</description></item><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: Edge Installation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/10/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-edge-installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 15:41:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/10/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-edge-installation/</guid><description>Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!
Lab Environment This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.</description></item><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: Adding a vCenter Compute Manager and Preparing Hosts</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/10/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-adding-a-vcenter-compute-manager-and-preparing-hosts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 14:08:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/10/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-adding-a-vcenter-compute-manager-and-preparing-hosts/</guid><description>Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!
Lab Environment This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.</description></item><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: ESXi Host Preparation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-esxi-host-preparation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 15:16:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-esxi-host-preparation/</guid><description>Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!
Lab Environment This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.</description></item><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: Deploying Controller Cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-deploying-controller-cluster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 12:13:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-deploying-controller-cluster/</guid><description>Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!
Lab Environment This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.</description></item><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: Deploying NSX Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-deploying-nsx-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 13:42:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-deploying-nsx-manager/</guid><description>Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!
Lab Environment This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Intro to NSX-T Architecture #NET1510BE and NSX-T and Kubernetes #NET1522BE</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-intro-to-nsx-t-architecture-net1510be-and-nsx-t-and-kubernetes-net1522be/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 11:23:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-intro-to-nsx-t-architecture-net1510be-and-nsx-t-and-kubernetes-net1522be/</guid><description>It will be no surprise, given my impending move to the VMware PSO NSX Practice, that this morning I&amp;rsquo;ve been focussing on NSX-T. The two sessions I attended were the Introduction to NSX-T Architecture and Integrating NSX-T with Kubernetes. In a weird twist of scheduling, the Kubernetes session was before the introduction session, but it worked out OK.
I found the Kubernetes session really enjoyable and really felt like the speakers delivered a great overview of the integration and how they work together.</description></item><item><title>Lab notes: Upgrading vSphere 6.0 and NSX 6.2 to vSphere 6.5a and NSX 6.3</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/02/lab-notes-upgrading-vsphere-6-0-and-nsx-6-2-to-vsphere-6-5a-and-nsx-6-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 14:07:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/02/lab-notes-upgrading-vsphere-6-0-and-nsx-6-2-to-vsphere-6-5a-and-nsx-6-3/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been holding off upgrading my lab to vSphere 6.5 because NSX 6.2.x doesn&amp;rsquo;t support it. With the release of NSX 6.3 and vSphere 6.5a, I can now upgrade.
The sequence of the upgrade is slightly different to the generic one published by VMware because vSphere 6.5 isn&amp;rsquo;t supported with NSX 6.2. If follows that I need to upgrade NSX to 6.3 (which supports vSphere 6.0u2) before I can upgrade vSphere to 6.</description></item><item><title>Deploying ECMP with NSX for a Provider Logical Router</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/01/deploying-ecmp-for-nsx-provider-logical-router/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 15:14:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/01/deploying-ecmp-for-nsx-provider-logical-router/</guid><description>Equal Cost Multipathing (ECMP), for the vSphere admin, is ability to create routes with an equal cost, which allows multiple paths to the same network to be created and traffic can be distributed over those paths. This is good for a couple of reasons - firstly is availability. If we were to lose a host, and an NSX Edge, the route will time out quicker than NSX Edge High Availability - thus providing higher availability for our network traffic.</description></item><item><title>Deploying F5 BIG-IP Virtual Edition (VE) in AWS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/deploying-f5-big-ip-virtual-edition-ve-in-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/deploying-f5-big-ip-virtual-edition-ve-in-aws/</guid><description>Recently I was asked to develop some vRealize Orchestrator workflows against the F5 BIG-IP iControl REST API, but I was not able to test freely against a production appliance. After a lot of attempts to get in contact with F5 for a 90-day trial of the full version, or to purchase a lab license, I came up empty handed. The free version you can download from F5&amp;rsquo;s website is version 11.</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation instance – Configuring NetScaler Monitors</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-instance-configuring-netscaler-monitors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 09:24:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-instance-configuring-netscaler-monitors/</guid><description>Enter a name for the monitor, and leave the other parameters the same. Select the &amp;ldquo;Special Parameters&amp;rdquo; tab and configure the send string to the URL to monitor - e.g for the PSC SSO it&amp;rsquo;s going to be:
GET /websso/HealthStatus For the receive string, enter the expected response (&amp;ldquo;GREEN&amp;rdquo;). Click Create.
Assigning a NetScaler Monitor to a Service Assign the monitor to the PSC Services (or Service Groups) configured for PSC by opening the Configuration &amp;gt; Traffic Management &amp;gt; Load Balancing &amp;gt; Services page and selecting the PSC service for HTTPS/443 and clicking Edit.</description></item><item><title>Updating Cisco SG300 firmware the command line way</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/02/updating-cisco-sg300-firmware-the-command-line-way/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 15:14:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/02/updating-cisco-sg300-firmware-the-command-line-way/</guid><description>&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright wp-image-5603 size-medium&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2015/02/cisco_SG300-20_1.png&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;Cisco SG300-20&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;180&amp;rdquo; of upgrading my lab switch, which is the excellent Cisco SG300-20, I&amp;rsquo;ve not had a chance to update the firmware since it was released 6 months ago because of the downtime. For some reason I prefer configuring the SG300 from the command line - a hangover from my old networking days I suppose, but somehow it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel right to me to use the GUI!</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2014: VCP NV Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 11:56:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/</guid><description>It is with great relief that I can announce I have passed my VCP NV (Network Virtualisation) having been caught out by the difficulty of the exam and failing previously.
Exam Preparation I was fortunate to attend a VMware internal bootcamp (roughly equivalent to the ICM course) for NSX and have had experience deploying production NSX environments, so that is by far the best preparation. As always, the exam blueprint is crucial, you *have* to know all areas covered there.</description></item><item><title>Configuring a remote access SSL VPN with VMware NSX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/configuring-a-remote-access-ssl-vpn-with-vmware-nsx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 12:35:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/configuring-a-remote-access-ssl-vpn-with-vmware-nsx/</guid><description>The NSX Edge Gateway comes pre-armed with the ability to provide an SSL VPN for remote access into your network. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a new feature (SSL VPN was available in vCloud Networking and Security), but it&amp;rsquo;s worth a run through. I&amp;rsquo;m configuring remote access to my Lab, since it&amp;rsquo;s often useful to access it when on a client site, but traditional VPN connections are often blocked on corporate networks where HTTPS isn&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>vSphere Security: Advanced SSH Configurations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vsphere-security-advanced-ssh-configurations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 14:26:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vsphere-security-advanced-ssh-configurations/</guid><description>There are different schools of thought as to whether you should have SSH enabled on your hosts. VMware recommend it is disabled. With SSH disabled there is no possibility of attack, so that’s the “most secure” option. Of course in the real world there’s a balance between “most secure” and “usability” (e.g. the most secure host is powered off and physically isolated from the network, but you can’t run any workloads ).</description></item><item><title>VMware vCenter Linked Mode not supported through firewalls</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vmware-vcenter-linked-mode-not-supported-through-firewalls/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 15:28:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vmware-vcenter-linked-mode-not-supported-through-firewalls/</guid><description>This article originally started off life as a record of how I managed to get this working, as a lot of my posts do, but this time it appears I am foiled.
Last week, I had 3 vCenter Servers that appeared to be happily talking to each other in Linked Mode sharing a singe Multi-site SSO domain without any real issues. I had a single-pane-of-glass view of all 3 and I could manage them all from the one client.</description></item><item><title>Site to Site VPN Tunnel traffic flow problems</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/site-to-site-vpn-tunnel-traffic-flow-problems/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 10:58:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/site-to-site-vpn-tunnel-traffic-flow-problems/</guid><description>Firewalls being used – Sonicwall 3500 &amp;amp; Cisco 506e
Several months ago we relocated and it was then necessary to setup a Site to Site VPN tunnel with another network. (In this instance the other network was not directly managed by us)
Upon the creation of the tunnel and after successful traffic tests all looked well. However after several hours or less in some cases traffic stopped flowing yet both firewalls reported the tunnel as “up”.</description></item><item><title>Installing a TMG Enterprise Management Server and Migrating and Existing Standalone Array: Part 1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/06/installing-a-tmg-enterprise-management-server-and-migrating-and-existing-standalone-array-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 11:21:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/06/installing-a-tmg-enterprise-management-server-and-migrating-and-existing-standalone-array-part-1/</guid><description>This is my current scenario: there are two existing servers in a stand-alone array - TMG01 and TMG02, and over in a DR site there is a new server (TMG03) that is in the process of being built. To comply with DR, all 3 servers must have their configurations up to date, however there is no direct communication allowed between the two DMZs, so simply adding to the new server as an array member is not possible.</description></item><item><title>Configuring a Guest wireless network with restricted access to Production VLANs</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/06/configuring-guest-wireless-network-restricted-access-production-vlans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 16:42:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/06/configuring-guest-wireless-network-restricted-access-production-vlans/</guid><description>It’s a fairly common requirement – setting up a guest WiFi network that is secure from the rest of your LAN. You need a secure WLAN access for the domain laptops which has full access to the Server and Client VLANs, but you also need a guest WLAN for visitors to the office which only allows internet access. Since the budget is limited, this must all be accomplished via a single Access Point – for this article, the access point is a Cisco WAP4410N.</description></item><item><title>Configuring SSTP VPN connections to Threat Management Gateway 2010</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/configuring-sstp-vpn-connections-threat-management-gateway-2010/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 17:31:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/configuring-sstp-vpn-connections-threat-management-gateway-2010/</guid><description>SSTP or SSL VPN connections are great for people working on client sites or behind very restrictive firewalls – they only require HTTPS (port 443) to be open to be able to connect. Unfortunately, you need to be running Windows 7 or Server 2008 (or newer) in order to make use of them. Threat Management Gateway 2010 is one option for an SSL VPN endpoint.
SSTP VPN Requirements Clients must be Windows 7/Server 2008 or newer Certificate – either commercial or an internal Certificate Authority Published CRL – SSTP clients check for the Certificate Revocation List of the CA If you already have an SSL listener (e.</description></item><item><title>In-depth: Installing and Configuring Threat Management Gateway 2010 in a Network Load Balanced Array</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/11/in-depth-installing-and-configuring-threat-management-gateway-2010-in-a-network-load-balanced-array/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 16:35:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/11/in-depth-installing-and-configuring-threat-management-gateway-2010-in-a-network-load-balanced-array/</guid><description>In this post I will be installing a TMG Array as a “back firewall” behind a hardware firewall. The Array will consist of two virtual servers, TMG01 and TMG02 which each have 3 NICs. One NIC will be dedicated to the LAN network, accessible internally. One NIC will be dedicated to the DMZ network, accessible to the outside world on a static mapped IP. The third NIC will be a dedicated intra-array communications NIC as per Microsoft’s recommendation.</description></item><item><title>Managing ESXi 4.1 with vMA 4.1 on VMware Workstation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/10/managing-esxi-4-1-with-vma-4-1-on-vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 21:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/10/managing-esxi-4-1-with-vma-4-1-on-vmware-workstation/</guid><description>vMA is available as a Virtual Appliance (OVF) from VMware. To install it on VMware Workstation 7, open Workstation and select Import or Export to import a new OVF, the URL for the latest OVF for vMA is on the vMA download page
As per this article on virtualkenneth.com, you need to edit the VMX file to change the SCSI card and OS type, otherwise you’ll have a kernel panic on boot.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Server 2008 R2 Core Series: Network Settings</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-network-settings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 14:22:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-network-settings/</guid><description>So, you’ve installed a new server with Server 2008 R2 Core – what next? Logging on, you’re presented with a shiny command prompt, you can run notepad or regedit…but aside from that, where do you go from there? In the next few series of posts I’ll hopefully point out the basics, and some not so basics!
Using the Server Configuration Tool The server configuration tool (sconfig.cmd) is provided in R2 for some of the basic setup tasks, so you can run that by issuing the “sconfig” command.</description></item><item><title>Teaming NICs with ESX 3.5 and Cisco Switches in an aggregate.</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/teaming-nics-with-esx-3-5-and-cisco-switches-in-an-aggregate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/teaming-nics-with-esx-3-5-and-cisco-switches-in-an-aggregate/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the setup. We have a core switch of 2 Cisco 3750s, connected together for fault tolerance as a single logical switch; we also have several ESX 3.5 hosts with 4 Gigabit Ethernet NICs installed each. The Virtual Machines will all be on VLAN 8 (reserved for internal servers) and the VMKernel will be on VLAN 107 (reserved for VMKernel traffic like VMotion). I want to create a load balanced, fault tolerant aggregate of these four NICs over the Core Switch.</description></item><item><title>DCDIAG /TEST:DNS fails with errors regarding root hint servers</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/dcdiag-testdns-fails-with-errors-regarding-root-hint-servers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 16:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/dcdiag-testdns-fails-with-errors-regarding-root-hint-servers/</guid><description>I recently resolved an ongoing DNS issue where the Active Directory Integrated DNS was loaded in both the Domain and the DomainDNSZones partition of AD - this is a separate issue and should be resolved differently. My problem when I tried to verify that the fixed DNS setup had propogated around my domain controllers, DC01 and DC02. DC01 kept failing &amp;ldquo;DCDIAG /TEST:DNS&amp;rdquo; with errors regarding the root hint servers. Googling about it was clear that a lot of people were suffering the same issue, but no article I read had correctly identified the solution.</description></item><item><title>SSH remote console to ESXi server</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/12/ssh-remote-console-to-esxi-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/12/ssh-remote-console-to-esxi-server/</guid><description>Having recently installed an ESXi server, I am getting to grips with the management and administration of it, one of the things that I wanted to be able to do was connect to the remote terminal through SSH.
I downloaded my SSH client of choice, PuTTY, and set about connecting, however the server refused the connection. It seems that SSH is not enabled out of the box for ESXi and you need to go through some steps to get there - I found some helpful hints here.</description></item><item><title>Cisco ASA – ASDM “cannot load configuration”</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/11/cisco-asa-asdm-cannot-load-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2008 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/11/cisco-asa-asdm-cannot-load-configuration/</guid><description>I was configuring our new Cisco ASA 5510 firewall today, as part of a major infrastructure upgrade. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty comfortable with the Cisco IOS, but I still prefer the GUI for the basic set up, using command line to tweak the finer or more complex configurations. However, straight out of the box, I had a very hard time getting the ASDM to load. Being familiar with the PDM from the PIX range of firewalls, I should have guessed the problem straight away.</description></item></channel></rss>