<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>South West UK on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/south-west-uk/</link><description>Recent content in South West UK on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 15:02:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/south-west-uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>South West UK VMUG ready to launch! – 18th February</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/south-west-uk-vmug-ready-to-launch-18th-february/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 15:02:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/south-west-uk-vmug-ready-to-launch-18th-february/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="so-what-is-vmug"&gt;So what is VMUG?&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2013/09/vmug-logo.jpg" alt=""&gt; &lt;a class="anchor" href="#so-what-is-vmug"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The VMware User Group (VMUG) is an independent, global, customer-led organization, created to maximize members’ use of VMware and partner solutions through knowledge sharing, training, collaboration, and events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presently there are five VMUGs in the UK including the latest addition - South West UK VMUG - @swukvmug&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-am-i-involved-and-why-should-you-come-along"&gt;Why am I involved and why should you come along? &lt;a class="anchor" href="#why-am-i-involved-and-why-should-you-come-along"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had been using VMware products for over 3 years and after joining twitter it was very clear to me the VMware user community was very friendly and also very helpful, it was there I learned about &lt;a href="http://www.vmug.com/" title="VMware user group"&gt;VMUG&lt;/a&gt; so the chance to meet and greet other users like myself and of course learn from the &amp;ldquo;rockstars&amp;rdquo; was to good an opportunity to pass up, after attending several meetings I was completely sold.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>New VMUG Launched – South West VMUG UK</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/new-vmug-launched-south-west-vmug-uk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 09:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/new-vmug-launched-south-west-vmug-uk/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The South West VMware User Group launches in the UK, bringing the best of VMware and the user community to The West, South West and South Wales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leadership team is pleased to announce the South West VMware User Group (VMUG). Meeting in Bristol at the crossroads to the South West, The West Country, South Wales and the Midlands, meetings will begin early in 2014, to bring together virtualization customers, end users and enthusiasts in an informal social setting for discussion, learning and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>