<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>policies on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/policies/</link><description>Recent content in policies on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 09:03:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/policies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Part 7 : Working with Alerts &amp; Symptoms</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vrops-webinar-2016-part-7-working-with-alerts-symptoms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 09:03:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vrops-webinar-2016-part-7-working-with-alerts-symptoms/</guid><description>Time to release the recording for the latest part of the vROps Webinar Series. We completed the 7th session of the series where we spoke about vRealize Operations Manager Alerts and Symptoms.
Alerts as we all know would always remain the heart and soul for the operations teams to run the data centers, whether old school or the modern software defined.
In all cases you need alerts and more importantly you need meaningful and actionable alerts.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 2 : Understanding vROps Policies</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-part-2-understanding-vrops-policies-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 10:31:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-part-2-understanding-vrops-policies-2/</guid><description>year long commitment of providing quality content on vRealize Operations Manager.
Please remember that this is an introductory session to policies and we intend to go deeper into policies in the next session in the month of March, where we deep dive into more details around capacity planning with vRealize Operations Manager. You will hear more about that as we progress into the next month.
A big thank you to Sunny Dua for presenting this session and Iwan Rahabok to provide all the lab equipment required for live demonstrations….</description></item><item><title>vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 2 : Understanding Policies.</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-2-understanding-policies-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 14:17:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-2-understanding-policies-2/</guid><description>vROps Webinar Series 2016 is back and as promised during the last session we would now take you to the world of vRealize Operations Policies Policies.
What is a Policy??
&amp;ldquo;A policy is a deliberate system of principles to guide decisions and achieve rational outcomes. A policy is a statement of intent, and is implemented as a procedure or protocol&amp;rdquo;
Source - Wikipedia
While the role of vRealize Operations Manager is to help you with Performance &amp;amp; Capacity Management of your Software Defined Datacenter (SDDC), it is important that you feed in the guiding principles of your Business Environment into vROps to get the rational outcomes.</description></item></channel></rss>