<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hybrid Cloud on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/hybrid-cloud/</link><description>Recent content in Hybrid Cloud on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 13:26:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/hybrid-cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adding a vCloud Air (PAYG/Gen2) instance to vRealize Orchestrator as a vCloud Director host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 13:26:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Big thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pipoe2h" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Jose Luis Gomez
&lt;/a&gt; for this solution, his response to my tweet was spot on and invaluable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to configure vCloud Air as a vCloud Director host in vRealize Orchestrator in order to create some custom resource actions for Day 2 operations in vRealize Automation. What I found was that there&amp;rsquo;s *very* little information out there on how to do this, and I ended up writing my own custom resource mapping for the virtual machines to VCAC:VirtualMachine objects - at least that way I could add my resource action. But this still didn&amp;rsquo;t expose the vCloud Director functionality for those machines. To do this I needed vCloud Air added as a vCloud Director host.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCHS – first impressions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vchs-first-impressions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:39:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vchs-first-impressions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/02/vCHS-Powered.png" alt=""&gt;In case you missed it VMware have now released &lt;a href="http://www.vmwareforyou.com/vchs/" title="vCHS" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; vCHS
&lt;/a&gt; (VMware vCloud Hybrid Service) in Europe! The first data center residing in Slough with more data centers planned across Europe in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in an SME that has several existing vSphere environments this was of real interest, as the need to scale out quickly from our Private clouds is rapidly becoming a requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having already spoken to VMware on the phone to get a rough idea on options and costs I decided to take a look at the &lt;a href="http://labs.hol.vmware.com/" title="Hands on Labs" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Hands-on-labs
&lt;/a&gt; to see how easy it really is to use and migrate VMs from an existing private cloud to vCHS.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>