<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Book Review on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/book-review/</link><description>Recent content in Book Review on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 14:36:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/book-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Review: VMware vSphere 6.5 Host Resources Deep Dive</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/book-review-vmware-vsphere-6-5-host-resources-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 14:36:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/book-review-vmware-vsphere-6-5-host-resources-deep-dive/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Host Resources Deep Dive book by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/frankdenneman"&gt;Frank Denneman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NHagoort"&gt;Niels Hagoort&lt;/a&gt; has been one of the most widely anticipated books in the VMware community - previous deep dive books by Frank (co-authored with Duncan Epping), tantalising blog posts and captivating presentations have whet the appetite for the last year or so. Having sat through some of these presentations at VMUGs and VMworld I can tell you the depth and understanding that the authors bring to the table is immense.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Book review: Networking for VMware Administrators</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/book-review-networking-for-vmware-administrators/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 09:34:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/book-review-networking-for-vmware-administrators/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I recently got my hands on a copy* of Chris Wahl and Steve Pantol’s Networking for VMware Administrators and was very keen to read it – especially given the reputation of the authors. I came to the book as someone who is at CCNA level (although now expired) and someone who regularly designs complex VMware networks using standard and distributed switches. I would class myself as having a fairly decent understanding of networking, though not a networking specialist.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>