<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>exam on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/exam/</link><description>Recent content in exam on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 22:44:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/exam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – VCAP6-DCA Deploy Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-vcap6-dca-deploy-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 22:44:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-vcap6-dca-deploy-exam-experience/</guid><description>Greetings from Day 1 of VMworld US 2016!
Every year I try and make use of the VMworld discount at the exam centre, and this year was no exception I sat the VCAP6-DCV Deploy exam, and results are still pending! Overall it&amp;rsquo;s a good exam, there was very little of the spelling and grammatical errors I&amp;rsquo;ve complained about in the past, performance was OK and the level of difficulty was good.</description></item><item><title>#VCDX-CMA 204</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vcdx-cma-204/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 11:51:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vcdx-cma-204/</guid><description>Apologies in advance if this is post is a jumbled nonsense, I&amp;rsquo;m still way too excited!
This morning I woke to the news that I have passed my VCDX-CMA!
This was my second attempt at VCDX and although the first failure was a painful experience, the lessons learned from it were invaluable to take into the defence the second time around. Failing doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be a negative experience - if there is one thing that I will take from the VCDX program it is that there is ALWAYS more I need to learn, and I can always do better.</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: VCIX-NV Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 16:58:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</guid><description>For the last few years at VMworld I’ve taken advantage of the discounted exam price and booked a “have-a-go” exam – typically an exam I’ve been wanting to do but not necessarily had the time I wanted to study for it. Since I have been fairly immersed in the NSX world for the last week, sitting in an NSX design and deploy class and surrounded by some very smart networking guys, I changed my “have-a-go” exam from the VCP6-CMA to the VCIX-NV.</description></item><item><title>My VCAP5-DCD experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/my-vcap5-dcd-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 08:59:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/my-vcap5-dcd-experience/</guid><description>A few months ago I decided to tackle the VCAP5-DCD exam and when booking I gave myself 2 months to study before the date of the exam.
I was keenly aware that at least in this calendar year the VCAP5-DCD exam and undergone some changes E.G. it no longer had multiple choice questions (think VCP5-DCV in terms of format)
There was a wealth of knowledge out there from people whom had either passed/failed or were currently studying so it didn&amp;rsquo;t take too long to get an understanding of what disciplines/knowledge VMware were looking for in the exam.</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2014: VCP NV Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 11:56:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/</guid><description>It is with great relief that I can announce I have passed my VCP NV (Network Virtualisation) having been caught out by the difficulty of the exam and failing previously.
Exam Preparation I was fortunate to attend a VMware internal bootcamp (roughly equivalent to the ICM course) for NSX and have had experience deploying production NSX environments, so that is by far the best preparation. As always, the exam blueprint is crucial, you *have* to know all areas covered there.</description></item><item><title>VCP5-IaaS &amp;ndash; Exam experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/vcp5-iaas-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 16:01:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/vcp5-iaas-exam-experience/</guid><description>So this morning I took the VMware Infrastructure as a Service exam (VCPVCD510) to gain the VCP5-Cloud qualification. The IaaS exam is available for existing VCP5-DCV holders to take without any other pre-requisites. I am very pleased to say I finished the exam in good time and scored 466/500 – the pass mark is 300.
The Exam The exam itself is 85 multiple choice questions, and gives you 90 minutes to do them.</description></item></channel></rss>