<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows Server on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/windows-server/</link><description>Recent content in Windows Server on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2010 10:07:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/windows-server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unable to access admin shares (c$, d$, ADMIN$, IPC$) on Windows Server 2008 in a Workgroup</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/06/unable-to-access-admin-shares-c-d-admin-ipc-on-windows-server-2008-in-a-workgroup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2010 10:07:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/06/unable-to-access-admin-shares-c-d-admin-ipc-on-windows-server-2008-in-a-workgroup/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you have a Windows Server 2008 box in a workgroup that you require access to one of the admin shares, it can be a little more complicated than with Server 2003. In my case, we had a SQL server on the back end which was trying to access the web server in the DMZ using PSExec.exe to remotely run a process. Executing PSExec and passing the correct credentials failed with “Access is Denied”.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Trace cables the easy way with Cisco CDP on Windows</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/trace-cables-the-easy-way-with-cisco-cdp-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 11:58:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/trace-cables-the-easy-way-with-cisco-cdp-on-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;No matter how good your network diagrams are, sometimes you need to verify the port your server/desktop is in. Cisco Discovery Protocol is a great tool for network admins when you need to quickly map routers and switches, and if you’ve got an ESX server connected you’ll see that it picks up CDP info too – but the vast majority of my managed systems are Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how to use &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;TCPDUMP by Micro Olap&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; to extend that functionality to your Windows boxes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>DCDIAG /TEST:DNS fails with errors regarding root hint servers</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/dcdiag-testdns-fails-with-errors-regarding-root-hint-servers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 16:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/dcdiag-testdns-fails-with-errors-regarding-root-hint-servers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently resolved an ongoing DNS issue where the Active Directory Integrated DNS was loaded in both the Domain and the DomainDNSZones partition of AD - this is a separate issue and should be resolved differently. My problem when I tried to verify that the fixed DNS setup had propogated around my domain controllers, DC01 and DC02. DC01 kept failing &amp;ldquo;DCDIAG /TEST:DNS&amp;rdquo; with errors regarding the root hint servers. Googling about it was clear that a lot of people were suffering the same issue, but no article I read had correctly identified the solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>