<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vmworld on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vmworld/</link><description>Recent content in vmworld on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vmworld/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My VMworld 2021 Tips and Top Picks</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/08/my-vmworld-2021-tips-and-top-picks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/08/my-vmworld-2021-tips-and-top-picks/</guid><description>I can tell from the ever-increasing urgency of emails from the events team that VMworld 2021 is just around the corner!
Virtual conference event fatigue is real. I have attended and presented at many since the pandemic began, with varying levels of engagement. As an introvert, I can&amp;rsquo;t quite believe I&amp;rsquo;m saying this, but I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to get pack to meeting up with people in the real world!
The value of a conference is super-charged by the mix of dedicated time, networking opportunities and quality live content.</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2020 and VMware {Code} Connect!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/09/vmworld-2020-and-vmware-code-connect/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/09/vmworld-2020-and-vmware-code-connect/</guid><description>Where can you find me at VMworld 2020 VMworld 2020 - possible together VMworld 2020 is fast approaching (Sept 29th-October 1st), and in case you hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard, it online and free! If you struggle getting funding for tickets and flights normally, this could be a golden opportunity to get involved! Register for VMworld 2020 for FREE here! Please come and talk to me for my round table session, it will be awkward by myself!</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2020 and VMware {Code} Connect!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/09/vmworld-2020-and-vmware-code-connect/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/09/vmworld-2020-and-vmware-code-connect/</guid><description>Where can you find me at VMworld 2020 VMworld 2020 - possible together VMworld 2020 is fast approaching (Sept 29th-October 1st), and in case you hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard, it online and free! If you struggle getting funding for tickets and flights normally, this could be a golden opportunity to get involved! Register for VMworld 2020 for FREE here! Please come and talk to me for my round table session, it will be awkward by myself!</description></item><item><title>Things we can look forward to seeing in #vROps 7.0</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/things-we-can-look-forward-to-seeing-in-vrops-7-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 11:51:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/things-we-can-look-forward-to-seeing-in-vrops-7-0/</guid><description>I did a quick search online and could not find a collated list so, by way of a quick summary from all the VMworld 2018 announcements and comments my good friend and PM for vRealize Operations Sunny Dua has made, I have collated a list of what we can expect to see in the next iteration of vROps (7.0). The list is in no order of interest or importance, some of the mentioned improvements have been long standing requests so enjoy and get hyped (I know I am).</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Wednesday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-4-wednesday/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 17:30:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-4-wednesday/</guid><description>This was as I expected, the busiest day sessions wise for me. There was so much good stuff I had to be a little ruthless on what I wanted and or needed to attend while also wanting to get into the solutions exchange.
Also at the end of the day the customer appreciate party was scheduled so that was something I was looking forward to a great deal (Hint - Kaiser Chiefs)</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Network and Security keynote and NSX-T Architecture Deep Dive #NET1863BE</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-network-and-security-keynote-and-nsx-t-architecture-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 14:19:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-network-and-security-keynote-and-nsx-t-architecture-deep-dive/</guid><description>Transforming Networking and Security for the Digital Era Wednesday morning I attended the Network and Security keynote which, if I&amp;rsquo;m honest, I found to be a bit boring. To be fair, it was probably aimed at business leaders and maybe not those that are technical. There were three customer stories, but I would have liked to have heard much more about the problems that NSX solved for them specifically, rather than being datacenter transformation/cloud journey stories that included NSX.</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Tuesday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-3-tuesday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-3-tuesday/</guid><description>I managed to dodge the rainstorms in the morning before arriving, the hotel being just across the road from the Venue was a huge help (Thank you Xtravirt)
The main session was great particularly HCX announcement and the VR admin demo.
I then hit the solutions exchange as soon as it opened. There are all the usual suspects there -except- Cisco (anyone know why?)
It was also great to see the guys from Blue Medora.</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Sunday and Monday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-1-and-2-sunday-and-monday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 13:29:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-1-and-2-sunday-and-monday/</guid><description>Sunday Arriving in early on Sunday as the local flight choices are more limited from Bristol than perhaps a larger Airport, very fortunate to have a hotel so close to the VMworld venue, perhaps not so great for the evening activities but I am happy with it this way around.
Other than registration (4pm-8pm) and hopefully catching up with a few folk who have also arrived early.
In the evening I had the pleasure to meet many awesome people from the vCommunity.</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Intro to NSX-T Architecture #NET1510BE and NSX-T and Kubernetes #NET1522BE</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-intro-to-nsx-t-architecture-net1510be-and-nsx-t-and-kubernetes-net1522be/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 11:23:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-intro-to-nsx-t-architecture-net1510be-and-nsx-t-and-kubernetes-net1522be/</guid><description>It will be no surprise, given my impending move to the VMware PSO NSX Practice, that this morning I&amp;rsquo;ve been focussing on NSX-T. The two sessions I attended were the Introduction to NSX-T Architecture and Integrating NSX-T with Kubernetes. In a weird twist of scheduling, the Kubernetes session was before the introduction session, but it worked out OK.
I found the Kubernetes session really enjoyable and really felt like the speakers delivered a great overview of the integration and how they work together.</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Day One General Session</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-day-one-general-session/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 11:17:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-day-one-general-session/</guid><description>I was honoured to be asked to be part of VMware&amp;rsquo;s CrowdChat for the general sessions this year, the idea being to live-tweet the General Session as it progressed. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to embed the session from CrowdChat itself below, but it might be blocked by your browser for running unsafe scripts. You can also see the commentary on the Day One General Session here.
[http://www.via-cc.at/057s1]</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: vSAN Specialist and VMware {Code} Hackathon</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-vsan-specialist-and-vmware-code-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 10:41:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-vsan-specialist-and-vmware-code-hackathon/</guid><description>VMware vSAN 2017 Specialist Exam I always like to take a discounted exam at VMworld, this year I opted for the VMware vSAN 2017 Specialist exam, which was released a few weeks ago. Having delivered quite a few vSAN based solutions over the last few years, I was fairly confident in the blueprint. I am pleased to say that I passed the exam with a score of 422, way higher than I expected!</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Before I go…</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-before-i-go/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 13:35:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-before-i-go/</guid><description>**a non-VMware employee! I am very much looking forward to meeting friends old and new during the week, so if you see me come say hi!
Where can you find me?
During the day I&amp;rsquo;m likely to be found in the bloggers area, or hanging around the vBrownbag stage, when I&amp;rsquo;m not in a session. Monday evening I&amp;rsquo;ll be leading a fearless team of hackers for the VMware {Code} Hackathon, hoping to create something cool!</description></item><item><title>Looking forward to #VMworld EMEA 2017</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/looking-forward-to-vmworld-emea-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 09:30:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/looking-forward-to-vmworld-emea-2017/</guid><description>Having missed last years VMworld I feel very ready for attending the EMEA VMworld in Barcelona.
I almost felt annoyed about missing last year as the big announcements really caused a stir in the community and wider afield. (VMware on AWS) The announcements from the US VMworld this year were equally exciting so I am very keen to hear what else VMware has planned to reveal in a Barcelona.
I have put a good deal of effort into planning what I will be doing and attending to maximise my time there without burnout (Veterans I hear you laughing)</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2016 – Day 2 workshops and sessions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-2-workshops-and-sessions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 16:50:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-2-workshops-and-sessions/</guid><description>vRealize Automation vExperts Workshop I attended a workshop with Jad El Zein in Barcelona last year and it was one of the best sessions I attended, especially as it was just on the news of vRA7&amp;rsquo;s release. This workshop was this year&amp;rsquo;s equivelant, but because the session included a lot of people just getting started with vRA a lot of the time was taken to explain what vRA does, so there was no real time for the more in depth details on the new features that are coming (some already announced and in Tech Preview).</description></item><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – VCAP6-DCA Deploy Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-vcap6-dca-deploy-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 22:44:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-vcap6-dca-deploy-exam-experience/</guid><description>Greetings from Day 1 of VMworld US 2016!
 Every year I try and make use of the VMworld discount at the exam centre, and this year was no exception I sat the VCAP6-DCV Deploy exam, and results are still pending! Overall it&amp;rsquo;s a good exam, there was very little of the spelling and grammatical errors I&amp;rsquo;ve complained about in the past, performance was OK and the level of difficulty was good.</description></item><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – Day 0, #vmunderground opening acts, #beVCDX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-0-vmunderground-opening-acts-bevcdx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 17:18:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-0-vmunderground-opening-acts-bevcdx/</guid><description>I landed in Las Vegas about 9:30PM local time on Saturday evening, having not executed my plan to sleep on the flight! I had planned to sleep on the Toronto to Vegas leg, which would have meant I could head over to the Sips and Stogies pre-event, however a very rowdy hen do a couple of rows away meant that I didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep at all, so I grabbed a taxi down to my hotel, the Excalibur, and got myself checked in.</description></item><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – My session picks</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vmworld-2016-my-session-picks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 11:13:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vmworld-2016-my-session-picks/</guid><description>In my post yesterday I promised to post my VMworld session picks, so here it is! I have filled my schedule, and even added some alternate picks when there were too many good sessions to go for. My session picks are focussing around:
vRealize Automation NSX VSAN PowerCLI, APIs and automation Now, before anyone tells me I&amp;rsquo;ve picked too many and I won&amp;rsquo;t make it to all of them - I know!</description></item><item><title>Heading to Las Vegas! #VMworld 2016</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/heading-to-vmworld-us-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 10:24:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/heading-to-vmworld-us-2016/</guid><description>I’ve been very fortunate to be able to go to VMworld Europe for the past 3 years, mainly thanks to the vExpert program and the availability of the blogger pass. This year I knew that I wouldn’t be able to get to Barcelona because of work, so I thought I’d apply for a VMworld US blogger pass - I’m very excited to have been given one! As with previous years, I'll be blogging at least once a day with my thoughts and any useful info I've gleaned - I definitely don't want to take the pass for granted!</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015 – Days 3 and 4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-2015-days-3-and-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 21:09:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-2015-days-3-and-4/</guid><description>Wednesday I had lined up several sessions so I was quick to get along to my first session - Operational Remediation with vRealize Operations… Tying it All Together - #MGT5735. The session was excellent and gave a great overview and introduction to what is possible with remediation in vROps 6.1. Big thanks to Chima Njaka for this session.
Aside from a few other sessions I spent a lot of the afternoon in the VMUG lounge with my colleagues from @xtravirt (see pic below) and meeting lots of other folk from the around the globe (this is what makes this conference so very great for me), putting faces to twitter handles for the first time and so on.</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: vRealize Automation 7 Briefing Notes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 08:20:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</guid><description>@vaficionado) – if that list of names doesn’t fill you with confidence for vRA.Next, then I suggest you follow them on twitter and trust me that it’s a crack team!
 So, my highlights:
Completely automated deployment…almost. The deployment of appliances and installation of IaaS components and pre-requisites will be wizard driven, the Window Servers will need to exist and have an agent installed, and the MSSQL server will also need to be installed.</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015 – Day 2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-day-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 06:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-day-2/</guid><description>The first full day of VMworld after PEX was a busy one.After the keynote (highlights were the docker announcements) I was on “booth babe” duty at the VMUG lounge. It was great to meet so many folk who were existing VMUG members and leaders as well as prospective new members. If you are at VMworld this year you should definitely stop by!
After lunch I hit the solutions exchange to catch up with a few vendors whom I had a few queries for also took the time to collect the #vExpert hoodie from @simplivity and the #vExpert tile from Tegile (thank you!</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: Pre-event and Partner Day</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-pre-event-and-partner-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 08:36:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-pre-event-and-partner-day/</guid><description>My trip started with a farcical attempt to fly – my 11:50am flight on Sunday didn’t leave ‘til 3:30pm, but in light of William Lam’s travel woes on the same day, I don’t think I’ll complain to heavily. After a quick stop off at the Fira to register and grab my VMworld bag and I headed off to meet DefinIT co-author Simon (@simoneady) at our AirBnB apartment (which, by the way is awesome and a whole load cheaper than a hotel).</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: VCIX-NV Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 16:58:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</guid><description>For the last few years at VMworld I’ve taken advantage of the discounted exam price and booked a “have-a-go” exam – typically an exam I’ve been wanting to do but not necessarily had the time I wanted to study for it. Since I have been fairly immersed in the NSX world for the last week, sitting in an NSX design and deploy class and surrounded by some very smart networking guys, I changed my “have-a-go” exam from the VCP6-CMA to the VCIX-NV.</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015 – Just getting started</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-just-getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 14:02:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-just-getting-started/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s PEX (Partner Exchange Day) at VMworld today so its busy but not the Tuesday (first day) of VMworld busy, last night saw a fantastic #vRockstar party and a great chance to meet and have a beer with many vTwitteratti.
     Today of course has been largely overshadowed by the big new concerning the Dell announcement to purchase EMC which has triggered a great deal of discussion and a healthy amount of banter and snark!</description></item><item><title>My first VMworld..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/my-first-vmworld/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 12:38:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/my-first-vmworld/</guid><description>As this was my first VMworld I am not ashamed to say I was really stoked about attending, many of my peers have attended in the past and were going to attend.
I flew in on the Sunday evening so that I could register early on Monday for partner day, however I did miss the chance to attend what turned out to be a very popular and very full Rockstar event on the Sunday evening.</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2014: Day Three and wrap-up</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-three-and-wrap-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 09:05:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-three-and-wrap-up/</guid><description>*This post was meant to be published on Friday, VMworld Sleep Deprivation meant I didn&amp;rsquo;t click the button!*
This is the last post and a bit of a wrap up on my VMworld 2014 series!
There isn&amp;rsquo;t a keynote on day three, and there&amp;rsquo;s definitely a &amp;ldquo;winding down&amp;rdquo; feel as people tend to arrive later (if at all) and many are…feeling the effects of the previous night shall we say! That said, every session I wanted to attend was still fully booked and it was a case of queuing for the spare seats.</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2014: Day Two</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-two/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 08:02:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-two/</guid><description>Day two of VMworld kicked off with a keynote session which traditionally includes demos of all that&amp;rsquo;s new. It was a well presented session with a glimpse into the sysadmin&amp;rsquo;s future with a demo of vCOps alerts popping up on Google glass. Since the sessions are available online I won&amp;rsquo;t go into detail, but it was worth a watch (if you didn&amp;rsquo;t watch the US one).
My morning consisted of preparations for the VCP NV (NSX) exam, which I detailed in a previous post.</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2014: VCP NV Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 11:56:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/</guid><description>It is with great relief that I can announce I have passed my VCP NV (Network Virtualisation) having been caught out by the difficulty of the exam and failing previously.
Exam Preparation I was fortunate to attend a VMware internal bootcamp (roughly equivalent to the ICM course) for NSX and have had experience deploying production NSX environments, so that is by far the best preparation. As always, the exam blueprint is crucial, you *have* to know all areas covered there.</description></item><item><title>VMWorld 2014: Day One</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-one/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 08:21:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-one/</guid><description>After a bit of a rocky start (missed my flight and the partner day due to tendonitis in my knee) I arrived in Barcelona for my 2nd VMworld Europe. I headed straight from the airport to the PernixData party and caught up with the rest of the Xtravirt guys.
Tuesday morning started as ever with a keynote address. It was a little disappointing, but not unexpected, that there were no real announcements or reveals in the keynote.</description></item><item><title>VMworld Europe 2013 &amp;ndash; Day 2, VCAP5-DCD Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-day-2-vcap5-dcd-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 15:45:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-day-2-vcap5-dcd-exam-experience/</guid><description>Today was always going to be a bit of a funny day as I scheduled the VCAP5-DCD exam for 10am this morning. I am happy to say that I passed! I’m a bit light on VMworld to report today, so forgive my DCD experience to pad it out!
Preparation I have to confess my prep for this exam was light – I literally only watched the TrainSignal course by Scott Lowe (@scott_lowe) and just about finished that last night in the hotel!</description></item><item><title>VMworld Europe 2013 – Day 1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-arriving-and-day-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 15:22:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-arriving-and-day-1/</guid><description>I flew from Gatwick to Barcelona last night to my very first VMworld!
I&amp;rsquo;m staying in a hotel that is actually quite far from the conference, it&amp;rsquo;s a metro, train and bus journey away from the conference center and it takes about 40 minutes to get here. On the plus side I was only 5 minutes away from the VMUG party last night so I went over there for an hour or so.</description></item><item><title>VCAP5-DCA &amp;ndash; Achievement Unlocked! And VMworld Europe</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vcap5-dca-achievement-unlocked-and-vmworld-europe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 15:47:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vcap5-dca-achievement-unlocked-and-vmworld-europe/</guid><description>After my previous post about studying and the exam experience of the VCAP5-DCA exam (and 3 weeks of waking up to check my phone for the email all night) I am pleased to say that I received my Exam Score last week and it was a pass! I was really pleased to see that I passed with a very decent margin too, which was great! The rushed nature of the exam and long wait for the results leaves you going over the exam in your head convincing yourself how badly you’ve done, so it came as a huge relief and surprise.</description></item></channel></rss>