<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>las vegas on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/las-vegas/</link><description>Recent content in las vegas on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 16:50:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/las-vegas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMworld 2016 – Day 2 workshops and sessions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-2-workshops-and-sessions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 16:50:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-2-workshops-and-sessions/</guid><description>vRealize Automation vExperts Workshop I attended a workshop with Jad El Zein in Barcelona last year and it was one of the best sessions I attended, especially as it was just on the news of vRA7&amp;rsquo;s release. This workshop was this year&amp;rsquo;s equivelant, but because the session included a lot of people just getting started with vRA a lot of the time was taken to explain what vRA does, so there was no real time for the more in depth details on the new features that are coming (some already announced and in Tech Preview).</description></item><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – My session picks</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vmworld-2016-my-session-picks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 11:13:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vmworld-2016-my-session-picks/</guid><description>In my post yesterday I promised to post my VMworld session picks, so here it is! I have filled my schedule, and even added some alternate picks when there were too many good sessions to go for. My session picks are focussing around:
vRealize Automation NSX VSAN PowerCLI, APIs and automation Now, before anyone tells me I&amp;rsquo;ve picked too many and I won&amp;rsquo;t make it to all of them - I know!</description></item><item><title>Heading to Las Vegas! #VMworld 2016</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/heading-to-vmworld-us-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 10:24:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/heading-to-vmworld-us-2016/</guid><description>I’ve been very fortunate to be able to go to VMworld Europe for the past 3 years, mainly thanks to the vExpert program and the availability of the blogger pass. This year I knew that I wouldn’t be able to get to Barcelona because of work, so I thought I’d apply for a VMworld US blogger pass - I’m very excited to have been given one! As with previous years, I'll be blogging at least once a day with my thoughts and any useful info I've gleaned - I definitely don't want to take the pass for granted!</description></item></channel></rss>