<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vCAC 6.0 Build Out on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/series/vcac-6.0-build-out/</link><description>Recent content in vCAC 6.0 Build Out on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 10:54:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/series/vcac-6.0-build-out/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 4: Deploying and clustering a secondary vCAC Appliance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-4-deploying-and-clustering-a-secondary-vcac-appliance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 10:54:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-4-deploying-and-clustering-a-secondary-vcac-appliance/</guid><description>This is the fourth article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
By the end of this post we will have deployed a second vCAC Appliance, clustered it with the first appliance and registered the load balanced URL with the Identity Appliance. This will mean logging on to https://vcloud.definit.local/shell-ui-app will be successful.
vCAC deployment with clustered and load balanced vCAC Appliances An overview of the steps required are below:</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 3.2: Configure load balancing with NSX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-2-configure-load-balancing-with-nsx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-2-configure-load-balancing-with-nsx/</guid><description>This is the second part of the 3rd article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
By the end of this part, we will not have modified the vCAC deployment in any way, we’ll just have 3 configured load balanced URLs
vCAC Simple Install with vPostgres deployed and load balancers prepared An overview of the steps required are below:</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 3.1: Configure Load Balancing with vCNS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 08:53:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</guid><description>This is the first part of the 3rd article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
By the end of this part, we will not have modified the vCAC deployment in any way, we’ll just have 3 configured load balanced URLs
vCAC simple configuration with vPostgres and Load Balancers prepared An overview of the steps required are below:
Issue and install certificates Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database Configure load balancing Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering Install and configure additional IaaS server Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster Deploy a vShield Edge appliance Log in to your vShield Manager and select your Datacenter, then the Network Virtualisation tab</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 2: vPostgres</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-2-vpostgres/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 09:01:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-2-vpostgres/</guid><description>This is the second article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
The diagram below shows the deployment at the end of this part, with vPostgres deployed and the vCAC Appliance running from the remote database.
vCAC deploymnent with vPostgres deployed An overview of the steps required are below:
Issue and install certificates Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database Configure load balancing Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering Install and configure additional IaaS server Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster Create the required DNS records First of all, create DNS records for your vPostgres database server – you need both an A and PTR record.</description></item><item><title>VCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 1: Certificates</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-1-certificates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 11:43:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-1-certificates/</guid><description>This is the first article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
Simple vCAC deployment In a simple installation you have the Identity Appliance, the vCAC appliance (which includes a vPostgres DB and vCenter Orchestrator instance) and an IaaS server. The distributed model still has a single Identity Appliance but clusters 2 or more vCAC appliances behind a load balancer, backed by a separate vPostgres database appliance.</description></item></channel></rss>