<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Office on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/office/</link><description>Recent content in Office on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 12:37:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/office/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Online Archiving with Exchange 2010? Can&amp;rsquo;t see your Online Archive in Outlook?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/online-archiving-with-exchange-2010-cant-see-your-online-archive-in-outlook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 12:37:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/online-archiving-with-exchange-2010-cant-see-your-online-archive-in-outlook/</guid><description>Having recently managed several Exchange 2010 migration projects, one of the best new features which really sells it to systems administrators is the Online Archive. “No more managing PST files? When can we have it installed by?”
The problem is, once they’ve purchased licensing for Exchange 2010 and installed and configured the server, migrated the users’ mailboxes and decommissioned the old Exchange 2003 server, the Online Archive feature is not available.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Office Communications Server 2007: [0x80070533] Logon failure: account currently disabled.</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/02/microsoft-office-communications-server-2007-0x80070533-logon-failure-account-currently-disabled/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 12:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/02/microsoft-office-communications-server-2007-0x80070533-logon-failure-account-currently-disabled/</guid><description>Just a quick note on a little error I had installing OCS 2007. We have a lot of users that are set up to run services for applications - as such we have a fairly tightly controlled group policy regarding the permissions required to run as a service. This causes the error above to occur because the newly created users aren&amp;rsquo;t given permissions to run a service. The solution is to add the newly created users to our Application Service group.</description></item><item><title>Exchange 2007 and Outlook 2007 remove categories from emails, tasks, calendar etc.</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/exchange-2007-and-outlook-2007-remove-categories-from-emails-tasks-calendar-etc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2008 11:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/exchange-2007-and-outlook-2007-remove-categories-from-emails-tasks-calendar-etc/</guid><description>It seems that the nice people at Microsoft were looking out for us, lest the evil people in the world see how we categorise our email, and decided to strip away any category information from sent and received objects by default. Sure, I understand if you were categorising emails from someone as &amp;ldquo;sneaky git&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;numbnuts&amp;rdquo; then you might not be too happy about sending those out…but really it should be your choice right?</description></item><item><title>Office 2007 woes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/05/office-2007-woes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 20:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/05/office-2007-woes/</guid><description>Originally published Wednesday, May 30th, 2007 Wahey! I got published this week in IT Week, ok it was only a readers letter, but I got in! Here’s what I wrote: “New software always excites me, so I was enthusiastic as I installed Office 2007 on my laptop. The machine offers more than enough grunt for my media applications, but sadly not quite enough to install Office in less than 15 minutes, plus one restart.</description></item></channel></rss>