<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SQL Server 2008 on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/sql-server-2008/</link><description>Recent content in SQL Server 2008 on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 11:45:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/sql-server-2008/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing SharePoint Foundation 2010 with Remote BLOB support in SQL 2008 R2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/04/installing-sharepoint-foundation-2010-remote-blob-support-sql-2008-r2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 11:45:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/04/installing-sharepoint-foundation-2010-remote-blob-support-sql-2008-r2/</guid><description>Configuring WSS or SharePoint Services for a small client is a pretty effective way of getting a document management solution for a reasonable cost point. One of the limitations that caused headaches was that it used to have a maximum storage of 4GB, which was the database limit. If you wanted to go larger, you would need either a) multiple SPS installations, b) a full version of SQL server, or c) the full version of MOSS.</description></item><item><title>Migrating the HP Systems Insight Manager 6.x database</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/04/migrating-the-hp-systems-insight-manager-6-x-database/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 10:57:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/04/migrating-the-hp-systems-insight-manager-6-x-database/</guid><description>We run to monitoring systems where I work, the first is HP SIM and the second is Microsoft System Center Operations Manager. Currently, they and their databases all reside on a single rather battered server, “MONITOR1”.
I’ve installed a new SQL Server 2008 server “SQL1” on Windows Server 2008 to take some of the load, and take advantage of the 64-bit OS and SQL installation.
Both servers are part of the domain “DOMAIN”</description></item><item><title>Creating a Windows Server 2008 Microsoft Cluster Service SQL Active/Passive Cluster on a single ESXi 4.0 Server</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/01/creating-a-windows-server-2008-microsoft-cluster-service-sql-activepassive-cluster-on-a-single-esxi-4-0-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 14:52:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/01/creating-a-windows-server-2008-microsoft-cluster-service-sql-activepassive-cluster-on-a-single-esxi-4-0-server/</guid><description>Configuring the Virtual Environment and Virtual Machines Note – this configuration will work for ESXi 4 upwards due to the server 2008 MSCS requirement for persistent SCSI-3 reservations.
The first step is to create a new vSwitch for the host-only cluster heartbeat network, don’t assign any network adaptors to the switch as it’s going to be local only.
Create a new virtual machine with a single hard disk. For the purposes of this test, I’ve assigned 2 vProcessors, 1GB RAM, 30GB drive for the OS, 1 vNIC in the default vSwitch0.</description></item></channel></rss>