<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>6.5 on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/6.5/</link><description>Recent content in 6.5 on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 09:02:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/6.5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 1 – What’s New with vROps 6.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-with-vrops-6-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 09:02:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-with-vrops-6-5/</guid><description>Time to share the recording of the first episode of the vROps Webinar Series 2017. This time around, Sunny and I spoke about the latest release of vRealize Operations Manager. We spoke about almost all the new features which were introduced with this version and went into some of them in detail. Like always we rounded up the session with Live Demo of the new features for our audiences.
We introduced a feedback form which can be used to provide your feedback in general and also request topics on which you would want us to focus this year.</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.5 – Two new enhancements/features I really liked</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/vrops-6-5-two-new-enhancementsfeatures-i-really-liked/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 08:37:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/vrops-6-5-two-new-enhancementsfeatures-i-really-liked/</guid><description>So vROps 6.5 has been out for around a month now and I finally have a little while to write a post on what I personally really like.
There is a lot of great new enhancements and improvements added in 6.5 but for the sake of brevity I shall highlight two that I really liked.
Flexibility to increase RAM in between node sizes So if you are familiar with vROps you will know that when you deploy it you have &amp;ldquo;T-Shirt&amp;rdquo; sizes to choose from, Small, Medium, Large and now Extra Large (6.</description></item><item><title>Announcing #vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 1 – What’s new in 6.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/announcing-vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-in-6-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:58:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/announcing-vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-in-6-5/</guid><description>Welcome to the vRealize Operations Manager Webinar Series 2017. With the huge success of the series back in 2016, we wanted to take a break, enjoy the success and come back with full rigor for this series in 2017. We are here and we are charged up to give you some more dope on vRealize Operations manager in the year 2017.
The delivery mechanism would be same as last year. We will start with talking about a topic and then jump into a live environment to see what happens when the rubber hits the road…</description></item></channel></rss>