<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vcap5-Dcd on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcap5-dcd/</link><description>Recent content in Vcap5-Dcd on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 08:59:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcap5-dcd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My VCAP5-DCD experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/my-vcap5-dcd-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 08:59:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/my-vcap5-dcd-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/08/VCAP-DCD-1.jpg" alt=""&gt;A few months ago I decided to tackle the VCAP5-DCD exam and when booking I gave myself 2 months to study before the date of the exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was keenly aware that at least in this calendar year the VCAP5-DCD exam and undergone some changes E.G. it no longer had multiple choice questions (think VCP5-DCV in terms of format)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a wealth of knowledge out there from people whom had either passed/failed or were currently studying so it didn&amp;rsquo;t take too long to get an understanding of what disciplines/knowledge VMware were looking for in the exam.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMworld Europe 2013 &amp;ndash; Day 2, VCAP5-DCD Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-day-2-vcap5-dcd-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 15:45:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-day-2-vcap5-dcd-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Today was always going to be a bit of a funny day as I scheduled the VCAP5-DCD exam for 10am this morning. I am happy to say that I passed! I’m a bit light on VMworld to report today, so forgive my DCD experience to pad it out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="preparation"&gt;Preparation &lt;a class="anchor" href="#preparation"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I have to confess my prep for this exam was light – I literally only watched the TrainSignal course by Scott Lowe (@scott_lowe) and just about finished that last night in the hotel! I don’t spend much time focussing on design during my day job, so I approached this exam as a bit of a learning experience rather than a serious bid to pass. I decided to book the exam here at VMworld just because you can get 75% off – if you’re funding yourself it’s not a discount to be dismissed easily!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>