<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Firewall on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/firewall/</link><description>Recent content in Firewall on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 14:26:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/firewall/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vSphere Security: Advanced SSH Configurations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vsphere-security-advanced-ssh-configurations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 14:26:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vsphere-security-advanced-ssh-configurations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2013/10/Security-Guard_thumb2_thumb.png" alt=""&gt;There are different schools of thought as to whether you should have SSH enabled on your hosts. VMware recommend it is disabled. With SSH disabled there is no possibility of attack, so that’s the “most secure” option. Of course in the real world there’s a balance between “most secure” and “usability” (e.g. the most secure host is powered off and physically isolated from the network, but you can’t run any workloads &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;). My preferred route is to have it enabled but locked down.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware vCenter Linked Mode not supported through firewalls</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vmware-vcenter-linked-mode-not-supported-through-firewalls/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 15:28:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vmware-vcenter-linked-mode-not-supported-through-firewalls/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This article originally started off life as a record of how I managed to get this working, as a lot of my posts do, but this time it appears I am foiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I had 3 vCenter Servers that appeared to be happily talking to each other in Linked Mode sharing a singe Multi-site SSO domain without any real issues. I had a single-pane-of-glass view of all 3 and I could manage them all from the one client. The reason for the 3 vCenter servers was segregation of LAN and DMZ networks: vCenter001 was in the LAN, vCenter002 sat in DMZ1 and vCenter003 sat in DMZ2.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>