<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/authors/simon-eady/</link><description>Recent content on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/authors/simon-eady/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why use Content Libraries with vRA 8</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/why-use-content-libraries-with-vra-8/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/why-use-content-libraries-with-vra-8/</guid><description>Why use Content Libraries with vRA 8 Product Version - vRealize Automation 8.x What are vSphere Content Libraries? A content library stores and manages content in the form of library items. A single library item can consist of one file or multiple files. For example, the OVF template is a set of files (.ovf, .vmdk, and .mf). When you upload an OVF template to the library, you upload the entire set of files, but the result is a single library item of the OVF Template type.</description></item><item><title>Using vRealize Orchestreator MP in vROps</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/using-vrealize-orchestreator-mp-in-vrops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/using-vrealize-orchestreator-mp-in-vrops/</guid><description>Using vRealize Orchestreator MP in vROps Product Version - vRealize Operations 7.x and 8.x A few years ago VMware released the Orchestrator MP which is a superb way to directly call vRO workflows from vROps by way of alerts and actions. This opens the door to all manner of ideas for conditional automation using vROps.
The limitation Recently for a customer we planned to use the vRO MP to assist a customer with a very unique/niche challenge.</description></item><item><title>vROps Remote Collectors - Design Considerations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/vrops-remote-collectors-design-considerations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/vrops-remote-collectors-design-considerations/</guid><description>vROps Remote Collectors - Design Considerations Product Version - vRealize Operations 7.x and 8.x As part of VMware Validated Designs tyically you would use Remote Collectors not just in different DCs but also local to the analytics cluster. However there are a circumstances where the rules &amp;ldquo;change&amp;rdquo;.
When using RecoverPoint or Site Recovery Manager Design Assumption - you have Remote Collectors on your Primary Site and on your Failover Site.</description></item><item><title>vROps Cluster without a Load Balancer (gotchas)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vrops-cluster-without-a-load-balancer-gotchas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vrops-cluster-without-a-load-balancer-gotchas/</guid><description>vROps Cluster without a Load Balancer (gotchas) Product Version - vRealize Operations 7.5 While it is far from recomended to deploy a vROps Cluster without a loadbalancer there are circumstances where this is done.
Recently helping a customer deploy a couple of simple issues cropped up that were not immediately obvious as to why they were issues.
Unable to connect to Master Node when expanding the cluster We hit this issue and initialy it was a question mark moment there were no firewalls in the way and network connectivity was good end to end.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Operations 8.1 - What's New</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vrealize-operations-8.1-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vrealize-operations-8.1-whats-new/</guid><description>VMware have been very busy in the last few months across many of their products and Operations Management has not gone untouched. We saw glimpses of things to come late last year and now we see the Cloud Management Team in VMware really ramping things up with vRealize Operation 8.1
vRealize Operations Cloud One of the bigger items to arrive very shortly is vRealize Operations Cloud (SaaS), this means you do not need to worry about standing vROps up in your environment to see what value it can bring to your infrastructure monitoring.</description></item><item><title>2020 - Simon's decade in review</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/2020-simons-decade-in-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/2020-simons-decade-in-review/</guid><description>So it being 2020 now I thought it would be a pleasant exercise to quickly glance over the previous ten years and reflect a little. Before I even begin I will say I have never been happier in my career and work/life balance (which is always an on going effort to keep appropriate)
I am going to break it down in a yearly format and then summarize at the end.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Foundation - Deployment Observations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/07/vmware-cloud-foundation-deployment-observations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/07/vmware-cloud-foundation-deployment-observations/</guid><description>I have been working with VMware Cloud Foundation recently and while for the most part things went well there were occasions where challenges were encountered which made the delivery to the customer all the more trickier than expected.
This article is a list of observations and things to most definitely check or watch out for when delivering a VCF project.
We were working with VCF version 3.7.2 (yes I am aware 3.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading vRA with vRLCM and JAVA versions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/upgrading-vra-with-vrlcm-and-java-versions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/upgrading-vra-with-vrlcm-and-java-versions/</guid><description>I recently upgraded an instance of vRA from 7.2 to 7.5 and rather than do it the manual way I used VMware’s vRealize LifeCycle Manager (version 2.0 update 3).
Everything was going great and according to plan, the vRLCM pre-requisites checker made short work of all of the checks you need to do before you start an upgrade of vRA. You can see below vRLCM does a great job of keeping you informed of the current progress and in a really elegant way.</description></item><item><title>Am I the best I can be right now?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/03/am-i-the-best-i-can-be-right-now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 09:55:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/03/am-i-the-best-i-can-be-right-now/</guid><description>It has been a few years since I read (and lost) a great article on career progression and personal insight. That article helped me relax into who I am from a professional point of view, but it also challenged me.
I have been in IT for over 20 years now and in truth the first 10 years were not so great (perhaps a story for another time) but it was when I stumbled upon the vCommunity by way of Twitter and then subsequently I attended my first VMUG (in London) which completely challenged and changed my way of thinking and approach to my career.</description></item><item><title>VCAP7-CMA Design Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/02/vcap7-cma-design-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 13:56:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/02/vcap7-cma-design-exam-experience/</guid><description>For the last month I had been preparing for the VCAP7-CMA Design exam and I am very glad to say I passed on my first attempt.
Oddly I found it slightly easier than the VCP7-CMA but that I suspect is down to the fact I spend a lot of my time designing and implementing solutions for customers as opposed to day to day administration of any given solution.
So what was the exam like?</description></item><item><title>New Year, new things oh and a VCP7-CMA</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/01/new-year-new-things-oh-and-a-vcp7-cma/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:20:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/01/new-year-new-things-oh-and-a-vcp7-cma/</guid><description>It has been a while since I have had time to write a blog post, the last quarter of last year was pretty crazy from a work point of view.
Regardless, it is now a New Year and my tech focus is turning very much on CMP related things particularly vRealize Automation. (I am also very much looking forward to learning more about VMware&amp;rsquo;s CaS which I saw demo&amp;rsquo;d at the UK VMUG late last year by Grant Orchard)</description></item><item><title>Things we can look forward to seeing in #vROps 7.0</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/things-we-can-look-forward-to-seeing-in-vrops-7-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 11:51:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/things-we-can-look-forward-to-seeing-in-vrops-7-0/</guid><description>I did a quick search online and could not find a collated list so, by way of a quick summary from all the VMworld 2018 announcements and comments my good friend and PM for vRealize Operations Sunny Dua has made, I have collated a list of what we can expect to see in the next iteration of vROps (7.0). The list is in no order of interest or importance, some of the mentioned improvements have been long standing requests so enjoy and get hyped (I know I am).</description></item><item><title>Cisco SG300 – Static route not showing, but already exists?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/cisco-sg300-static-route-not-showing-but-already-exists/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 08:21:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/cisco-sg300-static-route-not-showing-but-already-exists/</guid><description>OK, so recently I had been setting up NSX in my lab and I wanted to create some static routes on my SG300-20 so I could access the VMs that were on my NSX network.
I added the VLAN I wanted to use and added a VLAN interface. All good.
I went ahead and added the static route as shown below.
As you can see it was applied successfully.
However looking at the static routes I could not see the route I had just added.</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.7 – Automate all the things..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrops-6-7-automate-all-the-things/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 12:24:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrops-6-7-automate-all-the-things/</guid><description>There are many improvements, changes and new additions to vROps in version 6.7 but one of the aspects that stands out to me personally is the direction VMware are taking with the product. Aside from the obvious addition of cloud costings and comparisons and a reworked capacity planning (from the ground up) and new hook in to Wavefront (which I really like) there has been some real effort to improve how you can further automate things from vROps.</description></item><item><title>#vROps data retention and the Cleaner</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrops-data-retention-and-the-cleaner/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 13:36:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrops-data-retention-and-the-cleaner/</guid><description>Something that has come up with customers recently is why and when old data is cleaned up from your vROps instance.
I will make the assumption that you have your data retention set to 6 months but the process is the same whether the value is less than or greater than 6 months.
When data reaches and or goes beyond the age threshold set in the global settings it will be cleaned away by a daily process &amp;ldquo;Old Data Cleaner&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Looking back on 2017 and looking forward into 2018</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/looking-back-on-2017-and-looking-forward-into-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 09:59:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/looking-back-on-2017-and-looking-forward-into-2018/</guid><description>Upon seeing others in the wider community making a blog post like this as a marker in the sand I thought I would follow suit as a way to see what I have learned and goals I would like to achieve in the coming year. 2017 was a good year and a very busy one at that, I got to see a lot of new places on my work travels and met some really amazing, clever and talented people.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2017 – Part 4 : Optimizing Workload Performance Using Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 10:17:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</guid><description>In this episode, Sunny gave us a deep dive into the WLP and WLB features of vROps.
We were also joined by a special guest, Jad El-Zein who gave us a great insight into how vRA utilises vROps for initial placement of freshly provisioned VMs
We would highly appreciate it if you could spend 30 seconds to fill up this quick and simple survey to provide us your feedback. You can also request topics of your choice through this survey.</description></item><item><title>Why do IT projects struggle or fail?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/why-do-it-projects-struggle-or-fail/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:58:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/why-do-it-projects-struggle-or-fail/</guid><description>Why do IT projects fail?
I am sure if you ask that question to ten people you will get 10 different answers, or at the very least a wide variety of reasons. The product chosen to deliver the solution was a poor match, the product was implemented incorrectly, the PM sucked, the Vendor gave no support, insufficient training material/resources, poor interoperability, the list goes on and on.
One issue I have observed from time to time on my travels is quite different from the above listed examples.</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Wednesday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-4-wednesday/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 17:30:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-4-wednesday/</guid><description>This was as I expected, the busiest day sessions wise for me. There was so much good stuff I had to be a little ruthless on what I wanted and or needed to attend while also wanting to get into the solutions exchange.
Also at the end of the day the customer appreciate party was scheduled so that was something I was looking forward to a great deal (Hint - Kaiser Chiefs)</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Tuesday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-3-tuesday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-3-tuesday/</guid><description>I managed to dodge the rainstorms in the morning before arriving, the hotel being just across the road from the Venue was a huge help (Thank you Xtravirt)
The main session was great particularly HCX announcement and the VR admin demo.
I then hit the solutions exchange as soon as it opened. There are all the usual suspects there -except- Cisco (anyone know why?)
It was also great to see the guys from Blue Medora.</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Sunday and Monday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-1-and-2-sunday-and-monday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 13:29:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-1-and-2-sunday-and-monday/</guid><description>Sunday Arriving in early on Sunday as the local flight choices are more limited from Bristol than perhaps a larger Airport, very fortunate to have a hotel so close to the VMworld venue, perhaps not so great for the evening activities but I am happy with it this way around.
Other than registration (4pm-8pm) and hopefully catching up with a few folk who have also arrived early.
In the evening I had the pleasure to meet many awesome people from the vCommunity.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2017 – Announcing Part 4 : Optimizing Workload Performance Using Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-announcing-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 13:18:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-announcing-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</guid><description>In this coming episode, Sunny will DIVE DEEP into the interesting topic of introducing automation into operations.
While we all know that, automating day to day operations tasks is becoming the choice of an IT organization, it is hard for them to find a solution which can completely understand their business policies and provide them the efficiency they need from automating simple operational tasks.
Based on our research, we found that, one of the most time consuming activity done by an Virtual Infrastructure Administrator is to juggle resources between the changing business requirements and ensure that every VM which is being hosted in their environment is BEING SERVED WELL.</description></item><item><title>Looking forward to #VMworld EMEA 2017</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/looking-forward-to-vmworld-emea-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 09:30:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/looking-forward-to-vmworld-emea-2017/</guid><description>Having missed last years VMworld I feel very ready for attending the EMEA VMworld in Barcelona.
I almost felt annoyed about missing last year as the big announcements really caused a stir in the community and wider afield. (VMware on AWS) The announcements from the US VMworld this year were equally exciting so I am very keen to hear what else VMware has planned to reveal in a Barcelona.
I have put a good deal of effort into planning what I will be doing and attending to maximise my time there without burnout (Veterans I hear you laughing)</description></item><item><title> #vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 3 – What’s New with vROps 6.6</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 06:52:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</guid><description>[vRealize Operations Manager 6.6, which was recently released by VMware.
We started with an overview of all the cool new stuff and then drill down into individual areas. We then jumped into a Live Demo as usual to see the new features in action.
We would highly appreciate if you could spend 30 seconds to fill up this quick and simple survey to provide us your feedback. You can also request topics of your choice through this survey.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2017 – Announcing Part 3 : What’s New with #vROps 6.6</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-2017-announcing-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 07:13:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-2017-announcing-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</guid><description>Welcome to the next episode of vRealize Operations Manager Webinar Series. This time around we will talk about the latest release of vROps released in the month of June.
With this release, VMware has made drastic changes to the product and the initial reviews of the product have been great. Since I was a part of the team delivering this new release, I thought it would be a good topic to discuss in the next episode of the Webinar Series.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 2- Full Stack monitoring with vRealize Operations Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/05/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-2-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 07:18:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/05/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-2-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</guid><description>[&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-8035&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2017/03/logo.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; which vROps can provide by using various extensibility solutions.
We discussed the following use cases and demonstrated them in live environments:
Use Case 1 - Full-Stack vSphere Monitoring. From application to Infrastructure.
Use Case 2 - Amazon RDS Workloads. Monitoring public cloud workloads with vROps.
Use Case 3 - vROps Extensibility. Metrics, Logs and Costing come together along with other 3rd party extensibility options.</description></item><item><title>Can I monitor hardware OOTB with #vROps?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/05/can-i-monitor-hardware-ootb-with-vrops/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 11:42:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/05/can-i-monitor-hardware-ootb-with-vrops/</guid><description>So very recently i had a great question from a customer regarding ways to monitor things like the temperature of host systems. Would they need a management pack or is this something vROps can do out of the box?
The short answer to this is yes, but it is not immediately obvious how.
There are a great many metrics that come with a vanilla build of vROps but not all of them are enabled a good example of these are the sensor metrics.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Part 2 – #vROps Webinar series 2017 – “Full Stack” monitoring with vRealize Operations Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/announcing-part-2-vrops-webinar-series-2017-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 07:50:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/announcing-part-2-vrops-webinar-series-2017-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</guid><description>As promised, vROps Webinar Series 2017 is back with the second episode of the year. Last time around we looked closely into the features of vROps 6.5 and as stated during that webinar, we will now show you how you can unlock the full capabilities of vROps using the extensibility of the platform.
If you have been following the Webinar Series, by now you have a complete visibility into the capabilities of vROps, when it comes to monitoring the vSphere infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>#vROps hidden gem – XML Builder</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/vrops-hidden-gem-xml-builder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 08:06:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/vrops-hidden-gem-xml-builder/</guid><description>If you spend a good amount of time in vROps either at your place of work or with customers (like me) you will likely have had to create some custom XML (metric configuration) for custom dashboards.
In the past you would either use the sample/examples to get them started and then go and find the specific metric names while, this was usually quite time consuming.
In recent versions of vROps however, VMware have introduced a &amp;ldquo;builder&amp;rdquo; to help you properly format and slect the corect adapters/adapterkinds and metrics.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 1 – What’s New with vROps 6.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-with-vrops-6-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 09:02:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-with-vrops-6-5/</guid><description>Time to share the recording of the first episode of the vROps Webinar Series 2017. This time around, Sunny and I spoke about the latest release of vRealize Operations Manager. We spoke about almost all the new features which were introduced with this version and went into some of them in detail. Like always we rounded up the session with Live Demo of the new features for our audiences.
We introduced a feedback form which can be used to provide your feedback in general and also request topics on which you would want us to focus this year.</description></item><item><title>Understanding #vROps High Availability</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/understanding-vrops-high-availability/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 19:32:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/understanding-vrops-high-availability/</guid><description>While there is a reasonable amount of information about how HA works in vROps I have found there is still some confusion as to how HA actually works with vROps or rather what are the benefits and perhaps more importantly the cost for enabling the feature.
HA is a great feature and in my opinion should be considered seriously with any deployment (where possible).
Not only does HA protect your Master node (which essentially behaves as an index for your vROps cluster and if lost will render your cluster dead unless you have a working backup of your cluster) it will also allow your cluster to tolerate a data node failure.</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.5 – Two new enhancements/features I really liked</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/vrops-6-5-two-new-enhancementsfeatures-i-really-liked/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 08:37:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/vrops-6-5-two-new-enhancementsfeatures-i-really-liked/</guid><description>So vROps 6.5 has been out for around a month now and I finally have a little while to write a post on what I personally really like.
There is a lot of great new enhancements and improvements added in 6.5 but for the sake of brevity I shall highlight two that I really liked.
Flexibility to increase RAM in between node sizes So if you are familiar with vROps you will know that when you deploy it you have &amp;ldquo;T-Shirt&amp;rdquo; sizes to choose from, Small, Medium, Large and now Extra Large (6.</description></item><item><title>Announcing #vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 1 – What’s new in 6.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/announcing-vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-in-6-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:58:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/announcing-vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-in-6-5/</guid><description>Welcome to the vRealize Operations Manager Webinar Series 2017. With the huge success of the series back in 2016, we wanted to take a break, enjoy the success and come back with full rigor for this series in 2017. We are here and we are charged up to give you some more dope on vRealize Operations manager in the year 2017.
The delivery mechanism would be same as last year. We will start with talking about a topic and then jump into a live environment to see what happens when the rubber hits the road…</description></item><item><title>The Speed of Change in IT Infrastructure (Opinion)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/02/the-speed-of-change-in-it-infrastructure-opinion/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 09:34:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/02/the-speed-of-change-in-it-infrastructure-opinion/</guid><description>Over the past 6 months I have been dwelling more and more on the obvious speed of change and development in IT Infrastructure. What do I mean? Well each year there is the new hotness, the next thing/innovation you are told you need or should have.
In most cases the innovations and new tech are ground breaking awesomeness and most certainly offer new opportunities for the infrastructure masses.
I am all for progress, if you are not moving forward and regularly looking for sensible ways to improve what you do and the infrastructure you use then I really do think you are in the wrong industry.</description></item><item><title>#vSAN Cache Performance Dashboard in #vROps</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/02/vsan-cache-performance-dashboard-in-vrops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 14:09:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/02/vsan-cache-performance-dashboard-in-vrops/</guid><description>I have recently been able to get vSAN properly up and running in my lab and took a look at the OOTB Dashboards that come with the MPSD (Management Pack for Storage Devices).
As I have a hybrid build (I know many have All Flash Arrays) I was interested in how hard my Flash Cache was working so I built a dashboard purely focused on this aspect of the vSAN product.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Part 12 : What’s New with vROps 6.4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 12:02:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</guid><description>Time to publish the recording for the 12th episode of the vROps Webinar Series. This time we did a what’s new with vRealize Operations 6.4 and the changes made to vRealize Operations 6.4as you will see there has been a lot packed into this recent release!
It has been an awesome 12 months working with Sunny on this project and I am very glad to say we will be back next year (we will skip January and will return in February).</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 12 : What’s New with vROps 6.4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 08:36:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s the time of the month when I would like to invite you to join the next episode of our year long vROps Webinar Series. As we move towards the closure of a fantastic year, we would like to take a zoom out view at the vRealize Operations Manager solution with a What&amp;rsquo;s New Episode. We did a What&amp;rsquo;s new with vRealize Operations 6.3 a couple of months back, however looking at some awesome changes made to vRealize Operations 6.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series – Part 11 – Getting more out of #vROps with PowerCLI</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-part-11-getting-more-out-of-vrops-with-powercli-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 12:10:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-part-11-getting-more-out-of-vrops-with-powercli-2/</guid><description>Time to publish the recording for the 11th episode of the vROps Webinar Series. This time we were joined by Vinith Menon who spoke about getting more from your vROps builds with PowerCLI. Vinith demonstrated the many useful ways of leveraging PowerCLI to manage your vROps environments and also communicate with the vROps API.
Huge thanks to Vinith Menon for presenting this excellent session.
So without further ado, here is the recording for this session:</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series – Announcing Part 11 – Getting more out of #vROps with PowerCLI</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-part-11-getting-more-out-of-vrops-with-powercli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 13:05:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-part-11-getting-more-out-of-vrops-with-powercli/</guid><description>Another month has gone and Christmas is now looming large! It has been extremely busy but we still want to continue with the momentum of webinar series getting to the business end of the year. This time around we will talk about getting more out of vRealize Operations Manager using PowerCLI.
This session we will be joined by Vinith Menon who will show us all kinds of PowerCLI goodness.
So without further a do, save the date in your calendars and join use for the next episode of vRealize Operations Webinar Series 2016.</description></item><item><title>Security “fun” and embracing 2FA</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/security-fun-and-embracing-2fa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 10:47:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/security-fun-and-embracing-2fa/</guid><description>So the other day my Skype account was briefly compromised, a successful login from Russia (after digging through activity logs) and this was after many attempts from IP addresses all around the world (China, Korea, Argentina the list goes on). You can see from the picture below the successful login attempt.
My initial reaction was stress and panic, as I didn&amp;rsquo;t know precisely where I had been compromised I ran scans on my local machines while resetting passwords a plenty.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series Slide decks – available for download</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-slide-decks-available-for-download/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 23:27:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-slide-decks-available-for-download/</guid><description>If you have been following and enjoying the vROps Webinar series both Sunny and I have been running this year you may find it useful to know Sunny has put all the slide decks up and availble in one place for you to download and share if you so wish.
vROps Webinar Series Slide Decks
Enjoy and share the knowledge!
If you have any questions or comments just drop either Sunny or myself a comment on our respective blogs or contact us on twitter.</description></item><item><title>Adding and removing #vROps nodes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/adding-and-removing-vrops-nodes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 21:32:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/adding-and-removing-vrops-nodes/</guid><description>I was asked recently if there were any materials I could direct people to with regards to expanding existing vROps deployments. I did a brief search on the web to see what material was &amp;ldquo;out there&amp;rdquo; on how to perform what is a straight forward task. To my surprise very little came up. So I have decided to create this guide with all the things you need to consider when you are going to either expand or need to remove a node from one of your active vROps deployments.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series 2016 – Part 10 – A Deep Dive into vROps API</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-2016-part-10-a-deep-dive-into-vrops-api/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 12:37:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-2016-part-10-a-deep-dive-into-vrops-api/</guid><description>Time to publish the recording for the 10th episode of vROps Webinar Series. This time around we spoke about vRealize Operations Manager Resful API and how to use it. Post 20 minutes of slide-ware, I jumped into the lab and thanks to the demo god, we demonstrated a number of use cases and browsed through the documentation to make it easier for you to consume and use the same.
Big thanks to @sunny_dua for doing the session while I was MIA you are a legend buddy!</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 10 : A Deep Dive into vROps API</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-10-a-deep-dive-into-vrops-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 11:57:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-10-a-deep-dive-into-vrops-api/</guid><description>The month has been extremely busy but we still want to continue with the momentum of webinar series getting to the business end of the year. This time around we will talk about vRealize Operations Manager API. API is your friend if you are trying to automate things which you would normally do on GUI. While GUI is a favourite of most, the geeks prefer the API since that helps them to programatically initiate tasks and go out for a coffee.</description></item><item><title>There is no one cloud solution to rule them all..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/there-is-no-one-cloud-solution-to-rule-them-all/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 17:01:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/there-is-no-one-cloud-solution-to-rule-them-all/</guid><description>I have been musing this a little while and decided to write this post/rant/opinion post, feel free to post your thoughts and opinions in the comments.
OK so here it is, one thing I have observed for a good while now is how much noise there is about how -you- should be in the cloud (Public) and if you are not you&amp;rsquo;re already dead.
I call Bull****!
Public, Hybrid and Private clouds are solutions not final destinations, regardless of whether you are a customer, partner, or any other third thing you should be purely focused on what is best for you or (if you provide IT services) your customer.</description></item><item><title>How do you keep -your- IT skills relevant without burn out?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/how-do-you-keep-your-it-skills-relevant-without-burn-out/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 08:52:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/how-do-you-keep-your-it-skills-relevant-without-burn-out/</guid><description>I was having a chat with my Dad recently, about how those who work in IT keep their skills up to date. He is now retired but had spent 25+ years in the IT business so I always value his opinion. What occurred to me while we chewed the fat was the following.
If there is one thing we can be sure of in IT, it is that change will happen and faster than we think.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series – Part 9 – What’s New with vRealize Operations 6.3</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-6-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 08:27:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-6-3/</guid><description>Here is the recording for the episode 9 vRealize Operations Manager Webinar Series 2016. During this episode we discussed about the new features and functionalities of vRealize Operations Manager 6.3. With this release of the product, we can clearly see that VMware is clearly working on enhancing the user experience and the user interface with some great new features and UI changes.
I would encourage you to watch this session to understand the full potential of the product and how you can use the new features to meet your requirements and ease out operations in your Virtual / Cloud environments.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 9 : What’s New with vRealize Operations Manager 6.3</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/09/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-manager-6-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 12:42:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/09/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-manager-6-3/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s the time of the month when we invite you to join the next episode of our year long vROps Webinar Series. As we move towards winter, we would like to take a zoom out view at the vRealize Operations Manager solution with a What&amp;rsquo;s New Episode. For the past 8 months, we have give pretty deep into most of the product features and we believe it is time when we review the product in it&amp;rsquo;s current form and shape.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Part 8 : SDDC Operations with vROps Custom Dashboards</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-webinar-2016-part-8-sddc-operations-with-vrops-custom-dashboards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 14:52:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-webinar-2016-part-8-sddc-operations-with-vrops-custom-dashboards/</guid><description>With today, being the last day of the month, we wanted to make sure that we share this out with you folks out there to keep up with the practice.
Iwan Rahabok, did a great job on this one, talking about the the concept of SDDC operations and I would recommend this session to anyone who wants a jump-start into transforming their operations for SDDC. Quickly want to thank Iwan here for spending his valuable time with us and giving back to the community through this Webinar Series, Blogs, Books etc.</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.3 – SNMP filtering</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-6-3-snmp-filtering/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 09:42:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-6-3-snmp-filtering/</guid><description>So one of the most common questions I get from customers regarding vROps is alert filtering and up until very recently the only way to filter was either by email alerting or via the REST plugin. However 9/10 customers wanted to use SNMP and with vROps it was a question of switching on the fire-hose and pointing it to the receiver and let that end point or middle-ware handle the torrent of data.</description></item><item><title>Whats new in #vROps 6.3 part 2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 21:16:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3-part-2/</guid><description>In this post I will drill down to look at some of the enhancements, improvements and or new additions one by one.
New Home Dashboard - as you can see this is a very useful and helpful way or presenting a high level set of data about your environment with also many ways to interact and interrogate the data you are being presented with. Among other items you can filter on (Health/Risk/Efficiency), alter the scope, see alerts relative to the objects you are interested in.</description></item><item><title>Whats new in #vROps 6.3</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 16:40:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3/</guid><description>So the latest release of vROps has some cool new things and at a very high level below are the key stand out improvements and changes.
I will do a more deep dive in the next few days.
You can get the release notes here.
You can download it here.
New home dashboard Improved WLP and DRS integration Improved Workload Dashboard Wizard now available for policy creation or amendment Improved visibility of Data collection status Many new Hardening policies (6.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 8 : SDDC Operations with vROps Custom Dashboards</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-8-sddc-operations-with-vrops-custom-dashboards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 08:30:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-8-sddc-operations-with-vrops-custom-dashboards/</guid><description>This time around Iwan Rahabok will lead the next session of the vROps Webinar Series while Sunny and myself will support him to deliver some awesome content which Iwan has developed over the past few months.
Yes, this time around we will move our focus from vROps as a Product and related features to the concept of running your SDDC operations with vRealize Operations Dashboards. Just to clarify, this is not a session where we will teach you to create dashboards, but this is a session where we would share how a set of Customised Dashboards can help any organisation&amp;rsquo;s IT to get an insight into Storage, Network &amp;amp; Compute within your SDDC.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Part 7 : Working with Alerts &amp; Symptoms</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vrops-webinar-2016-part-7-working-with-alerts-symptoms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 09:03:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vrops-webinar-2016-part-7-working-with-alerts-symptoms/</guid><description>Time to release the recording for the latest part of the vROps Webinar Series. We completed the 7th session of the series where we spoke about vRealize Operations Manager Alerts and Symptoms.
Alerts as we all know would always remain the heart and soul for the operations teams to run the data centers, whether old school or the modern software defined.
In all cases you need alerts and more importantly you need meaningful and actionable alerts.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 7 : Working with Alerts &amp; Symptoms</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-7-working-with-alerts-symptoms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 17:54:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-7-working-with-alerts-symptoms/</guid><description>Time to announce the next part of the year long webinar series on vRealize Operations Manager. With the last part of the series, we started focusing on content withing vROps. We will continue the trend and talk about a major function of vROps a.k.a Alerts. Alerts is the most used and most ab-used part of vROps, and with this session we want to give you some insights on the entire life-cycle of the alerting function of vROps.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Part 6 : Understanding vROps SuperMetric &amp; Views</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/06/vrops-webinar-2016-part-6-understanding-vrops-supermetric-views/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 22:42:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/06/vrops-webinar-2016-part-6-understanding-vrops-supermetric-views/</guid><description>Sunny just completed the editing and upload of the the latest episode of the vROps Webinar Series 2016. With this we have completed 6 sessions this year. I am glad that we are able to dish out sessions every month and the interest level in these sessions just keeps on growing. Looking forward to deliver more content for the rest of the year. Session Details:-In this episode, we talk about content within vROps.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 6 : Understanding vROps SuperMetric &amp; Views</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/06/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-6-understanding-vrops-supermetric-views/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 09:31:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/06/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-6-understanding-vrops-supermetric-views/</guid><description>Time to announce the next part of the year long webinar series on vRealize Operations Manager. This time around, Sunny and I will take you to the world of Content within vROps. I will be honest in saying that this is an ocean in itself and we might not be able to touch upon all the aspects of developing content within vROps. During this effort we plan to start with giving you an overview of the various options available to develop content within vROps.</description></item><item><title>My Top Ten albums of all time</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/06/my-top-ten-albums-of-all-time/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 20:41:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/06/my-top-ten-albums-of-all-time/</guid><description>So recently a few folk whom I respect a great deal posted up their top 10 albums of all time, initially I was like, OK, but having gone through the exercise myself I found it really enjoyable. Sure its quite self indulgent but seeing other people&amp;rsquo;s lists gives you a small glimpse into their life. After all musical taste is a hugely personal thing.
I approached my top 10 by considering which bands and albums had the biggest impact on me at a given time in my life and that I still enjoy today.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 5 : Design and Deployment considerations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-part-5-design-and-deployment-considerations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 13:25:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-part-5-design-and-deployment-considerations/</guid><description>As promised, I am posting the recording for the 5th Session of vROps Webinar Series 2016. Both Sunny and I successfully delivered the session on Design and Deployment considerations.
Session Details:- In this instalment of the series, we discussed the steps and thought processes that should be used before and during the design and deployment of vRealize Operations Manager. During the session among other things we will cover the planning, core components, correct sizing, HA, clustering, DR and future growth**.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 5 : Design &amp; Deployment Considerations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-5-design-deployment-considerations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 06:52:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-5-design-deployment-considerations/</guid><description>Time to announce the next part of the year long webinar series on vRealize Operations Manager. This time around, Sunny and I thought about discussing Architecture of vROps. To some, it might sound strange as for smaller deployments you might not have to worry about Sizing and Architecture much since it is pretty simple to install and configure a small or a medium node for a small shop. However as your monitoring needs grow and you start adding solutions for monitoring data sources beyond vSphere, you would need to think about scaling up or scaling out.</description></item><item><title>What if I want full metrics? in #vROps</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/what-if-i-want-full-metrics-in-vrops/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 16:06:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/what-if-i-want-full-metrics-in-vrops/</guid><description>If you have used vCOps (previous version of vROPs) you will likely remember the option in the admin panel where you could change the number of metrics being collected from &amp;ldquo;balanced&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;full&amp;rdquo;.
As many found, this option drop down was not present in vROps and there appeared to be no replacement.
Here is the good news, the ability to collect those metrics has not been removed rather it&amp;rsquo;s just a little more hidden (by design)</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 4 – Contention Based Performance &amp; Capacity Management</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-webinar-2016-part-4-contention-based-performance-capacity-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 08:17:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-webinar-2016-part-4-contention-based-performance-capacity-management/</guid><description>As promised, I am posting the recording for the 4th Session of vROps Webinar Series 2016. We successfully delivered the session on Contention Based Performance &amp;amp; Capacity Management using vRealize Operations Manager!
This time around I could not not attend at short notice due to circumstances beyond my control but as you will see the session was awesome! &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Session Details:- &amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;With this instalment of the series, we have a new speaker &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.</description></item><item><title>#vROps what if I want to scale up?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-what-if-i-want-to-scale-up/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 21:42:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-what-if-i-want-to-scale-up/</guid><description>So a lot of noise is being made about vROps being able to scale out and rightly so it works -very- well.
However what if you want to scale up your node or nodes, going from say small to medium?
Reasons why?
Perhaps your POC has proved so useful you want to move it into production? You have lots of really useful historical on your existing smaller build and you don&amp;rsquo;t want to redeploy (therefore losing your historical data) You have limitations where scaling out is simply not an option but you need vROps to take on more work.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 4 : Contention Based Performance &amp; Capacity Management</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-4-contention-based-performance-capacity-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 11:33:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-4-contention-based-performance-capacity-management/</guid><description>We hope you are having fun with the vROps Webinar Series and learning in the process!
With the next instalment of this series, we have a new speaker who will entertain us 🙂 He is no stranger to the world of vRealize Operations Manager and has written a couple of books on vROps as well. I am referring to Iwan Rahabok who has been my partner in crime on all the vROps related work which we do, inside VMware or with the community.</description></item><item><title>When everyones an Architect.. no one is..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/when-everyones-an-architect-no-one-is/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 10:34:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/when-everyones-an-architect-no-one-is/</guid><description>I think this is the first time I have written a &amp;ldquo;rant&amp;rdquo; post (for a while at least) so if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear me whine run away now!
     In the past 12 months I think I have met more folk with Architect in their job title than I truly believe is valid. Now I will be clear this is not a slight on the individuals all of them have been exceptional (at least the ones I have had the pleasure to work with).</description></item><item><title>#vROps Hidden Gem – Automation Action Framework</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-hidden-gem-automation-action-framework/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 18:23:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-hidden-gem-automation-action-framework/</guid><description>&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-7206&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2016/03/aaf-logo.png&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;aaf-logo&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; gems deep inside, vROps in this case is not without exception.
The Automation Action Framework (AAF) is one of these, a really powerful vROps in-built automation tool.
Now when I have discussed this capability with my peers and friends many ask why not use vRO etc? My reply is quite simple, &amp;ldquo;what if you do not have vRO or the in house skills to utilise it properly?</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 3 – Capacity Planning De-Mystified!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 16:29:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</guid><description>Sunny and myself delivered the session on vROps Capacity Planning with some demo scenarios which will help you define your capacity monitoring goals. Session Details:-
Capacity Planning Demystified!
Capacity Planning is an integral part of vRealize Operations Manager and through this session we want to de-mystify the concepts of Capacity Planning in vROps using features such as projects and the out-of-box capacity views. We look at defining the capacity planning policies based on the business requirements of an organization</description></item><item><title>vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 3 : Capacity Planning De-Mystified!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 16:08:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</guid><description>we will now deep-dive into vRealize Operations Manager Policies, specifically around the area of Capacity Planning. Capacity Planning Demystified!**
**
Capacity Planning is an integral part of vRealize Operations Manager and through this session we want to de-mystify the concepts of Capacity Planning in vROps using features such as projects and the out-of-box capacity views. We will also look at defining the capacity planning policies based on the business requirements of an organization &amp; yeah this would be all done through LIVE DEMOS 🙂 Day &amp; Date : Thursday, 24th Mar 2016</description></item><item><title>Is there any #vROps reference architecture?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/is-there-any-vrops-reference-architecture/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 12:17:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/is-there-any-vrops-reference-architecture/</guid><description>Given the flexibility in which you can choose to use and deploy vROps a question that frequently comes out is “is there a best practice?”
While that phrase is getting pretty tired it is still valid if you are just starting a design for a new vROps build or trying to make the best of a bad implementation. Rather than me trying to tell you how you should use vROps in your place of work I would direct you to a very useful PDF VMware have produced vRealize Operations Manager Reference Architecture.</description></item><item><title>Can I secure #vROps?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/can-i-secure-vrops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 13:42:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/can-i-secure-vrops/</guid><description>Those of you used to using vSphere on a regular basis will already be aware of the hardening guide for ESXi and vSphere but what about vROps?
If the vROps appliance needs to be hardened there is already a VMware provided guide and tool to accommodate.
Secure configuration guide - http://pubs.vmware.com/vrealizeoperationsmanager-61/topic/com.vmware.ICbase/PDF/vrealize-operations-manager-61-secure-configuration-guide.pdf
“The documentation for Secure Configuration is intended to serve as a secure baseline for the deployment of vRealize Operations Manager.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 2 : Understanding vROps Policies</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-part-2-understanding-vrops-policies-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 10:31:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-part-2-understanding-vrops-policies-2/</guid><description>year long commitment of providing quality content on vRealize Operations Manager.
Please remember that this is an introductory session to policies and we intend to go deeper into policies in the next session in the month of March, where we deep dive into more details around capacity planning with vRealize Operations Manager. You will hear more about that as we progress into the next month.
A big thank you to Sunny Dua for presenting this session and Iwan Rahabok to provide all the lab equipment required for live demonstrations….</description></item><item><title>vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 2 : Understanding Policies.</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-2-understanding-policies-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 14:17:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-2-understanding-policies-2/</guid><description>vROps Webinar Series 2016 is back and as promised during the last session we would now take you to the world of vRealize Operations Policies Policies.
What is a Policy??
&amp;ldquo;A policy is a deliberate system of principles to guide decisions and achieve rational outcomes. A policy is a statement of intent, and is implemented as a procedure or protocol&amp;rdquo;
Source - Wikipedia
While the role of vRealize Operations Manager is to help you with Performance &amp;amp; Capacity Management of your Software Defined Datacenter (SDDC), it is important that you feed in the guiding principles of your Business Environment into vROps to get the rational outcomes.</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.2 – upgrade and utilization dashboards</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-6-2upgrade-and-utilization-dashboards/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 08:25:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-6-2upgrade-and-utilization-dashboards/</guid><description>As you will see the upgrade is simple and even though its early days I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen anything that has been broken!
If you are interested in seeing an example of the new utilization dashboard scroll to the bottom of this article.
Upgrading from 6.1 I will be doing this upgrade on a VA so to begin with I will need the vRealize Operations Manager - Virtual Appliance Operating System upgrade .</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.2 what&amp;rsquo;s new?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-6-2-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 07:25:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-6-2-whats-new/</guid><description>vRealize Operations 6.2 was released last night and is now available for download!
Looking at what’s new very quickly there are some good new enhancements but when you compare this to the 6.1 release it’s perhaps a little light, nevertheless there appears to be some new cool features and enhancements to be had in this version.
There does not appear to be any sizing/scale increases.
Upgrading from existing 6.1 versions can be done via a .</description></item><item><title>#vROps a new diva in the datacentre</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-a-new-diva-in-the-datacentre/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 16:06:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-a-new-diva-in-the-datacentre/</guid><description>For the last few months and certainly very recently (at the London VMUG meeting) I have had the chance to talk to peers and #vExperts and share “war stories” with regards to vRealize Operations Manager.
What has become a consistent theme in all the stories is just how much compute resources vROps requires when you “go big” and not just what is clearly defined in the sizing spreadsheet.
For example some of the large deployments I have either been involved in or heard about (to monitor upwards and beyond of 30000 VMs) required the deployment of Large vROps nodes.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Operations Webinar Series : 2015 :Part 1 : Building Self Healing Environments with #vROps</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrealize-operations-webinar-series-2015-part-1-building-self-healing-environments-with-vrops/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 10:20:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrealize-operations-webinar-series-2015-part-1-building-self-healing-environments-with-vrops/</guid><description>A series of webcasts on vRealize Operations Manager 6.x, helping you learn about anything and everything about the solution. Some of the examples include, vROps Policies, Alert Definitions, Automated Action Framework, integration to third party etc. This would include power point and live demonstrations. The session would range anywhere between 60 to 90 minutes.
With 100+ registrations and more than 70 live attendees, it was definitely a great start to this series.</description></item><item><title>Starting 2016 with a bang &amp;ndash; #vROps Webinar Series</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/starting-2016-with-a-bang-vrops-webinar-series/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 15:12:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/starting-2016-with-a-bang-vrops-webinar-series/</guid><description>With a new year comes new things and I am delighted to announce the start of a vROps based webinar series. These will consist of a set of live webcasts on different topics around vRealize Operations Manager open to public to attend live or view the recorded sessions later. Personally I am delighted to get the chance to work with Sunny Duaon this new project. Sunny is a well known and respected Senior Consultant at VMware and can be found often on twitter @Sunny_Dua.</description></item><item><title>vROps multinode SNMP gotcha</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/vrops-multinode-snmp-gotcha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 20:43:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/vrops-multinode-snmp-gotcha/</guid><description>So if you are already familiar with vROps you will know you can now have multiple nodes in your cluster.
8 nodes if you are on versions 6.0.x 16 nodes if you are on version 6.1 Why does this matter if you plan to use SNMP with your vROps cluster?
Quite simple really, what I discovered today is that even though you have a master node SNMP traps can and will be sent from all of the nodes to the destination you have configured.</description></item><item><title>#UKVMUG &amp;ndash; Curry &amp;ndash; Beer &amp;ndash; Sessions &amp;ndash; Weddings</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-curry-beer-sessions-weddings-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 13:25:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-curry-beer-sessions-weddings-2/</guid><description>This was my second UKVMUG and it was my first vCurry evening! so I was really looking forward to getting up to the event and seeing everyone.
The vCurry event was excellent and it was a great chance to enjoy good food in great company. Had the chance to meet with many people I would not normally get the chance to see, Frank @fbuechsel and Brad @VMUG_CEO to name a couple!</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015 – Days 3 and 4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-2015-days-3-and-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 21:09:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-2015-days-3-and-4/</guid><description>Wednesday I had lined up several sessions so I was quick to get along to my first session - Operational Remediation with vRealize Operations… Tying it All Together - #MGT5735. The session was excellent and gave a great overview and introduction to what is possible with remediation in vROps 6.1. Big thanks to Chima Njaka for this session.
Aside from a few other sessions I spent a lot of the afternoon in the VMUG lounge with my colleagues from @xtravirt (see pic below) and meeting lots of other folk from the around the globe (this is what makes this conference so very great for me), putting faces to twitter handles for the first time and so on.</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015 – Day 2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-day-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 06:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-day-2/</guid><description>The first full day of VMworld after PEX was a busy one.After the keynote (highlights were the docker announcements) I was on “booth babe” duty at the VMUG lounge. It was great to meet so many folk who were existing VMUG members and leaders as well as prospective new members. If you are at VMworld this year you should definitely stop by!
After lunch I hit the solutions exchange to catch up with a few vendors whom I had a few queries for also took the time to collect the #vExpert hoodie from @simplivity and the #vExpert tile from Tegile (thank you!</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015 – Just getting started</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-just-getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 14:02:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-just-getting-started/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s PEX (Partner Exchange Day) at VMworld today so its busy but not the Tuesday (first day) of VMworld busy, last night saw a fantastic #vRockstar party and a great chance to meet and have a beer with many vTwitteratti.
     Today of course has been largely overshadowed by the big new concerning the Dell announcement to purchase EMC which has triggered a great deal of discussion and a healthy amount of banter and snark!</description></item><item><title>Missing actions in vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/missing-actions-in-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 11:36:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/missing-actions-in-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>Recently the team I am working with came across an interesting bug/issue with actions missing from deployed VMs. We had checked and double checked the entitlements yet the actions that should be available to the end-user/customer were not listed.
Everything appeared to point to a permissions issue until one of the team members noticed something with regards to blueprints in the catalog.
Before I continue with what we observed and how we &amp;ldquo;fixed&amp;rdquo; it please bear in mind the blueprints were created programmatically.</description></item><item><title>vROps 6.1 – first glance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/vrops-6-1-first-glance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 15:04:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/vrops-6-1-first-glance/</guid><description>I must admit I have been quite keen to get a look at vROps 6.1 so I was quick to upgrade my lab from 6.0 to 6.1 (with not problems I might add) and have a good look at the new bits and pieces.
The bits I will cover briefly in this post are..
Upgrading from 6.0 EPO functionality Dashboards Automated actions (ON?) Upgrading from 6.0 Ensure you upgrade the OS of the appliance first (if you have one) - vRealize Operations Manager - Virtual Appliance Operating System upgrade (vRealize_Operations_Manager-VA-OS-6.</description></item><item><title>vROps 6.1 whats new?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/vrops-6-1-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 21:12:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/vrops-6-1-whats-new/</guid><description>So vROps 6.1 has gone GA!
What have the guys at VMware added? I have listed what I consider the hi-lights below
The maximum of 8 nodes has been doubled to 16!
SSO integration has been added (requires vSphere 6.0)
**Support for SRM has been added
**
         vRealize Hyperic functionality has been added</description></item><item><title>The vROps HA conundrum</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/the-vrops-ha-conundrum/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 14:54:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/the-vrops-ha-conundrum/</guid><description>One of the great new features included in vROps is High Availability, however when you look a little closer at how it works careful thought needs to go into whether you want to use it or not.
I have had several discussions with my colleagues on the subject about whether you should or should not enable it in any given deployment of a vROps cluster.
So the following are my thoughts and bullet points for you to consider when faced with same dilemma.</description></item><item><title>VCE Vision, vCOPs to vROps migration</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/vce-vision-vcops-to-vrops-migration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 22:26:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/vce-vision-vcops-to-vrops-migration/</guid><description>Recently I have been working with various products that compliment or are accessed by vCOPs/vROps via Management packs.
As vROps is still fairly new in comparative terms to other products like vCOPs and VCE Vision, when planning migrations from vCOPs to vROps it is naturally important to check compatibility and what is required for a successful migration.
If you are doing a greenfield deployment of vROps there is nothing to be concerned about, you simply need the VCE Vision appliance running version 2.</description></item><item><title>My VCAP5-DCD experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/my-vcap5-dcd-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 08:59:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/my-vcap5-dcd-experience/</guid><description>A few months ago I decided to tackle the VCAP5-DCD exam and when booking I gave myself 2 months to study before the date of the exam.
I was keenly aware that at least in this calendar year the VCAP5-DCD exam and undergone some changes E.G. it no longer had multiple choice questions (think VCP5-DCV in terms of format)
There was a wealth of knowledge out there from people whom had either passed/failed or were currently studying so it didn&amp;rsquo;t take too long to get an understanding of what disciplines/knowledge VMware were looking for in the exam.</description></item><item><title>Automate the deployment of vROps (supporting vDS)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/05/automate-the-deployment-of-vrops-supporting-vds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 12:50:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/05/automate-the-deployment-of-vrops-supporting-vds/</guid><description>Recently I have been looking at William Lam&amp;rsquo;s excellent post on automating the deployment of vROps.
After having a play around with it, to suit my own needs, I made some modifications to the Powershell script so it would support distributed switches.
# William Lam
# Edited by Simon Eady to support vDS
# www.virtuallyghetto.com
# Deployment of vRealize Operations Manager 6.0 (vROps)</description></item><item><title>Why should you go to a VMUG?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/why-should-you-go-to-a-vmug/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 15:37:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/why-should-you-go-to-a-vmug/</guid><description>Having been a VMUG member for several years and now a VMUG leader I have seen the value of being a VMUG member and attending the meetings/events/conferences continue to increase.
So why do I think you should you go? If you are using VMware technologies/products in your workplace or you are regularly consulting on said VMware products, the VMUG events are in my opinion invaluable.
It simply doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what experience/knowledge you have of the products, whether you are very new to virtualization or an old hand I guarantee you will come away from any VMUG meeting having learned something useful or dare I say been a great source/help to others whom you have met and networked with.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation (vRA) Manager Service error</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-automation-vra-manager-service-error/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 10:07:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-automation-vra-manager-service-error/</guid><description>Recently when do a fresh install of vRealize Automation (vRA) 6.2 I came across the following error after configuring the first end point.
 Error log example
     DataBaseStatsService: ignoring exception: Error executing query usp_SelectAgent Inner Exception: Error executing query usp_SelectAgentCapabilities
and Error processing ping response Error executing query usp_SelectAgent Inner Exception: Error executing query usp_SelectAgentCapabilities First of all I checked to see if the end points were working which in this case they appeared to be, but I wanted to clear the error before continuing the install.</description></item><item><title>vROps – first look – part 1 – installation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/vrops-first-look-part-1-installation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 11:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/vrops-first-look-part-1-installation/</guid><description>For several months now we have seen glimpses of vROps by way of limited blog posts and the HOL demo&amp;rsquo;s so it was great to see it finally released.
So what is it like out of the box?
vROps 6.0 Release notes
The first clear change is the move away from 2 VMs in a vAPP and consolidation down to 1 VM which is then easily scalable to more as you require.</description></item><item><title>vCOPs resources (vCenter Operations Manager)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/vcops-resources-vcenter-operations-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 12:57:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/vcops-resources-vcenter-operations-manager/</guid><description>vCOPs resources If you have spent time working with vCOPs you will be aware of the numerous and widespread resources out on the net to help you install and fine tune your deployment. Given there is a lot of content out there that is not always easy to fine immediately I wanted to collate a useful list for my own use and to share with others.
Still a work in progress.</description></item><item><title>My first VMworld..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/my-first-vmworld/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 12:38:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/my-first-vmworld/</guid><description>As this was my first VMworld I am not ashamed to say I was really stoked about attending, many of my peers have attended in the past and were going to attend.
I flew in on the Sunday evening so that I could register early on Monday for partner day, however I did miss the chance to attend what turned out to be a very popular and very full Rockstar event on the Sunday evening.</description></item><item><title>Fixing a couple of search/inventory service related errors with vCenter appliance 5.5 update 1c</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/08/fixing-a-couple-of-searchinventory-service-related-errors-with-vcenter-appliance-5-5-update-1c/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 11:56:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/08/fixing-a-couple-of-searchinventory-service-related-errors-with-vcenter-appliance-5-5-update-1c/</guid><description>So recently I came across an error in the vSphere windows &amp;ldquo;fat client&amp;rdquo; when trying to use the search field.
     So a quick look at the VMware knowledge base brought up the following article
http://kb.vmware.com/selfservice/microsites/search.do?language=en_US&amp;amp;cmd=displayKC&amp;amp;externalId=2063020
So I went ahead and followed the KB artricle and then tried to search again.. the following error was generated.
     Also while logging into the vSphere web client the following error appears.</description></item><item><title>VMware #vForum London and bloggers VSAN/vCHS lunch</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vmware-vforum-london-and-bloggers-vsanvchs-lunch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 15:35:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vmware-vforum-london-and-bloggers-vsanvchs-lunch/</guid><description>Fairly recently i attended the annual VMware vForum London 2014 at Wembley stadium!
If you have never been to a vForum i would certainly recommend it as it offers the chance to not only attend excellent and pertinent sessions but there is also the opportunity to network and visit the large vendor hall which as ever was a busy place!
 Keynote and sessions The opening keynote by @joebaguley (Joe Baguley) was excellent and as challenging as ever one aspect that stood out to me personally was the question &amp;ldquo;where are you on your journey?</description></item><item><title>Another fantastic South West UK VMUG</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/another-fantastic-south-west-uk-vmug/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 09:09:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/another-fantastic-south-west-uk-vmug/</guid><description>On the 3rd of June we had our second South West UK VMUG and I am pleased to say it went superbly well.
As before we held it at the Mshed facilities in Bristol.
We had a great day with many sessions from sponsors,vendors and community speakers alike!
Big thanks go to our speakers that day who were..
Justin Rohan - @justinrohan - Nimble Storage - Sponsor James Smith - @james55smith - PernixData - Sponsor Julian Regel - @jr_on_the_cloud - Community session on vCD Adam Bohle - @adambohle - VMware - vCAC session Jonathan Medd - @jonathanmedd - Community session on PowerCLI/Automation Richard Munro - @RikMunro - VMware - vCHS Session One of the South West UK VMUG leaders Barry Coombs took a fantastic time lapse video of the day which can be viewed on his blog site.</description></item><item><title>Blogger briefing with Satyam Vaghani – PernixData</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/blogger-briefing-with-satyam-vaghani-pernixdata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 15:31:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/blogger-briefing-with-satyam-vaghani-pernixdata/</guid><description>Recently I had the good fortune to be invited along to a blogger briefing with Satyam Vaghani CTO and Co-founder of PernixData.Those of you not in the know Satyam already has quite the track record, more notably for authoring 50+ patents, Principle engineer and Storage CTO for VMware (10 years). So it is safe to say he knows a thing or two about storage and related technology!
Nine of us (bloggers) were in attendance.</description></item><item><title>Online VMware Forum – my thoughts</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/online-vmware-forum-my-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 21:35:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/online-vmware-forum-my-thoughts/</guid><description>This was the second online event I have attended in the last few months, the first being the VMUG Virtual event back in January. One of the aspects I enjoyed the most about that event was being able to chat to many well known and familiar faces from the wider community.
In this recent event there was a lot of focus on the various offerings from VMware with a good deal of focus on VSAN, NSX, Horizon and vCHS but certainly not neglecting their other offerings.</description></item><item><title>Infinio accelerator – quick review</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/infinio-accelerator-quick-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 12:31:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/infinio-accelerator-quick-review/</guid><description>I recently came across Infinio and after reading about the unique way it tackled the problem of increasing I/O and reducing latency I was curious to see how it would perform in my lab.
A few things I would like to point out. First of all Infinio works only with NFS storage, secondly it does not require flash storage as it utilizes the host RAM instead however it provides only read acceleration.</description></item><item><title>Definit authors awarded vExpert 2014</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/definit-authors-awarded-vexpert-2014/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 22:19:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/definit-authors-awarded-vexpert-2014/</guid><description>It was with great honor both Sam and I were awarded vExpert 2014 (my first and Sam&amp;rsquo;s second award!) we are both proud to be listed alongside so many others in the vExpert programme.
You can view the announcement and the full list here - http://blogs.vmware.com/vmtn/2014/04/vexpert-2014-announcement.html</description></item><item><title>Some useful VMware related diagrams</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/some-useful-vsphere-related-diagrams/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 16:09:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/some-useful-vsphere-related-diagrams/</guid><description>One of the things that never fails to amaze me are the superb PDF diagrams I occasionally stumble upon so i thought it would be a useful idea to list some of the the ones I have found on my travels.
vSphere 6 ESXTOP quick Overview for Troubleshooting http://www.running-system.com/images/2015/04/ESXTOP_vSphere6.pdf
       VMware vSphere 5 Memory Management and Monitoring diagram http://kb.vmware.com/selfservice/microsites/search.do?language=en_US&amp;amp;cmd=displayKC&amp;amp;externalId=2017642
      Concepts and best practices in Resource Pools http://federicocinalli.</description></item><item><title>Path Selection Policies after removing PernixData</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/multipath-policies-after-removing-pernixdata/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 23:45:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/multipath-policies-after-removing-pernixdata/</guid><description>Recently I have had the pleasure to use PernixData but I did come across a bit of a &amp;lsquo;gotcha&amp;rsquo; after uninstalling it from my hosts.
If like me you use iSCSI then you will likely spend a bit of time setting up your Path Selection Polices to suit your specific needs, so it was interesting to note the following.
When you do uninstall and remove PernixData from your hosts your Path Selection Polices do not revert back to your original configuration rather they revert back to the default vSphere setting of MRU (Most recently used).</description></item><item><title>What about VSAN for SMB/SME?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/what-about-vsan-for-smbsme/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 15:30:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/what-about-vsan-for-smbsme/</guid><description>Unless you have been sleeping under a rock you will be aware that VSAN was launched last week and has gone GA today and from what I have seen so far I do think VSAN is a great product and I think VMware have done a superb job with it.
Aside from the -many- discussions on twitter and other channels regarding the then lack of licensing information and pricing I was eager to see if VMware would offer a &amp;ldquo;foundation&amp;rdquo; VSAN option for SMB/SME</description></item><item><title>How to backup and restore your ESXi host config</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/how-to-backup-and-restore-your-esxi-host-config/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 19:15:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/how-to-backup-and-restore-your-esxi-host-config/</guid><description>There are many ways to tackle the problem of quickly redeploying or recovering ESXi hosts, Host profiles, Auto deploy etc.. however such options are either out of reach for SME/SMB users where their license does not cover such features or they have very small clusters of which Auto deploy etc would perhaps be considered overkill.
So how can we backup the config of our ESXi hosts? There is a great command you can use in vSphere CLI &amp;ldquo;vicfg-cfgbackup.</description></item><item><title>Pernixdata – ICM and initial impressions – part 1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/pernixdata-icm-and-initial-impressions-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 17:37:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/pernixdata-icm-and-initial-impressions-part-1/</guid><description>Since the keynote by Frank Denneman at the LonVMUG many months ago the PernixData product has been something I wanted to test to see what benefits it may or may not bring to our SQL environment, I did have the good fortune to briefly beta test it last year but this blog post will cover the current full version (FVP 1.0.2.0). I am aware that 1.5 is just around the corner and with it comes full support for vSphere 5.</description></item><item><title>vCHS – first impressions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vchs-first-impressions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:39:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vchs-first-impressions/</guid><description>In case you missed it VMware have now released vCHS (VMware vCloud Hybrid Service) in Europe! The first data center residing in Slough with more data centers planned across Europe in the near future.
Working in an SME that has several existing vSphere environments this was of real interest, as the need to scale out quickly from our Private clouds is rapidly becoming a requirement.
Having already spoken to VMware on the phone to get a rough idea on options and costs I decided to take a look at the Hands-on-labs to see how easy it really is to use and migrate VMs from an existing private cloud to vCHS.</description></item><item><title>VMware vSphere Mobile Watchlist released</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vmware-vsphere-mobile-watchlist-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 23:10:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vmware-vsphere-mobile-watchlist-released/</guid><description>For those of you unaware VMware recently released the VMware vSphere Mobile Watchlist
What does it do?
&amp;ldquo;VMware vSphere Mobile Watchlist allows you to monitor the virtual machines you care about in your vSphere infrastructure remotely on your phone. Discover diagnostic information about any alerts on your VMs using VMware Knowledge Base Articles and the web. Remediate problems from your phone by using power operations or delegate the problem to someone on your team back at the datacenter.</description></item><item><title>Trouble shooting – esx.problem.visorfs.ramdisk.full</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/trouble-shooting-esx-problem-visorfs-ramdisk-full/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 14:47:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/trouble-shooting-esx-problem-visorfs-ramdisk-full/</guid><description>Problem Fairly recently I came across this error message on one of my hosts &amp;ldquo;esx.problem.visorfs.ramdisk.full&amp;rdquo;
Fallout While trying to address the issue I had the following problems when the ramdisk did indeed &amp;ldquo;fill up&amp;rdquo;
PSOD (worst case happened only once in my experience) VM&amp;rsquo;s struggling to vMotion from the affected host when putting into maintenance mode. Temporary workaround A reboot of the host would clear the problem (clear out the ramdisk) for a short while but the problem will return if not addressed properly.</description></item><item><title>vCSA 5.5 won’t join AD Domain‏</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/vcsa-5-5-wont-join-ad-domain%E2%80%8F/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 15:44:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/vcsa-5-5-wont-join-ad-domain%E2%80%8F/</guid><description>Just a quick post on something that was not immediately obvious when it happened to me.
When deploying vCSA 5.5 and trying to add it to the domain, I was presented with the following error.
     I immediately did all the all the usual checks, making sure it had a static IP and correct DNS servers etc..
The one thing missing however was a FQDN for the hostname (in the network tab).</description></item><item><title>South West UK VMUG ready to launch! – 18th February</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/south-west-uk-vmug-ready-to-launch-18th-february/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 15:02:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/south-west-uk-vmug-ready-to-launch-18th-february/</guid><description>So what is VMUG? The VMware User Group (VMUG) is an independent, global, customer-led organization, created to maximize members’ use of VMware and partner solutions through knowledge sharing, training, collaboration, and events.
Presently there are five VMUGs in the UK including the latest addition - South West UK VMUG - @swukvmug
Why am I involved and why should you come along? I had been using VMware products for over 3 years and after joining twitter it was very clear to me the VMware user community was very friendly and also very helpful, it was there I learned about VMUG so the chance to meet and greet other users like myself and of course learn from the &amp;ldquo;rockstars&amp;rdquo; was to good an opportunity to pass up, after attending several meetings I was completely sold.</description></item><item><title>How to Virtualize Mac OS X using ESXi 5.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/how-to-virtualize-mac-os-x-using-esxi-5-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 15:02:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/how-to-virtualize-mac-os-x-using-esxi-5-1/</guid><description>As a proof of concept I recently tried to virtualize OS X (Mountain Lion) - It is important to note that VMware is now licensed to do so and you can read more here.
The following is an overview of the steps I followed to achieve my goal in some cases it was trial an error as I am not a regular Mac user.
The Hardware As OS X requires Apple hardware to run you will have to find yourself a Mac that will install and run ESXi.</description></item><item><title>2014: what does the future look like?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/2014-what-does-the-future-look-like/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 09:46:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/2014-what-does-the-future-look-like/</guid><description>After attending the &amp;ldquo;Future of IT&amp;rdquo; Google hangout in September, I was asked to give a quick summary on what 2014 may hold.
So without further ado..
I believe in 2014, we will see an increased demand for - and usage of - hybrid clouds, especially among SMEs who are trying to avoid large investment on private clouds to accommodate high demand, short term projects.
End user computing will play an ever larger role, with BYOD becoming even more viable for businesses, including those with strict data controlled environments.</description></item><item><title>VMware – The future of IT Google Hangout</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmware-the-future-of-it-google-hangout/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 12:16:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmware-the-future-of-it-google-hangout/</guid><description>Recently I had the privilege to be asked to attend a Google hangout with Joe Baguley (VMware CTO EMEA), Paul Saffo (Technology Forecaster) and several other well known guys from the VMUG community VMware - The future of IT Google Hangout
It was a first for me but a really enjoyable experience.
Questions that were asked in the hour long session were..
To jump to specific questions, see the links below:</description></item><item><title>New VMUG Launched – South West VMUG UK</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/new-vmug-launched-south-west-vmug-uk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 09:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/new-vmug-launched-south-west-vmug-uk/</guid><description>South West VMware User Group: The Facts, The Figures, And The Events The South West VMware User Group launches in the UK, bringing the best of VMware and the user community to The West, South West and South Wales.
The leadership team is pleased to announce the South West VMware User Group (VMUG). Meeting in Bristol at the crossroads to the South West, The West Country, South Wales and the Midlands, meetings will begin early in 2014, to bring together virtualization customers, end users and enthusiasts in an informal social setting for discussion, learning and engagement.</description></item><item><title>vSphere 5.5 – what I like from what’s new..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vsphere-5-5-what-i-like-from-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 16:17:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vsphere-5-5-what-i-like-from-whats-new/</guid><description>With vSphere 5.5 being announced at VMworld San Francisco I was very eager to see what was new and after devouring all of the great blog posts out there of the guys in attendance I wanted to summarize in my own way the aspects I think are great!
**VMDK 2TB limitation removed! (also virtual mode RDMs) ** This has to be one of the best pieces of news as it has been in the rear trying to accommodate really large VMs (changes affect both VMFS and NFS)</description></item><item><title>vSphere Design Pocketbook Contributor</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/08/vsphere-design-pocketbook-contributor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 13:44:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/08/vsphere-design-pocketbook-contributor/</guid><description>Just a quick note to say that I made it in to a recent book release as a contributor and naturally I am delighted and proud!
You can find out more here - vSphere Design Pocketbook
 </description></item><item><title>Mid-year thoughts</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/07/mid-year-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 21:33:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/07/mid-year-thoughts/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a really great year so far and incredibly busy (no complaints though!)VMware products have featured very high on my to-do list so far this year, with new hosting and DR solutions either completed or well underway. The simplicity, resilience and strength of vSphere never gets old!
I have also had the privilege to attend several London VMUG meetings all of which have been excellent! They have been superb opportunities to meet new people, put faces to Twitter names and learn more about current and forthcoming technologies orientated around visualization.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Credibility</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/04/cloud-credibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 22:16:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/04/cloud-credibility/</guid><description>So then! of late my attention has been drawn to Cloud Credibility which is a fantastic place to help validate your own and others cloud expertise by completing various tasks.
Among other things it encourages you to read up on white papers, carry out lab work (Hands-on-labs), watch training and informational materials and thus rewarding you with points for you and your team. What is also great is points really do mean prizes!</description></item><item><title>Host disk write latency errors – troubleshooting – part 2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/03/host-disk-write-latency-errors-troubleshooting-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 13:23:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/03/host-disk-write-latency-errors-troubleshooting-part-2/</guid><description>As some of you read previously, I had been experiencing disk latency issues on our SAN and tried many initial methods to troubleshoot and understand the root cause. Due to other more pressing issues this was placed aside until we started to experience VMs being occasionaly restarted by vSphere HA as the lock had been lost on a given VMDK file. (NOT GOOD!!)
The Environment:-
3x vSphere 5.1 Hosts</description></item><item><title>Voting now open for the 2013 top VMware &amp; virtualization blogs</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/voting-now-open-for-the-2013-top-vmware-virtualization-blogs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 11:20:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/voting-now-open-for-the-2013-top-vmware-virtualization-blogs/</guid><description>The voting is now open for your favourite VMware virtulization blogs over at vmware-land.com
With 200+ blogs now up and running with content covering every aspect from PowerCLI to VDI, technical deepdives and general VMware topical blogging! there is a very strong chance you will have read an article in at least a few of them.</description></item><item><title>Fixing the – the server fault invalidargument had no message – error message</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/fixing-the-the-server-fault-invalidargument-had-no-message-error-message/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 10:55:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/fixing-the-the-server-fault-invalidargument-had-no-message-error-message/</guid><description>Today while creating new VMs from a template I got the error &amp;ldquo;the server fault invalidargument had no message&amp;rdquo; when editing the VM settings, the settings were modified successfully but the error was present whether a change had been made or not to the settings of the VM.
A quick search of the web suggested removing said VM from the inventory and re-adding from the datastore, for many this fixed the issue but not for me.</description></item><item><title>A good year with VMware and better things to come!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/12/a-good-year-with-vmware-and-better-things-to-come/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 11:15:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/12/a-good-year-with-vmware-and-better-things-to-come/</guid><description>This year for me personally has been extremely busy and eventful coupled with a great deal of learning.
Without wishing to bore the pants off of any would be reader I shall summarize my ruminations as someone whom is still quite new to the VMware world.
The first thing that comes to mind is a a couple of recent meetings I have had with VMware. Learning that they are now very keen to engage with &amp;lsquo;the rest of us&amp;rsquo; and by that I mean those of us working in SME&amp;rsquo;s as we represent well over 50% of their business revenue.</description></item><item><title>Host disk write latency errors – troubleshooting</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/host-disk-write-latency-errors-troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 11:02:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/host-disk-write-latency-errors-troubleshooting/</guid><description>So recently we upgraded our cluster monitoring suite to it&amp;rsquo;s latest iteration (Veeam ONE), it was not long before I began to receive emails from the monitor informing me of Host disk write latency &amp;ldquo;errors&amp;rdquo; (Datastore write latency had exceeded the defined threshold in the monitor) on several of the Datastores on our SAN.
Naturally I began the process of cross referencing backup routines and any heavy I/O routines that may have been running at the time the warning messages were generated.</description></item><item><title>Site to Site VPN Tunnel traffic flow problems</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/site-to-site-vpn-tunnel-traffic-flow-problems/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 10:58:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/site-to-site-vpn-tunnel-traffic-flow-problems/</guid><description>Firewalls being used – Sonicwall 3500 &amp;amp; Cisco 506e
Several months ago we relocated and it was then necessary to setup a Site to Site VPN tunnel with another network. (In this instance the other network was not directly managed by us)
Upon the creation of the tunnel and after successful traffic tests all looked well. However after several hours or less in some cases traffic stopped flowing yet both firewalls reported the tunnel as “up”.</description></item><item><title>A work/learn balance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/06/a-worklearn-balance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 10:50:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/06/a-worklearn-balance/</guid><description>As with all things IT the pace of technology change is relentless and we are constantly and rightly told that change is good and that being able to evolve and move with the times is an important skill and ability.
However I am often left wondering how we can maintain a balance. I have all to often seen IT professionals falling into the trap chasing the latest and greatest and rushing to try to implement or learn new emerging technologies without much thought to what they already have.</description></item><item><title>Keep it simple stupid!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/keep-it-simple-stupid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 10:57:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/keep-it-simple-stupid/</guid><description>I am a firm believer in trying to keep things simpler where ever possible (but not for the sake of it) In years gone by I have heard many admins lament about the complexities of deploying IIS to work alongside third party plugins such as PHP. I can remember numerous occasions where I have wrestled with the config and &amp;ldquo;best practice&amp;rdquo;.
I am however glad to say finally Microsoft have taken notice of this and produced a very simple and effective deployment toolkit.</description></item><item><title>A start is a start</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/a-start-is-a-start/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 11:04:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/a-start-is-a-start/</guid><description>So here we go, my very first tech blog… so what on earth do I start with?
Given I am unlikely to have any profound revelations I shall simply focus on what I have discovered as useful and helpful on my travels!
First up then…
I have been asked on many occasions by individuals and SMEs should they opt for a brand such as HP over Dell or vice versa… as ever my default response is a brief needs analysis.</description></item></channel></rss>