<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>distributed on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/distributed/</link><description>Recent content in distributed on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:40:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/distributed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components – Part 2: Database, Web and Manager services</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-2-database-web-and-manager-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:40:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-2-database-web-and-manager-services/</guid><description>Now that the prerequisites for the IaaS layer have been completed, it&amp;rsquo;s time to move on to the actual installation of the IaaS components, starting with the database. We then move onto the first Web server, which also imports the ModelManagerData configuration to the database, populating the database with all of the info the IaaS layer needs out of the box. We then install the second Web server before moving on to the active Manager server.</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 3.1: Configure Load Balancing with vCNS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 08:53:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</guid><description>This is the first part of the 3rd article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
By the end of this part, we will not have modified the vCAC deployment in any way, we’ll just have 3 configured load balanced URLs
vCAC simple configuration with vPostgres and Load Balancers prepared An overview of the steps required are below:
Issue and install certificates Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database Configure load balancing Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering Install and configure additional IaaS server Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster Deploy a vShield Edge appliance Log in to your vShield Manager and select your Datacenter, then the Network Virtualisation tab</description></item><item><title>VCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 1: Certificates</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-1-certificates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 11:43:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-1-certificates/</guid><description>This is the first article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
Simple vCAC deployment In a simple installation you have the Identity Appliance, the vCAC appliance (which includes a vPostgres DB and vCenter Orchestrator instance) and an IaaS server. The distributed model still has a single Identity Appliance but clusters 2 or more vCAC appliances behind a load balancer, backed by a separate vPostgres database appliance.</description></item></channel></rss>