<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PowerCLI on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/category/powercli/</link><description>Recent content in PowerCLI on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 13:31:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/category/powercli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to NSX APIs – vBrownBag</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/11/introduction-to-nsx-apis-vbrownbag/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 13:31:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/11/introduction-to-nsx-apis-vbrownbag/</guid><description>Last Tuesday I had the privilege of presenting an introduction to the NSX APIs on vBrownBag EMEA - you can view the recording below or on vBrownBag&amp;rsquo;s youtube channel.
During the presentation I showed a mind map of the API, which I&amp;rsquo;ve made
available on GitHub in PDF format
I&amp;rsquo;ve also published the Postman collection and environment I used during the demonstration, which covers some basic configuration and deploy tasks:</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Wednesday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-4-wednesday/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 17:30:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-4-wednesday/</guid><description>This was as I expected, the busiest day sessions wise for me. There was so much good stuff I had to be a little ruthless on what I wanted and or needed to attend while also wanting to get into the solutions exchange.
Also at the end of the day the customer appreciate party was scheduled so that was something I was looking forward to a great deal (Hint - Kaiser Chiefs)</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: vSAN Specialist and VMware {Code} Hackathon</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-vsan-specialist-and-vmware-code-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 10:41:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-vsan-specialist-and-vmware-code-hackathon/</guid><description>VMware vSAN 2017 Specialist Exam I always like to take a discounted exam at VMworld, this year I opted for the VMware vSAN 2017 Specialist exam, which was released a few weeks ago. Having delivered quite a few vSAN based solutions over the last few years, I was fairly confident in the blueprint. I am pleased to say that I passed the exam with a score of 422, way higher than I expected!</description></item><item><title>PowerShell: Deploying vCenter High Availability in Advanced Mode</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/06/powershell-deploying-vcenter-high-availability-in-advanced-mode/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 15:09:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/06/powershell-deploying-vcenter-high-availability-in-advanced-mode/</guid><description>With the release of vSphere 6.5, VMware upped the game for vCenter High Availability (vCHA) and introduced an active/passive/witness cluster setup to provide a failover cluster for vCenter Server Appliances. The diagram below shows the architecture of the solution.
Deploying vCHA can be done in two modes - &amp;ldquo;Basic&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Advanced&amp;rdquo;. You can use Basic mode if the vCenter you want to be HA is managing the hosts it resides on - in this scenario the wizard configures your vCenter and deploys the Passive and Witness nodes for you.</description></item></channel></rss>