<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Automation on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/automation/</link><description>Recent content in Automation on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vRealize Operations 8.4 - What's New</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/04/vrealize-operations-8.4-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/04/vrealize-operations-8.4-whats-new/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There has been some really exciting things being announced/relased by VMware and their respective product teams recently so lets take a look at all the new goodness in vRealize Operations 8.4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vrealize-operations-84"&gt;vRealize Operations 8.4 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vrealize-operations-84"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vRealize Operations 8.4 delivers new and enhanced capabilities for self-driving operations to help customers optimize, plan, and scale VMware Cloud, which includes on-premises private cloud or VMware SDDC in multiple public clouds such as VMware Cloud on AWS, Azure VMware Solution (AVS), and Google Cloud VMware Engine (GCVE), while at the same time unifying multi-cloud monitoring, and supporting AWS, Azure Cloud, and Google Cloud platforms. Powered by artificial intelligence (AI), this release will provide a unified operations platform, deliver continuous performance optimization, efficient capacity and cost management, proactive planning, app-aware intelligent remediation, and integrated compliance.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using vRealize Orchestreator MP in vROps</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/using-vrealize-orchestreator-mp-in-vrops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/using-vrealize-orchestreator-mp-in-vrops/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="using-vrealize-orchestreator-mp-in-vrops"&gt;Using vRealize Orchestreator MP in vROps &lt;a class="anchor" href="#using-vrealize-orchestreator-mp-in-vrops"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="product-version---vrealize-operations-7x-and-8x"&gt;Product Version - vRealize Operations 7.x and 8.x &lt;a class="anchor" href="#product-version---vrealize-operations-7x-and-8x"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago VMware released the Orchestrator MP which is a superb way to directly call vRO workflows from vROps by way of alerts and actions. This opens the door to all manner of ideas for conditional automation using vROps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="the-limitation"&gt;The limitation &lt;a class="anchor" href="#the-limitation"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently for a customer we planned to use the vRO MP to assist a customer with a very unique/niche challenge. vRO was a key component to the challenge and we identified a possible solution using the vRO MP in vROPs which for all intents and purposes looked ideal.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using GitLab Pipelines to deploy Hugo sites to AWS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/using-gitlab-pipelines-to-deploy-hugo-sites-to-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/using-gitlab-pipelines-to-deploy-hugo-sites-to-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve posted previously about &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/"&gt;moving to Hugo as a publishing platform for this blog&lt;/a&gt;, this post is a bit more about how I&amp;rsquo;m managing the publishing using GitLab&amp;rsquo;s CI/CD Pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I need to mention that I&amp;rsquo;m using three different repositories for my code base, and why. The three repositories are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;definit-hugo - this contains the hugo site configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;definit-content - this contains the site content - markdown files, images etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;definit-theme - this contains the VMware Clarity-based theme I use for my site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;definit-content&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;definit-theme&lt;/strong&gt; are git submodules in the &lt;strong&gt;definit-hugo&lt;/strong&gt; project, mapped into the /content and /themes folders respectively. This allows me to keep the configuration, content and theme separate, and to manage them as separate entities. The aim is that the theme will eventually be in a position to be released, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to extract it from my hugo code base later on.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VCAP7-CMA Design Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/02/vcap7-cma-design-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 13:56:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/02/vcap7-cma-design-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For the last month I had been preparing for the VCAP7-CMA Design exam and I am very glad to say I passed on my first attempt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oddly I found it slightly easier than the VCP7-CMA but that I suspect is down to the fact I spend a lot of my time designing and implementing solutions for customers as opposed to day to day administration of any given solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what was the exam like?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>New Year, new things oh and a VCP7-CMA</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/01/new-year-new-things-oh-and-a-vcp7-cma/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:20:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/01/new-year-new-things-oh-and-a-vcp7-cma/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since I have had time to write a blog post, the last quarter of last year was pretty crazy from a work point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, it is now a New Year and my tech focus is turning very much on CMP related things particularly vRealize Automation. (I am also very much looking forward to learning more about VMware&amp;rsquo;s CaS which I saw demo&amp;rsquo;d at the UK VMUG late last year by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/grantorchard"&gt;Grant Orchard&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Enable vCenter High Availability with vRealize Orchestrator</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/enable-vcenter-high-availability-with-vrealize-orchestrator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 11:45:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/enable-vcenter-high-availability-with-vrealize-orchestrator/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick post today to cover a new vRO action and workflow I’ve uploaded to GitHub that configures vCenter High Availability in the basic mode. This is based on &lt;a href="https://www.virtuallyghetto.com/2016/12/vcenter-server-high-availability-vcha-powercli-6-5-community-module.html"&gt;William Lam’s excellent PowerShell module&lt;/a&gt; that does the same, but using vRO. I also hope to release a version for the advanced mode based on my &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/06/powershell-deploying-vcenter-high-availability-in-advanced-mode/"&gt;PowerShell script&lt;/a&gt; in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR - &lt;a href="https://github.com/sammcgeown/org.definit.vcha"&gt;package is availabile on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workflow itself is pretty self explanatory, with my deployment action, which returns a VC:Task, and the standard “wait for a task to end” action.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Things we can look forward to seeing in #vROps 7.0</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/things-we-can-look-forward-to-seeing-in-vrops-7-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 11:51:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/things-we-can-look-forward-to-seeing-in-vrops-7-0/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I did a quick search online and could not find a collated list so, by way of a quick summary from all the VMworld 2018 announcements and comments my good friend and PM for vRealize Operations &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua"&gt;Sunny Dua&lt;/a&gt; has made, I have collated a list of what we can expect to see in the next iteration of vROps (7.0). The list is in no order of interest or importance, some of the mentioned improvements have been long standing requests so enjoy and get hyped (I know I am).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.7 – Automate all the things..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrops-6-7-automate-all-the-things/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 12:24:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrops-6-7-automate-all-the-things/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;There are many improvements, changes and new additions to vROps in version 6.7 but one of the aspects that stands out to me personally is the direction VMware are taking with the product. Aside from the obvious addition of cloud costings and comparisons and a reworked capacity planning (from the ground up) and new hook in to  Wavefront (which I really like) there has been some real effort to improve how you can further automate things from vROps.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Three Tier App for vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/03/three-tier-app-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/03/three-tier-app-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One question I’m asked quite a lot is what I use for a 3-tier application when I’m testing things like NSX micro-segmentation with vRealize Automation. The simple answer is that I used to make something up as I went along, deploying components by hand and generally repeating myself a lot. I had some cut/paste commands in my note application that sped things up a little, but nothing that developed. I’ve been meaning to rectify this for a while, and this is the result!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7.3 and NSX – Micro-segmentation strategies</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrealize-automation-7-3-and-nsx-micro-segmentation-strategies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 17:40:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrealize-automation-7-3-and-nsx-micro-segmentation-strategies/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2018/01/Firewall.jpg" alt=""&gt;vRealize Automation and NSX integration has introduced the ability to deploy multi-tiered applications with network services included. The current integration also enables a method to deploy micro-segmentation out of the box, based on dynamic Security Group membership and the Service Composer. This method does have some limitations, and can be inflexible for the on-going management of deployed applications. It requires in-depth knowledge and understanding of NSX and the Distributed Firewall, as well as access to the Networking and Security manager that is hosted by vCenter Server.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2017 – Announcing Part 4 : Optimizing Workload Performance Using Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-announcing-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 13:18:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-announcing-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/03/logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;In this coming episode, Sunny will DIVE DEEP into the interesting topic of introducing automation into operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we all know that, automating day to day operations tasks is becoming the choice of an IT organization, it is hard for them to find a solution which can completely understand their business policies and provide them the efficiency they need from automating simple operational tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on our research, we found that, one of the most time consuming activity done by an Virtual Infrastructure Administrator is to juggle resources between the changing business requirements and ensure that every VM which is being hosted in their environment is &lt;strong&gt;BEING SERVED WELL&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PowerShell: Deploying vCenter High Availability in Advanced Mode</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/06/powershell-deploying-vcenter-high-availability-in-advanced-mode/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 15:09:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/06/powershell-deploying-vcenter-high-availability-in-advanced-mode/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With the release of vSphere 6.5, VMware upped the game for vCenter High Availability (vCHA) and introduced an active/passive/witness cluster setup to provide a failover cluster for vCenter Server Appliances. The diagram below shows the architecture of the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deploying vCHA can be done in two modes - &amp;ldquo;Basic&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Advanced&amp;rdquo;. You can use Basic mode if the vCenter you want to be HA is managing the hosts it resides on - in this scenario the wizard configures your vCenter and deploys the Passive and Witness nodes for you. If you have a management cluster for your vCenter Server, or you are deploying a nested environment, you need to use the advanced mode - in this scenario you must configure your active node, deploy clones for the passive and witness nodes, then enable the configuration.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Alexa, turn on my workload cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 15:05:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I already have a vRealize Orchestrator workflow to shutdown my workload cluster. What I want to do is trigger that by a voice command from Alexa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the correct and proper thing to do here would be to create a new Alexa skill, write the function in Lambda and connect that to my Orchestrator REST API and execute the workflow. That way I could control the “intents” and “utterances” and have verbal feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator Workflow: shutdownVSANCluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vro-shutdownvsancluster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 13:21:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vro-shutdownvsancluster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;My vSphere lab is split into two halves - a low power management cluster, powered by 3 Intel NUCs, and a more hefty workload cluster powered by a Dell C6100 chassis with 3 nodes. The workload servers are noisy and power hungry so they tend to be powered off when I am not using them, and since they live in my garage, I power them on and off remotely.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series 2016 – Part 10 – A Deep Dive into vROps API</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-2016-part-10-a-deep-dive-into-vrops-api/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 12:37:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-2016-part-10-a-deep-dive-into-vrops-api/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Time to publish the recording for the 10th episode of vROps Webinar Series. This time around we spoke about vRealize Operations Manager Resful API and how to use it. Post 20 minutes of slide-ware, I jumped into the lab and thanks to the demo god, we demonstrated a number of use cases and browsed through the documentation to make it easier for you to consume and use the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua"&gt;@sunny_dua&lt;/a&gt; for doing the session while I was MIA you are a legend buddy!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying F5 BIG-IP Virtual Edition (VE) in AWS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/deploying-f5-big-ip-virtual-edition-ve-in-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/deploying-f5-big-ip-virtual-edition-ve-in-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Recently I was asked to develop some vRealize Orchestrator workflows against the F5 BIG-IP iControl REST API, but I was not able to test freely against a production appliance. After a lot of attempts to get in contact with F5 for a 90-day trial of the full version, or to purchase a lab license, I came up empty handed. The free version you can download from F5&amp;rsquo;s website is version 11.3, which does not feature the iControl REST API, which was released in 11.4.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Adding a vCloud Air (PAYG/Gen2) instance to vRealize Orchestrator as a vCloud Director host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 13:26:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Big thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pipoe2h"&gt;Jose Luis Gomez&lt;/a&gt; for this solution, his response to my tweet was spot on and invaluable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to configure vCloud Air as a vCloud Director host in vRealize Orchestrator in order to create some custom resource actions for Day 2 operations in vRealize Automation. What I found was that there&amp;rsquo;s *very* little information out there on how to do this, and I ended up writing my own custom resource mapping for the virtual machines to VCAC:VirtualMachine objects - at least that way I could add my resource action. But this still didn&amp;rsquo;t expose the vCloud Director functionality for those machines. To do this I needed vCloud Air added as a vCloud Director host.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Hidden Gem – Automation Action Framework</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-hidden-gem-automation-action-framework/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 18:23:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-hidden-gem-automation-action-framework/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-7206&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2016/03/aaf-logo.png&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;aaf-logo&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; gems deep inside, vROps in this case is not without exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Automation Action Framework (AAF) is one of these, a really powerful vROps in-built automation tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now when I have discussed this capability with my peers and friends many ask why not use vRO etc? My reply is quite simple, &amp;ldquo;what if you do not have vRO or the in house skills to utilise it properly?&amp;rdquo; also &amp;ldquo;With the AAF you do -not- need any scripting knowledge or have to setup any workflows.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What’s in my vRA7 EBS Payloads?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/whats-in-my-vra7-ebs-payloads/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 15:52:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/whats-in-my-vra7-ebs-payloads/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-6186&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;vRA&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; - a properties object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to create a workflow that I could enable to log all of the keys, values and types of the properties object for each stage of the vRA7 MachineProvisioning workflows, and create a reference for myself on the payload for each stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this I created a new workflow &amp;ldquo;debugProperties&amp;rdquo; and added an input variable called &amp;ldquo;payload&amp;rdquo;, type Properties. Next I added a single scriptable task and cycled through the properties. Some of the properties&amp;rsquo; values are actually other properties objects, so there&amp;rsquo;s a function to test the type and iterate through if required.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7 XaaS blueprint form displays: Failed to retrieve form from provider</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-xaas-blueprint-form-displays-failed-to-retrieve-form-from-provider/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 13:47:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-xaas-blueprint-form-displays-failed-to-retrieve-form-from-provider/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;VMware KB2140539&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; where requesting an XaaS (vRealize Orchestrator) blueprint fails with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Failed to retrieve form from provider&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The KB describes it occuring when &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;more than one VMware vRealize Orchestrator instance is configured for different tenants&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. The issue I faced is not the same - in my case, I had the system default tenant configured to use the embedded vRO, and the customer tenant configured to use the system default (which would be the embedded vRO!)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7 Custom Hostname with Event Broker (EB) Subscription</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-custom-hostname-with-event-broker-eb-subscription/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 17:54:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-custom-hostname-with-event-broker-eb-subscription/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The new Event Broker service in vRA7 is one of the most exciting features of this latest release, the possibilities for extensibility are huge. At this point it time you can still use the old method of using workflow stubs to customise machine lifecycle events, but at some point in the future this will be deprecated and the Event Broker will be the only way to extend.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Operations Webinar Series : 2015 :Part 1 : Building Self Healing Environments with #vROps</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrealize-operations-webinar-series-2015-part-1-building-self-healing-environments-with-vrops/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 10:20:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrealize-operations-webinar-series-2015-part-1-building-self-healing-environments-with-vrops/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;A series of webcasts on vRealize Operations Manager 6.x, helping you learn about anything and everything about the solution. Some of the examples include, vROps Policies, Alert Definitions, Automated Action Framework, integration to third party etc. This would include power point and live demonstrations. The session would range anywhere between 60 to 90 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 100+ registrations and more than 70 live attendees, it was definitely a great start to this series. On popular demand of many who could not attend the session due to time-zone differences, we have recorded the session and you can watch the same right here. It is recommended that you watch the video in HD quality for a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator REST API – "Connection pool shut down"</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/12/vrealize-orchestrator-rest-api-connection-pool-shut-down/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 17:29:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/12/vrealize-orchestrator-rest-api-connection-pool-shut-down/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you use the in-built vRealize Orchestrator instance shipped with the vRealize Automation appliance then you might run into this issue when working with the REST client:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connection pool shut down (Workflow:Get-IdentityToken / Scripting (item3)#14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/12/image_thumb.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vRA appliance version I have (6.2 - note to self, need to update lab!) includes the plugin version 1.0.4 for REST. According to the release notes, this was fixed in 1.0.5 - typical!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: vRealize Automation 7 Briefing Notes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 08:20:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;@vaficionado&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;) – if that list of names doesn’t fill you with confidence for vRA.Next, then I suggest you follow them on twitter and trust me that it’s a crack team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, my highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completely automated deployment…almost. The deployment of appliances and installation of IaaS components and pre-requisites will be wizard driven, the Window Servers will need to exist and have an agent installed, and the MSSQL server will also need to be installed. Anyone who’s done a distributed vRA install will know that this is a massive improvement over the current state of affairs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The vRealize Automation appliances will be clustered automatically for core services such as identity, cafe (portal), vPostgres and embedded vRealize Orchestrator (Embedded vRO is now recommended for production).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new identity service. No more vSphere SSO or PSC – VMware Identity Management (vIDM) is a new, highly scalable and performing federated identity platform. Any SAML identity source, and more than 3m users supported per source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An initial setup wizard that creates your first tenant, configuring things like fabric groups, business groups and vSphere endpoints automatically. It will even import your existing vSphere templates as clone blueprints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The old CDK is gone! Instead you can use any event within vRA that is pushed through the RabbitMQ message bus to trigger extensibility through workflow subscriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vRealize Orchestrator has a new HTML5 Control Center which is your single admin point for plugin configuration as well as adding metrics and monitoring for all workflows being executed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s no need for unique tenant URLs – the new vIDM platform allows a single logon interface for all tenants. (Though you can keep your URLs if you want!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vIDM can also be used to control authentication from IP source, e.g. to restrict logon to a specific subnet regardless of whether the credentials are valid or not. This has some cool ramifications for having the web layer in a DMZ, for example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality is slowly being migrated from the old IaaS/DynamicOps layer to the appliance – this is fantastic news. The migrated portions (such as vSphere Endpoint configuration) are now accessible through the vRA API, as well as gaining the speed and stability that the appliances provide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new blueprint designer is awesome. Added to that what was AppD is now called App Services and allows you to take a base blueprint (e.g. a CentOS VM) and drag and drop software components that you’ve scripted on top (e.g. Apache, then PHP). You can also drag and drop XaaS (vRO workflows) onto the blueprint, as well as existing blueprints to create nested blueprints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much fuller integration between NSX and vRA. There’s a whole raft of improvements in the integration between vRA and NSX – e.g. you can drag a new routed network onto a blueprint and it will automatically create a new Logical Switch and Distributed Logical Router to attach the Logical Switch to. Similarly load balancing applications is a drag and drop operation, as is applying existing security groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All blueprints can be imported and exported in YAML, which opens up exciting possibilities for storing versioned blueprints and retrieving programmatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are over 60 lifecycle events out of the box on which you can trigger Orchestrator workflows, but you can create custom filters based on properties and events to extend functionality – the only limitation is what you can imagine!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still several months of development to go between now and the GA of vRA 7 and the development seems to be moving at a great pace. Between beta 1 and beta 2 there was a huge amount of change, and even the version demoed today had new features and UI.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Missing actions in vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/missing-actions-in-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 11:36:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/missing-actions-in-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png" alt=""&gt;Recently the team I am working with came across an interesting bug/issue with actions missing from deployed VMs. We had checked and double checked the entitlements yet the actions that should be available to the end-user/customer were not listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything appeared to point to a permissions issue until one of the team members noticed something with regards to blueprints in the catalog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I continue with what we observed and how we &amp;ldquo;fixed&amp;rdquo; it &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;please bear in mind the blueprints were created programmatically&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. (&lt;a href="http://automate-it.today/automating-vra-iaas-blueprint-creation-with-vro/"&gt;Automating vRA IaaS Blueprint creation with vRO&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Automate changing the vSphere 6 Platform Services Controller IP address (and vRealize Automation)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/automate-changing-the-vsphere-6-platform-services-controller-ip-address/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 15:04:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/automate-changing-the-vsphere-6-platform-services-controller-ip-address/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Note: This falls under the “I don’t think this is supported” category – use this method at your own peril!&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;As part of some testing I’ve been doing for vRealize Automation DR scenarios, I wanted to test changing the IP address of a HA PSC pair using a script (think SRM failover to a new subnet).&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying vRealize Automation 6.2 Appliance Cluster with Postgres Replication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 19:57:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The recommendations for the vRealize Appliance have changed with 6.2, the published reference architecture now does not recommend using an external Postgres database (either vPostgres appliance, a 3rd party Postgres deployment or using a third vRealize Appliance as a stand-alone database installation). Instead the recommended layout is shown in the diagram below. One instance of postgres on the primary node becomes an active instance, replicating to the second node which is passive. In front of these a load balancer or DNS entry points to the active node only. Fail-over is still a manual task, but it does provide better protection than a single instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 HA SSO (PSC) with NetScaler VPX Load Balancer for vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 15:40:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Providing a highly available single sign on for vRealize Automation is a fundamental part of ensuring the availability of the platform. Traditionally, (vCAC) vRA uses the Identity Appliance and relies on vSphere HA to provide the availability of the SSO platform, but in a fully distributed HA environment that&amp;rsquo;s not really good enough. It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to use the vSphere 5.5 SSO install in a HA configuration - however, many companies are making the move to the latest version of vSphere and don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to maintain a 5.5 HA SSO instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Automate the deployment of vROps (supporting vDS)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/05/automate-the-deployment-of-vrops-supporting-vds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 12:50:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/05/automate-the-deployment-of-vrops-supporting-vds/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/05/powercli-logo.png" alt=""&gt;Recently I have been looking at &lt;a href="http://www.virtuallyghetto.com/" title="VirutallyGhetto"&gt;William Lam&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s excellent post on &lt;a href="http://www.virtuallyghetto.com/2014/12/automate-deployment-configuration-of-vrealize-operations-manager-6-0-part-1.html" title="Automate Deployment &amp;amp; Configuration of vRealize Operations Manager"&gt;automating&lt;/a&gt; the deployment of vROps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having a play around with it, to suit my own needs, I made some modifications to the Powershell script so it would support distributed switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# William Lam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Edited by Simon Eady to support vDS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# &lt;a href="https://www.virtuallyghetto.com"&gt;www.virtuallyghetto.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Deployment of vRealize Operations Manager 6.0 (vROps)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;### NOTE: SSH can not be enabled because hidden properties do not seem to be implemented in Get-OvfConfiguration cmdlet ###&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO) and vCloud Director – fixing bugs in "Add a vDC"</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-and-vcloud-director-fixing-bugs-in-add-a-vdc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 10:53:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-and-vcloud-director-fixing-bugs-in-add-a-vdc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;When you are using a VMware orchestration platform with an official VMware plugin to manage a VMware product, you don&amp;rsquo;t really expect to have to fix the out-of-the-box workflows. However, during some testing of some workflows with a client the other day we ran into a couple of issues with the vCloud Director plugin workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software versions used&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vCloud Director 5.5.1 (appliance for development) and 5.5.2 (production deployment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vRealize Orchestrator Appliance 5.5.2.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vCloud Director plugin 5.5.1.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="cpu-allocations-are-incorrect-for-both-add-a-vdc"&gt;CPU allocations are incorrect for both &amp;ldquo;Add a VDC&amp;rdquo; &lt;a class="anchor" href="#cpu-allocations-are-incorrect-for-both-add-a-vdc"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you provide the CPU allocation model properties for the Allocation Pool model the first problem is decrypting the naming - it doesn&amp;rsquo;t match the names in the vCloud Director interface!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Performance tweak – increasing Max Heap Size for the vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO) Client</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/performance-tweak-increasing-max-heap-size-for-the-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-client/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 20:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/performance-tweak-increasing-max-heap-size-for-the-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-client/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;[Update Dec 2016: &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/increasing-the-java-heap-size-for-vrealize-orchestrator-client-7-x/"&gt;An updated article for vRO 7.x is available here&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m developing some very large, very complicated workflows for vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO), and as it&amp;rsquo;s a Java based application it will probably come as no surprise to many that the performance of the client drops off sharply as the client&amp;rsquo;s RAM usage creeps up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When working on some of the larger workflows, or after long sessions and heavy clipboard use, the client would become (even more) sluggish and in some cases would freeze entirely. This is particularly annoying because the vRO client has a habit of forcing itself on top of other applications - for instance Task Manager.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation (vRA) Manager Service error</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-automation-vra-manager-service-error/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 10:07:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-automation-vra-manager-service-error/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently when do a fresh install of vRealize Automation (vRA) 6.2 I came across the following error after configuring the first end point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Error log example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/01/msdtc-error.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DataBaseStatsService: ignoring exception: Error executing query usp_SelectAgent Inner Exception: Error executing query usp_SelectAgentCapabilities&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all I checked to see if the end points were working which in this case they appeared to be, but I wanted to clear the error before continuing the install.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>3DES Password Based Encryption with vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/3des-password-based-encryption-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 21:38:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/3des-password-based-encryption-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A requirement that often arises in large, complex orchestration projects is the need to encrypt and decrypt information. One such requirement recently specified triple DES password based encryption as the standard, which led me through a lot of Google searches to &lt;a href="https://code.google.com/p/crypto-js/"&gt;CryptoJS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CryptoJS is a growing collection of standard and secure cryptographic algorithms implemented in JavaScript using best practices and patterns. They are fast, and they have a consistent and simple interface.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Generating a secure random password with vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/generating-a-secure-random-password-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 21:17:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/generating-a-secure-random-password-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly common requirement when creating a new user to assign a randomly generated password, so during a recent engagement I wrote a little password generator to do that. I wanted to be able to chose whether special characters were used, and the length of the password - typically if the password doesn&amp;rsquo;t used special characters I would increase the length significantly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Characters should be randomly picked from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a-z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A-Z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0-9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(optional) ASCII special characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="inputs"&gt;Inputs &lt;a class="anchor" href="#inputs"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;passwordLength - the length of the password to be generated (number)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;excludePunctuation - exclude the use of special characters if TRUE (boolean)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/01/image_thumb35.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator (vCO) Multi-node Plug-in use case: Remote Site Selection and Execution</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-operations-vco-multi-node-plug-in-use-case-remote-site-selection-and-execution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 16:46:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-operations-vco-multi-node-plug-in-use-case-remote-site-selection-and-execution/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One of the use cases I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on with a customer is based on the vRO/vCO multi-node plug-in and involves the master vRO/vCO node calling proxy workflows based on a parameter - in this case the target site. As you can see from this very simple diagram, a Cloud Management System (CMS) calls a workflow on the Master node, which then executes a proxy workflow on the correct site. The trick is getting the Master Orchestrator node to pick the right proxy workflow.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Configuring and Using vRealize Orchestrator (vCO/vRO) Multi-node plugin</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/configuring-and-using-vrealize-orchestrator-vcovro-multi-node-plugin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 16:50:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/configuring-and-using-vrealize-orchestrator-vcovro-multi-node-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;To quote the release notes for the latest version of vCO/vRO Multi-node Plugin:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VMware vCenter Orchestrator Multi-Node Plug-In allows organizations to manage environments with multiple vCenter Orchestrator server instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As organizations increase their level of automation, they often find the need to deploy multiple Orchestrator instances. With the VMware vCenter Orchestrator Multi-Node Plug-In, administrators have a more efficient way to manage multiple Orchestrator instances from a central point. The plug-in allows administrators to log in to a master Orchestrator server to view the inventories and workflows of remote Orchestrator servers, and to trigger workflows remotely.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Configuring a vRO/vCAC PowerShell host with Basic Authentication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/configuring-a-vrovcac-powershell-host-with-basic-authentication/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 15:50:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/configuring-a-vrovcac-powershell-host-with-basic-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/03/20140313-043.png" alt=""&gt;To add a Windows Server 2012 R2 PowerShell host using Basic Authentication only, follow these steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure that the Windows Firewall service is running (it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if the firewall is enabled or disabled, it should always be running! That&amp;rsquo;s a general rule, not just for this).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the PowerShell host open a command prompt (*NOT* PowerShell console) as administrator and run the quickconfig command - you can re-run it if it&amp;rsquo;s already been run - but make sure it has.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.1 – Creating a user selectable network dropdown that sets Network and Network Profile correctly</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vcac-6-1-creating-a-user-selectable-network-dropdown-that-sets-network-and-network-profile-correctly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 11:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vcac-6-1-creating-a-user-selectable-network-dropdown-that-sets-network-and-network-profile-correctly/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I am aware that that&amp;rsquo;s not a catchy blog post title. In fact, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even really describe the problem or solution very well - for that I need to go into a little bit more depth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose I have configured a Reservation with two Networks ticked (&amp;ldquo;192.168.1.0-VLAN1&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;192.168.10.0-VLAN10&amp;rdquo;). As you can see in the screenshot below, each of the networks has a Network Profile created and assigned with a network pool to provide IP addressing for the VMs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.1 build out to distributed model: Clustered vCAC Appliances</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/vcac-6-1-build-out-to-distributed-model-clustered-vcac-appliances/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 10:56:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/vcac-6-1-build-out-to-distributed-model-clustered-vcac-appliances/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;With the release of vCAC 6.1 there have been some great improvements in the setup of the clustered vCAC appliances - none of the previous copying of configuration files between appliances - just a simple wizard to do it all for you. In my opinion this is superb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need to have deployed a load balancer of some sort - &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/"&gt;vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model – Part 3.1: Configure Load Balancing with vCNS&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-2-configure-load-balancing-with-nsx/"&gt;vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model – Part 3.2: Configure load balancing with NSX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Configuring vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) with PowerShell over HTTPS with Kerberos Authentication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/configuring-vcenter-orchestrator-vco-with-powershell-over-https-with-kerberos-authentication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 11:01:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/configuring-vcenter-orchestrator-vco-with-powershell-over-https-with-kerberos-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;As a PowerShell fan I find using the vCO PowerShell plugin makes my life a whole lot easier. What isn&amp;rsquo;t easy however, is  the configuration of vCO and a PowerShell jump host. Having done it a few times, this is my method for ensuring a secure working connection using HTTPS and Kerberos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="configure-the-orchestrator-appliance"&gt;Configure the Orchestrator Appliance &lt;a class="anchor" href="#configure-the-orchestrator-appliance"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since we’re planning on using Kerberos authentication, we’d better ensure that the time is correct AND syncs to the same source as the domain.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>