<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vsphere on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vsphere/</link><description>Recent content in Vsphere on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vsphere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMware Validated Designs are discontinued - Long live VMware Validated Solutions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/11/vmware-validated-designs-are-discontinued-long-live-vmware-validated-solutions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/11/vmware-validated-designs-are-discontinued-long-live-vmware-validated-solutions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you have spent any time designing IT soutions with VMware products you will very likely have come into contact with VMware Validated Designs (VVD)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;VMware Validated Design is a family of solutions for data center designs that span compute, storage, networking, and management, serving as a blueprint for your Software-Defined Data Center (SDDC) implementation. The documentation of VMware Validated Design consists of succeeding deliverables for all stages of the SDDC life cycle.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware Certified Professional - Data Center Virtualization 2021 Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/11/vmware-certified-professional-data-center-virtualization-2021-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/11/vmware-certified-professional-data-center-virtualization-2021-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Having not sat any VMware exams recently (MSC exam not including) I had to update my VMware certification status and therefore sit the VCP exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The VCP-DCV 2021 certification validates candidate skills to implement, manage, and troubleshoot a vSphere infrastructure, using best practices to provide a powerful, flexible, and secure foundation for business agility that can accelerate the transformation to cloud computing.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Foundation - Deployment Observations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/07/vmware-cloud-foundation-deployment-observations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/07/vmware-cloud-foundation-deployment-observations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working with VMware Cloud Foundation recently and while for the most part things went well there were occasions where challenges were encountered which made the delivery to the customer all the more trickier than expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is a list of observations and things to most definitely check or watch out for when delivering a VCF project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were working with VCF version 3.7.2 (yes I am aware 3.8 has arrived but that was too late for the delivery in this project)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lab Guide - Kubernetes and Storage with the vSphere Cloud Provider - Step by Step</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/06/lab-guide-kubernetes-and-storage-with-the-vsphere-cloud-provider-step-by-step/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/06/lab-guide-kubernetes-and-storage-with-the-vsphere-cloud-provider-step-by-step/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from me recent post &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/06/lab-guide-kubernetes-and-nsx-t-container-network-plugin-step-by-step/"&gt;deploying Kubernetes with the NSX-T
CNP&lt;/a&gt;,
I wanted to extend my environment to make use of the &lt;a href="https://vmware.github.io/vsphere-storage-for-kubernetes/documentation/index.html"&gt;vSphere Cloud
Provider&lt;/a&gt;
to enable Persistent Volumes backed by vSphere storage. This allows me to use
Storage Policy to create Persistent Volumes based on policy. For example, I’m
going to create two classes of storage, &lt;em&gt;Fast&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Slow&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;em&gt;Fast&lt;/em&gt; will be vSAN
based and &lt;em&gt;Slow&lt;/em&gt; will be NFS based.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Lifecycle Manager 1.2 VC data collection fails when NSX-T hostswitches are in use</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-1-2-vc-data-collection-fails-when-nsx-t-hostswitches-are-in-use/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 10:17:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-1-2-vc-data-collection-fails-when-nsx-t-hostswitches-are-in-use/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;When vRealize Lifecycle Manager 1.2 was released recently, I was keen to get it installed in my lab, since I maintain several vRealize Automation deployments for development and testing, as well as performing upgrades. With vRLCM I can reduce the administrative overhead of managing the environments, as well as easily migrate content between environments (I&amp;rsquo;ll be blogging on some of these cool new features soon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I hit a snag when I began to import my existing environment - I couldn’t get the vCenter data collection to run.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>One Node vSAN Lab Host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/12/one-node-vsan-lab-host/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 12:43:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/12/one-node-vsan-lab-host/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A little while ago I replaced my three ageing Intel NUC hosts with a single (still ageing) Dell T7500 workstation. The workstation provides 24 processor cores and 96GB RAM for a really reasonable price, while still being quiet enough to sit in my home office. One of the driving factors in retiring the old NUCs was vSAN - I know in the newer generations of NUC you can get an M2 and a SATA SSD in, but my 1st gen. models could only do a single M2.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: Deploying NSX Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-deploying-nsx-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 13:42:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-deploying-nsx-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lab-environment"&gt;Lab Environment &lt;a class="anchor" href="#lab-environment"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Book Review: VMware vSphere 6.5 Host Resources Deep Dive</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/book-review-vmware-vsphere-6-5-host-resources-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 14:36:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/book-review-vmware-vsphere-6-5-host-resources-deep-dive/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Host Resources Deep Dive book by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/frankdenneman"&gt;Frank Denneman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NHagoort"&gt;Niels Hagoort&lt;/a&gt; has been one of the most widely anticipated books in the VMware community - previous deep dive books by Frank (co-authored with Duncan Epping), tantalising blog posts and captivating presentations have whet the appetite for the last year or so. Having sat through some of these presentations at VMUGs and VMworld I can tell you the depth and understanding that the authors bring to the table is immense.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Alexa, turn on my workload cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 15:05:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I already have a vRealize Orchestrator workflow to shutdown my workload cluster. What I want to do is trigger that by a voice command from Alexa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the correct and proper thing to do here would be to create a new Alexa skill, write the function in Lambda and connect that to my Orchestrator REST API and execute the workflow. That way I could control the “intents” and “utterances” and have verbal feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – VCAP6-DCA Deploy Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-vcap6-dca-deploy-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 22:44:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-vcap6-dca-deploy-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Greetings from Day 1 of VMworld US 2016!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year I try and make use of the VMworld discount at the exam centre, and this year was no exception I sat the VCAP6-DCV Deploy exam, and results are still pending! Overall it&amp;rsquo;s a good exam, there was very little of the spelling and grammatical errors I&amp;rsquo;ve complained about in the past, performance was OK and the level of difficulty was good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building a vRealize Automation NSX Lab on Ravello</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/building-a-vrealize-automation-nsx-lab-on-ravello/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 17:06:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/building-a-vrealize-automation-nsx-lab-on-ravello/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/09/image_thumb22.png" alt=""&gt;As a vExpert, I am blessed to get 1000 CPU hours access to Ravello&amp;rsquo;s awesome platform and recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with the AutoLab deployments tailored for Ravello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Ravello&amp;rsquo;s offering&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; (where have you been?!) then it&amp;rsquo;s basically a custom hypervisor (HVX) running on either AWS or Google Cloud that allows you to run nested environments on those platforms. I did say it&amp;rsquo;s awesome.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 HA SSO (PSC) with NetScaler VPX Load Balancer for vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 15:40:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Providing a highly available single sign on for vRealize Automation is a fundamental part of ensuring the availability of the platform. Traditionally, (vCAC) vRA uses the Identity Appliance and relies on vSphere HA to provide the availability of the SSO platform, but in a fully distributed HA environment that&amp;rsquo;s not really good enough. It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to use the vSphere 5.5 SSO install in a HA configuration - however, many companies are making the move to the latest version of vSphere and don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to maintain a 5.5 HA SSO instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 Lab Upgrade – vCenter Server Appliance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-vcenter-server-appliance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 15:23:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-vcenter-server-appliance/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/07/vSphereLogo.png" alt=""&gt;I tested vSphere 6 quite intensively when it was in beta, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t ever upgrade my lab - basically because I need a stable environment to work on and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure that I could maintain that with the beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id="upgrading-the-vcenter-server-appliance"&gt;Upgrading the vCenter Server Appliance &lt;a class="anchor" href="#upgrading-the-vcenter-server-appliance"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download and mount the VMware-VCSA-all-6.0.0-2562643 ISO image (mounted as G:\ on my workstation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browse the ISO and run the Client Integration Plugin &amp;ldquo;G:\vcsa\VMware-ClientIntegrationPlugin-6.0.0.exe&amp;rdquo; - it&amp;rsquo;s a simple next, next finish sort of install.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Slow or failed logon to VCSA 5.5 with vCOps in the environment</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/slow-or-failed-logon-to-vcsa-5-5-with-vcops-in-the-environment/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 09:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/slow-or-failed-logon-to-vcsa-5-5-with-vcops-in-the-environment/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Recently I encountered this problem in a customer site whereby the logon to VCSA 5.5 would either time out, or take 3-5 minutes to actually log on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a netstat on the VCSA during the attempt to logon showed there was a SYN packet sent to the vCOps appliance on port 443 that never established a connection. Another check was attempting to connect using curl &amp;lt;https://&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&amp;gt; –k  - this would time out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Book Review: Learning Veeam Backup and Replication for VMware vSphere</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/book-review-learning-veeam-backup-and-replication-for-vmware-vsphere/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 11:23:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/book-review-learning-veeam-backup-and-replication-for-vmware-vsphere/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I was recently sent a copy of Christian Mohn&amp;rsquo;s new book &amp;ldquo;Learning Veeam Backup and Replication for VMware vSphere&amp;rdquo; to review, and as ever this is my honest opinion of this book. I am not receiving anything other than the copy of the book for this review. I don&amp;rsquo;t work for a vendor, so I have no axe to grind!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="content"&gt;Content &lt;a class="anchor" href="#content"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book starts of with explanations of basic backup strategies and explains principals like Grandfather-Father-Son media rotation and RPO/RTOs. From there it dives into the architecture of Veeam BR and its components. The remainder of chapter 1 covers a walk through of the installation of the product.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Book review: Networking for VMware Administrators</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/book-review-networking-for-vmware-administrators/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 09:34:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/book-review-networking-for-vmware-administrators/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I recently got my hands on a copy* of Chris Wahl and Steve Pantol’s Networking for VMware Administrators and was very keen to read it – especially given the reputation of the authors. I came to the book as someone who is at CCNA level (although now expired) and someone who regularly designs complex VMware networks using standard and distributed switches. I would class myself as having a fairly decent understanding of networking, though not a networking specialist.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Some useful VMware related diagrams</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/some-useful-vsphere-related-diagrams/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 16:09:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/some-useful-vsphere-related-diagrams/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware1.jpg" alt=""&gt;One of the things that never fails to amaze me are the superb PDF diagrams I occasionally stumble upon so i thought it would be a useful idea to list some of the the ones I have found on my travels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vsphere-6-esxtop-quick-overview-for-troubleshooting"&gt;vSphere 6 ESXTOP quick Overview for Troubleshooting &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vsphere-6-esxtop-quick-overview-for-troubleshooting"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.running-system.com/images/2015/04/ESXTOP_vSphere6.pdf"&gt;http://www.running-system.com/images/2015/04/ESXTOP_vSphere6.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=""&gt; &lt;a class="anchor" href="#"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id="vmware-vsphere-5-memory-management-and-monitoring-diagram"&gt;VMware vSphere 5 Memory Management and Monitoring diagram &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vmware-vsphere-5-memory-management-and-monitoring-diagram"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://kb.vmware.com/selfservice/microsites/search.do?language=en_US&amp;amp;cmd=displayKC&amp;amp;externalId=2017642" title="vSphere 5 Memory Management diagram"&gt;http://kb.vmware.com/selfservice/microsites/search.do?language=en_US&amp;amp;cmd=displayKC&amp;amp;externalId=2017642&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM) 5.5 in the Lab</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/installing-vmware-site-recovery-manager-srm-5-5-in-the-lab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 12:04:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/installing-vmware-site-recovery-manager-srm-5-5-in-the-lab/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing about with a compact SRM install in my lab - since I have limited resources and only one site I wanted to create a run-through for anyone learning SRM to be able to do it in their own lab too. I am creating two sites on the same IP subnet (pretend it&amp;rsquo;s a stretched LAN across two sites) and will be protecting a single, tiny Linux web server using vSphere Replication. I&amp;rsquo;m aiming to cover SAN based replication in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VCSA 5.5 Web Client fails to log on with &amp;ldquo;SSL certificate verification failed&amp;rdquo;</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/vcsa-5-5-web-client-fails-to-log-on-with-ssl-certificate-verification-failed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 16:13:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/vcsa-5-5-web-client-fails-to-log-on-with-ssl-certificate-verification-failed/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This had me scratching my head, what seemed to be a common problem wasn’t fixed by the common solution. It was actually my fault – too familiar with the product and setting things up too quickly to test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed a VCSA 5.5 instance in my lab as a secondary site for some testing and during the process found I couldn’t log on to the web client – it failed with the error:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware vSphere Mobile Watchlist released</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vmware-vsphere-mobile-watchlist-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 23:10:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vmware-vsphere-mobile-watchlist-released/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For those of you unaware VMware recently released the &lt;a href="http://blogs.vmware.com/vsphere/2014/02/now-available-vmware-vsphere-mobile-watchlist.html" title="VMware vSphere Mobile Watchlist"&gt;VMware vSphere Mobile Watchlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;VMware vSphere Mobile Watchlist allows you to monitor the virtual machines you care about in your vSphere infrastructure remotely on your phone. Discover diagnostic information about any alerts on your VMs using VMware Knowledge Base Articles and the web. Remediate problems from your phone by using power operations or delegate the problem to someone on your team back at the datacenter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Avoid SSO Admin lockout &amp;ndash; a.k.a. your first task after installing vSphere SSO</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/11/avoid-sso-admin-lockout-a-k-a-your-first-task-after-installing-vsphere-sso/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 12:55:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/11/avoid-sso-admin-lockout-a-k-a-your-first-task-after-installing-vsphere-sso/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In my post yesterday (&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vexpert.me/hS&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;) I talked about how to recover from an expired default SSO administrator password – this prompted a discussion on twitter with Anthony Spiteri (@anthonyspiteri) and Grant Orchard (@grantorchard) about the defaults for expiration and how to mitigate the risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first solution is to modify the password expiration policy for SSO. I’m not advocating this necessarily – I think that expiring passwords ensure that you change them regularly and increase the overall security of your SSO solution. However, I can envisage situations (similar to mine) when the SSO administrator account is not used for a long time and expired – that causes headaches.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere Security: Understanding ESXi 5.x Lockdown Mode</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vsphere-security-understanding-esxi-5-x-lockdown-mode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 10:05:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vsphere-security-understanding-esxi-5-x-lockdown-mode/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This is the first article in a series of vSphere Security articles that I have planned. The majority of this article is based on vSphere/ESXi 5.1, though I will include any 5.5 information that I find relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think lockdown mode is a feature that is rarely understood, and even more rarely used. Researching this article I’ve already encountered several different definitions that weren’t quite right. As far as I can see there are no differences between lockdown more in 5.5 and 5.1.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing VMware vSphere Update Manager Download Service and publishing via IIS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-vmware-vsphere-update-manager-download-service-and-publishing-via-iis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 15:30:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-vmware-vsphere-update-manager-download-service-and-publishing-via-iis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The vSphere UMDS provides a way to download patches for VMware servers that have an air-gap, or for some reason aren’t allowed to go out to the internet themselves – in my case a security policy prevented a DMZ vCenter Server from connecting to the internet directly. The solution is to use UMDS to download the updates to a 2nd server that was hosted in the DMZ and then update the vCenter Server from there. It also can save on bandwidth if you’re running multiple vCenter Servers, which again was the case (though bandwidth isn’t really a constraint).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCenter 5.1 Single Sign On Multi-Site error: User credentials are incorrect or empty</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/vcenter-5-1-single-sign-on-multi-site-error-user-credentials-are-incorrect-or-empty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 20:24:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/vcenter-5-1-single-sign-on-multi-site-error-user-credentials-are-incorrect-or-empty/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;While adding an additional vCenter Server to our Multi-Site Single Sign On instance I encountered a problem as I entered the details of the existing SSO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2012/11/SingleSignOnMultiSite.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The error thrown was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User credentials are incorrect or empty. Provide correct credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2012/11/ErrorMessage.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple of hours online with VMware support I took a guess at the problem. On the existing Single Sign On Configuration I have added the Active Directory domain DefinIT and in order to enable integrated authentication from the vSphere Client I moved it to the top of the list - this meant that System-Domain is no longer the default authentication domain. The SSO admin account (admin@System-Domain) is a part of that domain and so my guess is that the installer tries to authenticate using &lt;a href="mailto:admin@definit.local"&gt;admin@definit.local&lt;/a&gt; rather than System-Domain, which of course failed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Powershell – Generate Microsoft CA signed SSL certificates with vSphere 5.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/powershell-generate-microsoft-ca-signed-ssl-certificates-with-vsphere-5-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 16:59:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/powershell-generate-microsoft-ca-signed-ssl-certificates-with-vsphere-5-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;The process of requesting certificates for vSphere 5.1 is a fairly grim, manual process. It&amp;rsquo;s repetitive and easy to make a mistake on any step of the way. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve got to do this for quite a few VirtualCenter Servers, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d script the certificate generation if nothing else. I am following the excellent documentation provided in &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Implementing CA signed SSL certificates with vSphere 5.1&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; and more specifically in &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Creating certificate requests and certificates for vCenter Server 5.1 components&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing VMware vSphere Single Sign On (SSO) in Multi-site Mode</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/installing-vmware-vsphere-single-sign-on-sso-in-multi-site-mode/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 19:33:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/installing-vmware-vsphere-single-sign-on-sso-in-multi-site-mode/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt; VMware vSphere Single Sign On (SSO) can be installed in Multi-site mode to support local sign-on to vCenters that you want to be part of the same single sign on domain - for example, if you want to install Linked-Mode and have the advantage of a single pane of glass view, but can&amp;rsquo;t risk using a single SSO instance across the WAN. In other words, from &lt;a href="http://blogs.vmware.com/vsphere/2012/09/vcenter-single-sign-on-part-1-what-is-vcenter-single-sign-on.html"&gt;VMware&amp;rsquo;s blog post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multisite deployments are  where a local replica is maintained at remote sites of the primary vCenter Single Sign-On instance. vCenter Servers are reconfigured to use the local vCenter Single Sign-On service and reduce authentication requests across the WAN. Multisite deployments do drop the support of single pane of glass views unless Linked Mode is utilized and multisite deployments are actually required to maintain Linked Mode configurations where roles, permissions and licenses are replicated between linked vCenter servers. Linked mode will re-enable single pane of glass views across multisite instances.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>