<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>memory on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/memory/</link><description>Recent content in memory on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 08:37:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/memory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#vROps 6.5 – Two new enhancements/features I really liked</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/vrops-6-5-two-new-enhancementsfeatures-i-really-liked/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 08:37:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/vrops-6-5-two-new-enhancementsfeatures-i-really-liked/</guid><description>So vROps 6.5 has been out for around a month now and I finally have a little while to write a post on what I personally really like.
There is a lot of great new enhancements and improvements added in 6.5 but for the sake of brevity I shall highlight two that I really liked.
Flexibility to increase RAM in between node sizes So if you are familiar with vROps you will know that when you deploy it you have &amp;ldquo;T-Shirt&amp;rdquo; sizes to choose from, Small, Medium, Large and now Extra Large (6.</description></item><item><title>Increasing the Java Heap size for vRealize Orchestrator Client (7.x)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/increasing-the-java-heap-size-for-vrealize-orchestrator-client-7-x/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 11:05:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/increasing-the-java-heap-size-for-vrealize-orchestrator-client-7-x/</guid><description>Back in January 2015 I wrote an article on how to modify the Java heap settings for the vCenter Orchestrator client when working with very large workflows. Since vRealize Orchestrator 7.x has been released, we no longer have an installable client, just a Java WebStart file (.jnlp) that you run, or a package that you can download - but nothing that installs.
Note that none of this is official or supported by VMware as far as I know - it&amp;rsquo;s the results of my experimentation which has shown some performance improvement by increasing the configured memory pool.</description></item></channel></rss>