<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vCommunity on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcommunity/</link><description>Recent content in vCommunity on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 09:55:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcommunity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Am I the best I can be right now?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/03/am-i-the-best-i-can-be-right-now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 09:55:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/03/am-i-the-best-i-can-be-right-now/</guid><description>It has been a few years since I read (and lost) a great article on career progression and personal insight. That article helped me relax into who I am from a professional point of view, but it also challenged me.
I have been in IT for over 20 years now and in truth the first 10 years were not so great (perhaps a story for another time) but it was when I stumbled upon the vCommunity by way of Twitter and then subsequently I attended my first VMUG (in London) which completely challenged and changed my way of thinking and approach to my career.</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Tuesday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-3-tuesday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-3-tuesday/</guid><description>I managed to dodge the rainstorms in the morning before arriving, the hotel being just across the road from the Venue was a huge help (Thank you Xtravirt)
The main session was great particularly HCX announcement and the VR admin demo.
I then hit the solutions exchange as soon as it opened. There are all the usual suspects there -except- Cisco (anyone know why?)
It was also great to see the guys from Blue Medora.</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Sunday and Monday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-1-and-2-sunday-and-monday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 13:29:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-1-and-2-sunday-and-monday/</guid><description>Sunday Arriving in early on Sunday as the local flight choices are more limited from Bristol than perhaps a larger Airport, very fortunate to have a hotel so close to the VMworld venue, perhaps not so great for the evening activities but I am happy with it this way around.
Other than registration (4pm-8pm) and hopefully catching up with a few folk who have also arrived early.
In the evening I had the pleasure to meet many awesome people from the vCommunity.</description></item></channel></rss>