<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Replication on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/replication/</link><description>Recent content in Replication on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 19:57:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/replication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying vRealize Automation 6.2 Appliance Cluster with Postgres Replication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 19:57:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The recommendations for the vRealize Appliance have changed with 6.2, the published reference architecture now does not recommend using an external Postgres database (either vPostgres appliance, a 3rd party Postgres deployment or using a third vRealize Appliance as a stand-alone database installation). Instead the recommended layout is shown in the diagram below. One instance of postgres on the primary node becomes an active instance, replicating to the second node which is passive. In front of these a load balancer or DNS entry points to the active node only. Fail-over is still a manual task, but it does provide better protection than a single instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Book Review: Learning Veeam Backup and Replication for VMware vSphere</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/book-review-learning-veeam-backup-and-replication-for-vmware-vsphere/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 11:23:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/book-review-learning-veeam-backup-and-replication-for-vmware-vsphere/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I was recently sent a copy of Christian Mohn&amp;rsquo;s new book &amp;ldquo;Learning Veeam Backup and Replication for VMware vSphere&amp;rdquo; to review, and as ever this is my honest opinion of this book. I am not receiving anything other than the copy of the book for this review. I don&amp;rsquo;t work for a vendor, so I have no axe to grind!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="content"&gt;Content &lt;a class="anchor" href="#content"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book starts of with explanations of basic backup strategies and explains principals like Grandfather-Father-Son media rotation and RPO/RTOs. From there it dives into the architecture of Veeam BR and its components. The remainder of chapter 1 covers a walk through of the installation of the product.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>