<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VCF on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/category/vcf/</link><description>Recent content in VCF on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/category/vcf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMware Validated Designs are discontinued - Long live VMware Validated Solutions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/11/vmware-validated-designs-are-discontinued-long-live-vmware-validated-solutions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/11/vmware-validated-designs-are-discontinued-long-live-vmware-validated-solutions/</guid><description>If you have spent any time designing IT soutions with VMware products you will very likely have come into contact with VMware Validated Designs (VVD)
VMware Validated Design is a family of solutions for data center designs that span compute, storage, networking, and management, serving as a blueprint for your Software-Defined Data Center (SDDC) implementation. The documentation of VMware Validated Design consists of succeeding deliverables for all stages of the SDDC life cycle.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Foundation Specialist Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/06/vmware-cloud-foundation-specialist-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/06/vmware-cloud-foundation-specialist-exam-experience/</guid><description>Being a Consultant within a VMware Principal Partner there are standards we need to meet and preferably exceed.
Master Services Competencies (MSCs) are VMware partner designations designed to recognize services-capable partners with delivery expertise and experience within a VMware solution area.
With that in mind I sat the VCF Specialist exam.
The Exam The exam covers a broad spectrum of VMware technologies (vSphere, NSX-T, vSAN, Tanzu) I was apprehensive about it as there is an awful lot of material to cover that the exam expects you to have good knowledge of.</description></item></channel></rss>