<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/category/vmware/</link><description>Recent content in VMware on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/category/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Looking forward to VMware Explore - the artist formerly known as VMworld</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2022/07/looking-forward-to-vmware-explore-the-artist-formerly-known-as-vmworld/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2022/07/looking-forward-to-vmware-explore-the-artist-formerly-known-as-vmworld/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe that my &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-arriving-and-day-1/"&gt;
 first VMworld
&lt;/a&gt; was almost 9 years ago! I feel very blessed to have attended in &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-one/"&gt;
 2014 (EU)
&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-pre-event-and-partner-day/"&gt;
 2015 (EU)
&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/heading-to-vmworld-us-2016/"&gt;
 2016 (US)
&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-before-i-go/"&gt;
 2017 (EU)
&lt;/a&gt;, 2018 (my first as an employee), 2019 (my first time as a speaker!), and virtually in 2020 and 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years VMworld has been hugely formative in my career, I&amp;rsquo;ve talked many times before about how the trajectory of my career really took off when I got involved with the London VMUG, and how that led to being awarded vExpert in 2013. Through the vExpert programme, I got my first blogger pass for VMworld, and from there the networking opportunities led to certification, career advances, and ultimately making the contacts (and friends) that got me in the door at VMware. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to overstate how much VMworld has helped over the years.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Forwarding Tanzu Kubernetes Grid logs to vRealize Log Insight Cloud using the Fluent-bit Package</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/12/forwarding-tanzu-kubernetes-grid-logs-to-vrealize-log-insight-cloud-using-the-fluent-bit-package/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/12/forwarding-tanzu-kubernetes-grid-logs-to-vrealize-log-insight-cloud-using-the-fluent-bit-package/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In my previous post I walked through &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/12/ingress-ssl-and-dns-using-tkg-1.4-packages-on-tkgs-clusters/"&gt;
 configuring kubernetes ingress with automatically generated SSL certificates and DNS registration
&lt;/a&gt; using Tanzu Kubernetes Grid&amp;rsquo;s Packages. Another of the packaged applications available is Fluent-bit, which enables log forwarding from your Kubernetes cluster and workloads to a range of supported logging endpoints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of tweaks required in order to forward logs to vRealize Automation Log Insight Cloud. We need to use the HTTP output in the Fluent Bit configuration to forward the logs as a JSON payload to the Log Insight API. We also need to append an authentication header with an API key, and configure some tags so that the Tanzu Kubnernetes Grid Content Pack will pick up the logs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ingress, SSL and DNS using TKG 1.4 Packages on TKGs Clusters</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/12/ingress-ssl-and-dns-using-tkg-1.4-packages-on-tkgs-clusters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/12/ingress-ssl-and-dns-using-tkg-1.4-packages-on-tkgs-clusters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So, you&amp;rsquo;ve set up your shiny new Workload Management on vSphere, created a Namespace and deployed a cluster&amp;hellip;now what?! When you deploy a workload cluster from Workload Management on vSphere 7, it comes with basic functionality, but in order to start running workloads you will inevitably need to install additional tools. That&amp;rsquo;s where Tanzu&amp;rsquo;s Packages come into play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tanzu&amp;rsquo;s User Managed Packages are based on a project called &lt;a href="https://github.com/vmware-tanzu/carvel" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Carvel
&lt;/a&gt; which:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Replacing Docker Desktop with VMware Fusion or Workstation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/09/replacing-docker-desktop-with-vmware-fusion-or-workstation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/09/replacing-docker-desktop-with-vmware-fusion-or-workstation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just recently Docker announced some new pricing tiers for it&amp;rsquo;s almost ubiquitous Docker Desktop. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to opine much on this, time will tell whether this is a company saving move or not. Suffice to say that I work for a large company and would need a subscription to continue using Docker Desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The venerable &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/QuinnyPig" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Corey Quinn
&lt;/a&gt; was on the news like a flash, so I&amp;rsquo;ll let you &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/QuinnyPig/status/1432720164169076755" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; read his thread
&lt;/a&gt; for some hard core &lt;del&gt;snark&lt;/del&gt; analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Backing up Tanzu Kubernetes Grid (TKG) on vSphere Workloads to AWS with Velero</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/10/backing-up-tanzu-kubernetes-grid-tkg-on-vsphere-workloads-to-aws-with-velero/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/10/backing-up-tanzu-kubernetes-grid-tkg-on-vsphere-workloads-to-aws-with-velero/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As more services go live on my Kubernetes clusters and more people start relying on them, I get nervous. For the most part, I try and keep my applications and configurations stateless - relying on &lt;code&gt;ConfigMaps&lt;/code&gt; for example to store application configuration. This means with a handful of YAML files in my Git repository I can restore everything to working order. Sometimes though, there&amp;rsquo;s no choice but to use a &lt;code&gt;PersistentVolume&lt;/code&gt; to provide some data persistance where you can&amp;rsquo;t capture it in a config file. This is where a backup of the cluster - and specifically the &lt;code&gt;PersistentVolume&lt;/code&gt; is really important.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2020 and VMware {Code} Connect!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/09/vmworld-2020-and-vmware-code-connect/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/09/vmworld-2020-and-vmware-code-connect/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="where-can-you-find-me-at-vmworld-2020"&gt;Where can you find me at VMworld 2020 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#where-can-you-find-me-at-vmworld-2020"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;




 


&lt;br clear="none"&gt;
&lt;div class="clr-content-image-wrap"&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href="2020-09-16-15-11-09.png" data-lightbox="2020-09-16-15-11-09.png" data-title="VMworld 2020 - possible together" class="lb"&gt;
 &lt;img class="lb" src="2020-09-16-15-11-09.png" alt="VMworld 2020 - possible together" /&gt;
 &lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;figcaption class="clr-caption"&gt;VMworld 2020 - possible together&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;VMworld 2020 is fast approaching (Sept 29th-October 1st), and in case you hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard, it online and free! If you struggle getting funding for tickets and flights normally, this could be a golden opportunity to get involved! &lt;a href="https://reg.rainfocus.com/flow/vmware/vmworld2020/reg/form/contactInfo?src=em_5f24f618aca08&amp;amp;cid=7012H000001xDgF" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Register for VMworld 2020 for FREE here!
&lt;/a&gt; Please come and talk to me for my round table session, it will be awkward by myself!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lab Guide - Kubernetes Load Balancer and Ingress with MetalLB and Contour</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/08/lab-guide-kubernetes-load-balancer-and-ingress-with-metallb-and-contour/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/08/lab-guide-kubernetes-load-balancer-and-ingress-with-metallb-and-contour/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I run quite a few applications in Docker as part of my home network - there&amp;rsquo;s a small selection below, but at any one time there might be 10-15 more apps I&amp;rsquo;m playing around with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plex - Streaming media server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unifi - Ubiquiti Network Controller&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;homebridge - Apple Homekit compatible smart home integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;influxdb - Open source time series database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grafana - Data visualization &amp;amp; Monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pihole - internet tracking and ad blocker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vault - Hashicorp secret management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently a single PhotonOS VM with Docker was all I needed to run - everything shared the same host IP, stored it&amp;rsquo;s configuration locally or on an NFS mount and generally ran fine. However, my wife and kids have become more dependant on plex, and homebridge (which I use to control the air conditioning in my house), and if they&amp;rsquo;re down, it&amp;rsquo;s a problem. So, I embarked on a little project to provide some better availability, and learn a little in the process.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Foundation - Deployment Observations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/07/vmware-cloud-foundation-deployment-observations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/07/vmware-cloud-foundation-deployment-observations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working with VMware Cloud Foundation recently and while for the most part things went well there were occasions where challenges were encountered which made the delivery to the customer all the more trickier than expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is a list of observations and things to most definitely check or watch out for when delivering a VCF project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were working with VCF version 3.7.2 (yes I am aware 3.8 has arrived but that was too late for the delivery in this project)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lab Guide - Kubernetes and Storage with the vSphere Cloud Provider - Step by Step</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/06/lab-guide-kubernetes-and-storage-with-the-vsphere-cloud-provider-step-by-step/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/06/lab-guide-kubernetes-and-storage-with-the-vsphere-cloud-provider-step-by-step/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from me recent post &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/06/lab-guide-kubernetes-and-nsx-t-container-network-plugin-step-by-step/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; deploying Kubernetes with the NSX-T
CNP
&lt;/a&gt;,
I wanted to extend my environment to make use of the &lt;a href="https://vmware.github.io/vsphere-storage-for-kubernetes/documentation/index.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; vSphere Cloud
Provider
&lt;/a&gt;
to enable Persistent Volumes backed by vSphere storage. This allows me to use
Storage Policy to create Persistent Volumes based on policy. For example, I’m
going to create two classes of storage, &lt;em&gt;Fast&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Slow&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;em&gt;Fast&lt;/em&gt; will be vSAN
based and &lt;em&gt;Slow&lt;/em&gt; will be NFS based.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lab Guide - Kubernetes and NSX-T Container Network Plugin - Step by Step</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/06/lab-guide-kubernetes-and-nsx-t-container-network-plugin-step-by-step/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/06/lab-guide-kubernetes-and-nsx-t-container-network-plugin-step-by-step/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve done a fair amount of work learning VMware PKS and NSX-T, but I wanted to
drop down a level and get more familiar with the inner workings for Kubernetes,
as well as explore some of the newer features that are exposed by the NSX
Container Plugin that are not yet in the PKS integrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NSX-T docs are…not great, I certainly don’t think you can work out the steps
required from the official &lt;a href="https://docs.vmware.com/en/VMware-NSX-T-Data-Center/2.4/com.vmware.nsxt.ncp_kubernetes.doc/GUID-FB641321-319D-41DC-9D16-37D6BA0BC0DE.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; NCP installation
guide
&lt;/a&gt;
without a healthy dollop of background knowledge and familiarity with Kubernetes
and CNI. &lt;a href="https://networkinferno.net/preparing-a-node-for-kubernetes-and-nsx-ncp" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Anthony Burke published this
guide
&lt;/a&gt;
which is great, and I am lucky enough to be able to pick his brains on our
corporate slack.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unable to configure route redistribution with cross-vCenter NSX 6.4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/05/unable-to-configure-route-redistribution-with-cross-vcenter-nsx-6.4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/05/unable-to-configure-route-redistribution-with-cross-vcenter-nsx-6.4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I ran into this UI bug the other day when I was trying to enable route
redistribution on an Edge in a Secondary site of a cross-vCenter NSX deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Edge itself was deployed correctly, and configured to peer with a physical
northbound router, however when I attempted to configure the route
redistribution I was unable to do so.&lt;/p&gt;




 


 


&lt;br clear="none"&gt;
&lt;div class="clr-content-image-wrap"&gt;
 
 &lt;a href="images/CsWy53.jpg" data-lightbox="images/CsWy53.jpg" data-title="" class="lb"&gt;
 &lt;img class="lb" src="images/CsWy53.jpg" alt="" /&gt;
 &lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the solution was simple - use the API.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Upgrading vRA withvRLCM and JAVA versions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/upgrading-vra-withvrlcm-and-java-versions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/upgrading-vra-withvrlcm-and-java-versions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently upgraded an instance of vRA from 7.2 to 7.5 and rather than do it the manual way I used VMware’s vRealize LifeCycle Manager (version 2.0 update 3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything was going great and according to plan, the vRLCM pre-requisites checker made short work of all of the checks you need to do before you start an upgrade of vRA. You can see below vRLCM does a great job of keeping you informed of the current progress and in a really elegant way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Configuring Update Manager Download Service 6.7 on CentOS/RHEL 7 with SSL certificates</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/03/configuring-update-manager-download-service-6-7-on-centos-rhel-7-with-ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 15:47:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/03/configuring-update-manager-download-service-6-7-on-centos-rhel-7-with-ssl-certificates/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Most vSphere admins are more than comfortable with using Update Manager to download patches and update their environment, but few that I talk to actually know a huge amount about the Update Mangaer Download Service (UMDS). UMDS is tool you can install to download patches (and third party VIBs - I&amp;rsquo;ll get to that) for Update Manager and it&amp;rsquo;s useful for environments that don&amp;rsquo;t have access to the internet, or air-gapped, and also for environments with multiple vCenter Servers where you don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to download the same patch on every server. You can control which patches you download (for example, limiting to ESXi 6.7+ only) and you can add third party Vendor repositories (e.g. Dell or HPE).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VCAP7-CMA Design Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/02/vcap7-cma-design-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 13:56:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/02/vcap7-cma-design-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For the last month I had been preparing for the VCAP7-CMA Design exam and I am very glad to say I passed on my first attempt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oddly I found it slightly easier than the VCP7-CMA but that I suspect is down to the fact I spend a lot of my time designing and implementing solutions for customers as opposed to day to day administration of any given solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what was the exam like?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lab Notes – vCloud Director 9.1 for Service Providers – Part 1: Pre-requisites</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/02/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9.1-for-service-providers-part-1-pre-requisites/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/02/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9.1-for-service-providers-part-1-pre-requisites/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This series was originally going to be a more polished endeavour, but unfortunately time got in the way. A prod from James Kilby (@jameskilbynet) has convinced me to publish as is, as a series of lab notes. Maybe one day I&amp;rsquo;ll loop back and finish them…&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="requirements"&gt;Requirements &lt;a class="anchor" href="#requirements"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="routing"&gt;Routing &lt;a class="anchor" href="#routing"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because I’m backing my vCloud Director installation with NSX-T, I will be using my existing Tier-0 router, which interfaces with my physical router via BGP. The Tier-0 router will be connected to the Tier-1 router, the NSX-T logical switches will be connected to the Tier-1, and the IP networks advertised to the Tier-0 (using NSX-T’s internal routing mechanism) and up via eBGP to the physical router.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Enable vCenter High Availability with vRealize Orchestrator</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/enable-vcenter-high-availability-with-vrealize-orchestrator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 11:45:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/enable-vcenter-high-availability-with-vrealize-orchestrator/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick post today to cover a new vRO action and workflow I’ve uploaded to GitHub that configures vCenter High Availability in the basic mode. This is based on &lt;a href="https://www.virtuallyghetto.com/2016/12/vcenter-server-high-availability-vcha-powercli-6-5-community-module.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; William Lam’s excellent PowerShell module
&lt;/a&gt; that does the same, but using vRO. I also hope to release a version for the advanced mode based on my &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/06/powershell-deploying-vcenter-high-availability-in-advanced-mode/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; PowerShell script
&lt;/a&gt; in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR - &lt;a href="https://github.com/sammcgeown/org.definit.vcha" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; package is availabile on GitHub
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Things we can look forward to seeing in #vROps 7.0</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/things-we-can-look-forward-to-seeing-in-vrops-7-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 11:51:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/things-we-can-look-forward-to-seeing-in-vrops-7-0/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I did a quick search online and could not find a collated list so, by way of a quick summary from all the VMworld 2018 announcements and comments my good friend and PM for vRealize Operations &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Sunny Dua
&lt;/a&gt; has made, I have collated a list of what we can expect to see in the next iteration of vROps (7.0). The list is in no order of interest or importance, some of the mentioned improvements have been long standing requests so enjoy and get hyped (I know I am).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lab Notes – vCloud Director 9.1 for Service Providers – Part 4: RabbitMQ Cluster Installation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9.1-for-service-providers-part-4-rabbitmq-cluster-installation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 17:07:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9.1-for-service-providers-part-4-rabbitmq-cluster-installation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This series was originally going to be a more polished endeavour, but unfortunately time got in the way. A prod from James Kilby (@jameskilbynet) has convinced me to publish as is, as a series of lab notes. Maybe one day I&amp;rsquo;ll loop back and finish them…&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="rabbitmq-for-vcloud-director"&gt;RabbitMQ for vCloud Director &lt;a class="anchor" href="#rabbitmq-for-vcloud-director"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="rabbitmq-high-availability-and-load-balancing"&gt;RabbitMQ High Availability and Load Balancing &lt;a class="anchor" href="#rabbitmq-high-availability-and-load-balancing"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vCloud Architecture Toolkit states&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lab Notes – vCloud Director 9.1 for Service Providers – Part 3: NFS Server Installation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9-1-for-service-providers-part-3-nfs-server-installation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 16:57:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9-1-for-service-providers-part-3-nfs-server-installation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This series was originally going to be a more polished endeavour, but unfortunately time got in the way. A prod from James Kilby (@jameskilbynet) has convinced me to publish as is, as a series of lab notes. Maybe one day I&amp;rsquo;ll loop back and finish them…&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites"&gt;Prerequisites &lt;a class="anchor" href="#prerequisites"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve deployed a CentOS7 VM from my standard template, and configured the prerequisites as per my prerequisites post. Updates, NTP, DNS and  SELinux have all been configured. I have added a 200GB disk to the base VM, which has then been partitioned, formatted and mounted to /nfs/data - this will be the share used for vCloud Director.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lab Notes – vCloud Director 9.1 for Service Providers – Part 5: vRealize Orchestrator Cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9-1-for-service-providers-part-5-vrealize-orchestrator-cluster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 16:07:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9-1-for-service-providers-part-5-vrealize-orchestrator-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This series was originally going to be a more polished endeavour, but unfortunately time got in the way. A prod from James Kilby (@jameskilbynet) has convinced me to publish as is, as a series of lab notes. Maybe one day I&amp;rsquo;ll loop back and finish them…&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites"&gt;Prerequisites &lt;a class="anchor" href="#prerequisites"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL server deployed and configured&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two vRO 7.4 appliances deployed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before powering them on, add an additional network card on the vcd-sql network&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lab Notes – vCloud Director 9.1 for Service Providers – Part 2: PostgreSQL Installation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9-1-for-service-providers-part-2-postgresql-installation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 14:18:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9-1-for-service-providers-part-2-postgresql-installation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This series was originally going to be a more polished endeavour, but unfortunately time got in the way. A prod from James Kilby (@jameskilbynet) has convinced me to publish as is, as a series of lab notes. Maybe one day I&amp;rsquo;ll loop back and finish them…&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="installing-postgresql-10-server"&gt;Installing PostgreSQL 10 Server &lt;a class="anchor" href="#installing-postgresql-10-server"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The base OS for the PostgreSQL server is CentOS7, deployed from the same template and with the same preparation as detailed in the prerequisites post.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Upgrading PKS with NSX-T from 1.0.x to 1.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/06/upgrading-pks-with-nsx-t-from-1-0-x-to-1-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 19:31:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/06/upgrading-pks-with-nsx-t-from-1-0-x-to-1-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Yesterday, Pivotal Container Service 1.1 dropped and, as it’s something I’ve been actively learning in my lab, I wanted to jump on the upgrade straight away. PKS with NSX-T is a really hot topic right now and I think it’s going to be a big part of the future CNA landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Lab PKS 1.0.4 deployment is configured as a &amp;ldquo;NO-NAT with Logical Switch (NSX-T) Topology” as depicted in the diagram below (from the PKS documentation). My setup has these network characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware Clarity based WordPress Theme – v0.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/06/vmware-clarity-based-wordpress-theme-v0-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 21:12:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/06/vmware-clarity-based-wordpress-theme-v0-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago I saw a tweet from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/codydearkland" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Cody De Arkland
&lt;/a&gt; showing his new tweaked VMware Clarity based theme on his website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Staying up until 3am to get the brisket on, so what do I do? Work on tuning up &lt;a href="https://t.co/YDiFkGIKLY"&gt;https://t.co/YDiFkGIKLY&lt;/a&gt; with some better &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VMwareClarity?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@VMwareClarity&lt;/a&gt; styling! Check out the differences below! Subtle changes but I think it&amp;#39;s a lot better. Thoughts? &lt;a href="https://t.co/6sYnuBahwI"&gt;pic.twitter.com/6sYnuBahwI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Cody De Arkland (@Codydearkland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Codydearkland/status/1008269216049291264?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 17, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Cody has gone down the route of using Hugo and AWS, which I respect, but just seems like too much work for me at the moment! I am familiar with WordPress, and Simon is barely computer literate at the best of times, so I can&amp;rsquo;t ask him to start writing in markdown. But I did want some of this Clarity goodness - so I set about learning how to create a WordPress theme, and how to integrate Clarity with this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Lifecycle Manager 1.2 VC data collection fails when NSX-T hostswitches are in use</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-1-2-vc-data-collection-fails-when-nsx-t-hostswitches-are-in-use/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 10:17:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-1-2-vc-data-collection-fails-when-nsx-t-hostswitches-are-in-use/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;When vRealize Lifecycle Manager 1.2 was released recently, I was keen to get it installed in my lab, since I maintain several vRealize Automation deployments for development and testing, as well as performing upgrades. With vRLCM I can reduce the administrative overhead of managing the environments, as well as easily migrate content between environments (I&amp;rsquo;ll be blogging on some of these cool new features soon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I hit a snag when I began to import my existing environment - I couldn’t get the vCenter data collection to run.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Three Tier App for vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/03/three-tier-app-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/03/three-tier-app-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One question I’m asked quite a lot is what I use for a 3-tier application when I’m testing things like NSX micro-segmentation with vRealize Automation. The simple answer is that I used to make something up as I went along, deploying components by hand and generally repeating myself a lot. I had some cut/paste commands in my note application that sped things up a little, but nothing that developed. I’ve been meaning to rectify this for a while, and this is the result!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Retrieve Blueprint or Virtual Machine Custom Properties using the vRealize Automation API</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/02/retrieve-blueprint-or-virtual-machine-custom-properties-using-the-vrealize-automation-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 14:11:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/02/retrieve-blueprint-or-virtual-machine-custom-properties-using-the-vrealize-automation-api/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Just a quick post today, as I was working with a customer recently and we were trying to retrieve the Custom Properties assigned to a vRealize Automation 7.3 deployed Virtual Machine, similar to the one in the image below. It’s not as intuitive as you’d like it to be because of the split between IaaS APIs and Cafe APIs. Below you can see I’ve deployed a simple CentOS blueprint with a custom property at the Blueprint level (called “BlueprintLevel” with a value of “CustomProperty”) and a custom property at the VM level (called “CustomProperty” and a value of “Test123”).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NSX 6.x Network Communications Diagram</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/nsx-6-x-network-communications-diagram/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 12:01:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/nsx-6-x-network-communications-diagram/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;There are a few NSX Communications network diagrams floating around, but none have really displayed the info in a way I found to be clear or complete enough. To that end, I have been working on a diagram that covers as much of the communications between NSX Components as I can. I&amp;rsquo;ve currently only covered single site NSX (not Cross vCenter) but I&amp;rsquo;ll publish an updated version soon including that.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7.3 and NSX – Micro-segmentation strategies</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrealize-automation-7-3-and-nsx-micro-segmentation-strategies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 17:40:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrealize-automation-7-3-and-nsx-micro-segmentation-strategies/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2018/01/Firewall.jpg" alt=""&gt;vRealize Automation and NSX integration has introduced the ability to deploy multi-tiered applications with network services included. The current integration also enables a method to deploy micro-segmentation out of the box, based on dynamic Security Group membership and the Service Composer. This method does have some limitations, and can be inflexible for the on-going management of deployed applications. It requires in-depth knowledge and understanding of NSX and the Distributed Firewall, as well as access to the Networking and Security manager that is hosted by vCenter Server.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: Upgrading to NSX-T 2.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/12/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-upgrading-to-nsx-t-2-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 18:31:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/12/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-upgrading-to-nsx-t-2-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday saw the release of NSX-T 2.1, with some new features and also some usability enhancements. You can check out the release notes here &lt;a href="https://docs.vmware.com/en/VMware-NSX-T/2.1/rn/VMware-NSX-T-21-Release-Notes.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; https://docs.vmware.com/en/VMware-NSX-T/2.1/rn/VMware-NSX-T-21-Release-Notes.html
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;m mid-way through this blog series, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d stick in the upgrade as a little bonus!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="download-the-upgrade-bundle"&gt;Download the upgrade bundle &lt;a class="anchor" href="#download-the-upgrade-bundle"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/12/2017-12-22_09-26-25.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="validate-the-version-and-status-of-nsx-t-components"&gt;Validate the version and status of NSX-T components &lt;a class="anchor" href="#validate-the-version-and-status-of-nsx-t-components"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/12/2017-12-22_09-52-05.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the Controller cluster status and Manager connections are up.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>One Node vSAN Lab Host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/12/one-node-vsan-lab-host/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 12:43:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/12/one-node-vsan-lab-host/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A little while ago I replaced my three ageing Intel NUC hosts with a single (still ageing) Dell T7500 workstation. The workstation provides 24 processor cores and 96GB RAM for a really reasonable price, while still being quiet enough to sit in my home office. One of the driving factors in retiring the old NUCs was vSAN - I know in the newer generations of NUC you can get an M2 and a SATA SSD in, but my 1st gen. models could only do a single M2.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: Transport Zones and Transport Nodes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/10/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-transport-zones-and-transport-nodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 21:17:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/10/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-transport-zones-and-transport-nodes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lab-environment"&gt;Lab Environment &lt;a class="anchor" href="#lab-environment"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: Edge Installation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/10/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-edge-installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 15:41:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/10/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-edge-installation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lab-environment"&gt;Lab Environment &lt;a class="anchor" href="#lab-environment"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: Adding a vCenter Compute Manager and Preparing Hosts</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/10/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-adding-a-vcenter-compute-manager-and-preparing-hosts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 14:08:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/10/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-adding-a-vcenter-compute-manager-and-preparing-hosts/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lab-environment"&gt;Lab Environment &lt;a class="anchor" href="#lab-environment"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: ESXi Host Preparation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-esxi-host-preparation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 15:16:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-esxi-host-preparation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lab-environment"&gt;Lab Environment &lt;a class="anchor" href="#lab-environment"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: Deploying Controller Cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-deploying-controller-cluster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 12:13:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-deploying-controller-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lab-environment"&gt;Lab Environment &lt;a class="anchor" href="#lab-environment"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: Deploying NSX Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-deploying-nsx-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 13:42:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-deploying-nsx-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="lab-environment"&gt;Lab Environment &lt;a class="anchor" href="#lab-environment"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Network and Security keynote and NSX-T Architecture Deep Dive #NET1863BE</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-network-and-security-keynote-and-nsx-t-architecture-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 14:19:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-network-and-security-keynote-and-nsx-t-architecture-deep-dive/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="transforming-networking-and-security-for-the-digital-era"&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Transforming Networking and Security for the Digital Era &lt;a class="anchor" href="#transforming-networking-and-security-for-the-digital-era"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wednesday morning I attended the Network and Security keynote which, if I&amp;rsquo;m honest, I found to be a bit boring. To be fair, it was probably aimed at business leaders and maybe not those that are technical. There were three customer stories, but I would have liked to have heard much more about the problems that NSX solved for them specifically, rather than being datacenter transformation/cloud journey stories that included NSX. For me, it felt like there was nothing new in the presentation that hadn&amp;rsquo;t been covered in the general sessions. I would have liked to have seen and heard a bit more what the NSBU&amp;rsquo;s leadership think is going to be big over the next 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Day Two General Session</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-day-two-general-session/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 13:09:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-day-two-general-session/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was honoured to be asked to be part of VMware&amp;rsquo;s CrowdChat for the general sessions this year, the idea being to live-tweet the General Session as it progressed. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to embed the session from CrowdChat itself below, but it might be blocked by your browser for running unsafe scripts. You can also see the commentary on the &lt;a href="https://www.crowdchat.net/VMworldDayTwo" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Day Two General Session here
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[http://www.via-cc.at/657sc]&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Intro to NSX-T Architecture #NET1510BE and NSX-T and Kubernetes #NET1522BE</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-intro-to-nsx-t-architecture-net1510be-and-nsx-t-and-kubernetes-net1522be/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 11:23:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-intro-to-nsx-t-architecture-net1510be-and-nsx-t-and-kubernetes-net1522be/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be no surprise, given &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/the-next-big-thing/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; my impending move to the VMware PSO NSX Practice
&lt;/a&gt;, that this morning I&amp;rsquo;ve been focussing on NSX-T. The two sessions I attended were the Introduction to NSX-T Architecture and Integrating NSX-T with Kubernetes. In a weird twist of scheduling, the Kubernetes session was before the introduction session, but it worked out OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the Kubernetes session really enjoyable and really felt like the speakers delivered a great overview of the integration and how they work together. I was pleasantly surprised with how fami&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;liar a lot of the concepts were, coming from an NSX-v and vRealize Automation background. It&amp;rsquo;s similar, but different! This is something I can really get my teeth into.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Day One General Session</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-day-one-general-session/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 11:17:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-day-one-general-session/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was honoured to be asked to be part of VMware&amp;rsquo;s CrowdChat for the general sessions this year, the idea being to live-tweet the General Session as it progressed. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to embed the session from CrowdChat itself below, but it might be blocked by your browser for running unsafe scripts. You can also see the commentary on the &lt;a href="https://www.crowdchat.net/VMworldDayOne" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Day One General Session here.
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[http://www.via-cc.at/057s1]&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Before I go…</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-before-i-go/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 13:35:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-before-i-go/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;**&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;a non-VMware employee&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;! I am very much looking forward to meeting friends old and new during the week, so if you see me come say hi!&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where can you find me?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the day I&amp;rsquo;m likely to be found in the bloggers area, or hanging around the vBrownbag stage, when I&amp;rsquo;m not in a session. Monday evening I&amp;rsquo;ll be leading a fearless team of hackers for the VMware {Code} Hackathon, hoping to create something cool! Tuesday evening I will be at the vExpert party, and Wednesday is the VMworld Customer Appreciation Party (I&amp;rsquo;m pretty excited to see Kaiser Chiefs play!). This year I&amp;rsquo;ve opted to fly back on Thursday morning and see my wife and kids, so I won&amp;rsquo;t be about.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The next big thing…</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/the-next-big-thing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 10:01:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/the-next-big-thing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Just under two months ago I left my role at Xtravirt and started life as a contractor. At that point I was content to live the contractor life for a year or so and see what opportunities came along. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect opportunity to come along so quickly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLDR; I&amp;rsquo;m joining VMware as part of the PSO NSX practice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen VMware as the place that I would end up working for a while now, having worked as a customer and a partner it seemed like a logical progression. And NSX is a rocket-ship that is gathering speed and momentum, it&amp;rsquo;s viewed by many as critical to the future of VMware as the public cloud begins to eat the more traditional datacenter. With so much focus on NSX at VMworld this year, I am convinced of this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title> #vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 3 – What’s New with vROps 6.6</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 06:52:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;[&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vRealize Operations Manager 6.6&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, which was recently released by VMware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started with an overview of all the cool new stuff and then drill down into individual areas. We then jumped into a Live Demo as usual to see the new features in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We would highly appreciate if you could spend 30 seconds to fill up this quick and simple survey to provide us your feedback. You can also request topics of your choice through this survey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7.3 Distributed Install – Prerequisites</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrealize-automation-7-3-distributed-install-prerequisites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 13:33:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrealize-automation-7-3-distributed-install-prerequisites/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;As a consultant I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to design, install and configure dozens of production vRealize Automation deployments, from reasonably small Proof of Concept environments to globally-scaled multi-datacenter fully distributed behemoths. It&amp;rsquo;s fair to say, that I&amp;rsquo;ve made mistakes along the way - and learned a lot of lessons as to what makes a deployment a success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, pretty much everything comes down to getting the pre-requisites right. Nothing that I&amp;rsquo;ve written here is not already documented in the official documentation, and the installation wizard does a huge amount of the work for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Book Review: VMware vSphere 6.5 Host Resources Deep Dive</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/book-review-vmware-vsphere-6-5-host-resources-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 14:36:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/book-review-vmware-vsphere-6-5-host-resources-deep-dive/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Host Resources Deep Dive book by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/frankdenneman" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Frank Denneman
&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NHagoort" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Niels Hagoort
&lt;/a&gt; has been one of the most widely anticipated books in the VMware community - previous deep dive books by Frank (co-authored with Duncan Epping), tantalising blog posts and captivating presentations have whet the appetite for the last year or so. Having sat through some of these presentations at VMUGs and VMworld I can tell you the depth and understanding that the authors bring to the table is immense.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PowerShell: Deploying vCenter High Availability in Advanced Mode</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/06/powershell-deploying-vcenter-high-availability-in-advanced-mode/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 15:09:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/06/powershell-deploying-vcenter-high-availability-in-advanced-mode/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With the release of vSphere 6.5, VMware upped the game for vCenter High Availability (vCHA) and introduced an active/passive/witness cluster setup to provide a failover cluster for vCenter Server Appliances. The diagram below shows the architecture of the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deploying vCHA can be done in two modes - &amp;ldquo;Basic&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Advanced&amp;rdquo;. You can use Basic mode if the vCenter you want to be HA is managing the hosts it resides on - in this scenario the wizard configures your vCenter and deploys the Passive and Witness nodes for you. If you have a management cluster for your vCenter Server, or you are deploying a nested environment, you need to use the advanced mode - in this scenario you must configure your active node, deploy clones for the passive and witness nodes, then enable the configuration.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Alexa, turn on my workload cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 15:05:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I already have a vRealize Orchestrator workflow to shutdown my workload cluster. What I want to do is trigger that by a voice command from Alexa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the correct and proper thing to do here would be to create a new Alexa skill, write the function in Lambda and connect that to my Orchestrator REST API and execute the workflow. That way I could control the “intents” and “utterances” and have verbal feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Getting started with vRealize Log Insight 4.3 for vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/getting-started-with-vrealize-log-insight-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 12:09:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/getting-started-with-vrealize-log-insight-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In this humble consultant&amp;rsquo;s opinion, Log Insight is one of the most useful tools in the administrator&amp;rsquo;s tool belt for troubleshooting vRealize Automation. I have lost count of the number of times I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to help troubleshoot an issue that, when asked, people don&amp;rsquo;t know which log they should be looking at. The simple fact is that vRealize Automation has a lot of log files. Correlating these log sources to provide an overall picture is a painful, manual process - unless you have Log Insight!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lab notes: Upgrading vSphere 6.0 and NSX 6.2 to vSphere 6.5a and NSX 6.3</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/02/lab-notes-upgrading-vsphere-6-0-and-nsx-6-2-to-vsphere-6-5a-and-nsx-6-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 14:07:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/02/lab-notes-upgrading-vsphere-6-0-and-nsx-6-2-to-vsphere-6-5a-and-nsx-6-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been holding off upgrading my lab to vSphere 6.5  because NSX 6.2.x doesn&amp;rsquo;t support it. With the release of NSX 6.3 and vSphere 6.5a, I can now upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sequence of the upgrade is slightly different to the generic one published by VMware because vSphere 6.5 isn&amp;rsquo;t supported with NSX 6.2. If follows that I need to upgrade NSX to 6.3 (which supports vSphere 6.0u2) before I can upgrade vSphere to 6.5a.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying ECMP with NSX for a Provider Logical Router</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/01/deploying-ecmp-for-nsx-provider-logical-router/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 15:14:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/01/deploying-ecmp-for-nsx-provider-logical-router/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Equal Cost Multipathing (ECMP), for the vSphere admin, is ability to create routes with an equal cost, which allows multiple paths to the same network to be created and traffic can be distributed over those paths. This is good for a couple of reasons - firstly is availability. If we were to lose a host, and an NSX Edge, the route will time out quicker than NSX Edge High Availability - thus providing higher availability for our network traffic. Then second reason is throughput - each NSX Edge is capable of ~10Gbps throughput, but with ECMP we can have multiple NSX Edges (up to 8) providing 10Gbps each - that&amp;rsquo;s a significant performance boost.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator Workflow: shutdownVSANCluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vro-shutdownvsancluster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 13:21:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vro-shutdownvsancluster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;My vSphere lab is split into two halves - a low power management cluster, powered by 3 Intel NUCs, and a more hefty workload cluster powered by a Dell C6100 chassis with 3 nodes. The workload servers are noisy and power hungry so they tend to be powered off when I am not using them, and since they live in my garage, I power them on and off remotely.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Increasing the Java Heap size for vRealize Orchestrator Client (7.x)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/increasing-the-java-heap-size-for-vrealize-orchestrator-client-7-x/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 11:05:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/increasing-the-java-heap-size-for-vrealize-orchestrator-client-7-x/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Back in January 2015 I wrote an article on &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/performance-tweak-increasing-max-heap-size-for-the-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-client/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; how to modify the Java heap settings for the vCenter Orchestrator client
&lt;/a&gt; when working with very large workflows. Since vRealize Orchestrator 7.x has been released, we no longer have an installable client, just a Java WebStart file (.jnlp) that you run, or a package that you can download - but nothing that installs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Note that none of this is official or supported by VMware as far as I know - it&amp;rsquo;s the results of my experimentation which has shown some performance improvement by increasing the configured memory pool. Use it at your own risk!&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying to AWS with Software Components on vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/deploying-to-aws-with-software-components-on-vrealize-automation-7/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 17:09:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/deploying-to-aws-with-software-components-on-vrealize-automation-7/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id=""&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/11/AWS-vRA.png" alt=""&gt; &lt;a class="anchor" href="#"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on some ideas in my lab to leverage the AWS endpoint on vRealize Automation. One of the things I needed to get working was getting Software Components working on my AWS deployed instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diagram to the right shows my end-stage network - the instance deployed by vRA into AWS should be in a private subnet in my VPC, and should use my local lab DNS server and be able to access my vRA instance. This allows me to make use of the vRA guest agent for software components on the deployed VMs. I also wanted to have the deployed VMs use their local NAT gateway for internet traffic, rather than paying for the data over my VPN connection.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Creating an AWS Hardware VPN Connection with Ubiquiti EdgeRouterX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/creating-an-aws-hardware-vpn-connection-with-ubiquiti-edgerouterx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 22:38:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/creating-an-aws-hardware-vpn-connection-with-ubiquiti-edgerouterx/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/11/Multiple_VPN_Tunnels_diagram.png" alt=""&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re working with Amazon and vRealize Automation Software Components, one of the requirements is for the Guest Agent (gugent) to talk back to the vRealize Automation APIs - the gugent polls the API for tasks it should perform, downloads them from the API and executes them, then updates the tasks with a status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that Virtual Machines deployed as EC2 instances in an AWS VPC require the ability to talk back to internal corporate networks - not something you&amp;rsquo;d want to publish on the internet! That&amp;rsquo;s where AWS&amp;rsquo;s VPN connections come in - you can create several types of VPN that allow such communication over a secure (encrypted) virtual private network.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>There is no one cloud solution to rule them all..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/there-is-no-one-cloud-solution-to-rule-them-all/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 17:01:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/there-is-no-one-cloud-solution-to-rule-them-all/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/10/theonering.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have been musing this a little while and decided to write this post/rant/opinion post, feel free to post your thoughts and opinions in the comments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK so here it is, one thing I have observed for a good while now is how much noise there is about how -you- should be in the cloud (Public) and if you are not you&amp;rsquo;re already dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I call Bull****!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public, Hybrid and Private clouds are &lt;strong&gt;solutions&lt;/strong&gt; not final destinations, regardless of whether you are a customer, partner, or any other third thing you should be purely focused on what is best for you or (if you provide IT services) your customer. It is plainly obvious to me that in -all- of the customers I have visited there has been no appetite or reason to mass adopt any single one solution/option as it simply would not fit how they do business and function day to day. There will of course be exceptions to this rule but they are indeed exceptions not the norm.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing .NET core, PowerShell and PowerCLI on macOS Sierra</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/installing-net-core-powershell-and-powercli-on-macos-sierra/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 10:52:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/installing-net-core-powershell-and-powercli-on-macos-sierra/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/10/powerclicore140x140.jpg" alt=""&gt;So, this is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting to write up for a while! PowerShell for macOS has been available for a while now, but what a lot of PowerCLI fans have been waiting for is to be able to use PowerCLI direct from their Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, amidst all of the noise from VMWorld, PowerCLI Core dropped as a Fling! That means that although it&amp;rsquo;s not ready for production use yet, it is ready to start testing - and I&amp;rsquo;m way more excited than I should be!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere Web Client – VSAN is Turned Off – Edit button disappears</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/09/vsphere-web-client-vsan-is-turned-off-edit-button-disappears/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 16:10:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/09/vsphere-web-client-vsan-is-turned-off-edit-button-disappears/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I ran into a strange one with my lab today where the previously working VSAN cluster couldn&amp;rsquo;t be enabled. Symptoms included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The button to enable VSAN was missing from vSphere Web Client&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vsphere_client_virgo.log had the following error:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2016-09-16T14:49:03.473Z] [ERROR] http-bio-9090-exec-18 70001918 100023 200008 com.vmware.vise.data.query.impl.DataServiceImpl Error occurred while executing query:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QuerySpec&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QueryName: dam-auto-generated: ConfigureVsanActionResolver:dr-57&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ResourceSpec&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constraint: ObjectIdentityConstraint&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TargetType: ClusterComputeResource&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target: ManagedObjectReference: type = ClusterComputeResource, value = domain-c481, serverGuid = a44e7d15-e63f-46c2-a1aa-b9b1cbf972be&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2016 – Day 2 workshops and sessions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-2-workshops-and-sessions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 16:50:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-2-workshops-and-sessions/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vrealize-automation-vexperts-workshop"&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vRealize Automation vExperts Workshop &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vrealize-automation-vexperts-workshop"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I attended a workshop with Jad El Zein in Barcelona last year and it was one of the best sessions I attended, especially as it was just on the news of vRA7&amp;rsquo;s release. This workshop was this year&amp;rsquo;s equivelant, but because the session included a lot of people just getting started with vRA a lot of the time was taken to explain what vRA does, so there was no real time for the more in depth details on the new features that are coming (some already announced and in Tech Preview). I certainly don&amp;rsquo;t begrudge the guys just starting the chance to hear the basics from Jad, but I think a more expert session would also be good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – VCAP6-DCA Deploy Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-vcap6-dca-deploy-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 22:44:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-vcap6-dca-deploy-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Greetings from Day 1 of VMworld US 2016!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year I try and make use of the VMworld discount at the exam centre, and this year was no exception I sat the VCAP6-DCV Deploy exam, and results are still pending! Overall it&amp;rsquo;s a good exam, there was very little of the spelling and grammatical errors I&amp;rsquo;ve complained about in the past, performance was OK and the level of difficulty was good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – Day 0, #vmunderground opening acts, #beVCDX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-0-vmunderground-opening-acts-bevcdx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 17:18:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-0-vmunderground-opening-acts-bevcdx/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I landed in Las Vegas about 9:30PM local time on Saturday evening, having not executed my plan to sleep on the flight! I had planned to sleep on the Toronto to Vegas leg, which would have meant I could head over to the Sips and Stogies pre-event, however a very rowdy hen do a couple of rows away meant that I didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep at all, so I grabbed a taxi down to my hotel, the Excalibur, and got myself checked in.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Adding an AWS endpoint to vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/adding-an-amazon-web-services-endpoint-to-vrealize-automation-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 09:46:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/adding-an-amazon-web-services-endpoint-to-vrealize-automation-7/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Although it&amp;rsquo;s fairly limited, you can add AWS as an endpoint for vRealize Automation 7  and consume EC2 AMIs as part of a blueprint. You can even add the deployed instances to an existing Elastic Load Balancer at deploy time. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll run through the basics to get up and running and deploy your first highly available (multiple Availability Zone, load balanced) blueprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="preparing-aws-for-use-as-a-vra-endpoint"&gt;Preparing AWS for use as a vRA endpoint &lt;a class="anchor" href="#preparing-aws-for-use-as-a-vra-endpoint"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are some obvious pre-requisites for attaching an AWS endpoint - for example, you need to have a VPC configured. There are plenty of resources out there for creating a VPC, so I won&amp;rsquo;t extend this post by replicating them. This is what I&amp;rsquo;m using:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – My session picks</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vmworld-2016-my-session-picks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 11:13:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vmworld-2016-my-session-picks/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In my post yesterday I promised to post my VMworld session picks, so here it is! I have filled my schedule, and even added some alternate picks when there were too many good sessions to go for. My session picks are focussing around:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vRealize Automation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NSX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VSAN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PowerCLI, APIs and automation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, before anyone tells me I&amp;rsquo;ve picked too many and I won&amp;rsquo;t make it to all of them - I know! I can guarantee I&amp;rsquo;ll get distracted/tired/hungry and won&amp;rsquo;t make all of them, but if I could…&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Heading to Las Vegas! #VMworld 2016</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/heading-to-vmworld-us-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 10:24:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/heading-to-vmworld-us-2016/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if I’ll take advantage of the cheap certifications this year - in previous years I’ve take &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vcix-nv-exam-experience/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; VCIX-NV
&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; VCP-NV
&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-day-2-vcap5-dcd-exam-experience/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; VCAP5-DCD
&lt;/a&gt; all with great results, so it’s something I’d consider, although at this point I’m not 100% sure what exam I’d take (I’ve done a lot of betas recently!)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Log Insight services not starting after cluster IP changes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/log-insight-services-not-starting-after-cluster-ip-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:26:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/log-insight-services-not-starting-after-cluster-ip-changes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I ran into this problem at a customer site where all the Log Insight nodes were changed due to some IP address conflicts. I think the problem occurred because the IP addresses were all changed and the VMs shut down, without time for the application to update the node IPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The symptoms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The web interface was down, a &lt;em&gt;netstat -ano | grep -i “443”&lt;/em&gt; showed the service was listening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;_service loginsight status|restart|stop|start _hung and then timed out on the Master node&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The loginsight service was not running on the Worker nodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/var/log/loginsight/runtime.log contains warning messages about “Cassandra cluster not ready yet”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running /usr/lib/loginsight/application/lib/apache-cassandra-*/bin/nodetool status showed the two data nodes down (DN) and used the old IP address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the nodes were up with their new IP addresses, however Cassandra on the Master node was still looking for the old IP addresses for the Worker nodes. The Worker nodes were in a similar state, knowing their own new IP addresses but not being able to update the Master node because they didn’t have the Master node’s new IP address.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Adding a vCloud Air (PAYG/Gen2) instance to vRealize Orchestrator as a vCloud Director host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 13:26:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Big thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pipoe2h" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Jose Luis Gomez
&lt;/a&gt; for this solution, his response to my tweet was spot on and invaluable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to configure vCloud Air as a vCloud Director host in vRealize Orchestrator in order to create some custom resource actions for Day 2 operations in vRealize Automation. What I found was that there&amp;rsquo;s *very* little information out there on how to do this, and I ended up writing my own custom resource mapping for the virtual machines to VCAC:VirtualMachine objects - at least that way I could add my resource action. But this still didn&amp;rsquo;t expose the vCloud Director functionality for those machines. To do this I needed vCloud Air added as a vCloud Director host.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What’s in my vRA7 EBS Payloads?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/whats-in-my-vra7-ebs-payloads/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 15:52:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/whats-in-my-vra7-ebs-payloads/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-6186&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;vRA&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; - a properties object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to create a workflow that I could enable to log all of the keys, values and types of the properties object for each stage of the vRA7 MachineProvisioning workflows, and create a reference for myself on the payload for each stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this I created a new workflow &amp;ldquo;debugProperties&amp;rdquo; and added an input variable called &amp;ldquo;payload&amp;rdquo;, type Properties. Next I added a single scriptable task and cycled through the properties. Some of the properties&amp;rsquo; values are actually other properties objects, so there&amp;rsquo;s a function to test the type and iterate through if required.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7 XaaS blueprint form displays: Failed to retrieve form from provider</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-xaas-blueprint-form-displays-failed-to-retrieve-form-from-provider/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 13:47:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-xaas-blueprint-form-displays-failed-to-retrieve-form-from-provider/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;VMware KB2140539&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; where requesting an XaaS (vRealize Orchestrator) blueprint fails with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Failed to retrieve form from provider&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The KB describes it occuring when &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;more than one VMware vRealize Orchestrator instance is configured for different tenants&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. The issue I faced is not the same - in my case, I had the system default tenant configured to use the embedded vRO, and the customer tenant configured to use the system default (which would be the embedded vRO!)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7 Custom Hostname with Event Broker (EB) Subscription</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-custom-hostname-with-event-broker-eb-subscription/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 17:54:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-custom-hostname-with-event-broker-eb-subscription/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The new Event Broker service in vRA7 is one of the most exciting features of this latest release, the possibilities for extensibility are huge. At this point it time you can still use the old method of using workflow stubs to customise machine lifecycle events, but at some point in the future this will be deprecated and the Event Broker will be the only way to extend.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Can I secure #vROps?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/can-i-secure-vrops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 13:42:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/can-i-secure-vrops/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Those of you used to using vSphere on a regular basis will already be aware of the hardening guide for ESXi and vSphere but what about vROps?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the vROps appliance needs to be hardened there is already a VMware provided guide and tool to accommodate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secure configuration guide - &lt;a href="http://pubs.vmware.com/vrealizeoperationsmanager-61/topic/com.vmware.ICbase/PDF/vrealize-operations-manager-61-secure-configuration-guide.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; http://pubs.vmware.com/vrealizeoperationsmanager-61/topic/com.vmware.ICbase/PDF/vrealize-operations-manager-61-secure-configuration-guide.pdf
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The documentation for Secure Configuration is intended to serve as a secure baseline for the deployment of vRealize Operations Manager.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 2 : Understanding vROps Policies</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-part-2-understanding-vrops-policies-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 10:31:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-part-2-understanding-vrops-policies-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;year long commitment&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; of providing quality content on vRealize Operations Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please remember that this is an introductory session to policies and we intend to go deeper into policies in the next session in the month of March, where we deep dive into more details around capacity planning with vRealize Operations Manager. You will hear more about that as we progress into the next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Running Platypus in Docker on Photon with AppCatalyst</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/platypusindockeronphotonwithappcatalyst/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 08:09:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/platypusindockeronphotonwithappcatalyst/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick little post this morning! Anyone who works with the vRealize Automation APIs should definitely check out Grant Orchard and Roman Tarnavski’s awesome little side project, &lt;a href="http://grantorchard.com/uncategorized/platypus-vra7-api-documentation/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Platypus
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It only took me a couple of minutes to get it running on my MacBook - here’s how!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download and install &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;AppCatalyst&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open a new terminal window&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a new VM called “photon&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.2 – upgrade and utilization dashboards</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-6-2upgrade-and-utilization-dashboards/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 08:25:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-6-2upgrade-and-utilization-dashboards/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;As you will see the upgrade is simple and even though its early days I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen anything that has been broken!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in seeing an example of the new utilization dashboard scroll to the bottom of this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="upgrading-from-61"&gt;Upgrading from 6.1 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#upgrading-from-61"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will be doing this upgrade on a VA so to begin with I will need the vRealize Operations Manager - Virtual Appliance Operating System upgrade .pak file (Realize_Operations_Manager-VA-OS-6.2.0.3445569.pak)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.2 what&amp;rsquo;s new?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-6-2-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 07:25:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-6-2-whats-new/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;vRealize Operations 6.2 was released last night and is now available for &lt;a href="https://my.vmware.com/group/vmware/details?downloadGroup=VROPS-620&amp;amp;productId=563&amp;amp;rPId=10016" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; download!
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at what’s new very quickly there are some good new enhancements but when you compare this to the 6.1 release it’s perhaps a little light, nevertheless there appears to be some new cool features and enhancements to be had in this version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There does not appear to be any sizing/scale increases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upgrading from existing 6.1 versions can be done via a .pak file.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps a new diva in the datacentre</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-a-new-diva-in-the-datacentre/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 16:06:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-a-new-diva-in-the-datacentre/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;For the last few months and certainly very recently (at the London VMUG meeting) I have had the chance to talk to peers and #vExperts and share “war stories” with regards to vRealize Operations Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What has become a consistent theme in all the stories is just how much compute resources vROps requires when you “go big” and not just what is clearly defined in the sizing spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example some of the large deployments I have either been involved in or heard about (to monitor upwards and beyond of 30000 VMs) required the deployment of Large vROps nodes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Operations Webinar Series : 2015 :Part 1 : Building Self Healing Environments with #vROps</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrealize-operations-webinar-series-2015-part-1-building-self-healing-environments-with-vrops/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 10:20:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrealize-operations-webinar-series-2015-part-1-building-self-healing-environments-with-vrops/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;A series of webcasts on vRealize Operations Manager 6.x, helping you learn about anything and everything about the solution. Some of the examples include, vROps Policies, Alert Definitions, Automated Action Framework, integration to third party etc. This would include power point and live demonstrations. The session would range anywhere between 60 to 90 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 100+ registrations and more than 70 live attendees, it was definitely a great start to this series. On popular demand of many who could not attend the session due to time-zone differences, we have recorded the session and you can watch the same right here. It is recommended that you watch the video in HD quality for a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator REST API – "Connection pool shut down"</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/12/vrealize-orchestrator-rest-api-connection-pool-shut-down/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 17:29:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/12/vrealize-orchestrator-rest-api-connection-pool-shut-down/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you use the in-built vRealize Orchestrator instance shipped with the vRealize Automation appliance then you might run into this issue when working with the REST client:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connection pool shut down (Workflow:Get-IdentityToken / Scripting (item3)#14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/12/image_thumb.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vRA appliance version I have (6.2 - note to self, need to update lab!) includes the plugin version 1.0.4 for REST. According to the release notes, this was fixed in 1.0.5 - typical!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>MindMap: vRealize Automation Roles</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/mindmap-vrealize-automation-roles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 20:45:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/mindmap-vrealize-automation-roles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I use mind maps quite a lot for study, I find the visual representation of info makes it a lot easier for me to remember! Below is a mind map I created for learning the roles in vRealize Automation, which I used during my presentation for #vBrownBag on VCP6-CMA objective 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download a PDF version here: &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vRealize Automation Roles Mind Map&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VCDX-CMA 204</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vcdx-cma-204/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 11:51:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vcdx-cma-204/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apologies in advance if this is post is a jumbled nonsense, I&amp;rsquo;m still way too excited!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning I woke to the news that I have passed my VCDX-CMA!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my second attempt at VCDX and although the first failure was a painful experience, the lessons learned from it were invaluable to take into the defence the second time around. Failing doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be a negative experience - if there is one thing that I will take from the VCDX program it is that there is ALWAYS more I need to learn, and I can always do better. Learning has to be a way of life (in this industry especially!) and the minute you stop, you start falling back.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015 – Days 3 and 4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-2015-days-3-and-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 21:09:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-2015-days-3-and-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="wednesday"&gt;Wednesday &lt;a class="anchor" href="#wednesday"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had lined up several sessions so I was quick to get along to my first session - Operational Remediation with vRealize Operations… Tying it All Together - #MGT5735. The session was excellent and gave a great overview and introduction to what is possible with remediation in vROps 6.1. Big thanks to Chima Njaka for this session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/10/CRRF3iyW8AA6yHx_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from a few other sessions I spent a lot of the afternoon in the VMUG lounge with my colleagues from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Xtravirt" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; @xtravirt
&lt;/a&gt; (see pic below) and meeting lots of other folk from the around the globe (this is what makes this conference so very great for me), putting faces to twitter handles for the first time and so on. Networking with your peers at an event such as this is incredibly valuable, educational and really enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: vRealize Automation 7 Briefing Notes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 08:20:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;@vaficionado&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;) – if that list of names doesn’t fill you with confidence for vRA.Next, then I suggest you follow them on twitter and trust me that it’s a crack team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, my highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completely automated deployment…almost. The deployment of appliances and installation of IaaS components and pre-requisites will be wizard driven, the Window Servers will need to exist and have an agent installed, and the MSSQL server will also need to be installed. Anyone who’s done a distributed vRA install will know that this is a massive improvement over the current state of affairs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The vRealize Automation appliances will be clustered automatically for core services such as identity, cafe (portal), vPostgres and embedded vRealize Orchestrator (Embedded vRO is now recommended for production).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new identity service. No more vSphere SSO or PSC – VMware Identity Management (vIDM) is a new, highly scalable and performing federated identity platform. Any SAML identity source, and more than 3m users supported per source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An initial setup wizard that creates your first tenant, configuring things like fabric groups, business groups and vSphere endpoints automatically. It will even import your existing vSphere templates as clone blueprints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The old CDK is gone! Instead you can use any event within vRA that is pushed through the RabbitMQ message bus to trigger extensibility through workflow subscriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vRealize Orchestrator has a new HTML5 Control Center which is your single admin point for plugin configuration as well as adding metrics and monitoring for all workflows being executed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s no need for unique tenant URLs – the new vIDM platform allows a single logon interface for all tenants. (Though you can keep your URLs if you want!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vIDM can also be used to control authentication from IP source, e.g. to restrict logon to a specific subnet regardless of whether the credentials are valid or not. This has some cool ramifications for having the web layer in a DMZ, for example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality is slowly being migrated from the old IaaS/DynamicOps layer to the appliance – this is fantastic news. The migrated portions (such as vSphere Endpoint configuration) are now accessible through the vRA API, as well as gaining the speed and stability that the appliances provide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new blueprint designer is awesome. Added to that what was AppD is now called App Services and allows you to take a base blueprint (e.g. a CentOS VM) and drag and drop software components that you’ve scripted on top (e.g. Apache, then PHP). You can also drag and drop XaaS (vRO workflows) onto the blueprint, as well as existing blueprints to create nested blueprints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much fuller integration between NSX and vRA. There’s a whole raft of improvements in the integration between vRA and NSX – e.g. you can drag a new routed network onto a blueprint and it will automatically create a new Logical Switch and Distributed Logical Router to attach the Logical Switch to. Similarly load balancing applications is a drag and drop operation, as is applying existing security groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All blueprints can be imported and exported in YAML, which opens up exciting possibilities for storing versioned blueprints and retrieving programmatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are over 60 lifecycle events out of the box on which you can trigger Orchestrator workflows, but you can create custom filters based on properties and events to extend functionality – the only limitation is what you can imagine!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still several months of development to go between now and the GA of vRA 7 and the development seems to be moving at a great pace. Between beta 1 and beta 2 there was a huge amount of change, and even the version demoed today had new features and UI.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: Pre-event and Partner Day</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-pre-event-and-partner-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 08:36:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-pre-event-and-partner-day/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;My trip started with a farcical attempt to fly – my 11:50am flight on Sunday didn’t leave ‘til 3:30pm, but in light of William Lam’s travel woes on the same day, I don’t think I’ll complain to heavily. After a quick stop off at the Fira to register and grab my VMworld bag and I headed off to meet DefinIT co-author Simon (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/simoneady" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; @simoneady
&lt;/a&gt;) at our AirBnB apartment (which, by the way is awesome and a whole load cheaper than a hotel).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: VCIX-NV Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 16:58:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;For the last few years at VMworld I’ve taken advantage of the discounted exam price and booked a “have-a-go” exam – typically an exam I’ve been wanting to do but not necessarily had the time I wanted to study for it. Since I have been fairly immersed in the NSX world for the last week, sitting in an NSX design and deploy class and surrounded by some very smart networking guys, I changed my “have-a-go” exam from the VCP6-CMA to the VCIX-NV.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015 – Just getting started</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-just-getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 14:02:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-just-getting-started/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/10/vmworld2015-logo1.png" alt=""&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s PEX (Partner Exchange Day) at VMworld today so its busy but not the Tuesday (first day) of VMworld busy, last night saw a fantastic #vRockstar party and a great chance to meet and have a beer with many vTwitteratti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/10/CRDv2S4WsAA5Auz.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today of course has been largely overshadowed by the big new concerning the Dell announcement to purchase EMC which has triggered a great deal of discussion and a healthy amount of banter and snark! It should be interesting to see how it all pans out and tomorrows keynote will have a great deal of interest regarding any comments on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building a vRealize Automation NSX Lab on Ravello</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/building-a-vrealize-automation-nsx-lab-on-ravello/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 17:06:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/building-a-vrealize-automation-nsx-lab-on-ravello/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/09/image_thumb22.png" alt=""&gt;As a vExpert, I am blessed to get 1000 CPU hours access to Ravello&amp;rsquo;s awesome platform and recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with the AutoLab deployments tailored for Ravello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Ravello&amp;rsquo;s offering&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; (where have you been?!) then it&amp;rsquo;s basically a custom hypervisor (HVX) running on either AWS or Google Cloud that allows you to run nested environments on those platforms. I did say it&amp;rsquo;s awesome.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PernixData FVP 3.0 GA and Lab Install</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/pernixdata-fvp-3-0-ga-and-lab-install/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 12:56:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/pernixdata-fvp-3-0-ga-and-lab-install/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;[&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright size-medium wp-image-3968&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2014/02/pernixdata1.png&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;pernixdata&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;80&amp;rdquo; since vSphere 6 was released, simply because I can&amp;rsquo;t afford to wait on learning new versions until 3rd party software catches up. It makes you truly appreciate the awesome power of FVP, even on my less than spectacular hardware in my lab, when it&amp;rsquo;s taken away for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that FVP 3.0 has GA&amp;rsquo;d, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to getting my lab storage accelerated - it makes a huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Joining vSphere 6 Platform Services Controller Appliance to an Active Directory domain via the command line</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/joining-vsphere-6-platform-services-controller-appliance-to-an-active-directory-domain-via-the-command-line-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 14:48:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/joining-vsphere-6-platform-services-controller-appliance-to-an-active-directory-domain-via-the-command-line-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/07/vSphereLogo.png" alt=""&gt;With a Platform Services Controller appliance deployed as part of a vCenter Server installation, either integrated as part of the vCSA or as a separate PSC appliance, you can easily join the PSC to an Active Directory domain using the Web Client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;ve deployed the PSC as the single sign on layer of a distributed vRealize Automation deployment, you don&amp;rsquo;t have the vSphere Web Client to configure it in the same way. This means that you can&amp;rsquo;t add an integrated Active Directory identity source to the default tenant, either using the PSC machine account or an SPN for Kerberos.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation instance – Configuring NetScaler Monitors</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-instance-configuring-netscaler-monitors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 09:24:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-instance-configuring-netscaler-monitors/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter a name for the monitor, and leave the other parameters the same. Select the &amp;ldquo;Special Parameters&amp;rdquo; tab and configure the send string to the URL to monitor - e.g for the PSC SSO it&amp;rsquo;s going to be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the receive string, enter the expected response (&amp;ldquo;GREEN&amp;rdquo;). Click Create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/08/image_thumb40.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="assigning-a-netscaler-monitor-to-a-service"&gt;Assigning a NetScaler Monitor to a Service &lt;a class="anchor" href="#assigning-a-netscaler-monitor-to-a-service"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assign the monitor to the PSC Services (or Service Groups) configured for PSC by opening the Configuration &amp;gt; Traffic Management &amp;gt; Load Balancing &amp;gt; Services page and selecting the PSC service for HTTPS/443 and clicking Edit.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components – Part 2: Database, Web and Manager services</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-2-database-web-and-manager-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:40:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-2-database-web-and-manager-services/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png" alt=""&gt;Now that the prerequisites for the IaaS layer have been completed, it&amp;rsquo;s time to move on to the actual installation of the IaaS components, starting with the database. We then move onto the first Web server, which also imports the ModelManagerData configuration to the database, populating the database with all of the info the IaaS layer needs out of the box. We then install the second Web server before moving on to the active Manager server. The second Manager server is passive and the service should be disabled - I&amp;rsquo;ll cover installing DEM Orchestrators, Workers and the vSphere Agents in the next article.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components – Part 1: Pre-requisites</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-1-pre-requisites/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:15:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-1-pre-requisites/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One of the trickiest parts of deploying vRealize Automation is the IaaS layer - people sometimes look at me like I&amp;rsquo;m a crazy person when I say that, normally because they&amp;rsquo;ve deployed a PoC or small deployment with just a single IaaS server. Add in 5 more servers, some load balancers, certificates, a distributed setup and MSDTC to the mix and you have a huge potential for pain!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation Infrastructure Tab displays incorrect labels</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vrealize-automation-infrastructure-tab-displays-incorrect-labels/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 08:24:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vrealize-automation-infrastructure-tab-displays-incorrect-labels/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png" alt=""&gt;Having just completed a particularly problem-prone distributed IaaS install, this was almost the straw that broke the camel&amp;rsquo;s back. Logging into vRealize Automation for the first time as an Infrastructure Admin displayed the infrastructure tab and all menu labels as big ugly references, and no functionality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:%7bcom.cmware.cap.component.iaas.proxy.provider@csp.places.iaas.label"&gt;
 {com.cmware.cap.component.iaas.proxy.provider@csp.places.iaas.label
&lt;/a&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/clip_image002_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebooting the IaaS web servers restored the functionality of the IaaS layer but still did not fix the label issue, it took a further reboot of both vRealize Automation appliances, then the IaaS web servers to finally view the correct labels.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Automate changing the vSphere 6 Platform Services Controller IP address (and vRealize Automation)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/automate-changing-the-vsphere-6-platform-services-controller-ip-address/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 15:04:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/automate-changing-the-vsphere-6-platform-services-controller-ip-address/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Note: This falls under the “I don’t think this is supported” category – use this method at your own peril!&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;As part of some testing I’ve been doing for vRealize Automation DR scenarios, I wanted to test changing the IP address of a HA PSC pair using a script (think SRM failover to a new subnet).&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Resetting the vSphere 6 vCenter Server Appliance or Platform Services Controller root password</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/resetting-the-vsphere-6-platform-services-controller-root-password/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 13:58:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/resetting-the-vsphere-6-platform-services-controller-root-password/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how supported this is, but this process can recover a vSphere 6 vCenter Server Appliance or Platform Services Controller when you&amp;rsquo;ve lost the root password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the OpenSUSE Rescue CD - &lt;a href="http://download.opensuse.org/distribution/13.2/iso/" title="http://download.opensuse.org/distribution/13.2/iso/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; http://download.opensuse.org/distribution/13.2/iso/
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mount the CD to the PSC Appliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/image_thumb94.png" alt=""&gt; &lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/image_thumb95.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reboot the appliance and enter the BIOS setup using F2, configure the CD-ROM as first-boot device. Save and exit to reboot into the SUSE Live-CD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/image_thumb96.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying vRealize Automation 6.2 Appliance Cluster with Postgres Replication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 19:57:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The recommendations for the vRealize Appliance have changed with 6.2, the published reference architecture now does not recommend using an external Postgres database (either vPostgres appliance, a 3rd party Postgres deployment or using a third vRealize Appliance as a stand-alone database installation). Instead the recommended layout is shown in the diagram below. One instance of postgres on the primary node becomes an active instance, replicating to the second node which is passive. In front of these a load balancer or DNS entry points to the active node only. Fail-over is still a manual task, but it does provide better protection than a single instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 HA SSO (PSC) with NetScaler VPX Load Balancer for vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 15:40:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Providing a highly available single sign on for vRealize Automation is a fundamental part of ensuring the availability of the platform. Traditionally, (vCAC) vRA uses the Identity Appliance and relies on vSphere HA to provide the availability of the SSO platform, but in a fully distributed HA environment that&amp;rsquo;s not really good enough. It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to use the vSphere 5.5 SSO install in a HA configuration - however, many companies are making the move to the latest version of vSphere and don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to maintain a 5.5 HA SSO instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying VMTurbo Virtual Health Monitor</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vmturbo-virtual-health-monitor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 09:43:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vmturbo-virtual-health-monitor/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Having just welcomed VMTurbo on board as a blog sponsor, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do a quick posting on how to deploy their free Virtual Health Monitor appliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up for a &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;free license here and download the appropriate version&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="deploy-the-vmturbo-appliance"&gt;Deploy the VMTurbo Appliance &lt;a class="anchor" href="#deploy-the-vmturbo-appliance"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deploying the appliance is simply a case of importing the OVA downloaded. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing really to configure and it took 61 seconds in my lab environment, so it&amp;rsquo;s pretty quick! Network configuration is via DHCP and you can configure a static IP by logging into the console and running &amp;ldquo;ipsetup&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My #VCDX-CMA defense experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/06/my-vcdx-cma-defense-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 11:31:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/06/my-vcdx-cma-defense-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I received the dreaded email&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We regret to inform you that your attempt to achieve VCDX certification on June 09-11, 2015 in Frimley, UK was unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely unexpected, but somehow I still hoped my assessment of the defense was pessimistic and so it was nonetheless disappointing. It&amp;rsquo;s a big hit to not achieve something I have been focusing on for months and it is hard not to feel embarrassed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t make the grade. I am looking forward to receiving some feedback from the panelists and will be gearing up for another attempt in October.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 Lab Upgrade – vCenter Orchestrator to vRealize Orchestrator</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-vcenter-orchestrator-to-vrealize-orchestrator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 16:23:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-vcenter-orchestrator-to-vrealize-orchestrator/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/07/vSphereLogo.png" alt=""&gt;I tested vSphere 6 quite intensively when it was in beta, but I didn’t ever upgrade my lab – basically because I need a stable environment to work on and I wasn’t sure that I could maintain that with the beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now 6 has been GA a while and I have a little bit of time, I have begun the lab upgrade process. You can see a bit more about my lab hardware over on my &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/lab/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; lab page
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 Lab Upgrade – VSAN</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-vsan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 11:16:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-vsan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/07/vSphereLogo.png" alt=""&gt;I tested vSphere 6 quite intensively when it was in beta, but I didn’t ever upgrade my lab – basically because I need a stable environment to work on and I wasn’t sure that I could maintain that with the beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now 6 has been GA a while and I have a little bit of time, I have begun the lab upgrade process. You can see a bit more about my lab hardware over on my &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/lab/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; lab page
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 Lab Upgrade – Overview</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 19:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-overview/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/07/vSphereLogo.png" alt=""&gt;I tested vSphere 6 quite intensively when it was in beta, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t ever upgrade my lab - basically because I need a stable environment to work on and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure that I could maintain that with the beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be upgrading&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vCenter Server Appliance - currently 5.5 update 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vSphere Update Manager - currently 5.5 update 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 HP N54L resource hosts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Intel NUC management host&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my lab I run various VMware software suites listed below, although I typically run them in nested environments to keep my lab install relatively clean.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 Lab Upgrade – Upgrading ESXi 5.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-upgrading-esxi-5-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 19:11:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-upgrading-esxi-5-5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/07/vSphereLogo.png" alt=""&gt;I tested vSphere 6 quite intensively when it was in beta, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t ever upgrade my lab - basically because I need a stable environment to work on and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure that I could maintain that with the beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id="checking-for-driver-compatibility"&gt;Checking for driver compatibility &lt;a class="anchor" href="#checking-for-driver-compatibility"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In vSphere 5.5, VMware dropped the drivers for quite a few consumer grade NICs - in 6 they&amp;rsquo;ve gone a step further and actually blocked quite a few of these using a VIB package. For more information, see this &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;excellent article by Andreas Peetz&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 Lab Upgrade – vCenter Server Appliance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-vcenter-server-appliance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 15:23:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-vcenter-server-appliance/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/07/vSphereLogo.png" alt=""&gt;I tested vSphere 6 quite intensively when it was in beta, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t ever upgrade my lab - basically because I need a stable environment to work on and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure that I could maintain that with the beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id="upgrading-the-vcenter-server-appliance"&gt;Upgrading the vCenter Server Appliance &lt;a class="anchor" href="#upgrading-the-vcenter-server-appliance"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download and mount the VMware-VCSA-all-6.0.0-2562643 ISO image (mounted as G:\ on my workstation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browse the ISO and run the Client Integration Plugin &amp;ldquo;G:\vcsa\VMware-ClientIntegrationPlugin-6.0.0.exe&amp;rdquo; - it&amp;rsquo;s a simple next, next finish sort of install.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Creating a vRealize Log Insight 2.5 cluster with Integrated Load Balancing</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/02/creating-a-vrealize-log-insight-2-5-cluster-with-integrated-load-balancing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 15:36:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/02/creating-a-vrealize-log-insight-2-5-cluster-with-integrated-load-balancing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vRealize Log Insight 2.5 improves on the clustering in previous versions with an Integrated Load Balancer (ILB) which allows you to distribute load across your cluster of Log Insight instances without actually needing an external load balancer. The advantage of this over an external load balancer is that the source IP is maintained which allows for easier analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The minimum number of nodes in a cluster is three, the first node becomes the Master node and the other two become Worker nodes. The maximum number of nodes supported is six, though acording to Mr Log Insight himself, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/smflanders" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Steve Flanders
&lt;/a&gt;, the hard limit is more:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO) – Troubleshooting SOAP operations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-troubleshooting-soap-operations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 12:09:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-troubleshooting-soap-operations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a bit of a SOAP baptism of fire - the project I am working on makes hundreds of SOAP calls to multiple SOAP APIs on multiple hosts. During this time I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered some common and rare problems and troubleshooting them seems to be a bit of a black art, if the number of results in Google is any measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate some of these troubleshooting methods I will use a global weather SOAP service, &lt;a href="http://www.webservicex.com/globalweather.asmx?WSDL" title="http://www.webservicex.com/globalweather.asmx?WSDL" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; http://www.webservicex.com/globalweather.asmx?WSDL
&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve added the web service to vRO using the &amp;ldquo;Add a SOAP host&amp;rdquo; workflow, and then used the &amp;ldquo;Generate a new workflow from a SOAP operation&amp;rdquo; workflow to create a new workflow: GetWeather. This simple workflow runs successfully:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why should you go to a VMUG?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/why-should-you-go-to-a-vmug/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 15:37:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/why-should-you-go-to-a-vmug/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/06/vmw_vmug_logo_square_small.png" alt=""&gt;Having been a &lt;a href="http://www.vmug.com" title="VMUG Website" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; VMUG
&lt;/a&gt; member for several years and now a VMUG leader I have seen the value of being a VMUG member and attending the meetings/events/conferences continue to increase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="so-why-do-i-think-you-should-you-go"&gt;So why do I think you should you go? &lt;a class="anchor" href="#so-why-do-i-think-you-should-you-go"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are using VMware technologies/products in your workplace or you are regularly consulting on said VMware products, the VMUG events are in my opinion invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It simply doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what experience/knowledge you have of the products, whether you are very new to virtualization or an old hand I  guarantee you will come away from any VMUG meeting having learned something useful or dare I say been a great source/help to others whom you have met and networked with.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO) and vCloud Director – fixing bugs in "Add a vDC"</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-and-vcloud-director-fixing-bugs-in-add-a-vdc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 10:53:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-and-vcloud-director-fixing-bugs-in-add-a-vdc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;When you are using a VMware orchestration platform with an official VMware plugin to manage a VMware product, you don&amp;rsquo;t really expect to have to fix the out-of-the-box workflows. However, during some testing of some workflows with a client the other day we ran into a couple of issues with the vCloud Director plugin workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software versions used&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vCloud Director 5.5.1 (appliance for development) and 5.5.2 (production deployment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vRealize Orchestrator Appliance 5.5.2.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vCloud Director plugin 5.5.1.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="cpu-allocations-are-incorrect-for-both-add-a-vdc"&gt;CPU allocations are incorrect for both &amp;ldquo;Add a VDC&amp;rdquo; &lt;a class="anchor" href="#cpu-allocations-are-incorrect-for-both-add-a-vdc"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you provide the CPU allocation model properties for the Allocation Pool model the first problem is decrypting the naming - it doesn&amp;rsquo;t match the names in the vCloud Director interface!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Performance tweak – increasing Max Heap Size for the vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO) Client</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/performance-tweak-increasing-max-heap-size-for-the-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-client/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 20:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/performance-tweak-increasing-max-heap-size-for-the-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-client/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;[Update Dec 2016: &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/increasing-the-java-heap-size-for-vrealize-orchestrator-client-7-x/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; An updated article for vRO 7.x is available here
&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m developing some very large, very complicated workflows for vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO), and as it&amp;rsquo;s a Java based application it will probably come as no surprise to many that the performance of the client drops off sharply as the client&amp;rsquo;s RAM usage creeps up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When working on some of the larger workflows, or after long sessions and heavy clipboard use, the client would become (even more) sluggish and in some cases would freeze entirely. This is particularly annoying because the vRO client has a habit of forcing itself on top of other applications - for instance Task Manager.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Configuring and Using vRealize Orchestrator (vCO/vRO) Multi-node plugin</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/configuring-and-using-vrealize-orchestrator-vcovro-multi-node-plugin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 16:50:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/configuring-and-using-vrealize-orchestrator-vcovro-multi-node-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;To quote the release notes for the latest version of vCO/vRO Multi-node Plugin:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VMware vCenter Orchestrator Multi-Node Plug-In allows organizations to manage environments with multiple vCenter Orchestrator server instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As organizations increase their level of automation, they often find the need to deploy multiple Orchestrator instances. With the VMware vCenter Orchestrator Multi-Node Plug-In, administrators have a more efficient way to manage multiple Orchestrator instances from a central point. The plug-in allows administrators to log in to a master Orchestrator server to view the inventories and workflows of remote Orchestrator servers, and to trigger workflows remotely.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#UKVMUG 2014</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/11/ukvmug-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 12:27:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/11/ukvmug-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday (in case you missed it) was the fourth annual UK national VMUG at the National Motorcycle Museum in Birmingham. It was my second year attending and I continue to be blown away with the quality and value available at this event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a huge amount of content packed into this one-day event, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try and summarise my day…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vcurry-and-vquiz"&gt;vCurry and vQuiz &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vcurry-and-vquiz"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vCurry event was hosted on Monday night and is a great way to chill out after a long drive up to the midlands. It&amp;rsquo;s always well attended and there are always familiar faces from the London VMUG there. Also there is the now legendary vQuiz, hosted by Stuart Thompson (@virtual_stu) which is great for a laugh or two and makes a good ice breaker if you&amp;rsquo;re there on your own. Oh, and free curry and a free beer or two…what&amp;rsquo;s not to like?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unable to start PernixData FVP Management Server – service-specific error code 0</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/unable-to-start-pernixdata-fvp-management-server-service-specific-error-code-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 10:14:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/unable-to-start-pernixdata-fvp-management-server-service-specific-error-code-0/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Having finally got some SSDs to be able to use my PernixPro/PernixPrime NFR license, I thought it was about time to get PernixData&amp;rsquo;s FVP 2.0 running in my lab again. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used FVP in my lab since it was running in beta, so I was keen to see the awesome new features in action. It really is an easy install process and took me less than an hour to get my cluster up and running with VMs I/O being accelerated.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My first VMworld..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/my-first-vmworld/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 12:38:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/my-first-vmworld/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/10/vmworld2014.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this was my first VMworld I am not ashamed to say I was really stoked about attending, many of my peers have attended in the past and were going to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I flew in on the Sunday evening so that I could register early on Monday for partner day, however I did miss the chance to attend what turned out to be a very popular and very full Rockstar event on the Sunday evening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.1 – Creating a user selectable network dropdown that sets Network and Network Profile correctly</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vcac-6-1-creating-a-user-selectable-network-dropdown-that-sets-network-and-network-profile-correctly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 11:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vcac-6-1-creating-a-user-selectable-network-dropdown-that-sets-network-and-network-profile-correctly/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I am aware that that&amp;rsquo;s not a catchy blog post title. In fact, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even really describe the problem or solution very well - for that I need to go into a little bit more depth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose I have configured a Reservation with two Networks ticked (&amp;ldquo;192.168.1.0-VLAN1&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;192.168.10.0-VLAN10&amp;rdquo;). As you can see in the screenshot below, each of the networks has a Network Profile created and assigned with a network pool to provide IP addressing for the VMs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2014: Day Three and wrap-up</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-three-and-wrap-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 09:05:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-three-and-wrap-up/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/10/wpid-wp-1413446501457.jpeg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*This post was meant to be published on Friday, VMworld Sleep Deprivation meant I didn&amp;rsquo;t click the button!*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the last post and a bit of a wrap up on my VMworld 2014 series!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t a keynote on day three, and there&amp;rsquo;s definitely a &amp;ldquo;winding down&amp;rdquo; feel as people tend to arrive later (if at all) and many are…feeling the effects of the previous night shall we say! That said, every session I wanted to attend was still fully booked and it was a case of queuing for the spare seats.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2014: Day Two</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-two/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 08:02:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-two/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/10/wpid-wp-1413446501457.jpeg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day two of VMworld kicked off with a keynote session which traditionally includes demos of all that&amp;rsquo;s new. It was a well presented session with a glimpse into the sysadmin&amp;rsquo;s future with a demo of vCOps alerts popping up on Google glass. Since the sessions are available online I won&amp;rsquo;t go into detail, but it was worth a watch (if you didn&amp;rsquo;t watch the US one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My morning consisted of preparations for the VCP NV (NSX) exam, which I detailed in a previous post. Very pleased to have passed what is a difficult exam.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2014: VCP NV Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 11:56:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/10/wpid-wp-1413374112925.jpeg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is with great relief that I can announce I have passed my VCP NV (Network Virtualisation) having been caught out by the difficulty of the exam and failing previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="exam-preparation"&gt;Exam Preparation &lt;a class="anchor" href="#exam-preparation"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate to attend a VMware internal bootcamp (roughly equivalent to the ICM course) for NSX and have had experience deploying production NSX environments, so that is by far the best preparation. As always, the &lt;a href="https://mylearn.vmware.com/lcms/web/portals/certification/VCP_Blueprints/VCP-NV-Exam-Blueprint-v1_2.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; exam blueprint
&lt;/a&gt; is crucial, you *have* to know all areas covered there. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been reading the &lt;a href="http://pubs.vmware.com/NSX-6/index.jsp#com.vmware.nsx.install.doc/GUID-D8578F6E-A40C-493A-9B43-877C2B75ED52.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; documentation
&lt;/a&gt; and design and deploy guides published by VMware, and completed the basic and advanced &lt;a href="http://www.projectnee.com/HOL/catalogs/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; hands on labs
&lt;/a&gt; that are also freely available. On top of that there is the &lt;a href="http://mylearn.vmware.com/quiz.cfm?item=57466" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; official practice exam
&lt;/a&gt; which I strongly suggest you do as it reflects the real exam well, and there are a series of fantastic &lt;a href="http://www.elasticsky.co.uk/practice-questions/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; practice tests by Paul McSharry
&lt;/a&gt; available while provide a decent test of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMWorld 2014: Day One</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-one/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 08:21:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-one/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/10/wpid-wp-1413361235057.jpeg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a bit of a rocky start (missed my flight and the partner day due to tendonitis in my knee) I arrived in Barcelona for my 2nd VMworld Europe. I headed straight from the airport to the PernixData party and caught up with the rest of the Xtravirt guys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday morning started as ever with a keynote address. It was a little disappointing, but not unexpected, that there were no real announcements or reveals in the keynote. It was essentially a repeat of the VMworld US keynote with a couple of new betas announced. Nothing really revolutionary, a new vCloud Air datacenter in Germany and some new partners for EVO:RAIL. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see that the pace of traction for both cloud and hyperconverged is increasing for VMware&amp;rsquo;s portfolio though.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0/6.1 build out to distributed model: Deploy the Identity Appliance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/vcac-6-06-1-build-out-to-distributed-model-deploy-the-identity-appliance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 14:55:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/vcac-6-06-1-build-out-to-distributed-model-deploy-the-identity-appliance/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;SSO is a fundamental requirement when deploying vCAC, whether for a distributed or simple installation. This walk through goes through the deployment and configuration of the vCAC Identity Appliance, which provides a stand alone SSO instance for vCAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the posts in this series are completed with vCAC 6.0.1, others will be with 6.1. Where there are differences I will aim to point them out!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Configuring a remote access SSL VPN with VMware NSX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/configuring-a-remote-access-ssl-vpn-with-vmware-nsx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 12:35:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/configuring-a-remote-access-ssl-vpn-with-vmware-nsx/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The NSX Edge Gateway comes pre-armed with the ability to provide an SSL VPN for remote access into your network. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a new feature (SSL VPN was available in vCloud Networking and Security), but it&amp;rsquo;s worth a run through. I&amp;rsquo;m configuring remote access to my Lab, since it&amp;rsquo;s often useful to access it when on a client site, but traditional VPN connections are often blocked on corporate networks where HTTPS isn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing SRM VNXe SRA &amp;ndash; Failed to load SRA, &amp;lsquo;queryInfo&amp;rsquo; didn&amp;rsquo;t return a response</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/installing-srm-vnxe-sra-failed-to-load-sra-queryinfo-didnt-return-a-response/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 13:23:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/installing-srm-vnxe-sra-failed-to-load-sra-queryinfo-didnt-return-a-response/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Quick post to cover a fix for installing the VNXe SRA when you encounter the below error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Failed to load SRA from &amp;lsquo;C:/Program Files/VMware/VMware vCenter Site Recovery Manager/storage/sra/EMC VNXe SRA&amp;rsquo;. SRA command &amp;lsquo;queryInfo&amp;rsquo; didn&amp;rsquo;t return a response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The components installed (in this order) are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vSphere 5.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SRM 5.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UNISphere CLI 1.5.4.1.0027-1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VNXe SRA 5.0.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The root cause is that the system locale is EN-GB rather than EN-US, however even changing the locale does not resolve the issue. The Java installation will still try and load an en_GB module and fail. The solution is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Configuring vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) with PowerShell over HTTPS with Kerberos Authentication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/configuring-vcenter-orchestrator-vco-with-powershell-over-https-with-kerberos-authentication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 11:01:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/configuring-vcenter-orchestrator-vco-with-powershell-over-https-with-kerberos-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;As a PowerShell fan I find using the vCO PowerShell plugin makes my life a whole lot easier. What isn&amp;rsquo;t easy however, is  the configuration of vCO and a PowerShell jump host. Having done it a few times, this is my method for ensuring a secure working connection using HTTPS and Kerberos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="configure-the-orchestrator-appliance"&gt;Configure the Orchestrator Appliance &lt;a class="anchor" href="#configure-the-orchestrator-appliance"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since we’re planning on using Kerberos authentication, we’d better ensure that the time is correct AND syncs to the same source as the domain.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>HTTP Error 500 installing vCAC IaaS Model Manager Data</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/http-error-500-installing-vcac-iaas-model-manager-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 16:16:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/http-error-500-installing-vcac-iaas-model-manager-data/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This was a fun little error, whilst installing the distributed IaaS roles I couldn’t seem to get the IaaS components to install – when I got the Website and Model Manager Data install it would fail with the following message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/07/image_thumb.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve pasted it in here because I couldn’t find anything through google that referred to my error messages – hopefully if you’re reading this you’ve found it because you’re looking for it!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Slow or failed logon to VCSA 5.5 with vCOps in the environment</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/slow-or-failed-logon-to-vcsa-5-5-with-vcops-in-the-environment/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 09:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/slow-or-failed-logon-to-vcsa-5-5-with-vcops-in-the-environment/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Recently I encountered this problem in a customer site whereby the logon to VCSA 5.5 would either time out, or take 3-5 minutes to actually log on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a netstat on the VCSA during the attempt to logon showed there was a SYN packet sent to the vCOps appliance on port 443 that never established a connection. Another check was attempting to connect using curl &amp;lt;https://&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&amp;gt; –k  - this would time out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 4: Deploying and clustering a secondary vCAC Appliance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-4-deploying-and-clustering-a-secondary-vcac-appliance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 10:54:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-4-deploying-and-clustering-a-secondary-vcac-appliance/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This is the fourth article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this post we will have deployed a second vCAC Appliance, clustered it with the first appliance and registered the load balanced URL with the Identity Appliance. This will mean logging on to &lt;a href="https://vcloud.definit.local/shell-ui-app" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; https://vcloud.definit.local/shell-ui-app
&lt;/a&gt; will be successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overview of the steps required are below:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 3.2: Configure load balancing with NSX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-2-configure-load-balancing-with-nsx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-2-configure-load-balancing-with-nsx/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This is the second part of the 3rd article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this part, we will not have modified the vCAC deployment in any way, we’ll just have 3 configured load balanced URLs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overview of the steps required are below:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 3.1: Configure Load Balancing with vCNS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 08:53:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This is the first part of the 3rd article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this part, we will not have modified the vCAC deployment in any way, we’ll just have 3 configured load balanced URLs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overview of the steps required are below:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 2: vPostgres</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-2-vpostgres/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 09:01:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-2-vpostgres/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This is the second article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diagram below shows the deployment at the end of this part, with vPostgres deployed and the vCAC Appliance running from the remote database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overview of the steps required are below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Issue and install certificates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure load balancing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install and configure additional IaaS server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="create-the-required-dns-records"&gt;Create the required DNS records &lt;a class="anchor" href="#create-the-required-dns-records"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;First of all, create DNS records for your vPostgres database server – you need both an A and PTR record. Most VMware appliances will check for a reverse DNS lookup when they boot and will set the hostname accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 1: Certificates</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-1-certificates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 11:43:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-1-certificates/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This is the first article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a simple installation you have the Identity Appliance, the vCAC appliance (which includes a vPostgres DB and vCenter Orchestrator instance) and an IaaS server. The distributed model still has a single Identity Appliance but clusters 2 or more vCAC appliances behind a load balancer, backed by a separate vPostgres database appliance. The IaaS components are installed on 2 or more IaaS Windows servers and are load balanced, backed by an external MSSQL database. Additionally, the vCenter Orchestrator appliance is used in a failover cluster, backed by the external vPostgres database appliance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCenter 5.5 Certificate Toolkit for Distributed Environments</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcenter-5-5-certificate-toolkit-for-distributed-environments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 10:50:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcenter-5-5-certificate-toolkit-for-distributed-environments/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Derek Seaman’s excellent SSL toolkit&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. I know that there are hours and hours of work put into this script by Derek and I want to thank him for that – it’s a massive time saver. This modification is to fit a different set of circumstances – “standing on the shoulders of giants” – and should in no way be seen as me criticising or stealing Derek’s work.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#LonVMUG 15th May &amp;ndash; another great VMUG!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/lonvmug-15th-may-another-great-vmug/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 09:44:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/lonvmug-15th-may-another-great-vmug/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Yesterday saw another fantastic London VMUG with lots of quality sessions and opportunities to network with peers and friends. The committee seem to do a fantastic job every time and this one was no exception, so thanks to &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Alaric Davies&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jane Rimmer&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Stuart Thompson&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Simon Gallagher&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Online VMware Forum – my thoughts</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/online-vmware-forum-my-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 21:35:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/online-vmware-forum-my-thoughts/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/05/2014-05-08_130651.png" alt=""&gt;This was the second online event I have attended in the last few months, the first being the &lt;a href="www.vmug.com" title="VMware user group"&gt;
 VMUG
&lt;/a&gt; Virtual event back in January. One of the aspects I enjoyed the most about that event was being able to chat  to many well known and familiar faces from the wider community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this recent event there was a lot of focus on the various offerings from VMware  with a good deal of focus on VSAN, NSX, Horizon and vCHS but certainly not neglecting their other offerings.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Infinio accelerator – quick review</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/infinio-accelerator-quick-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 12:31:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/infinio-accelerator-quick-review/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/04/infinio_logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;I recently came across Infinio and after reading about the unique way it tackled the problem of increasing I/O and reducing latency I was curious to see how it would perform in my lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few things I would like to point out. First of all Infinio works &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;only with NFS storage&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, secondly it &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;does not require flash storage&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; as it utilizes the host RAM instead however it provides &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;only&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;read acceleration&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Definit authors awarded vExpert 2014</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/definit-authors-awarded-vexpert-2014/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 22:19:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/definit-authors-awarded-vexpert-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2013/06/vExpert.jpg" alt=""&gt;It was with great honor both Sam and I were awarded vExpert 2014 (my first and Sam&amp;rsquo;s second award!) we are both proud to be listed alongside so many others in the vExpert programme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the announcement and the full list here - &lt;a href="http://blogs.vmware.com/vmtn/2014/04/vexpert-2014-announcement.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; http://blogs.vmware.com/vmtn/2014/04/vexpert-2014-announcement.html
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Extending a vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) Workflow with ForEach &amp;ndash; Backing up all ESXi hosts in a Cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/extending-a-vcenter-orchestrator-vco-workflow-with-foreach-backing-up-all-esxi-hosts-in-a-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 12:38:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/extending-a-vcenter-orchestrator-vco-workflow-with-foreach-backing-up-all-esxi-hosts-in-a-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In my previous post &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/?p=4262" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Backing up ESXi 5.5 host configurations with vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) – Workflow design walkthrough
&lt;/a&gt; I showed how to create a workflow to back up host configurations, but it was limited to one host at a time. For this post I’m going to show how to create a new workflow that calls the previous one on multiple hosts using a ForEach loop to run it against each one. This was actually easier than I had anticipated (having read posts on previous versions of vCO that involved created the loops manually).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Backing up ESXi 5.5 host configurations with vCenter Orchestrator (vCO) &amp;ndash; Workflow design walkthrough</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/backing-up-esxi-5-5-host-configurations-with-vcenter-orchestrator-vco-workflow-design-walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 16:27:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/backing-up-esxi-5-5-host-configurations-with-vcenter-orchestrator-vco-workflow-design-walkthrough/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;As a little learning project, I thought I’d take on &lt;a href="http://vexpert.me/kd" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Simon’s previous post
&lt;/a&gt; about backing up ESXi configurations and extend it to vCenter Orchestrator (vCO), and document how I go about building up a workflow. I&amp;rsquo;m learning more and more about vCO all the time, but I found it has a really steep entry point, and finding use cases is hard if you haven&amp;rsquo;t explored capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM) 5.5 in the Lab</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/installing-vmware-site-recovery-manager-srm-5-5-in-the-lab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 12:04:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/installing-vmware-site-recovery-manager-srm-5-5-in-the-lab/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing about with a compact SRM install in my lab - since I have limited resources and only one site I wanted to create a run-through for anyone learning SRM to be able to do it in their own lab too. I am creating two sites on the same IP subnet (pretend it&amp;rsquo;s a stretched LAN across two sites) and will be protecting a single, tiny Linux web server using vSphere Replication. I&amp;rsquo;m aiming to cover SAN based replication in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Generating and Installing CA Signed Certificates for VMware SRM 5.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/generating-and-installing-ca-signed-certificates-for-vmware-srm-5-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 10:11:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/generating-and-installing-ca-signed-certificates-for-vmware-srm-5-5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I’m fairly new to SRM, but even so this one seemed like a real head-scratcher! If you happen to be using CA signed certificates on your “protected site” vCenter and “recovery site” vCenter servers, when you come to linking the two SRM sites you encounter SSLHandShake errors – basically SRM assumes you want to use certificates for authentication because you’re using signed certificates. If you use the default self-signed certificates, SRM will default to using password authentication (see &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;SRM Authentication&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;). Where the process fails is during the “configure connection” stage, if either one of your vCenter servers does not have CA signed and the other does (throws an error that they are using different authentication methods) or that you are using self-signed certificates for either SRM installation (throws an error that the certificate or CA could not be trusted).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VCSA 5.5 Web Client fails to log on with &amp;ldquo;SSL certificate verification failed&amp;rdquo;</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/vcsa-5-5-web-client-fails-to-log-on-with-ssl-certificate-verification-failed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 16:13:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/vcsa-5-5-web-client-fails-to-log-on-with-ssl-certificate-verification-failed/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This had me scratching my head, what seemed to be a common problem wasn’t fixed by the common solution. It was actually my fault – too familiar with the product and setting things up too quickly to test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed a VCSA 5.5 instance in my lab as a secondary site for some testing and during the process found I couldn’t log on to the web client – it failed with the error:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Reclaiming an SSD device from ESXi 5.5 Virtual Flash</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/reclaiming-an-ssd-device-from-esxi-5-5-virtual-flash/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 14:02:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/reclaiming-an-ssd-device-from-esxi-5-5-virtual-flash/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After having a play with Virtual Flash and Host Caching on one of my lab hosts I wanted to re-use the SSD drive, but couldn’t seem to get vFlash to release the drive. I disabled flash usage on all VMs and disabled the Host Cache, then went to the Virtual Flash Resource Management page to click the “Remove All” button. That failed with errors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Host’s virtual flash resource is inaccessible.”&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCHS – first impressions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vchs-first-impressions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:39:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vchs-first-impressions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/02/vCHS-Powered.png" alt=""&gt;In case you missed it VMware have now released &lt;a href="http://www.vmwareforyou.com/vchs/" title="vCHS" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; vCHS
&lt;/a&gt; (VMware vCloud Hybrid Service) in Europe! The first data center residing in Slough with more data centers planned across Europe in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in an SME that has several existing vSphere environments this was of real interest, as the need to scale out quickly from our Private clouds is rapidly becoming a requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having already spoken to VMware on the phone to get a rough idea on options and costs I decided to take a look at the &lt;a href="http://labs.hol.vmware.com/" title="Hands on Labs" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Hands-on-labs
&lt;/a&gt; to see how easy it really is to use and migrate VMs from an existing private cloud to vCHS.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware vSphere Mobile Watchlist released</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vmware-vsphere-mobile-watchlist-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 23:10:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vmware-vsphere-mobile-watchlist-released/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For those of you unaware VMware recently released the &lt;a href="http://blogs.vmware.com/vsphere/2014/02/now-available-vmware-vsphere-mobile-watchlist.html" title="VMware vSphere Mobile Watchlist" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; VMware vSphere Mobile Watchlist
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;VMware vSphere Mobile Watchlist allows you to monitor the virtual machines you care about in your vSphere infrastructure remotely on your phone. Discover diagnostic information about any alerts on your VMs using VMware Knowledge Base Articles and the web. Remediate problems from your phone by using power operations or delegate the problem to someone on your team back at the datacenter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCSA 5.5 won’t join AD Domain‏</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/vcsa-5-5-wont-join-ad-domain%E2%80%8F/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 15:44:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/vcsa-5-5-wont-join-ad-domain%E2%80%8F/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick post on something that was not immediately obvious when it happened to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When deploying  vCSA 5.5 and trying to add it to the domain, I was presented with the following error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/01/2014-01-30_090806.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I immediately did all the all the usual checks, making sure it had a static IP and correct DNS servers etc..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing missing however was a FQDN for the hostname (in the network tab).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VCP5-IaaS &amp;ndash; Exam experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/vcp5-iaas-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 16:01:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/vcp5-iaas-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;So this morning I took the VMware Infrastructure as a Service exam (VCPVCD510) to gain the VCP5-Cloud qualification. The IaaS exam is available for existing VCP5-DCV holders to take without any other pre-requisites. I am very pleased to say I finished the exam in good time and scored 466/500 – the pass mark is 300.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://mylearn.vmware.com/lcms/web/portals/certification/PathDiagrams/VCP-Cloud.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-exam"&gt;The Exam &lt;a class="anchor" href="#the-exam"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The exam itself is 85 multiple choice questions, and gives you 90 minutes to do them. The last two exams I’ve sat were VCAPs, which require you to move very quickly through the questions, so I am in the habit of answering quickly: I finished with over an hour to spare! The questions and answers are not particularly wordy but it is important to read carefully and pick out the important information.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing and configuring VMware Infrastructure Navigator 5.8</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/installing-and-configuring-vmware-infrastructure-navigator-5-8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 10:40:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/installing-and-configuring-vmware-infrastructure-navigator-5-8/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;According to VMware, Infrastructure Navigator is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…a component of the VMware vCenter Operations Management Suite. It automatically discovers application services, visualizes relationships and maps dependencies of applications on virtualized compute, storage and network resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effectively it takes a look at the network connections that are running between your VMs (and physical servers) and works out which applications and services are running on each, and the dependencies – both upstream and downstream – for each VM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing vCOps 5.8 in the DefinIT Lab &amp;ndash; 4GB RAM and 2 vCPU</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/installing-vcops-5-8-in-the-definit-lab-4gb-ram-and-2-vcpu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 11:38:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/installing-vcops-5-8-in-the-definit-lab-4gb-ram-and-2-vcpu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;There’s no doubt that vCOps is a great product for proactively monitoring your vSphere environment, but it’s a hefty package for the lab. The minimum recommended RAM is a whopping 16GB – in my lab that’s the whole of my management host! I recently needed to do some testing so I wanted to get it running in the lab with the barest minimum I could get working, and it turns out you can get working with just 4GB and 2 CPU…albeit you wouldn’t want to monitor much! I also want to use vFlash Read Cache to accelerate I/O in the lab – this requires upgrading VMtools and the VM hardware to version 10.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2014: what does the future look like?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/2014-what-does-the-future-look-like/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 09:46:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/2014-what-does-the-future-look-like/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After attending the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.vmwareemeablog.com/events-uk/hangout-with-joe-baguley-and-paul-saffo-to-hear-them-discuss-technology-past-present-and-future-1" title="Hangout with Joe Baguley and Paul Saffo to hear them discuss technology past, present and future" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Future of IT
&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; Google hangout in September, I was asked to give a quick summary on what 2014 may hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So without further ado..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I believe in 2014, we will see an increased demand for - and usage of - hybrid clouds, especially among SMEs who are trying to avoid large investment on private clouds to accommodate high demand, short term projects.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Moving on – I&amp;rsquo;ve got a new job!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/11/moving-on-ive-got-a-new-job/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 16:31:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/11/moving-on-ive-got-a-new-job/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;2013 has been an amazing year for me – I was awarded the vExpert title, I’ve taken and passed my VCP5-DCV, VCAP5-DCA and VCAP5-DCD and spoken at the London and UK national VMUGs. I’ve attended my first VMworld and spent countless hours in the lab and on study, generating about 30 blog posts. All I can say is that it’s been a truly blessed year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After two and a half years working as a Senior Infrastructure Analyst for a global insurance company, the time has come for a change! For a while now I’ve felt that I’ve outgrown my current role and that perhaps it was time for a change. I have worked with some really excellent people on my team while here, and I’ll definitely be sad to say goodbye to some of them! I’ve had the opportunity to work on some huge-scale environments and highly complex systems – all of which allowed me to learn and grow in ways not possible in a “normal” size environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Avoid SSO Admin lockout &amp;ndash; a.k.a. your first task after installing vSphere SSO</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/11/avoid-sso-admin-lockout-a-k-a-your-first-task-after-installing-vsphere-sso/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 12:55:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/11/avoid-sso-admin-lockout-a-k-a-your-first-task-after-installing-vsphere-sso/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In my post yesterday (&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vexpert.me/hS&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;) I talked about how to recover from an expired default SSO administrator password – this prompted a discussion on twitter with Anthony Spiteri (@anthonyspiteri) and Grant Orchard (@grantorchard) about the defaults for expiration and how to mitigate the risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first solution is to modify the password expiration policy for SSO. I’m not advocating this necessarily – I think that expiring passwords ensure that you change them regularly and increase the overall security of your SSO solution. However, I can envisage situations (similar to mine) when the SSO administrator account is not used for a long time and expired – that causes headaches.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SSO Admin password reset with ssopass – SslHandshakeFailed – vSphere 5.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/11/sso-admin-password-reset-with-ssopass-sslhandshakefailed-vsphere-5-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 12:53:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/11/sso-admin-password-reset-with-ssopass-sslhandshakefailed-vsphere-5-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Today I found out that in vSphere 5.1 the SSO administrator account (admin@system-domain) has a password that expires after 365 days. See &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;KB2035864&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;vCenter Single Sign-On account (SSO) passwords expire after 365 days, including the password for admin@system-domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In vSphere 5.5 it gets even better – the password expires every 90 days by default! (&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;See the vSphere 5.5 SSO documentation&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere Security: Advanced SSH Configurations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vsphere-security-advanced-ssh-configurations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 14:26:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vsphere-security-advanced-ssh-configurations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2013/10/Security-Guard_thumb2_thumb.png" alt=""&gt;There are different schools of thought as to whether you should have SSH enabled on your hosts. VMware recommend it is disabled. With SSH disabled there is no possibility of attack, so that’s the “most secure” option. Of course in the real world there’s a balance between “most secure” and “usability” (e.g. the most secure host is powered off and physically isolated from the network, but you can’t run any workloads &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;). My preferred route is to have it enabled but locked down.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMworld Europe 2013 &amp;ndash; Day 2, VCAP5-DCD Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-day-2-vcap5-dcd-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 15:45:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-day-2-vcap5-dcd-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Today was always going to be a bit of a funny day as I scheduled the VCAP5-DCD exam for 10am this morning. I am happy to say that I passed! I’m a bit light on VMworld to report today, so forgive my DCD experience to pad it out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="preparation"&gt;Preparation &lt;a class="anchor" href="#preparation"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I have to confess my prep for this exam was light – I literally only watched the TrainSignal course by Scott Lowe (@scott_lowe) and just about finished that last night in the hotel! I don’t spend much time focussing on design during my day job, so I approached this exam as a bit of a learning experience rather than a serious bid to pass. I decided to book the exam here at VMworld just because you can get 75% off – if you’re funding yourself it’s not a discount to be dismissed easily!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMworld Europe 2013 – Day 1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-arriving-and-day-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 15:22:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-arriving-and-day-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I flew from Gatwick to Barcelona last night to my very first VMworld!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m staying in a hotel that is actually quite far from the conference, it&amp;rsquo;s a metro, train and bus journey away from the conference center and it takes about 40 minutes to get here. On the plus side I was only 5 minutes away from the VMUG party last night so I went over there for an hour or so. Note for future years - stay a little closer to the conference!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware – The future of IT Google Hangout</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmware-the-future-of-it-google-hangout/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 12:16:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmware-the-future-of-it-google-hangout/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EmlVxldz2r4" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; VMware - The future of IT Google Hangout
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a first for me but a really enjoyable experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions that were asked in the hour long session were..&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To jump to specific questions, see the links below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What have been your biggest successes during your time at VMware? - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/16uWKBj" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; http://bit.ly/16uWKBj
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Recover ESXi Root Password using AD Authentication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/recover-esxi-root-password-using-ad-authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 10:12:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/recover-esxi-root-password-using-ad-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;Losing a root password isn’t something that happens often, but when it does it’s normally a really irritating time. I have to rotate the password of all hosts once a month for compliance, but sometimes a host drops out of the loop and the root password gets lost. Fortunately, as the vpxuser is still valid I can manage the host via vCenter - this lends itself to this little recovery process:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere Security: Active Directory Authentication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vsphere-security-active-directory-authentication/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 15:13:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vsphere-security-active-directory-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This is the second article in a series of vSphere Security articles that I have planned. The majority of this article is based on vSphere/ESXi 5.1, though I will include any 5.5 information that I find relevant. The first article in this series was &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vsphere-security-understanding-esxi-5-x-lockdown-mode/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; vSphere Security: Understanding ESXi 5.x Lockdown Mode
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would you want to join an ESXi host to an Active Directory domain? Well you’re not going to get Group Policies applying, what you’re really doing is adding another authentication provider directly to the ESXi host. You will see a computer object created in AD, but you will still need to create a DNS entry (or configure DHCP to do it for you). What you will get is a way to audit root access to your hosts, to give administrators a single sign on for managing all aspects of your virtual environment and more options in your administrative arsenal – for example, if you’re using an AD group to manage host root access, you don’t have to log onto however many ESXi hosts you have to remove a user’s permissions, simply remove them from the group. You can keep your root passwords in a sealed envelope for emergencies! 😉&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere Security: Understanding ESXi 5.x Lockdown Mode</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vsphere-security-understanding-esxi-5-x-lockdown-mode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 10:05:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vsphere-security-understanding-esxi-5-x-lockdown-mode/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This is the first article in a series of vSphere Security articles that I have planned. The majority of this article is based on vSphere/ESXi 5.1, though I will include any 5.5 information that I find relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think lockdown mode is a feature that is rarely understood, and even more rarely used. Researching this article I’ve already encountered several different definitions that weren’t quite right. As far as I can see there are no differences between lockdown more in 5.5 and 5.1.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What sort of lab would you build for $2000?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/what-sort-of-lab-would-you-build-for-2000/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 10:39:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/what-sort-of-lab-would-you-build-for-2000/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;John Troyer (@jtroyer) asked a question on Twitter last night about a CloudCred prize of $1000-2000:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That got me thinking – was it possible to create an entire 2 host lab with storage on a $2000 budget? My first step was to convert it into a proper currency:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured that I’d stick to the Intel NUC route that I’ve gone down for &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/lab/" title="Lab" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; my lab
&lt;/a&gt; at home – I love the NUC for its tiny form factor, silent operation and really low power consumption. There are down sides – it can only take 16GB RAM, only one mSATA disk and only has one gigabit NIC. I don’t think any of those are too big a deal for a personal lab though – certainly I’ve not had any problems building and testing VMware products on my single NUC. I’d drop in an 8GB stick of RAM and an Intel 60GB mSATA SSD per NUC – you could always go 16GB later by adding another 8GB stick in the 2nd slot. I picked the Intel mSATA disk for it’s controller and throughput figures – there are larger and cheaper ones but not with the same write performance. Since the use of SSD is massively in focus with vFlash, PernixData FVP and several other technologies, you wouldn’t want to miss out. I’ve also added an 8GB USB3 flash drive per NUC to boot ESXi from.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 5.5 – what I like from what’s new..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vsphere-5-5-what-i-like-from-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 16:17:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vsphere-5-5-what-i-like-from-whats-new/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With vSphere 5.5 being announced at VMworld San Francisco I was very eager to see what was new and after devouring all of the great blog posts out there of the guys in attendance I wanted to summarize in my own way the aspects I think are great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**VMDK 2TB limitation removed! (also virtual mode RDMs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** This has to be one of the best pieces of news as it has been in the rear trying to accommodate really large VMs (changes affect both VMFS and NFS)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VCAP5-DCA &amp;ndash; Achievement Unlocked! And VMworld Europe</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vcap5-dca-achievement-unlocked-and-vmworld-europe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 15:47:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vcap5-dca-achievement-unlocked-and-vmworld-europe/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;After my previous post about &lt;a href="http://vexpert.me/eW" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; studying and the exam experience of the VCAP5-DCA exam
&lt;/a&gt; (and 3 weeks of waking up to check my phone for the email all night) I am pleased to say that I received my Exam Score last week and it was a pass! I was really pleased to see that I passed with a  very decent margin too, which was great! The rushed nature of the exam and long wait for the results leaves you going over the exam in your head convincing yourself how badly you’ve done, so it came as a huge relief and surprise.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PowerCLI &amp;ndash; Warning! New-VirtualSwitch without the &amp;ndash;NumPorts parameter defaults to 56 ports!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/08/powercli-warning-new-virtualswitch-without-the-numports-parameter-defaults-to-56-ports/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 10:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/08/powercli-warning-new-virtualswitch-without-the-numports-parameter-defaults-to-56-ports/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;There’s not a lot more to say than the title of this post – if you create a new Virtual Switch using PowerCLI without specifying the NumPorts parameter, it defaults to 64 ports. This strikes me as odd when the default for a standard switch is 120.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see in the screenshot below that when I create a Virtual Switch without the parameter, it creates it with 64 ports. Once you minus the 8 reserved for physical NIC ports (uplinks), CDP traffic, and network discovery it leaves you with 56 ports available for VMs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using the vExpert.me URL shortener and WordPress</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/08/using-the-vexpert-me-url-shortener-and-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 15:30:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/08/using-the-vexpert-me-url-shortener-and-wordpress/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One of the many perks of being a vExpert is the cool vexpert.me URL shortener provided by Darren Woollard (@dawoo). There are several ways for vExperts to use it once they’ve &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;signed up&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; – there’s a &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;PowerShell&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;script&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; by Jonathan Medd (@jonathanmedd) and Maish Saidel-Keesing (@maishsk) and now even a &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;GUI interface&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; based on the PowerShell.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere Basics: Correctly decommissioning a vSphere Datastore</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/08/vsphere-basics-correctly-decommissioning-a-vsphere-datastore/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 12:04:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/08/vsphere-basics-correctly-decommissioning-a-vsphere-datastore/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;You’d be surprised how many times I see datastore that’s just been un-presented from hosts rather than decommissioned correctly – in one notable case I saw a distributed switch crippled for a whole cluster because the datastore in question was being used to store the VDS configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the process that I follow to ensure datastores are decommissioned without any issues – they need to comply with these requirements&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Preparing for the VCAP5-DCA exam</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/08/preparing-for-the-vcap5-dca-exam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 10:41:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/08/preparing-for-the-vcap5-dca-exam/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="learning"&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Learning &lt;a class="anchor" href="#learning"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started the TrainSignal VMware vSphere Optimize and Scale (VCAP5-DCA) Training course as part of my preparation for taking the exam which I took at the beginning of this week - I&amp;rsquo;m still waiting to hear the results. One thing I found when I started preparing is that there is an overwhelming volume of information - the Exam Blueprint is a great place to start as that lays out what will be tested. There are 9 sections and 27 objectives laid out, with knowledge, skills and abilities and tools required for each objective. The volume can be overwhelming, even if you already know most of it!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mid-year thoughts</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/07/mid-year-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 21:33:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/07/mid-year-thoughts/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a really great year so far and incredibly busy (no complaints though!)&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VMware products have featured very high on my to-do list so far this year, with new hosting and DR solutions either completed or well underway. The simplicity, resilience and strength of vSphere never gets old!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also had the privilege to attend several London VMUG meetings all of which have been excellent! They have been superb opportunities to meet new people, put faces to Twitter names and learn more about current and forthcoming technologies orientated around visualization. If you have not had chance to get to one yet, do try, they are really worthwhile!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PowerCLI Basics: Auditing Virtual Machine Hardware and Tools using PowerCLI</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/powercli-basics-auditing-virtual-machine-hardware-and-tools-using-powercli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 15:38:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/powercli-basics-auditing-virtual-machine-hardware-and-tools-using-powercli/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The VM estate that I manage is large: there are more than 20 different clusters and over 300 hosts of varying ages and hardware levels – as a consequence there are various different versions of ESX and ESXi running. Upgrading the hosts is somewhat akin to painting the Forth Bridge, a never-ending task. So keeping the thousands of VMs at the correct hardware and VMtools versions can be a bit of a losing battle.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing and Configuring vCenter Log Insight</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-and-configuring-vcenter-log-insight/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 13:32:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-and-configuring-vcenter-log-insight/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;With the release of vCenter Log Insight Public Beta (&lt;a href="http://communities.vmware.com/community/vmtn/vcenter/vcenter-log-insight" title="http://communities.vmware.com/community/vmtn/vcenter/vcenter-log-insight" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; http://communities.vmware.com/community/vmtn/vcenter/vcenter-log-insight
&lt;/a&gt;) I thought I’d strike while the iron is hot and run through the installation and configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="deploying-the-ovf"&gt;Deploying the OVF &lt;a class="anchor" href="#deploying-the-ovf"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is such a bread and butter task that it doesn’t require more than a few words – it’s definitely worth looking at the Sizing PDF before you deploy (&lt;a href="http://communities.vmware.com/servlet/JiveServlet/downloadBody/23714-102-1-31648/VMware-vCenter-Log-Insight-1.0-Beta-Virtual-Appliance-Sizing.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; VMware-vCenter-Log-Insight-1.0-Beta-Virtual-Appliance-Sizing.pdf
&lt;/a&gt;) as it’s not small even for a test installation. If you’re using less than the recommended 8GB RAM there are additional steps to change the heap size for performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing VMware vSphere Update Manager Download Service and publishing via IIS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-vmware-vsphere-update-manager-download-service-and-publishing-via-iis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 15:30:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-vmware-vsphere-update-manager-download-service-and-publishing-via-iis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The vSphere UMDS provides a way to download patches for VMware servers that have an air-gap, or for some reason aren’t allowed to go out to the internet themselves – in my case a security policy prevented a DMZ vCenter Server from connecting to the internet directly. The solution is to use UMDS to download the updates to a 2nd server that was hosted in the DMZ and then update the vCenter Server from there. It also can save on bandwidth if you’re running multiple vCenter Servers, which again was the case (though bandwidth isn’t really a constraint).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Changing ESXi root passwords the smart way (via PowerCLI)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/changing-esxi-root-passwords-the-smart-way-via-powercli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 15:08:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/changing-esxi-root-passwords-the-smart-way-via-powercli/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;If you work in company with strict password compliance rules, for example under SOX, you might well have to change administrator passwords every month. Doing this on any more than a few hosts is tedious work – even on two hosts it seems like a waste of time logging on the host via SSH (or even enabling it first) before changing the password. Then we also need to audit the change, there’s no point making it for compliance reasons if we can’t then prove we did it!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Awarded vExpert 2013 – and vote for Simon!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/05/awarded-vexpert-2013-and-vote-for-simon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 09:24:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/05/awarded-vexpert-2013-and-vote-for-simon/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am absolutely thrilled to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve been awarded vExpert 2013 - it&amp;rsquo;s such an honour to be listed  among these others and hopefully I can continue to contribute throughout the year. I am looking forward to getting stuck in to the vExpert programme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vExpert announcement is here: &lt;a href="http://blogs.vmware.com/vmtn/2013/05/vexpert-2013-awardees-announced.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; http://blogs.vmware.com/vmtn/2013/05/vexpert-2013-awardees-announced.html
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, one of DefinIT&amp;rsquo;s contributing authors @SimonEady is a finalist for the VMware V.I.T. Competition and needs your votes!y I can continue making a contribution to the VMware community for the coming year. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to getting stuck in to the programme!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why secure your vSphere environment with valid SSL certificates?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/05/why-secure-your-vsphere-environment-with-valid-ssl-certificates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 15:39:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/05/why-secure-your-vsphere-environment-with-valid-ssl-certificates/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that installing certificates from an internal CA is a pain in the…vCenter, but having just gone through the process of updating 3 vCenter installations with the 5-7 certificates required for each server I was asked &amp;ldquo;just why is it we need to do this again?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="why-does-it-requiremultiple-certificates-for-my-vcenter-server"&gt;Why does it require multiple certificates for my vCenter server? &lt;a class="anchor" href="#why-does-it-requiremultiple-certificates-for-my-vcenter-server"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In short, each service requires a certificate because it could feasibly be on a server (or servers) of it&amp;rsquo;s own - take this hypothetical design - each role is hosted on it&amp;rsquo;s own VM, and there are 7 certificates required - SSO, Inventory Service, vCenter Server, Orchestrator, Web Client, Log Browser and Update Manager. If you install all these services on one server you still have to create certificates for those individual services.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Updating ESXi Fibre Channel HBA Drivers via VMware Update Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/05/updating-esxi-fibre-channel-hba-drivers-via-vmware-update-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 14:41:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/05/updating-esxi-fibre-channel-hba-drivers-via-vmware-update-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware2.jpg" alt=""&gt;A problem reared it&amp;rsquo;s head over the weekend with one of our hosts&amp;rsquo; Fibre Channel HBAs negotiating it&amp;rsquo;s way down to 2GB, and consequently introducing massive latency for the LUNs behind it. Analysis showed that the drivers for the HBA were over a year out of date so the suggested fix from VMware was to update the drivers. This is fine to do manually for a few hosts, but would be a real pain for the 300+ hosts in the environment I manage.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cloud Credibility</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/04/cloud-credibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 22:16:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/04/cloud-credibility/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So then! of late my attention has been drawn to &lt;a href="https://www.cloudcredibility.com" title="Cloud Credibility" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Cloud Credibility
&lt;/a&gt; which is a fantastic place to help validate your own and others cloud expertise by completing various tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among other things it encourages you to read up on white papers, carry out lab work (&lt;a href="https://www.vmware.com/landing_pages/hands-on-labs-beta.html" title="Hands on Labs" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Hands-on-labs
&lt;/a&gt;), watch training and informational materials and thus rewarding you with points for you and your team. What is also great is points really do mean prizes!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using the VMware SSL Certificate Automation Tool with a Microsoft Certificate Authority</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/04/using-the-vmware-ssl-certificate-automation-tool-with-a-microsoft-certificate-authority/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 14:38:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/04/using-the-vmware-ssl-certificate-automation-tool-with-a-microsoft-certificate-authority/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Updating vCenter Server certificates has always been a pain - it has only got worse with the sheer number of services that are running under vSphere 5.1 - each service requiring a unique certificate and to be installed in many complex steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately , with the release of the SSL Certificate Automation Tool, VMware have gone some way to reducing the headache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="gather-all-the-components-you-need"&gt;Gather all the components you need &lt;a class="anchor" href="#gather-all-the-components-you-need"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;OpenSSL installer: &lt;a href="http://slproweb.com/products/Win32OpenSSL.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; http://slproweb.com/products/Win32OpenSSL.html
&lt;/a&gt; (I downloaded &amp;ldquo;Win32 OpenSSL v0.9.8y Light&amp;rdquo;, even though it&amp;rsquo;s a 64-bit server)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PowerCLI Script to set RDM LUNs to Perennially Reserved – Fixes Slow Boot of ESXi 5.1 with MSCS RDMs</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/03/powercli-script-to-set-rdm-luns-to-perennially-reserved-fixes-slow-boot-of-esxi-5-1-with-mscs-rdms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 14:02:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/03/powercli-script-to-set-rdm-luns-to-perennially-reserved-fixes-slow-boot-of-esxi-5-1-with-mscs-rdms/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve previously &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/Ppl7Hl" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; posted around this topic
&lt;/a&gt; as part of another problem but having had to figure out the process again I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth re-posting a proper script for this. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;VMware KB 1016106 &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;is snappily titled &amp;ldquo;ESXi/ESX hosts with visibility to RDM LUNs being used by MSCS nodes with RDMs may take a long time to boot or during LUN rescan&amp;rdquo; and describes the situation where booting ESXi (5.1 in my case) takes a huge amount of time to boot because it&amp;rsquo;s attempting to gain a SCSI reservation on an RDM disk used by MS Clustering Services. It also details the fix.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware vCenter Linked Mode not supported through firewalls</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vmware-vcenter-linked-mode-not-supported-through-firewalls/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 15:28:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vmware-vcenter-linked-mode-not-supported-through-firewalls/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This article originally started off life as a record of how I managed to get this working, as a lot of my posts do, but this time it appears I am foiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I had 3 vCenter Servers that appeared to be happily talking to each other in Linked Mode sharing a singe Multi-site SSO domain without any real issues. I had a single-pane-of-glass view of all 3 and I could manage them all from the one client. The reason for the 3 vCenter servers was segregation of LAN and DMZ networks: vCenter001 was in the LAN, vCenter002 sat in DMZ1 and vCenter003 sat in DMZ2.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fixing the – the server fault invalidargument had no message – error message</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/fixing-the-the-server-fault-invalidargument-had-no-message-error-message/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 10:55:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/fixing-the-the-server-fault-invalidargument-had-no-message-error-message/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;Today while creating new VMs from a template I got the error &amp;ldquo;the server fault invalidargument had no message&amp;rdquo; when editing the VM settings, the settings were modified successfully but the error was present whether a change had been made or not to the settings of the VM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick search of the web suggested removing said VM from the inventory and re-adding from the datastore, for many this fixed the issue but not for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VM Power On fails with error: cpuid.coresPerSocket must be a number between 1 and 8</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vm-power-on-fails-with-error-cpuid-corespersocket-must-be-a-number-between-1-and-8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 11:10:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vm-power-on-fails-with-error-cpuid-corespersocket-must-be-a-number-between-1-and-8/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Had a strange one after deploying an XP VM from a template today - the VM would not power on and threw the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An error was received from the ESX host while powering on VM [VM name].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cpuid.coresPerSocket must be a number between 1 and 8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2013/02/2013-02-01-000.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digging around on google the error seemed to be related to over-allocating vCPUs (e.g. assigning 8 vCPUs on a VM with 4 physical CPU cores). This was a single vCPU machine on a 12 processor host, so not likely to be that! It did give me the idea that maybe the VMX had an error, so I edited the VM hardware and added an extra CPU and saved the config. I then edited it back to a single CPU and powered on the machine - it worked!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing the VMware Support Assistant</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/01/installing-the-vmware-support-assistant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 14:25:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/01/installing-the-vmware-support-assistant/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;So VMware&amp;rsquo;s Support Assistant is pretty awesome and it&amp;rsquo;s free! I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do a quick run through of the installation and set up for anyone who was interested, it&amp;rsquo;s fairly straightforward and if you raise a lot of calls or have multiple calls on the go it&amp;rsquo;s a time saver!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VMware&amp;rsquo;s official page for the Support Assistant is here - &lt;a href="https://www.vmware.com/products/datacenter-virtualization/vcenter-support-assistant/overview.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; https://www.vmware.com/products/datacenter-virtualization/vcenter-support-assistant/overview.html
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OVF deploy is so simple I&amp;rsquo;ve just taken screenshots:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Passed the VCP510 exam – VCP5-DV Qualified!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/12/passed-the-vcp510-exam-vcp5-dv-qualified/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 14:27:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/12/passed-the-vcp510-exam-vcp5-dv-qualified/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased to say that as of 21st December, I passed my VCP510 exam and am now VCP5 qualified! It&amp;rsquo;s something that I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do for a long time (since VCP3) but have never been able to get funding for the required course. My current employer sent me on the vSphere 5 Fast Track course earlier this year, so I was all set to take the exam.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A good year with VMware and better things to come!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/12/a-good-year-with-vmware-and-better-things-to-come/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 11:15:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/12/a-good-year-with-vmware-and-better-things-to-come/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;This year for me personally has been extremely busy and eventful coupled with a great deal of learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without wishing to bore the pants off of any would be reader I shall summarize my ruminations as someone whom is still quite new to the VMware world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that comes to mind is a a couple of recent meetings I have had with VMware. Learning that they are now very keen to engage with &amp;rsquo;the rest of us&amp;rsquo; and by that I mean those of us working in SME&amp;rsquo;s as we represent well over 50% of their business revenue. For me personally this was excellent news as we have already invested heavily into the VMware product range and plan to carry on doing so in the future. The recent release of VMware suites was a good step forward but I still feel they need to do a lot better in communicating to SME&amp;rsquo;s about their vast (and ever increasing) product range as there are many gems that can often go unoticed. Our discovery of vCops earlier this year was a good example of this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCenter 5.1 Single Sign On Multi-Site error: User credentials are incorrect or empty</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/vcenter-5-1-single-sign-on-multi-site-error-user-credentials-are-incorrect-or-empty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 20:24:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/vcenter-5-1-single-sign-on-multi-site-error-user-credentials-are-incorrect-or-empty/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;While adding an additional vCenter Server to our Multi-Site Single Sign On instance I encountered a problem as I entered the details of the existing SSO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2012/11/SingleSignOnMultiSite.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The error thrown was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User credentials are incorrect or empty. Provide correct credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2012/11/ErrorMessage.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple of hours online with VMware support I took a guess at the problem. On the existing Single Sign On Configuration I have added the Active Directory domain DefinIT and in order to enable integrated authentication from the vSphere Client I moved it to the top of the list - this meant that System-Domain is no longer the default authentication domain. The SSO admin account (admin@System-Domain) is a part of that domain and so my guess is that the installer tries to authenticate using &lt;a href="mailto:admin@definit.local"&gt;
 admin@definit.local
&lt;/a&gt; rather than System-Domain, which of course failed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VCP5 – vSphere 5 Configuration Maximums Quiz in PowerShell</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/vcp5-vsphere-5-configuration-maximums-quiz-in-powershell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 16:48:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/vcp5-vsphere-5-configuration-maximums-quiz-in-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2012/02/powershell.png" alt=""&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning my vSphere 5 config maximums before my upcoming VCP5 exam, so in a supreme effort of procrastination I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a PowerShell quiz script: here it is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save the QuizMe.ps1 file into a folder and then place one or more text file in the same folder containing a comma delimited set of questions and answers. Then run QuizMe.ps1!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can choose the quiz you take (which text file it will use).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Powershell – Generate Microsoft CA signed SSL certificates with vSphere 5.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/powershell-generate-microsoft-ca-signed-ssl-certificates-with-vsphere-5-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 16:59:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/powershell-generate-microsoft-ca-signed-ssl-certificates-with-vsphere-5-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;The process of requesting certificates for vSphere 5.1 is a fairly grim, manual process. It&amp;rsquo;s repetitive and easy to make a mistake on any step of the way. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve got to do this for quite a few VirtualCenter Servers, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d script the certificate generation if nothing else. I am following the excellent documentation provided in &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Implementing CA signed SSL certificates with vSphere 5.1&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; and more specifically in &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Creating certificate requests and certificates for vCenter Server 5.1 components&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing VMware vSphere Single Sign On (SSO) in Multi-site Mode</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/installing-vmware-vsphere-single-sign-on-sso-in-multi-site-mode/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 19:33:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/installing-vmware-vsphere-single-sign-on-sso-in-multi-site-mode/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt; VMware vSphere Single Sign On (SSO) can be installed in Multi-site mode to support local sign-on to vCenters that you want to be part of the same single sign on domain - for example, if you want to install Linked-Mode and have the advantage of a single pane of glass view, but can&amp;rsquo;t risk using a single SSO instance across the WAN. In other words, from &lt;a href="http://blogs.vmware.com/vsphere/2012/09/vcenter-single-sign-on-part-1-what-is-vcenter-single-sign-on.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; VMware&amp;rsquo;s blog post
&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>DataStore conflicts with an existing DataStore in the DataCenter – Manually disabling Storage I/O Control</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/datastore-conflicts-with-an-existing-datastore-in-the-datacenter-manually-disabling-storage-io-control/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 15:31:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/datastore-conflicts-with-an-existing-datastore-in-the-datacenter-manually-disabling-storage-io-control/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;I ran into this issue yesterday while reconnecting hosts in our vCenter Server following a complete reinstall - the reasons for which are a long story, but suffice to say that there were new certificates and the host passwords were encrypted with the old ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LUNs had been unpresented at the hardware level by the storage team, but had not been unmounted or removed from vCenter. This is &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; the way to remove storage - let me re-iterate: &lt;a href="http://blogs.vmware.com/vsphere/2011/11/best-practice-how-to-correctly-remove-a-lun-from-an-esx-host.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; remove storage properly
&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately in this case the storage was removed badly - doing this can lead to a condition called &amp;ldquo;All Paths Down&amp;rdquo; or APD which is best explained by Cormac Hogan (@vmwarestorage) in the article &lt;a href="http://blogs.vmware.com/vsphere/2011/08/all-path-down-apd-handling-in-50.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Handling the All Paths Down (APD) condition
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Host disk write latency errors – troubleshooting</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/host-disk-write-latency-errors-troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 11:02:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/host-disk-write-latency-errors-troubleshooting/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;So recently we upgraded our cluster monitoring suite to it&amp;rsquo;s latest iteration (Veeam ONE), it was not long before I began to receive emails from the monitor informing me of Host disk write latency &amp;ldquo;errors&amp;rdquo; (Datastore write latency had exceeded the defined threshold in the monitor) on several of the Datastores on our SAN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally I began the process of cross referencing backup routines and any heavy I/O routines that may have been running at the time the warning messages were generated. My conclusion was that even under average load these alerts were being generated, which was far from ideal even if we had not noticed any performance problems with any of the busy VMs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCenter 5.1 – Configuring vCenter Linked Mode</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/vcenter-5-1-configuring-vcenter-linked-mode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 15:42:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/vcenter-5-1-configuring-vcenter-linked-mode/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;One thing we have been meaning to do for a while but haven&amp;rsquo;t got round to is getting our Virtual Center Servers into &amp;ldquo;Linked&amp;rdquo; mode - essentially to provide a single pane of glass view of our entire virtual estate. One vCenter resides on the other side of our DMZ and manages hosts isolated for security purposes. I&amp;rsquo;ve created an IPSec server-to-server connection and allowed that through the firewall to secure traffic between the DMZ VC and LAN VC.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Converting vSphere Custom Attributes to Categories and Tags</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/09/converting-vsphere-custom-attributes-to-categories-and-tags/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 09:34:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/09/converting-vsphere-custom-attributes-to-categories-and-tags/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;In vSphere 5.1 &amp;ldquo;Tags&amp;rdquo; replace the old custom attributes to provide a way of adding metadata to vSphere objects. The &amp;ldquo;Tags&amp;rdquo; are organised into categories to &amp;ldquo;define how the tags can be applied to inventory objects&amp;rdquo;. The easiest way to think of the difference is that custom attributes are &amp;ldquo;free text&amp;rdquo; and the tags are statically defined properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a wizard for converting custom attributes to tags, but it can get a bit confusing and is pretty poor - let me explain. We use four custom attributes in my current environment: CreatedBy, CreatedOn, Owner and ServiceType. CreatedBy contains the user ID of the person who created the VM, CreatedOn is the timestamp of when the VM was created, Owner is the Business Unit who own the server and ServiceType is the type of service - e.g. Active Directory, or SQL.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere HA agent for host [Host’s Name] has an error in [Cluster’s Name] in [Datacenter’s Name]: vSphere HA agent cannot be correctly installed or configured</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/vsphere-ha-agent-for-host-hosts-name-has-an-error-in-clusters-name-in-datacenters-name-vsphere-ha-agent-cannot-be-correctly-installed-or-configured/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 10:23:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/vsphere-ha-agent-for-host-hosts-name-has-an-error-in-clusters-name-in-datacenters-name-vsphere-ha-agent-cannot-be-correctly-installed-or-configured/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a lesson in checking the basics! I added new ESXi 5 host to a cluster today and spent a good couple of hours troubleshooting the error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vSphere HA agent for host [Host&amp;rsquo;s Name] has an error in [Cluster&amp;rsquo;s Name] in [Datacenter&amp;rsquo;s Name]: vSphere HA agent cannot be correctly installed or configured &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;After a few basic checks, migrating the host in and out of the cluster and rebooting, I headed off to google and began troubleshooting.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vMA 5: Cannot initialize property ‘ vami.DNS0.vSphere_Management_Assistant_(vMA)’</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/vma-5-cannot-initialize-property-vami-dns0-vsphere_management_assistant_vma/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 17:25:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/vma-5-cannot-initialize-property-vami-dns0-vsphere_management_assistant_vma/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;Just a quick post regarding the vSphere Management Assistant 5 - when deploying the vMA with a static IP address, you might see the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2012/08/2012-08-23-002.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power On virtual machine &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; Cannot initialize property &amp;rsquo; vami.DNS0.vSphere_Man- agement_Assistant_(vMA)&amp;rsquo; , since network &amp;lsquo;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&amp;rsquo; has no associated IP pool configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit the vMA virtual machine&amp;rsquo;s properties and go to Options, vApp Options and select disable. Acknowledge the warning and click OK to close the VM properties.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware ESXi Maximum paths includes local storage</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/vmware-esxi-maximum-paths-includes-local-storage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 09:45:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/vmware-esxi-maximum-paths-includes-local-storage/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;If you are close to the VMware ESXi storage path limit of 1024 paths per host, you may want to consider the following: &lt;strong&gt;local storage, including CD-ROMs, are counted in your total paths&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply because of the size and age of the environment, some of our production clusters have now reached the limit (including local paths) - you see this message in the logs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2012-08-20 01:48:52.256 77C3DB90 info &amp;lsquo;ha-eventmgr&amp;rsquo;] Event 2003 : The maximum number of supported paths of 1024 has been reached. Path vmhba3:C0:T4:L0 could not be added.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Upgrading to ESXi 5.0 Update 1 using VMware Update Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/07/upgrading-to-esxi-5-0-update-1-using-vmware-update-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 15:34:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/07/upgrading-to-esxi-5-0-update-1-using-vmware-update-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently updating a very small 4-host cluster built for a specific application within our datacentre, the hosts are IBM HS22 blades. Since we have the VMware Update Manager infrastructure in place already, I downloaded the IBM ESXi 5.0 Update 2 ISO and imported it into Update Manager, created a baseline and then applied it to the cluster. I scanned the cluster with the baseline and was issued this warning for each host:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware PowerCLI – Set Path Selection Policy on all LUNs for a host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/10/vmware-powercli-set-path-selection-policy-on-all-luns-for-a-host/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 11:08:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/10/vmware-powercli-set-path-selection-policy-on-all-luns-for-a-host/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick script to set the Path Selection Policy on any LUNs on a host that do not have your target policy enabled. The script sets the server to Maintenance mode first, evacuating any VMs if you are in a full DRS automated environment. While this is not strictly necessary, it was required for my production environment just to be safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description></item><item><title>The case of the missing network adaptor: a.k.a Installing additional drivers on ESXi 4.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/the-case-of-the-missing-network-adaptor-a-k-a-installing-additional-drivers-on-esxi-4-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 14:15:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/the-case-of-the-missing-network-adaptor-a-k-a-installing-additional-drivers-on-esxi-4-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Recently I installed and configured a client’s new ESXi host, they’re a small company and only require a single host. The host in question was an IBM x3650 M3, an excellent workhorse for virtualisation and one of 5 or 6 of the same model that I’ve installed in the last year. In addition to the onboard Broadcom Dual Gigabit NIC, we always install at least a second Intel PCIx Dual Gigabit card for resilience/redundancy/performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Configuring Software iSCSI multipathing on ESXi 4.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/11/configuring-software-iscsi-multipathing-on-esxi-4-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 16:40:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/11/configuring-software-iscsi-multipathing-on-esxi-4-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;Recently I had cause to configure iSCSI multipathing on a test ESXi server. The production environment servers use iSCSI HBAs to connect to the back end storage, so multipathing them is a straight-forward setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s good practice to separate VMotion, virtual machine and iSCSI traffic, it also helps you manage those logical and physical connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connect to your ESXi server using the vSphere Client and select the host. Go to the configuration tab and click “Add Networking…”. Select a new VMKernel connection type.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Managing ESXi 4.1 with vMA 4.1 on VMware Workstation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/10/managing-esxi-4-1-with-vma-4-1-on-vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 21:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/10/managing-esxi-4-1-with-vma-4-1-on-vmware-workstation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;vMA is available as a Virtual Appliance (OVF) from VMware. To install it on VMware Workstation 7, open Workstation and select Import or Export to import a new OVF, the URL for the latest OVF for vMA is on the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vMA download page&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/10/image_thumb.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;per this article on virtualkenneth.com&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, you need to edit the VMX file to change the SCSI card and OS type, otherwise you’ll have a kernel panic on boot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware vSphere – DRS only shows one host in cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/05/vmware-vsphere-drs-only-shows-one-host-in-cluster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 15:54:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/05/vmware-vsphere-drs-only-shows-one-host-in-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I rebuilt an ESX host in my HA/DRS cluster today, following my build procedure to configure as per VMware best practices and internal guidelines. When the host was fully configured and up-to-date, I added it to the cluster and enabled HA and DRS. Then I went to generate some DRS recommendations to balance the load an ease off my overstretched host, but no recommendations were made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t manually migrate any VMs either – it was odd, because both hosts were added into the cluster, and could ping and vmkping each other from the console.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to enable hot memory add on vSphere and ESX 4.0 after upgrade</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/how-to-enable-hot-memory-add-on-vsphere-and-esx-4-0-after-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 12:29:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/how-to-enable-hot-memory-add-on-vsphere-and-esx-4-0-after-upgrade/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So you’ve upgraded your ESX 3.x servers to 4.0 and you’ve upgraded your vCenter server, now you want to access the shiny new hot-add feature to upgrade some running server’s memory. Except you can’t, the feature is no-where to be seen. Something to bear in mind though, your OS needs to support hot-add, so you’ll need a Windows Enterprise or Datacenter edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how to enable it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upgrade the VM’s tools, if you haven’t already. This requires a re-boot, but don’t reboot, shut the server down down, otherwise you’ll require another reboot to add the feature. The tools can be upgraded from the system tray icon.&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/image_thumb_27.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Creating a Windows Server 2008 Microsoft Cluster Service SQL Active/Passive Cluster on a single ESXi 4.0 Server</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/01/creating-a-windows-server-2008-microsoft-cluster-service-sql-activepassive-cluster-on-a-single-esxi-4-0-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 14:52:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/01/creating-a-windows-server-2008-microsoft-cluster-service-sql-activepassive-cluster-on-a-single-esxi-4-0-server/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="configuring-the-virtual-environment-and-virtual-machines"&gt;Configuring the Virtual Environment and Virtual Machines &lt;a class="anchor" href="#configuring-the-virtual-environment-and-virtual-machines"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note – this configuration will work for ESXi 4 upwards due to the server 2008 MSCS requirement for persistent SCSI-3 reservations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to create a new vSwitch for the host-only cluster heartbeat network, don’t assign any network adaptors to the switch as it’s going to be local only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a new virtual machine with a single hard disk. For the purposes of this test, I’ve assigned 2 vProcessors, 1GB RAM, 30GB drive for the OS, 1 vNIC in the default vSwitch0.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Migrating VMware Virtual Infrastructure 3 HA Cluster to vSphere 4 – Stage 1: vCenter Upgrade</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/11/migrating-vmware-virtual-infrastructure-3-ha-cluster-to-vsphere-4-%E2%80%93-stage-1-vcenter-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/11/migrating-vmware-virtual-infrastructure-3-ha-cluster-to-vsphere-4-%E2%80%93-stage-1-vcenter-upgrade/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the process of migrating a 2-host High Availability cluster of ESX 3.5u4 servers to vSphere 4. This is going to come in 3 distinct stages: Stage 1 is to upgrade VirtualCenter Server 2.5 to vCenter 4, which I am going to cover today. Stage 2 is to upgrade each host, and will be covered as I do it. Stage 3 is the upgrade of the Virtual Machines to the latest VMware Tools and then the new VM hardware.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The requested Storage VMotion would move a virtual machine’s disks without assigning the virtual machine a new home, but such a move is not supported on the source host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/10/the-requested-storage-vmotion-would-move-a-virtual-machines-disks-without-assigning-the-virtual-machine-a-new-home-but-such-a-move-is-not-supported-on-the-source-host/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 14:04:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/10/the-requested-storage-vmotion-would-move-a-virtual-machines-disks-without-assigning-the-virtual-machine-a-new-home-but-such-a-move-is-not-supported-on-the-source-host/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m migrating some hosts off of an older storage LUN, but when I drag the disk to the new Datastore with the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;SVMotion plug-in&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; the job fails with the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The error occurs because the virtual disk cannot be moved without moving the source files, the .vmx, .vswap etc. Simply drag the entire VM, rather than the virtual disk to the new Datastore.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ESX 3.5 snapshots of disks on different storage are stored with the VM files</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/10/esx-3-5-snapshots-of-disks-on-different-storage-are-stored-with-the-vm-files/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2009 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/10/esx-3-5-snapshots-of-disks-on-different-storage-are-stored-with-the-vm-files/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="aka-why-not-to-use-snapshots"&gt;A.K.A Why not to use snapshots &lt;a class="anchor" href="#aka-why-not-to-use-snapshots"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I ran into a slightly confusing problem today - our SQL servers are all created with 4 disks on 4 separate LUNs (System, Swap, SQL Data and SQL Logs). When viewing the server through Virtual Center I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see all of the LUNs, just the System LUN. It&amp;rsquo;s not a major problem as the VM can see the storage, but a little annoying when you have to remember what LUN the disks are on.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Teaming NICs with ESX 3.5 and Cisco Switches in an aggregate.</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/teaming-nics-with-esx-3-5-and-cisco-switches-in-an-aggregate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/teaming-nics-with-esx-3-5-and-cisco-switches-in-an-aggregate/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the setup. We have a core switch of 2 Cisco 3750s, connected together for fault tolerance as a single logical switch; we also have several ESX 3.5 hosts with 4 Gigabit Ethernet NICs installed each. The Virtual Machines will all be on VLAN 8 (reserved for internal servers) and the VMKernel will be on VLAN 107 (reserved for VMKernel traffic like VMotion).  I want to create a load balanced, fault tolerant aggregate of these four NICs over the Core Switch.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMWare Server: The VMware Host Agent service terminated with service-specific error 4294967295 (0xFFFFFFFF).</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/02/vmware-server-the-vmware-host-agent-service-terminated-with-service-specific-error-4294967295-0xffffffff/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/02/vmware-server-the-vmware-host-agent-service-terminated-with-service-specific-error-4294967295-0xffffffff/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Having just rebooted my laptop, I clicked on the link to open VMWare Infrastructure Web Access in the my browser and was slightly puzzled by the &amp;ldquo;page cannot be displayed&amp;rdquo; error. I figured it was probably the VMWare Server Web Access service not starting for some reason, so I opened services.msc and checked it out. The Web Access service was actually running, but the Host Agent service was not, so I tried to start it - it failed. Dutifully opening Event Viewer for some more information I found the error:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SSH remote console to ESXi server</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/12/ssh-remote-console-to-esxi-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/12/ssh-remote-console-to-esxi-server/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having recently installed an ESXi server, I am getting to grips with the management and administration of it, one of the things that I wanted to be able to do was connect to the remote terminal through SSH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I downloaded my SSH client of choice, PuTTY, and set about connecting, however the server refused the connection. It seems that SSH is not enabled out of the box for ESXi and you need to go through some steps to get there - I found some &lt;a href="http://www.yellow-bricks.com/2008/08/10/howto-esxi-and-ssh/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; helpful hints here
&lt;/a&gt;.These are the steps that I took, based on the advice and some other research.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Utilising more than 4GB of RAM with Windows Server 2003 Standard Edition – Enabling /PAE /3GB</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/utilising-more-than-4gb-of-ram-with-windows-server-2003-standard-edition-enabling-pae-3gb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 11:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/utilising-more-than-4gb-of-ram-with-windows-server-2003-standard-edition-enabling-pae-3gb/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We recently needed to upgrade one of our applications, and the new version requires an addition server instead of the application and SQL it requires a back end search, a front end web server and a SQL server. The specifications of the new server which are &amp;ldquo;required&amp;rdquo; to qualify for support are pretty high. The problem is that the actual processor usage is very light, and it is very hard to justify buying a whole new server that I know is going to be barely used.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMWare Server 2 Beta fails to connect to virtual machine with “Error opening the remote virtual machine [machine] The host name could not be resolved.”</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/vmware-server-2-beta-fails-to-connect-to-virtual-machine-with-error-opening-the-remote-virtual-machine-machine-the-host-name-could-not-be-resolved/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 10:17:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/vmware-server-2-beta-fails-to-connect-to-virtual-machine-with-error-opening-the-remote-virtual-machine-machine-the-host-name-could-not-be-resolved/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just upgraded my VMWare Server install to the latest version of the VMWare Server beta, which I have to say, is looking pretty good! One slight niggle that I had was that when I opened the VMWare Remote Console it would tell me that I could not connect, with the error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Error opening the remote virtual machine SM-00109:8333\16:  The host name could not be resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly THAT&amp;rsquo;s a pain in the proverbial. A quick trawl through VMWare&amp;rsquo;s forums reveals two solutions, one that is clunky and stupid, the other that works. For brevity, the one that works is…&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Moving and resizing a VMWare System Disk</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/06/moving-and-resizing-a-vmware-system-disk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2007 19:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/06/moving-and-resizing-a-vmware-system-disk/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;font size=&amp;quot;2&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;Next time you boot&amp;amp;nbsp;the Virual Machine, you&amp;amp;rsquo;ll have to re-attach the .vmdk in it&amp;amp;rsquo;s correct location. &amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>