<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>appliance on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/appliance/</link><description>Recent content in appliance on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 19:57:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/appliance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying vRealize Automation 6.2 Appliance Cluster with Postgres Replication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 19:57:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</guid><description>The recommendations for the vRealize Appliance have changed with 6.2, the published reference architecture now does not recommend using an external Postgres database (either vPostgres appliance, a 3rd party Postgres deployment or using a third vRealize Appliance as a stand-alone database installation). Instead the recommended layout is shown in the diagram below. One instance of postgres on the primary node becomes an active instance, replicating to the second node which is passive.</description></item><item><title>Deploying VMTurbo Virtual Health Monitor</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vmturbo-virtual-health-monitor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 09:43:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vmturbo-virtual-health-monitor/</guid><description>Having just welcomed VMTurbo on board as a blog sponsor, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do a quick posting on how to deploy their free Virtual Health Monitor appliance.
Sign up for a free license here and download the appropriate version
Deploy the VMTurbo Appliance Deploying the appliance is simply a case of importing the OVA downloaded. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing really to configure and it took 61 seconds in my lab environment, so it&amp;rsquo;s pretty quick!</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 Lab Upgrade – vCenter Server Appliance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-vcenter-server-appliance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 15:23:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-vcenter-server-appliance/</guid><description>I tested vSphere 6 quite intensively when it was in beta, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t ever upgrade my lab - basically because I need a stable environment to work on and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure that I could maintain that with the beta.
Now 6 has been GA a while and I have a little bit of time, I have begun the lab upgrade process. You can see a bit more about my lab hardware over on my lab page.</description></item><item><title>vROps – first look – part 1 – installation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/vrops-first-look-part-1-installation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 11:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/vrops-first-look-part-1-installation/</guid><description>For several months now we have seen glimpses of vROps by way of limited blog posts and the HOL demo&amp;rsquo;s so it was great to see it finally released.
So what is it like out of the box?
vROps 6.0 Release notes
The first clear change is the move away from 2 VMs in a vAPP and consolidation down to 1 VM which is then easily scalable to more as you require.</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 4: Deploying and clustering a secondary vCAC Appliance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-4-deploying-and-clustering-a-secondary-vcac-appliance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 10:54:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-4-deploying-and-clustering-a-secondary-vcac-appliance/</guid><description>This is the fourth article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
By the end of this post we will have deployed a second vCAC Appliance, clustered it with the first appliance and registered the load balanced URL with the Identity Appliance. This will mean logging on to https://vcloud.definit.local/shell-ui-app will be successful.
vCAC deployment with clustered and load balanced vCAC Appliances An overview of the steps required are below:</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 3.2: Configure load balancing with NSX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-2-configure-load-balancing-with-nsx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-2-configure-load-balancing-with-nsx/</guid><description>This is the second part of the 3rd article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
By the end of this part, we will not have modified the vCAC deployment in any way, we’ll just have 3 configured load balanced URLs
vCAC Simple Install with vPostgres deployed and load balancers prepared An overview of the steps required are below:
Issue and install certificates Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database Configure load balancing Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering Install and configure additional IaaS server Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster I’ve previously configured 3 DNS records for the load balanced services (see part 3.</description></item><item><title>Installing and configuring VMware Infrastructure Navigator 5.8</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/installing-and-configuring-vmware-infrastructure-navigator-5-8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 10:40:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/installing-and-configuring-vmware-infrastructure-navigator-5-8/</guid><description>According to VMware, Infrastructure Navigator is
…a component of the VMware vCenter Operations Management Suite. It automatically discovers application services, visualizes relationships and maps dependencies of applications on virtualized compute, storage and network resources.
Effectively it takes a look at the network connections that are running between your VMs (and physical servers) and works out which applications and services are running on each, and the dependencies – both upstream and downstream – for each VM.</description></item><item><title>Installing and Configuring vCenter Log Insight</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-and-configuring-vcenter-log-insight/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 13:32:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-and-configuring-vcenter-log-insight/</guid><description>With the release of vCenter Log Insight Public Beta (http://communities.vmware.com/community/vmtn/vcenter/vcenter-log-insight) I thought I’d strike while the iron is hot and run through the installation and configuration.
Deploying the OVF This is such a bread and butter task that it doesn’t require more than a few words – it’s definitely worth looking at the Sizing PDF before you deploy (VMware-vCenter-Log-Insight-1.0-Beta-Virtual-Appliance-Sizing.pdf) as it’s not small even for a test installation. If you’re using less than the recommended 8GB RAM there are additional steps to change the heap size for performance.</description></item><item><title>Installing the VMware Support Assistant</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/01/installing-the-vmware-support-assistant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 14:25:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/01/installing-the-vmware-support-assistant/</guid><description>So VMware&amp;rsquo;s Support Assistant is pretty awesome and it&amp;rsquo;s free! I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do a quick run through of the installation and set up for anyone who was interested, it&amp;rsquo;s fairly straightforward and if you raise a lot of calls or have multiple calls on the go it&amp;rsquo;s a time saver!
VMware&amp;rsquo;s official page for the Support Assistant is here - https://www.vmware.com/products/datacenter-virtualization/vcenter-support-assistant/overview.html
The OVF deploy is so simple I&amp;rsquo;ve just taken screenshots:</description></item></channel></rss>