<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Qualifications on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/qualifications/</link><description>Recent content in Qualifications on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2010 10:35:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/qualifications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MCITP: Server Administrator and MCITP: Enterprise Administrator</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/mcitp-server-administrator-and-mcitp-enterprise-administrator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2010 10:35:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/mcitp-server-administrator-and-mcitp-enterprise-administrator/</guid><description>I’m pleased to say that yesterday I took and passed two Microsoft Certified IT Professional exams, the Server Administrator (70-646) and the Enterprise Administrator (70-647). Hopefully I can take a bit of a break from study and write a few more technical posts here now!</description></item><item><title>70-649: TS: Upgrading Your MCSE on Windows Server 2003 to Windows Server 2008, Technology Specialist</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/70-649-ts-upgrading-your-mcse-on-windows-server-2003-to-windows-server-2008-technology-specialist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 10:14:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/70-649-ts-upgrading-your-mcse-on-windows-server-2003-to-windows-server-2008-technology-specialist/</guid><description>I’m pleased to announce that I’ve passed the 70-649, which gives me the following MCTS certifications:
Windows Server 2008 Active Directory, Configuration
Windows Server 2008 Applications Infrastructure, Configuration
Windows Server 2008 Network Infrastructure, Configuration
Next I’ll be looking at the 70-647 to get the full MCITP: Enterprise Administrator (I already took the 70-620 exam for my MCSE).</description></item><item><title>CCNA Qualified</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/ccna-qualified/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 15:56:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/ccna-qualified/</guid><description>After some pretty heavy investment in terms of time and money, I’ve passed my ICND2 exam and am now qualified as a Cisco Certified Network Associate (anyone else find it odd that you’re not even considered a professional by Cisco at this level?!)
I do consider the Cisco qualifications as significantly more valuable than the others that I hold, simply because of the difficulty of the exams. I do find them “honest” in that they’re not trick questions, and you don’t need a technique to pass – just in depth knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Cisco Qualified!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/12/cisco-qualified/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 10:46:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/12/cisco-qualified/</guid><description>As is normally the case when I’m studying, I haven’t had time to post much on here lately. I’ve been studying to pass the ICND1 exam (snappily titled “Interconnecting Cisco Network Devices Part 1”)
I’m really pleased to say that neglecting this site paid off, or rather the study did – I passed with a score of 930! It was a LOT harder than I had expected, I thought I’d walk out after 20m!</description></item></channel></rss>