<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nodes on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/nodes/</link><description>Recent content in nodes on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 21:32:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/nodes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adding and removing #vROps nodes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/adding-and-removing-vrops-nodes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 21:32:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/adding-and-removing-vrops-nodes/</guid><description>I was asked recently if there were any materials I could direct people to with regards to expanding existing vROps deployments. I did a brief search on the web to see what material was &amp;ldquo;out there&amp;rdquo; on how to perform what is a straight forward task. To my surprise very little came up. So I have decided to create this guide with all the things you need to consider when you are going to either expand or need to remove a node from one of your active vROps deployments.</description></item><item><title>#vROps a new diva in the datacentre</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-a-new-diva-in-the-datacentre/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 16:06:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-a-new-diva-in-the-datacentre/</guid><description>For the last few months and certainly very recently (at the London VMUG meeting) I have had the chance to talk to peers and #vExperts and share “war stories” with regards to vRealize Operations Manager.
What has become a consistent theme in all the stories is just how much compute resources vROps requires when you “go big” and not just what is clearly defined in the sizing spreadsheet.
For example some of the large deployments I have either been involved in or heard about (to monitor upwards and beyond of 30000 VMs) required the deployment of Large vROps nodes.</description></item></channel></rss>