<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ukvmug on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/ukvmug/</link><description>Recent content in Ukvmug on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 13:25:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/ukvmug/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#UKVMUG &amp;ndash; Curry &amp;ndash; Beer &amp;ndash; Sessions &amp;ndash; Weddings</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-curry-beer-sessions-weddings-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 13:25:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-curry-beer-sessions-weddings-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vmug-usercon_thumb.png" alt=""&gt;This was my second UKVMUG and it was my first vCurry evening! so I was really looking forward to getting up to the event and seeing everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vCurry event was excellent and it was a great chance to enjoy good food in great company. Had the chance to meet with many people I would not normally get the chance to see, Frank &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fbuechsel" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; @fbuechsel
&lt;/a&gt; and Brad &lt;a href="mailto:V@VMUG_CEO"&gt;
 @VMUG_CEO
&lt;/a&gt; to name a couple! To top off a really great evening we (my table/team) won the vQuiz which was organised and conducted by Stuart &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virtual_Stu" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; @Virtual_Stu
&lt;/a&gt; (thanks Stuart!), a big thank you to Matt &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Twickersmatt" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; @Twickersmatt
&lt;/a&gt; for the beers (one of the prizes).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#UKVMUG Ravello Home Lab Winner!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-ravello-home-lab-winner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 11:11:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-ravello-home-lab-winner/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;First of all, thank you to everyone who came along to my session at the UKVMUG yesterday, it was great to see so many people at a round table discussion, sorry for those that had to stand! I hope that it was helpful and maybe a few of you will be building some awesome labs in the cloud!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ravello very kindly sponsored a free home lab, equivalent to the vExpert 1000 hours account as a prize for my session at the UKVMUG yesterday. Using a high tech random number generator and an Excel spread sheet the winner was picked, so without further ado, congratulations go to…&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#UKVMUG 2014</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/11/ukvmug-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 12:27:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/11/ukvmug-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday (in case you missed it) was the fourth annual UK national VMUG at the National Motorcycle Museum in Birmingham. It was my second year attending and I continue to be blown away with the quality and value available at this event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a huge amount of content packed into this one-day event, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try and summarise my day…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vcurry-and-vquiz"&gt;vCurry and vQuiz &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vcurry-and-vquiz"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vCurry event was hosted on Monday night and is a great way to chill out after a long drive up to the midlands. It&amp;rsquo;s always well attended and there are always familiar faces from the London VMUG there. Also there is the now legendary vQuiz, hosted by Stuart Thompson (@virtual_stu) which is great for a laugh or two and makes a good ice breaker if you&amp;rsquo;re there on your own. Oh, and free curry and a free beer or two…what&amp;rsquo;s not to like?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>