<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ukvmug on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/ukvmug/</link><description>Recent content in ukvmug on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 13:25:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/ukvmug/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#UKVMUG &amp;ndash; Curry &amp;ndash; Beer &amp;ndash; Sessions &amp;ndash; Weddings</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-curry-beer-sessions-weddings-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 13:25:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-curry-beer-sessions-weddings-2/</guid><description>This was my second UKVMUG and it was my first vCurry evening! so I was really looking forward to getting up to the event and seeing everyone.
The vCurry event was excellent and it was a great chance to enjoy good food in great company. Had the chance to meet with many people I would not normally get the chance to see, Frank @fbuechsel and Brad @VMUG_CEO to name a couple!</description></item><item><title>#UKVMUG Ravello Home Lab Winner!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-ravello-home-lab-winner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 11:11:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-ravello-home-lab-winner/</guid><description>First of all, thank you to everyone who came along to my session at the UKVMUG yesterday, it was great to see so many people at a round table discussion, sorry for those that had to stand! I hope that it was helpful and maybe a few of you will be building some awesome labs in the cloud!
Ravello very kindly sponsored a free home lab, equivalent to the vExpert 1000 hours account as a prize for my session at the UKVMUG yesterday.</description></item><item><title>#UKVMUG 2014</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/11/ukvmug-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 12:27:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/11/ukvmug-2014/</guid><description>Yesterday (in case you missed it) was the fourth annual UK national VMUG at the National Motorcycle Museum in Birmingham. It was my second year attending and I continue to be blown away with the quality and value available at this event.
There&amp;rsquo;s a huge amount of content packed into this one-day event, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try and summarise my day…
vCurry and vQuiz The vCurry event was hosted on Monday night and is a great way to chill out after a long drive up to the midlands.</description></item></channel></rss>