<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Iaas on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/iaas/</link><description>Recent content in Iaas on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:40:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/iaas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components – Part 2: Database, Web and Manager services</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-2-database-web-and-manager-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:40:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-2-database-web-and-manager-services/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png" alt=""&gt;Now that the prerequisites for the IaaS layer have been completed, it&amp;rsquo;s time to move on to the actual installation of the IaaS components, starting with the database. We then move onto the first Web server, which also imports the ModelManagerData configuration to the database, populating the database with all of the info the IaaS layer needs out of the box. We then install the second Web server before moving on to the active Manager server. The second Manager server is passive and the service should be disabled - I&amp;rsquo;ll cover installing DEM Orchestrators, Workers and the vSphere Agents in the next article.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components – Part 1: Pre-requisites</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-1-pre-requisites/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:15:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-1-pre-requisites/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One of the trickiest parts of deploying vRealize Automation is the IaaS layer - people sometimes look at me like I&amp;rsquo;m a crazy person when I say that, normally because they&amp;rsquo;ve deployed a PoC or small deployment with just a single IaaS server. Add in 5 more servers, some load balancers, certificates, a distributed setup and MSDTC to the mix and you have a huge potential for pain!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>HTTP Error 500 installing vCAC IaaS Model Manager Data</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/http-error-500-installing-vcac-iaas-model-manager-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 16:16:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/http-error-500-installing-vcac-iaas-model-manager-data/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This was a fun little error, whilst installing the distributed IaaS roles I couldn’t seem to get the IaaS components to install – when I got the Website and Model Manager Data install it would fail with the following message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/07/image_thumb.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve pasted it in here because I couldn’t find anything through google that referred to my error messages – hopefully if you’re reading this you’ve found it because you’re looking for it!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>