<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vcops on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcops/</link><description>Recent content in vcops on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 15:12:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Starting 2016 with a bang &amp;ndash; #vROps Webinar Series</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/starting-2016-with-a-bang-vrops-webinar-series/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 15:12:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/starting-2016-with-a-bang-vrops-webinar-series/</guid><description>With a new year comes new things and I am delighted to announce the start of a vROps based webinar series. These will consist of a set of live webcasts on different topics around vRealize Operations Manager open to public to attend live or view the recorded sessions later. Personally I am delighted to get the chance to work with Sunny Duaon this new project. Sunny is a well known and respected Senior Consultant at VMware and can be found often on twitter @Sunny_Dua.</description></item><item><title>VCE Vision, vCOPs to vROps migration</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/vce-vision-vcops-to-vrops-migration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 22:26:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/vce-vision-vcops-to-vrops-migration/</guid><description>Recently I have been working with various products that compliment or are accessed by vCOPs/vROps via Management packs.
As vROps is still fairly new in comparative terms to other products like vCOPs and VCE Vision, when planning migrations from vCOPs to vROps it is naturally important to check compatibility and what is required for a successful migration.
If you are doing a greenfield deployment of vROps there is nothing to be concerned about, you simply need the VCE Vision appliance running version 2.</description></item><item><title>vROps – first look – part 1 – installation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/vrops-first-look-part-1-installation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 11:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/vrops-first-look-part-1-installation/</guid><description>For several months now we have seen glimpses of vROps by way of limited blog posts and the HOL demo&amp;rsquo;s so it was great to see it finally released.
So what is it like out of the box?
vROps 6.0 Release notes
The first clear change is the move away from 2 VMs in a vAPP and consolidation down to 1 VM which is then easily scalable to more as you require.</description></item><item><title>vCOPs resources (vCenter Operations Manager)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/vcops-resources-vcenter-operations-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 12:57:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/vcops-resources-vcenter-operations-manager/</guid><description>vCOPs resources If you have spent time working with vCOPs you will be aware of the numerous and widespread resources out on the net to help you install and fine tune your deployment. Given there is a lot of content out there that is not always easy to fine immediately I wanted to collate a useful list for my own use and to share with others.
Still a work in progress.</description></item><item><title>Slow or failed logon to VCSA 5.5 with vCOps in the environment</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/slow-or-failed-logon-to-vcsa-5-5-with-vcops-in-the-environment/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 09:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/slow-or-failed-logon-to-vcsa-5-5-with-vcops-in-the-environment/</guid><description>Recently I encountered this problem in a customer site whereby the logon to VCSA 5.5 would either time out, or take 3-5 minutes to actually log on.
Running a netstat on the VCSA during the attempt to logon showed there was a SYN packet sent to the vCOps appliance on port 443 that never established a connection. Another check was attempting to connect using curl &amp;lt;https://&amp;gt; –k - this would time out.</description></item></channel></rss>