<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CertificateValidationException on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/certificatevalidationexception/</link><description>Recent content in CertificateValidationException on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 12:26:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/certificatevalidationexception/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unable to connect NSX to Lookup Service when using a vSphere 6 subordinate certificate authority (VMCA)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/06/unable-to-connect-nsx-to-lookup-service-when-using-a-vsphere-6-subordinate-certificate-authority-vmca/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 12:26:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/06/unable-to-connect-nsx-to-lookup-service-when-using-a-vsphere-6-subordinate-certificate-authority-vmca/</guid><description>After deploying a new vSphere 6 vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) and configuring the Platform Services Controller (PSC) to act as a subordinate Certificate Authority (CS), I was unable to register the NSX Manager to the Lookup Service. Try saying that fast after a pint or two!?
Attempting to register NSX to the Lookup Service would result in the following error:
NSX Management Service operation failed.( Initialization of Admin Registration Service Provider failed.</description></item><item><title>SSO Admin password reset with ssopass – SslHandshakeFailed – vSphere 5.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/11/sso-admin-password-reset-with-ssopass-sslhandshakefailed-vsphere-5-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 12:53:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/11/sso-admin-password-reset-with-ssopass-sslhandshakefailed-vsphere-5-1/</guid><description>Today I found out that in vSphere 5.1 the SSO administrator account (admin@system-domain) has a password that expires after 365 days. See KB2035864:
vCenter Single Sign-On account (SSO) passwords expire after 365 days, including the password for admin@system-domain.
Awesome.
In vSphere 5.5 it gets even better – the password expires every 90 days by default! (See the vSphere 5.5 SSO documentation)
By default, vCenter Single Sign-On passwords, including the password for administrator@vsphere.</description></item></channel></rss>