<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>esxi 5.1 on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/esxi-5.1/</link><description>Recent content in esxi 5.1 on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 15:02:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/esxi-5.1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Virtualize Mac OS X using ESXi 5.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/how-to-virtualize-mac-os-x-using-esxi-5-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 15:02:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/how-to-virtualize-mac-os-x-using-esxi-5-1/</guid><description>As a proof of concept I recently tried to virtualize OS X (Mountain Lion) - It is important to note that VMware is now licensed to do so and you can read more here.
The following is an overview of the steps I followed to achieve my goal in some cases it was trial an error as I am not a regular Mac user.
The Hardware As OS X requires Apple hardware to run you will have to find yourself a Mac that will install and run ESXi.</description></item><item><title>vSphere Security: Understanding ESXi 5.x Lockdown Mode</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vsphere-security-understanding-esxi-5-x-lockdown-mode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 10:05:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vsphere-security-understanding-esxi-5-x-lockdown-mode/</guid><description>This is the first article in a series of vSphere Security articles that I have planned. The majority of this article is based on vSphere/ESXi 5.1, though I will include any 5.5 information that I find relevant.
I think lockdown mode is a feature that is rarely understood, and even more rarely used. Researching this article I’ve already encountered several different definitions that weren’t quite right. As far as I can see there are no differences between lockdown more in 5.</description></item><item><title>DataStore conflicts with an existing DataStore in the DataCenter – Manually disabling Storage I/O Control</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/datastore-conflicts-with-an-existing-datastore-in-the-datacenter-manually-disabling-storage-io-control/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 15:31:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/datastore-conflicts-with-an-existing-datastore-in-the-datacenter-manually-disabling-storage-io-control/</guid><description>I ran into this issue yesterday while reconnecting hosts in our vCenter Server following a complete reinstall - the reasons for which are a long story, but suffice to say that there were new certificates and the host passwords were encrypted with the old ones.
The LUNs had been unpresented at the hardware level by the storage team, but had not been unmounted or removed from vCenter. This is not the way to remove storage - let me re-iterate: remove storage properly.</description></item></channel></rss>