<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>JavaScript on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/javascript/</link><description>Recent content in JavaScript on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 12:09:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO) – Troubleshooting SOAP operations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-troubleshooting-soap-operations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 12:09:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-troubleshooting-soap-operations/</guid><description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a bit of a SOAP baptism of fire - the project I am working on makes hundreds of SOAP calls to multiple SOAP APIs on multiple hosts. During this time I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered some common and rare problems and troubleshooting them seems to be a bit of a black art, if the number of results in Google is any measure.
To demonstrate some of these troubleshooting methods I will use a global weather SOAP service, http://www.</description></item><item><title>Generating a secure random password with vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/generating-a-secure-random-password-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 21:17:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/generating-a-secure-random-password-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly common requirement when creating a new user to assign a randomly generated password, so during a recent engagement I wrote a little password generator to do that. I wanted to be able to chose whether special characters were used, and the length of the password - typically if the password doesn&amp;rsquo;t used special characters I would increase the length significantly!
Characters should be randomly picked from:
a-z A-Z 0-9 (optional) ASCII special characters Inputs passwordLength - the length of the password to be generated (number) excludePunctuation - exclude the use of special characters if TRUE (boolean) Outputs generatedPassword - the generated password (SecureString) The SecureString type prevents the string from being displayed in the workflow attributes - it can be used as a normal string, but will be asterisk&amp;rsquo;d when displayed.</description></item></channel></rss>