<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VRealize Automation on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vrealize-automation/</link><description>Recent content in VRealize Automation on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vrealize-automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Integrating vROps with vRA 8 using Workspace One Auth Source</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/03/integrating-vrops-with-vra-8-using-workspace-one-auth-source/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/03/integrating-vrops-with-vra-8-using-workspace-one-auth-source/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="integrating-vrops-with-vra-8-using-workspace-one-auth-source"&gt;Integrating vROps with vRA 8 using Workspace One Auth Source &lt;a class="anchor" href="#integrating-vrops-with-vra-8-using-workspace-one-auth-source"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="product-version---vrealize-automation-8x"&gt;Product Version - vRealize Automation 8.x &lt;a class="anchor" href="#product-version---vrealize-automation-8x"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id="why-integrate-vrops-with-vra-8"&gt;Why integrate vROps with vRA 8? &lt;a class="anchor" href="#why-integrate-vrops-with-vra-8"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vRealize Automation can work with vRealize Operations Manager to perform advanced workload placement, provide deployment health and virtual machine metrics, and display pricing.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="so-what-is-the-problem"&gt;So what is the problem? &lt;a class="anchor" href="#so-what-is-the-problem"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When configuring the integration, you will input the vROps URL and it will also ask you to input a username and password of the service account you wish to use. This is no problem if the accouint is a locally created account in vROps itself but most enterprises will want to use AD created service accounts which are then imported into vROps via WorkSpace One (vIDM)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why use Content Libraries with vRA 8</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/why-use-content-libraries-with-vra-8/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/why-use-content-libraries-with-vra-8/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="why-use-content-libraries-with-vra-8"&gt;Why use Content Libraries with vRA 8 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#why-use-content-libraries-with-vra-8"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="product-version---vrealize-automation-8x"&gt;Product Version - vRealize Automation 8.x &lt;a class="anchor" href="#product-version---vrealize-automation-8x"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id="what-are-vsphere-content-libraries"&gt;What are vSphere Content Libraries? &lt;a class="anchor" href="#what-are-vsphere-content-libraries"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;A content library stores and manages content in the form of library items. A single library item can consist of one file or multiple files. For example, the OVF template is a set of files (.ovf, .vmdk, and .mf). When you upload an OVF template to the library, you upload the entire set of files, but the result is a single library item of the OVF Template type.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>New Year, new things oh and a VCP7-CMA</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/01/new-year-new-things-oh-and-a-vcp7-cma/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:20:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/01/new-year-new-things-oh-and-a-vcp7-cma/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since I have had time to write a blog post, the last quarter of last year was pretty crazy from a work point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, it is now a New Year and my tech focus is turning very much on CMP related things particularly vRealize Automation. (I am also very much looking forward to learning more about VMware&amp;rsquo;s CaS which I saw demo&amp;rsquo;d at the UK VMUG late last year by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/grantorchard" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Grant Orchard
&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Lifecycle Manager 1.2 VC data collection fails when NSX-T hostswitches are in use</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-1-2-vc-data-collection-fails-when-nsx-t-hostswitches-are-in-use/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 10:17:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-1-2-vc-data-collection-fails-when-nsx-t-hostswitches-are-in-use/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;When vRealize Lifecycle Manager 1.2 was released recently, I was keen to get it installed in my lab, since I maintain several vRealize Automation deployments for development and testing, as well as performing upgrades. With vRLCM I can reduce the administrative overhead of managing the environments, as well as easily migrate content between environments (I&amp;rsquo;ll be blogging on some of these cool new features soon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I hit a snag when I began to import my existing environment - I couldn’t get the vCenter data collection to run.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Three Tier App for vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/03/three-tier-app-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/03/three-tier-app-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One question I’m asked quite a lot is what I use for a 3-tier application when I’m testing things like NSX micro-segmentation with vRealize Automation. The simple answer is that I used to make something up as I went along, deploying components by hand and generally repeating myself a lot. I had some cut/paste commands in my note application that sped things up a little, but nothing that developed. I’ve been meaning to rectify this for a while, and this is the result!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7.3 and NSX – Micro-segmentation strategies</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrealize-automation-7-3-and-nsx-micro-segmentation-strategies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 17:40:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrealize-automation-7-3-and-nsx-micro-segmentation-strategies/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2018/01/Firewall.jpg" alt=""&gt;vRealize Automation and NSX integration has introduced the ability to deploy multi-tiered applications with network services included. The current integration also enables a method to deploy micro-segmentation out of the box, based on dynamic Security Group membership and the Service Composer. This method does have some limitations, and can be inflexible for the on-going management of deployed applications. It requires in-depth knowledge and understanding of NSX and the Distributed Firewall, as well as access to the Networking and Security manager that is hosted by vCenter Server.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Wednesday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-4-wednesday/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 17:30:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-4-wednesday/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/09/VMworld-2017.jpg" alt=""&gt;This was as I expected, the busiest day sessions wise for me. There was so much good stuff I had to be a little ruthless on what I wanted and or needed to attend while also wanting to get into the solutions exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also at the end of the day the customer appreciate party was scheduled so that was something I was looking forward to a great deal (Hint - Kaiser Chiefs)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7.3 Distributed Install – Prerequisites</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrealize-automation-7-3-distributed-install-prerequisites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 13:33:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrealize-automation-7-3-distributed-install-prerequisites/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;As a consultant I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to design, install and configure dozens of production vRealize Automation deployments, from reasonably small Proof of Concept environments to globally-scaled multi-datacenter fully distributed behemoths. It&amp;rsquo;s fair to say, that I&amp;rsquo;ve made mistakes along the way - and learned a lot of lessons as to what makes a deployment a success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, pretty much everything comes down to getting the pre-requisites right. Nothing that I&amp;rsquo;ve written here is not already documented in the official documentation, and the installation wizard does a huge amount of the work for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Getting started with vRealize Log Insight 4.3 for vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/getting-started-with-vrealize-log-insight-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 12:09:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/getting-started-with-vrealize-log-insight-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In this humble consultant&amp;rsquo;s opinion, Log Insight is one of the most useful tools in the administrator&amp;rsquo;s tool belt for troubleshooting vRealize Automation. I have lost count of the number of times I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to help troubleshoot an issue that, when asked, people don&amp;rsquo;t know which log they should be looking at. The simple fact is that vRealize Automation has a lot of log files. Correlating these log sources to provide an overall picture is a painful, manual process - unless you have Log Insight!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRA7.2 and vSphere Integrated Containers</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vra7-2-and-vsphere-integrated-containers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 15:28:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vra7-2-and-vsphere-integrated-containers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One of the cool new features released with vRealize Automation 7.2 was the integration of VMware Admiral (container management) into the product, and recently VMware made version 1 of vSphere Integrated Containers generally available (GA), so I thought it was time I started playing around with the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover deploying VIC to my vSphere environment and then adding that host to the vRA 7.2 container management.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying to AWS with Software Components on vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/deploying-to-aws-with-software-components-on-vrealize-automation-7/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 17:09:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/deploying-to-aws-with-software-components-on-vrealize-automation-7/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id=""&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/11/AWS-vRA.png" alt=""&gt; &lt;a class="anchor" href="#"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on some ideas in my lab to leverage the AWS endpoint on vRealize Automation. One of the things I needed to get working was getting Software Components working on my AWS deployed instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diagram to the right shows my end-stage network - the instance deployed by vRA into AWS should be in a private subnet in my VPC, and should use my local lab DNS server and be able to access my vRA instance. This allows me to make use of the vRA guest agent for software components on the deployed VMs. I also wanted to have the deployed VMs use their local NAT gateway for internet traffic, rather than paying for the data over my VPN connection.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Adding an AWS endpoint to vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/adding-an-amazon-web-services-endpoint-to-vrealize-automation-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 09:46:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/adding-an-amazon-web-services-endpoint-to-vrealize-automation-7/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Although it&amp;rsquo;s fairly limited, you can add AWS as an endpoint for vRealize Automation 7  and consume EC2 AMIs as part of a blueprint. You can even add the deployed instances to an existing Elastic Load Balancer at deploy time. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll run through the basics to get up and running and deploy your first highly available (multiple Availability Zone, load balanced) blueprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="preparing-aws-for-use-as-a-vra-endpoint"&gt;Preparing AWS for use as a vRA endpoint &lt;a class="anchor" href="#preparing-aws-for-use-as-a-vra-endpoint"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are some obvious pre-requisites for attaching an AWS endpoint - for example, you need to have a VPC configured. There are plenty of resources out there for creating a VPC, so I won&amp;rsquo;t extend this post by replicating them. This is what I&amp;rsquo;m using:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Adding a vCloud Air (PAYG/Gen2) instance to vRealize Orchestrator as a vCloud Director host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 13:26:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Big thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pipoe2h" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Jose Luis Gomez
&lt;/a&gt; for this solution, his response to my tweet was spot on and invaluable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to configure vCloud Air as a vCloud Director host in vRealize Orchestrator in order to create some custom resource actions for Day 2 operations in vRealize Automation. What I found was that there&amp;rsquo;s *very* little information out there on how to do this, and I ended up writing my own custom resource mapping for the virtual machines to VCAC:VirtualMachine objects - at least that way I could add my resource action. But this still didn&amp;rsquo;t expose the vCloud Director functionality for those machines. To do this I needed vCloud Air added as a vCloud Director host.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>MindMap: vRealize Automation Roles</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/mindmap-vrealize-automation-roles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 20:45:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/mindmap-vrealize-automation-roles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I use mind maps quite a lot for study, I find the visual representation of info makes it a lot easier for me to remember! Below is a mind map I created for learning the roles in vRealize Automation, which I used during my presentation for #vBrownBag on VCP6-CMA objective 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download a PDF version here: &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vRealize Automation Roles Mind Map&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building a vRealize Automation NSX Lab on Ravello</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/building-a-vrealize-automation-nsx-lab-on-ravello/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 17:06:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/building-a-vrealize-automation-nsx-lab-on-ravello/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/09/image_thumb22.png" alt=""&gt;As a vExpert, I am blessed to get 1000 CPU hours access to Ravello&amp;rsquo;s awesome platform and recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with the AutoLab deployments tailored for Ravello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Ravello&amp;rsquo;s offering&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; (where have you been?!) then it&amp;rsquo;s basically a custom hypervisor (HVX) running on either AWS or Google Cloud that allows you to run nested environments on those platforms. I did say it&amp;rsquo;s awesome.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation instance – Configuring NetScaler Monitors</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-instance-configuring-netscaler-monitors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 09:24:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-instance-configuring-netscaler-monitors/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter a name for the monitor, and leave the other parameters the same. Select the &amp;ldquo;Special Parameters&amp;rdquo; tab and configure the send string to the URL to monitor - e.g for the PSC SSO it&amp;rsquo;s going to be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the receive string, enter the expected response (&amp;ldquo;GREEN&amp;rdquo;). Click Create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/08/image_thumb40.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="assigning-a-netscaler-monitor-to-a-service"&gt;Assigning a NetScaler Monitor to a Service &lt;a class="anchor" href="#assigning-a-netscaler-monitor-to-a-service"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assign the monitor to the PSC Services (or Service Groups) configured for PSC by opening the Configuration &amp;gt; Traffic Management &amp;gt; Load Balancing &amp;gt; Services page and selecting the PSC service for HTTPS/443 and clicking Edit.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components – Part 2: Database, Web and Manager services</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-2-database-web-and-manager-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:40:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-2-database-web-and-manager-services/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png" alt=""&gt;Now that the prerequisites for the IaaS layer have been completed, it&amp;rsquo;s time to move on to the actual installation of the IaaS components, starting with the database. We then move onto the first Web server, which also imports the ModelManagerData configuration to the database, populating the database with all of the info the IaaS layer needs out of the box. We then install the second Web server before moving on to the active Manager server. The second Manager server is passive and the service should be disabled - I&amp;rsquo;ll cover installing DEM Orchestrators, Workers and the vSphere Agents in the next article.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components – Part 1: Pre-requisites</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-1-pre-requisites/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:15:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-1-pre-requisites/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One of the trickiest parts of deploying vRealize Automation is the IaaS layer - people sometimes look at me like I&amp;rsquo;m a crazy person when I say that, normally because they&amp;rsquo;ve deployed a PoC or small deployment with just a single IaaS server. Add in 5 more servers, some load balancers, certificates, a distributed setup and MSDTC to the mix and you have a huge potential for pain!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation Infrastructure Tab displays incorrect labels</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vrealize-automation-infrastructure-tab-displays-incorrect-labels/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 08:24:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vrealize-automation-infrastructure-tab-displays-incorrect-labels/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png" alt=""&gt;Having just completed a particularly problem-prone distributed IaaS install, this was almost the straw that broke the camel&amp;rsquo;s back. Logging into vRealize Automation for the first time as an Infrastructure Admin displayed the infrastructure tab and all menu labels as big ugly references, and no functionality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:%7bcom.cmware.cap.component.iaas.proxy.provider@csp.places.iaas.label"&gt;
 {com.cmware.cap.component.iaas.proxy.provider@csp.places.iaas.label
&lt;/a&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/clip_image002_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebooting the IaaS web servers restored the functionality of the IaaS layer but still did not fix the label issue, it took a further reboot of both vRealize Automation appliances, then the IaaS web servers to finally view the correct labels.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying vRealize Automation 6.2 Appliance Cluster with Postgres Replication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 19:57:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The recommendations for the vRealize Appliance have changed with 6.2, the published reference architecture now does not recommend using an external Postgres database (either vPostgres appliance, a 3rd party Postgres deployment or using a third vRealize Appliance as a stand-alone database installation). Instead the recommended layout is shown in the diagram below. One instance of postgres on the primary node becomes an active instance, replicating to the second node which is passive. In front of these a load balancer or DNS entry points to the active node only. Fail-over is still a manual task, but it does provide better protection than a single instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation (vRA) Manager Service error</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-automation-vra-manager-service-error/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 10:07:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-automation-vra-manager-service-error/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently when do a fresh install of vRealize Automation (vRA) 6.2 I came across the following error after configuring the first end point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Error log example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/01/msdtc-error.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DataBaseStatsService: ignoring exception: Error executing query usp_SelectAgent Inner Exception: Error executing query usp_SelectAgentCapabilities&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all I checked to see if the end points were working which in this case they appeared to be, but I wanted to clear the error before continuing the install.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>