<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vra7 on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vra7/</link><description>Recent content in vra7 on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 15:28:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vra7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vRA7.2 and vSphere Integrated Containers</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vra7-2-and-vsphere-integrated-containers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 15:28:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vra7-2-and-vsphere-integrated-containers/</guid><description>One of the cool new features released with vRealize Automation 7.2 was the integration of VMware Admiral (container management) into the product, and recently VMware made version 1 of vSphere Integrated Containers generally available (GA), so I thought it was time I started playing around with the two.
In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover deploying VIC to my vSphere environment and then adding that host to the vRA 7.2 container management.</description></item><item><title>Deploying to AWS with Software Components on vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/deploying-to-aws-with-software-components-on-vrealize-automation-7/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 17:09:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/deploying-to-aws-with-software-components-on-vrealize-automation-7/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on some ideas in my lab to leverage the AWS endpoint on vRealize Automation. One of the things I needed to get working was getting Software Components working on my AWS deployed instances.
The diagram to the right shows my end-stage network - the instance deployed by vRA into AWS should be in a private subnet in my VPC, and should use my local lab DNS server and be able to access my vRA instance.</description></item><item><title>What’s in my vRA7 EBS Payloads?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/whats-in-my-vra7-ebs-payloads/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 15:52:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/whats-in-my-vra7-ebs-payloads/</guid><description>&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-6186&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;vRA&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; - a properties object.
I wanted to create a workflow that I could enable to log all of the keys, values and types of the properties object for each stage of the vRA7 MachineProvisioning workflows, and create a reference for myself on the payload for each stage.
To do this I created a new workflow &amp;ldquo;debugProperties&amp;rdquo; and added an input variable called &amp;ldquo;payload&amp;rdquo;, type Properties.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7 Custom Hostname with Event Broker (EB) Subscription</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-custom-hostname-with-event-broker-eb-subscription/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 17:54:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-custom-hostname-with-event-broker-eb-subscription/</guid><description>The new Event Broker service in vRA7 is one of the most exciting features of this latest release, the possibilities for extensibility are huge. At this point it time you can still use the old method of using workflow stubs to customise machine lifecycle events, but at some point in the future this will be deprecated and the Event Broker will be the only way to extend.
With this in mind, I wanted to use the Event Broker to do something that I am asked on almost every customer engagement - custom hostnames beyond what the Machine Prefixes mechanism can do.</description></item></channel></rss>