<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>health check on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/health-check/</link><description>Recent content in health check on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 13:57:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/health-check/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SCOM 2007 R2: Daily Health Check Script v2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/05/scom-2007-r2-daily-health-check-script-v2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 13:57:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/05/scom-2007-r2-daily-health-check-script-v2/</guid><description>A couple of months ago I posted the first version of my SCOM 2007 R2 Daily Health Check Script - here is version 2. It&amp;rsquo;s more than a little motivated by some friendly competition with a Microsoft PFE for SCOM, hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ll agree it&amp;rsquo;s a big improvement on the last version.
Updated for this version
Formatting changed to make it more readable and more compatible Added &amp;ldquo;Report generated on &amp;rdquo; to the top of the report Management Server states reported as one section Default MP check moved to beneath the Management servers Agents in pending states moved to be with the Agent health states Clarified &amp;ldquo;Unresponsive Agents&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Agents reporting errors&amp;rdquo; Management server alerts streamlined Added top 10 alerts for the last 7 days, and added top alerters for each I&amp;rsquo;m planning to wrap in some SQL database size checks and some of the other recommendations later - I&amp;rsquo;ll post again here when that&amp;rsquo;s ready 🙂</description></item><item><title>SCOM 2007 R2: Daily Health Check Script</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/01/scom-2007-r2-daily-health-check-script/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 16:59:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/01/scom-2007-r2-daily-health-check-script/</guid><description>An updated version of this script has been released: https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/05/scom-2007-r2-daily-health-check-script-v2/
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with a Microsft SCOM PFE (Premier Field Engineer) for the last few months and part of the engagement is an environment health check for the SCOM setup. Based on this Microsoft recommend a series of health checks to for the environment that should be carried out every day. This is summarised as the following:
Check the health of all Management Servers and Gateways Check the RMS is not in maintenance mode Review Outstanding Alerts Review Agent&amp;rsquo;s Health Status Review Backup Status Review any Management Group Alerts Review the Pending Management status Review Database Sizes (Operations, Data warehouse, ACS) Review Volume of Alerts Review Alert Latency Document any changes  From this, there are certain aspects that can&amp;rsquo;t be automated so easily, or shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be - e.</description></item></channel></rss>