<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>What's new on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/whats-new/</link><description>Recent content in What's new on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/whats-new/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vRealize Operations 8.4 - What's New</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/04/vrealize-operations-8.4-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/04/vrealize-operations-8.4-whats-new/</guid><description>There has been some really exciting things being announced/relased by VMware and their respective product teams recently so lets take a look at all the new goodness in vRealize Operations 8.4
vRealize Operations 8.4 vRealize Operations 8.4 delivers new and enhanced capabilities for self-driving operations to help customers optimize, plan, and scale VMware Cloud, which includes on-premises private cloud or VMware SDDC in multiple public clouds such as VMware Cloud on AWS, Azure VMware Solution (AVS), and Google Cloud VMware Engine (GCVE), while at the same time unifying multi-cloud monitoring, and supporting AWS, Azure Cloud, and Google Cloud platforms.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Operations 8.1 - What's New</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vrealize-operations-8.1-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vrealize-operations-8.1-whats-new/</guid><description>VMware have been very busy in the last few months across many of their products and Operations Management has not gone untouched. We saw glimpses of things to come late last year and now we see the Cloud Management Team in VMware really ramping things up with vRealize Operation 8.1
vRealize Operations Cloud One of the bigger items to arrive very shortly is vRealize Operations Cloud (SaaS), this means you do not need to worry about standing vROps up in your environment to see what value it can bring to your infrastructure monitoring.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Operations 8.1 - What's New</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vrealize-operations-8.1-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vrealize-operations-8.1-whats-new/</guid><description>VMware have been very busy in the last few months across many of their products and Operations Management has not gone untouched. We saw glimpses of things to come late last year and now we see the Cloud Management Team in VMware really ramping things up with vRealize Operation 8.1
vRealize Operations Cloud One of the bigger items to arrive very shortly is vRealize Operations Cloud (SaaS), this means you do not need to worry about standing vROps up in your environment to see what value it can bring to your infrastructure monitoring.</description></item><item><title> #vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 3 – What’s New with vROps 6.6</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 06:52:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</guid><description>[vRealize Operations Manager 6.6, which was recently released by VMware.
We started with an overview of all the cool new stuff and then drill down into individual areas. We then jumped into a Live Demo as usual to see the new features in action.
We would highly appreciate if you could spend 30 seconds to fill up this quick and simple survey to provide us your feedback. You can also request topics of your choice through this survey.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2017 – Announcing Part 3 : What’s New with #vROps 6.6</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-2017-announcing-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 07:13:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-2017-announcing-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</guid><description>Welcome to the next episode of vRealize Operations Manager Webinar Series. This time around we will talk about the latest release of vROps released in the month of June.
With this release, VMware has made drastic changes to the product and the initial reviews of the product have been great. Since I was a part of the team delivering this new release, I thought it would be a good topic to discuss in the next episode of the Webinar Series.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 1 – What’s New with vROps 6.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-with-vrops-6-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 09:02:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-with-vrops-6-5/</guid><description>Time to share the recording of the first episode of the vROps Webinar Series 2017. This time around, Sunny and I spoke about the latest release of vRealize Operations Manager. We spoke about almost all the new features which were introduced with this version and went into some of them in detail. Like always we rounded up the session with Live Demo of the new features for our audiences.
We introduced a feedback form which can be used to provide your feedback in general and also request topics on which you would want us to focus this year.</description></item><item><title>Announcing #vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 1 – What’s new in 6.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/announcing-vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-in-6-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:58:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/announcing-vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-in-6-5/</guid><description>Welcome to the vRealize Operations Manager Webinar Series 2017. With the huge success of the series back in 2016, we wanted to take a break, enjoy the success and come back with full rigor for this series in 2017. We are here and we are charged up to give you some more dope on vRealize Operations manager in the year 2017.
The delivery mechanism would be same as last year. We will start with talking about a topic and then jump into a live environment to see what happens when the rubber hits the road…</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Part 12 : What’s New with vROps 6.4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 12:02:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</guid><description>Time to publish the recording for the 12th episode of the vROps Webinar Series. This time we did a what’s new with vRealize Operations 6.4 and the changes made to vRealize Operations 6.4as you will see there has been a lot packed into this recent release!
It has been an awesome 12 months working with Sunny on this project and I am very glad to say we will be back next year (we will skip January and will return in February).</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 12 : What’s New with vROps 6.4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 08:36:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s the time of the month when I would like to invite you to join the next episode of our year long vROps Webinar Series. As we move towards the closure of a fantastic year, we would like to take a zoom out view at the vRealize Operations Manager solution with a What&amp;rsquo;s New Episode. We did a What&amp;rsquo;s new with vRealize Operations 6.3 a couple of months back, however looking at some awesome changes made to vRealize Operations 6.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 9 : What’s New with vRealize Operations Manager 6.3</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/09/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-manager-6-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 12:42:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/09/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-manager-6-3/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s the time of the month when we invite you to join the next episode of our year long vROps Webinar Series. As we move towards winter, we would like to take a zoom out view at the vRealize Operations Manager solution with a What&amp;rsquo;s New Episode. For the past 8 months, we have give pretty deep into most of the product features and we believe it is time when we review the product in it&amp;rsquo;s current form and shape.</description></item><item><title>Whats new in #vROps 6.3 part 2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 21:16:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3-part-2/</guid><description>In this post I will drill down to look at some of the enhancements, improvements and or new additions one by one.
New Home Dashboard - as you can see this is a very useful and helpful way or presenting a high level set of data about your environment with also many ways to interact and interrogate the data you are being presented with. Among other items you can filter on (Health/Risk/Efficiency), alter the scope, see alerts relative to the objects you are interested in.</description></item><item><title>Whats new in #vROps 6.3</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 16:40:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3/</guid><description>So the latest release of vROps has some cool new things and at a very high level below are the key stand out improvements and changes.
I will do a more deep dive in the next few days.
You can get the release notes here.
You can download it here.
New home dashboard Improved WLP and DRS integration Improved Workload Dashboard Wizard now available for policy creation or amendment Improved visibility of Data collection status Many new Hardening policies (6.</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.2 what&amp;rsquo;s new?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-6-2-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 07:25:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-6-2-whats-new/</guid><description>vRealize Operations 6.2 was released last night and is now available for download!
Looking at what’s new very quickly there are some good new enhancements but when you compare this to the 6.1 release it’s perhaps a little light, nevertheless there appears to be some new cool features and enhancements to be had in this version.
There does not appear to be any sizing/scale increases.
Upgrading from existing 6.1 versions can be done via a .</description></item><item><title>vSphere 5.5 – what I like from what’s new..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vsphere-5-5-what-i-like-from-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 16:17:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vsphere-5-5-what-i-like-from-whats-new/</guid><description>With vSphere 5.5 being announced at VMworld San Francisco I was very eager to see what was new and after devouring all of the great blog posts out there of the guys in attendance I wanted to summarize in my own way the aspects I think are great!
**VMDK 2TB limitation removed! (also virtual mode RDMs) ** This has to be one of the best pieces of news as it has been in the rear trying to accommodate really large VMs (changes affect both VMFS and NFS)</description></item></channel></rss>