<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>load balancer on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/load-balancer/</link><description>Recent content in load balancer on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 09:24:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/load-balancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation instance – Configuring NetScaler Monitors</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-instance-configuring-netscaler-monitors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 09:24:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-instance-configuring-netscaler-monitors/</guid><description>Enter a name for the monitor, and leave the other parameters the same. Select the &amp;ldquo;Special Parameters&amp;rdquo; tab and configure the send string to the URL to monitor - e.g for the PSC SSO it&amp;rsquo;s going to be:
GET /websso/HealthStatus For the receive string, enter the expected response (&amp;ldquo;GREEN&amp;rdquo;). Click Create.
Assigning a NetScaler Monitor to a Service Assign the monitor to the PSC Services (or Service Groups) configured for PSC by opening the Configuration &amp;gt; Traffic Management &amp;gt; Load Balancing &amp;gt; Services page and selecting the PSC service for HTTPS/443 and clicking Edit.</description></item><item><title>Deploying vRealize Automation 6.2 Appliance Cluster with Postgres Replication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 19:57:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</guid><description>The recommendations for the vRealize Appliance have changed with 6.2, the published reference architecture now does not recommend using an external Postgres database (either vPostgres appliance, a 3rd party Postgres deployment or using a third vRealize Appliance as a stand-alone database installation). Instead the recommended layout is shown in the diagram below. One instance of postgres on the primary node becomes an active instance, replicating to the second node which is passive.</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 HA SSO (PSC) with NetScaler VPX Load Balancer for vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 15:40:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>vSphere 6 HA SSO (PSC) with NetScaler VPX Load Balancer for vRealize Automation Deploying vRealize Automation 6.2 Appliance Cluster with Postgres Replication Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components - Part 1: Pre-requisites Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components - Part 2: Database, Web and Manager services Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation instance - Configuring NetScaler Monitors Providing a highly available single sign on for vRealize Automation is a fundamental part of ensuring the availability of the platform.</description></item><item><title>Creating a vRealize Log Insight 2.5 cluster with Integrated Load Balancing</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/02/creating-a-vrealize-log-insight-2-5-cluster-with-integrated-load-balancing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 15:36:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/02/creating-a-vrealize-log-insight-2-5-cluster-with-integrated-load-balancing/</guid><description>vRealize Log Insight 2.5 improves on the clustering in previous versions with an Integrated Load Balancer (ILB) which allows you to distribute load across your cluster of Log Insight instances without actually needing an external load balancer. The advantage of this over an external load balancer is that the source IP is maintained which allows for easier analysis.
The minimum number of nodes in a cluster is three, the first node becomes the Master node and the other two become Worker nodes.</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.1 build out to distributed model: Clustered vCAC Appliances</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/vcac-6-1-build-out-to-distributed-model-clustered-vcac-appliances/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 10:56:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/vcac-6-1-build-out-to-distributed-model-clustered-vcac-appliances/</guid><description>With the release of vCAC 6.1 there have been some great improvements in the setup of the clustered vCAC appliances - none of the previous copying of configuration files between appliances - just a simple wizard to do it all for you. In my opinion this is superb.
You&amp;rsquo;ll need to have deployed a load balancer of some sort - vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model – Part 3.1: Configure Load Balancing with vCNS or vCAC 6.</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 3.2: Configure load balancing with NSX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-2-configure-load-balancing-with-nsx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-2-configure-load-balancing-with-nsx/</guid><description>This is the second part of the 3rd article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
By the end of this part, we will not have modified the vCAC deployment in any way, we’ll just have 3 configured load balanced URLs
vCAC Simple Install with vPostgres deployed and load balancers prepared An overview of the steps required are below:
Issue and install certificates Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database Configure load balancing Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering Install and configure additional IaaS server Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster I’ve previously configured 3 DNS records for the load balanced services (see part 3.</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 3.1: Configure Load Balancing with vCNS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 08:53:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</guid><description>This is the first part of the 3rd article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
By the end of this part, we will not have modified the vCAC deployment in any way, we’ll just have 3 configured load balanced URLs
vCAC simple configuration with vPostgres and Load Balancers prepared An overview of the steps required are below:
Issue and install certificates Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database Configure load balancing Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering Install and configure additional IaaS server Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster Deploy a vShield Edge appliance Log in to your vShield Manager and select your Datacenter, then the Network Virtualisation tab</description></item></channel></rss>