<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMworld 2014 on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/series/vmworld-2014/</link><description>Recent content in VMworld 2014 on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 09:05:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/series/vmworld-2014/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMworld 2014: Day Three and wrap-up</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-three-and-wrap-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 09:05:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-three-and-wrap-up/</guid><description>*This post was meant to be published on Friday, VMworld Sleep Deprivation meant I didn&amp;rsquo;t click the button!*
This is the last post and a bit of a wrap up on my VMworld 2014 series!
There isn&amp;rsquo;t a keynote on day three, and there&amp;rsquo;s definitely a &amp;ldquo;winding down&amp;rdquo; feel as people tend to arrive later (if at all) and many are…feeling the effects of the previous night shall we say!</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2014: Day Two</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-two/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 08:02:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-two/</guid><description>Day two of VMworld kicked off with a keynote session which traditionally includes demos of all that&amp;rsquo;s new. It was a well presented session with a glimpse into the sysadmin&amp;rsquo;s future with a demo of vCOps alerts popping up on Google glass. Since the sessions are available online I won&amp;rsquo;t go into detail, but it was worth a watch (if you didn&amp;rsquo;t watch the US one).
My morning consisted of preparations for the VCP NV (NSX) exam, which I detailed in a previous post.</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2014: VCP NV Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 11:56:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/</guid><description>It is with great relief that I can announce I have passed my VCP NV (Network Virtualisation) having been caught out by the difficulty of the exam and failing previously.
Exam Preparation I was fortunate to attend a VMware internal bootcamp (roughly equivalent to the ICM course) for NSX and have had experience deploying production NSX environments, so that is by far the best preparation. As always, the exam blueprint is crucial, you *have* to know all areas covered there.</description></item><item><title>VMWorld 2014: Day One</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-one/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 08:21:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-one/</guid><description>After a bit of a rocky start (missed my flight and the partner day due to tendonitis in my knee) I arrived in Barcelona for my 2nd VMworld Europe. I headed straight from the airport to the PernixData party and caught up with the rest of the Xtravirt guys.
Tuesday morning started as ever with a keynote address. It was a little disappointing, but not unexpected, that there were no real announcements or reveals in the keynote.</description></item></channel></rss>