<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Edge Transport on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/edge-transport/</link><description>Recent content in Edge Transport on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 21:17:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/edge-transport/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NSX-T 2.0 Lab Build: Transport Zones and Transport Nodes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/10/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-transport-zones-and-transport-nodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 21:17:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/10/nsx-t-2-0-lab-build-transport-zones-and-transport-nodes/</guid><description>Disclaimer! I am learning NSX-T, part of my learning is to deploy in my lab - if I contradict the official docs then go with the docs!
Lab Environment This NSX-T lab environment is built as a nested lab on my physical hosts. There are four physical ESXi hosts, onto which I will deploy three ESXi VMs, a vCenter Server Appliance, NSX Manager, an NSX Controller cluster, and two NSX Edge Nodes.</description></item><item><title>Installing Exchange 2010 Edge Server with Forefront Protection for Exchange (FPE) and Threat Management Gateway (TMG) – Part 1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/08/installing-exchange-2010-edge-server-with-forefront-protection-for-exchange-fpe-and-threat-management-gateway-tmg-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 13:59:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/08/installing-exchange-2010-edge-server-with-forefront-protection-for-exchange-fpe-and-threat-management-gateway-tmg-part-1/</guid><description>I am mid-migration, in a co-existence setup with Exchange 2010, 2007 and 2003. So far the roles installed for Exchange 2010 are CAS, Hub and Mailbox on a single server. Into this mix I need to introduce an Edge Server, with message hygiene in the form of Forefront Protection for Exchange (FPE) and Threat Management Gateway (TMG) as a reverse proxy to publish OWA, ActiveSync et-al.
Since Edge, FPE and TMG can now all exist on a single 64-bit server, I will start with a clean installation of Windows Server 2008 R2, up to date with all the latest hot fixes.</description></item></channel></rss>