<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware ESX 3.5 on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vmware-esx-3.5/</link><description>Recent content in VMware ESX 3.5 on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 15:54:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vmware-esx-3.5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMware vSphere – DRS only shows one host in cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/05/vmware-vsphere-drs-only-shows-one-host-in-cluster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 15:54:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/05/vmware-vsphere-drs-only-shows-one-host-in-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I rebuilt an ESX host in my HA/DRS cluster today, following my build procedure to configure as per VMware best practices and internal guidelines. When the host was fully configured and up-to-date, I added it to the cluster and enabled HA and DRS. Then I went to generate some DRS recommendations to balance the load an ease off my overstretched host, but no recommendations were made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t manually migrate any VMs either – it was odd, because both hosts were added into the cluster, and could ping and vmkping each other from the console.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The requested Storage VMotion would move a virtual machine’s disks without assigning the virtual machine a new home, but such a move is not supported on the source host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/10/the-requested-storage-vmotion-would-move-a-virtual-machines-disks-without-assigning-the-virtual-machine-a-new-home-but-such-a-move-is-not-supported-on-the-source-host/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 14:04:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/10/the-requested-storage-vmotion-would-move-a-virtual-machines-disks-without-assigning-the-virtual-machine-a-new-home-but-such-a-move-is-not-supported-on-the-source-host/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m migrating some hosts off of an older storage LUN, but when I drag the disk to the new Datastore with the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;SVMotion plug-in&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; the job fails with the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The error occurs because the virtual disk cannot be moved without moving the source files, the .vmx, .vswap etc. Simply drag the entire VM, rather than the virtual disk to the new Datastore.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ESX 3.5 snapshots of disks on different storage are stored with the VM files</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/10/esx-3-5-snapshots-of-disks-on-different-storage-are-stored-with-the-vm-files/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2009 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/10/esx-3-5-snapshots-of-disks-on-different-storage-are-stored-with-the-vm-files/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="aka-why-not-to-use-snapshots"&gt;A.K.A Why not to use snapshots &lt;a class="anchor" href="#aka-why-not-to-use-snapshots"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I ran into a slightly confusing problem today - our SQL servers are all created with 4 disks on 4 separate LUNs (System, Swap, SQL Data and SQL Logs). When viewing the server through Virtual Center I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see all of the LUNs, just the System LUN. It&amp;rsquo;s not a major problem as the VM can see the storage, but a little annoying when you have to remember what LUN the disks are on.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Teaming NICs with ESX 3.5 and Cisco Switches in an aggregate.</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/teaming-nics-with-esx-3-5-and-cisco-switches-in-an-aggregate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/teaming-nics-with-esx-3-5-and-cisco-switches-in-an-aggregate/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the setup. We have a core switch of 2 Cisco 3750s, connected together for fault tolerance as a single logical switch; we also have several ESX 3.5 hosts with 4 Gigabit Ethernet NICs installed each. The Virtual Machines will all be on VLAN 8 (reserved for internal servers) and the VMKernel will be on VLAN 107 (reserved for VMKernel traffic like VMotion).  I want to create a load balanced, fault tolerant aggregate of these four NICs over the Core Switch.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>