<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Networking on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/networking/</link><description>Recent content in Networking on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 13:31:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to NSX APIs – vBrownBag</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/11/introduction-to-nsx-apis-vbrownbag/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 13:31:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/11/introduction-to-nsx-apis-vbrownbag/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday I had the privilege of presenting an introduction to the NSX APIs on vBrownBag EMEA - you can view the recording below or on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCaZf13iWhwnBdpIkrEmHLbA" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; vBrownBag&amp;rsquo;s youtube channel.
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the presentation I showed a mind map of the API, which I&amp;rsquo;ve made&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sammcgeown/vBrownBagNSXAPI/blob/master/vBrownbag%20Introduction%20to%20NSX%20API.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; available on GitHub in PDF format
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/11/2017-11-24_13-22-20.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also published the &lt;a href="https://github.com/sammcgeown/vBrownBagNSXAPI" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Postman collection and environment
&lt;/a&gt; I used during the demonstration, which covers some basic configuration and deploy tasks:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 HA SSO (PSC) with NetScaler VPX Load Balancer for vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 15:40:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Providing a highly available single sign on for vRealize Automation is a fundamental part of ensuring the availability of the platform. Traditionally, (vCAC) vRA uses the Identity Appliance and relies on vSphere HA to provide the availability of the SSO platform, but in a fully distributed HA environment that&amp;rsquo;s not really good enough. It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to use the vSphere 5.5 SSO install in a HA configuration - however, many companies are making the move to the latest version of vSphere and don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to maintain a 5.5 HA SSO instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.1 – Creating a user selectable network dropdown that sets Network and Network Profile correctly</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vcac-6-1-creating-a-user-selectable-network-dropdown-that-sets-network-and-network-profile-correctly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 11:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vcac-6-1-creating-a-user-selectable-network-dropdown-that-sets-network-and-network-profile-correctly/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I am aware that that&amp;rsquo;s not a catchy blog post title. In fact, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even really describe the problem or solution very well - for that I need to go into a little bit more depth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose I have configured a Reservation with two Networks ticked (&amp;ldquo;192.168.1.0-VLAN1&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;192.168.10.0-VLAN10&amp;rdquo;). As you can see in the screenshot below, each of the networks has a Network Profile created and assigned with a network pool to provide IP addressing for the VMs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Book review: Networking for VMware Administrators</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/book-review-networking-for-vmware-administrators/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 09:34:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/book-review-networking-for-vmware-administrators/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I recently got my hands on a copy* of Chris Wahl and Steve Pantol’s Networking for VMware Administrators and was very keen to read it – especially given the reputation of the authors. I came to the book as someone who is at CCNA level (although now expired) and someone who regularly designs complex VMware networks using standard and distributed switches. I would class myself as having a fairly decent understanding of networking, though not a networking specialist.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMworld Europe 2013 &amp;ndash; Day 2, VCAP5-DCD Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-day-2-vcap5-dcd-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 15:45:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-day-2-vcap5-dcd-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Today was always going to be a bit of a funny day as I scheduled the VCAP5-DCD exam for 10am this morning. I am happy to say that I passed! I’m a bit light on VMworld to report today, so forgive my DCD experience to pad it out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id="preparation"&gt;Preparation &lt;a class="anchor" href="#preparation"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I have to confess my prep for this exam was light – I literally only watched the TrainSignal course by Scott Lowe (@scott_lowe) and just about finished that last night in the hotel! I don’t spend much time focussing on design during my day job, so I approached this exam as a bit of a learning experience rather than a serious bid to pass. I decided to book the exam here at VMworld just because you can get 75% off – if you’re funding yourself it’s not a discount to be dismissed easily!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Host disk write latency errors – troubleshooting – part 2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/03/host-disk-write-latency-errors-troubleshooting-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 13:23:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/03/host-disk-write-latency-errors-troubleshooting-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As some of you read previously, I had been experiencing disk latency issues on our SAN and tried many initial methods to troubleshoot and understand the root cause. Due to other more pressing issues this was placed aside until we started to experience VMs being occasionaly restarted by vSphere HA as the lock had been lost on a given VMDK file. (NOT GOOD!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Environment:-&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Configuring Server 2008 R2 Core Series: Network Settings</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-network-settings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 14:22:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-network-settings/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So, you’ve installed a new server with Server 2008 R2 Core – what next? Logging on, you’re presented with a shiny command prompt, you can run notepad or regedit…but aside from that, where do you go from there? In the next few series of posts I’ll hopefully point out the basics, and some not so basics!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="using-the-server-configuration-tool"&gt;Using the Server Configuration Tool &lt;a class="anchor" href="#using-the-server-configuration-tool"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The server configuration tool (sconfig.cmd) is provided in R2 for some of the basic setup tasks, so you can run that by issuing the “sconfig” command. Out of the box, it looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Trace cables the easy way with Cisco CDP on Windows</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/trace-cables-the-easy-way-with-cisco-cdp-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 11:58:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/trace-cables-the-easy-way-with-cisco-cdp-on-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;No matter how good your network diagrams are, sometimes you need to verify the port your server/desktop is in. Cisco Discovery Protocol is a great tool for network admins when you need to quickly map routers and switches, and if you’ve got an ESX server connected you’ll see that it picks up CDP info too – but the vast majority of my managed systems are Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how to use &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;TCPDUMP by Micro Olap&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; to extend that functionality to your Windows boxes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Teaming NICs with ESX 3.5 and Cisco Switches in an aggregate.</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/teaming-nics-with-esx-3-5-and-cisco-switches-in-an-aggregate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/teaming-nics-with-esx-3-5-and-cisco-switches-in-an-aggregate/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the setup. We have a core switch of 2 Cisco 3750s, connected together for fault tolerance as a single logical switch; we also have several ESX 3.5 hosts with 4 Gigabit Ethernet NICs installed each. The Virtual Machines will all be on VLAN 8 (reserved for internal servers) and the VMKernel will be on VLAN 107 (reserved for VMKernel traffic like VMotion).  I want to create a load balanced, fault tolerant aggregate of these four NICs over the Core Switch.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>DCDIAG /TEST:DNS fails with errors regarding root hint servers</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/dcdiag-testdns-fails-with-errors-regarding-root-hint-servers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 16:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/dcdiag-testdns-fails-with-errors-regarding-root-hint-servers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently resolved an ongoing DNS issue where the Active Directory Integrated DNS was loaded in both the Domain and the DomainDNSZones partition of AD - this is a separate issue and should be resolved differently. My problem when I tried to verify that the fixed DNS setup had propogated around my domain controllers, DC01 and DC02. DC01 kept failing &amp;ldquo;DCDIAG /TEST:DNS&amp;rdquo; with errors regarding the root hint servers. Googling about it was clear that a lot of people were suffering the same issue, but no article I read had correctly identified the solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Multi-homed Domain controller logs Event ID 1030 and 1058</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/multi-homed-domain-controller-logs-event-id-1030-and-1058/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/multi-homed-domain-controller-logs-event-id-1030-and-1058/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had an issue where a hosting environment was registering a lot of Netlogon Event 1030/1058 issues, being unable to find the Group Policy objects or download them. In this example, the server DC is the domain controller for DOMAIN.LCL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_Event Type: Error&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event Source: Userenv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event Category: None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event ID: 1030&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date:  10/09/2009&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time:  06:24:29&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User:  NT AUTHORITY\SYSTEM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer: DC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows cannot query for the list of Group Policy objects. Check the event log for possible messages previously logged by the policy engine that describes the reason for this. For more information, see Help and Support Center at_ &lt;a href="http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/events.asp" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; &lt;em&gt;http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/events.asp&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Windows Vista Local Area Network Connection “Authentication Failed”</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/01/windows-vista-local-area-network-connection-%E2%80%9Cauthentication-failed%E2%80%9D/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 13:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/01/windows-vista-local-area-network-connection-%E2%80%9Cauthentication-failed%E2%80%9D/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re getting a error on your LAN connection it’s possible that your network connection is attempting 802.11 authentication on your wired network. Unfortunately, it seems that Vista/Server 2008 both attempt it before reverting. As far as I can see, it’s not causing any issues, other than irritating me with a “failed” and a red question mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cisco ASA – ASDM “cannot load configuration”</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/11/cisco-asa-asdm-cannot-load-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2008 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/11/cisco-asa-asdm-cannot-load-configuration/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was configuring our new Cisco ASA 5510 firewall today, as part of a major infrastructure upgrade. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty comfortable with the Cisco IOS, but I still prefer the GUI for the basic set up, using command line to tweak the finer or more complex configurations. However, straight out of the box, I had a very hard time getting the ASDM to load. Being familiar with the PDM from the PIX range of firewalls, I should have guessed the problem straight away. Essentially, whatever problem you&amp;rsquo;re having with the ASDM, whether it&amp;rsquo;s not loading, not reading the configuration or whatever, the answer is likely to be &amp;ldquo;uninstall your current version of Java, google java 1.4.2, install it, try again&amp;rdquo;. It was the same with the PDM, and guess what? It&amp;rsquo;s the same with the ASDM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>