<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vcac on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcac/</link><description>Recent content in vcac on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 11:52:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vCAC 6.1 – Creating a user selectable network dropdown that sets Network and Network Profile correctly</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vcac-6-1-creating-a-user-selectable-network-dropdown-that-sets-network-and-network-profile-correctly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 11:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vcac-6-1-creating-a-user-selectable-network-dropdown-that-sets-network-and-network-profile-correctly/</guid><description>I am aware that that&amp;rsquo;s not a catchy blog post title. In fact, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even really describe the problem or solution very well - for that I need to go into a little bit more depth!
Suppose I have configured a Reservation with two Networks ticked (&amp;ldquo;192.168.1.0-VLAN1&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;192.168.10.0-VLAN10&amp;rdquo;). As you can see in the screenshot below, each of the networks has a Network Profile created and assigned with a network pool to provide IP addressing for the VMs.</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.1 build out to distributed model: Clustered vCAC Appliances</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/vcac-6-1-build-out-to-distributed-model-clustered-vcac-appliances/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 10:56:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/vcac-6-1-build-out-to-distributed-model-clustered-vcac-appliances/</guid><description>With the release of vCAC 6.1 there have been some great improvements in the setup of the clustered vCAC appliances - none of the previous copying of configuration files between appliances - just a simple wizard to do it all for you. In my opinion this is superb.
You&amp;rsquo;ll need to have deployed a load balancer of some sort - vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model – Part 3.1: Configure Load Balancing with vCNS or vCAC 6.</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0/6.1 build out to distributed model: Deploy the Identity Appliance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/vcac-6-06-1-build-out-to-distributed-model-deploy-the-identity-appliance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 14:55:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/vcac-6-06-1-build-out-to-distributed-model-deploy-the-identity-appliance/</guid><description>SSO is a fundamental requirement when deploying vCAC, whether for a distributed or simple installation. This walk through goes through the deployment and configuration of the vCAC Identity Appliance, which provides a stand alone SSO instance for vCAC.
Some of the posts in this series are completed with vCAC 6.0.1, others will be with 6.1. Where there are differences I will aim to point them out!
Deploying the OVF Deploying the OVF is very simple, just run through the wizard:</description></item><item><title>HTTP Error 500 installing vCAC IaaS Model Manager Data</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/http-error-500-installing-vcac-iaas-model-manager-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 16:16:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/http-error-500-installing-vcac-iaas-model-manager-data/</guid><description>This was a fun little error, whilst installing the distributed IaaS roles I couldn’t seem to get the IaaS components to install – when I got the Website and Model Manager Data install it would fail with the following message:
##InitializeRepo Registering solution user in the VA, initializing Repository MetaModel and Authorization "C:\Program Files (x86)\VMware\vCAC\Server\Model Manager Data\Cafe\Vcac-Config.exe" RegisterSolutionUser -url https://vcloud.definit.local --Tenant "vsphere.local" -cu "administrator@vsphere.local" -cp ****** --FileName "C:\Program Files (x86)\VMware\vCAC\Server\Model Manager Data\Cafe\Vcac-Config.</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 4: Deploying and clustering a secondary vCAC Appliance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-4-deploying-and-clustering-a-secondary-vcac-appliance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 10:54:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-4-deploying-and-clustering-a-secondary-vcac-appliance/</guid><description>This is the fourth article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
By the end of this post we will have deployed a second vCAC Appliance, clustered it with the first appliance and registered the load balanced URL with the Identity Appliance. This will mean logging on to https://vcloud.definit.local/shell-ui-app will be successful.
vCAC deployment with clustered and load balanced vCAC Appliances An overview of the steps required are below:</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 3.2: Configure load balancing with NSX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-2-configure-load-balancing-with-nsx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-2-configure-load-balancing-with-nsx/</guid><description>This is the second part of the 3rd article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
By the end of this part, we will not have modified the vCAC deployment in any way, we’ll just have 3 configured load balanced URLs
vCAC Simple Install with vPostgres deployed and load balancers prepared An overview of the steps required are below:
Issue and install certificates Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database Configure load balancing Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering Install and configure additional IaaS server Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster I’ve previously configured 3 DNS records for the load balanced services (see part 3.</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 3.1: Configure Load Balancing with vCNS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 08:53:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</guid><description>This is the first part of the 3rd article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
By the end of this part, we will not have modified the vCAC deployment in any way, we’ll just have 3 configured load balanced URLs
vCAC simple configuration with vPostgres and Load Balancers prepared An overview of the steps required are below:
Issue and install certificates Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database Configure load balancing Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering Install and configure additional IaaS server Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster Deploy a vShield Edge appliance Log in to your vShield Manager and select your Datacenter, then the Network Virtualisation tab</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 2: vPostgres</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-2-vpostgres/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 09:01:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-2-vpostgres/</guid><description>This is the second article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
The diagram below shows the deployment at the end of this part, with vPostgres deployed and the vCAC Appliance running from the remote database.
vCAC deploymnent with vPostgres deployed An overview of the steps required are below:
Issue and install certificates Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database Configure load balancing Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering Install and configure additional IaaS server Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster Create the required DNS records First of all, create DNS records for your vPostgres database server – you need both an A and PTR record.</description></item><item><title>VCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 1: Certificates</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-1-certificates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 11:43:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-1-certificates/</guid><description>This is the first article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
Simple vCAC deployment In a simple installation you have the Identity Appliance, the vCAC appliance (which includes a vPostgres DB and vCenter Orchestrator instance) and an IaaS server. The distributed model still has a single Identity Appliance but clusters 2 or more vCAC appliances behind a load balancer, backed by a separate vPostgres database appliance.</description></item><item><title>Another fantastic South West UK VMUG</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/another-fantastic-south-west-uk-vmug/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 09:09:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/another-fantastic-south-west-uk-vmug/</guid><description>On the 3rd of June we had our second South West UK VMUG and I am pleased to say it went superbly well.
As before we held it at the Mshed facilities in Bristol.
We had a great day with many sessions from sponsors,vendors and community speakers alike!
Big thanks go to our speakers that day who were..
Justin Rohan - @justinrohan - Nimble Storage - Sponsor James Smith - @james55smith - PernixData - Sponsor Julian Regel - @jr_on_the_cloud - Community session on vCD Adam Bohle - @adambohle - VMware - vCAC session Jonathan Medd - @jonathanmedd - Community session on PowerCLI/Automation Richard Munro - @RikMunro - VMware - vCHS Session One of the South West UK VMUG leaders Barry Coombs took a fantastic time lapse video of the day which can be viewed on his blog site.</description></item></channel></rss>