<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vRA on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vra/</link><description>Recent content in vRA on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Goodbye VMware PSO...</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/09/goodbye-vmware-pso.../</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/09/goodbye-vmware-pso.../</guid><description>Autumn seems to be a time for the winds of change to blow through our industry, and this year that&amp;rsquo;s true for me.
TL;DR - I&amp;rsquo;m leaving VMware PSO to join the Cloud Management Business Unit as a Technical Marketing Manager for Cloud Automation!
It&amp;rsquo;s been a little over two years since I joined VMware as a Senior Conusltant in the EMEA NSX Practice, and in that time I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed some great opportunities, worked with some great people and technologies.</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Foundation - Deployment Observations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/07/vmware-cloud-foundation-deployment-observations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/07/vmware-cloud-foundation-deployment-observations/</guid><description>I have been working with VMware Cloud Foundation recently and while for the most part things went well there were occasions where challenges were encountered which made the delivery to the customer all the more trickier than expected.
This article is a list of observations and things to most definitely check or watch out for when delivering a VCF project.
We were working with VCF version 3.7.2 (yes I am aware 3.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading vRA with vRLCM and JAVA versions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/upgrading-vra-with-vrlcm-and-java-versions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/upgrading-vra-with-vrlcm-and-java-versions/</guid><description>I recently upgraded an instance of vRA from 7.2 to 7.5 and rather than do it the manual way I used VMware’s vRealize LifeCycle Manager (version 2.0 update 3).
Everything was going great and according to plan, the vRLCM pre-requisites checker made short work of all of the checks you need to do before you start an upgrade of vRA. You can see below vRLCM does a great job of keeping you informed of the current progress and in a really elegant way.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Lifecycle Manager 1.2 VC data collection fails when NSX-T hostswitches are in use</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-1-2-vc-data-collection-fails-when-nsx-t-hostswitches-are-in-use/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 10:17:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrealize-lifecycle-manager-1-2-vc-data-collection-fails-when-nsx-t-hostswitches-are-in-use/</guid><description>When vRealize Lifecycle Manager 1.2 was released recently, I was keen to get it installed in my lab, since I maintain several vRealize Automation deployments for development and testing, as well as performing upgrades. With vRLCM I can reduce the administrative overhead of managing the environments, as well as easily migrate content between environments (I&amp;rsquo;ll be blogging on some of these cool new features soon).
However, I hit a snag when I began to import my existing environment - I couldn’t get the vCenter data collection to run.</description></item><item><title>Retrieve Blueprint or Virtual Machine Custom Properties using the vRealize Automation API</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/02/retrieve-blueprint-or-virtual-machine-custom-properties-using-the-vrealize-automation-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 14:11:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/02/retrieve-blueprint-or-virtual-machine-custom-properties-using-the-vrealize-automation-api/</guid><description>Just a quick post today, as I was working with a customer recently and we were trying to retrieve the Custom Properties assigned to a vRealize Automation 7.3 deployed Virtual Machine, similar to the one in the image below. It’s not as intuitive as you’d like it to be because of the split between IaaS APIs and Cafe APIs. Below you can see I’ve deployed a simple CentOS blueprint with a custom property at the Blueprint level (called “BlueprintLevel” with a value of “CustomProperty”) and a custom property at the VM level (called “CustomProperty” and a value of “Test123”).</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7.3 and NSX – Micro-segmentation strategies</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrealize-automation-7-3-and-nsx-micro-segmentation-strategies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 17:40:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrealize-automation-7-3-and-nsx-micro-segmentation-strategies/</guid><description>vRealize Automation and NSX integration has introduced the ability to deploy multi-tiered applications with network services included. The current integration also enables a method to deploy micro-segmentation out of the box, based on dynamic Security Group membership and the Service Composer. This method does have some limitations, and can be inflexible for the on-going management of deployed applications. It requires in-depth knowledge and understanding of NSX and the Distributed Firewall, as well as access to the Networking and Security manager that is hosted by vCenter Server.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2017 – Part 4 : Optimizing Workload Performance Using Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 10:17:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</guid><description>In this episode, Sunny gave us a deep dive into the WLP and WLB features of vROps.
We were also joined by a special guest, Jad El-Zein who gave us a great insight into how vRA utilises vROps for initial placement of freshly provisioned VMs
We would highly appreciate it if you could spend 30 seconds to fill up this quick and simple survey to provide us your feedback. You can also request topics of your choice through this survey.</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Sunday and Monday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-1-and-2-sunday-and-monday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 13:29:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-1-and-2-sunday-and-monday/</guid><description>Sunday Arriving in early on Sunday as the local flight choices are more limited from Bristol than perhaps a larger Airport, very fortunate to have a hotel so close to the VMworld venue, perhaps not so great for the evening activities but I am happy with it this way around.
Other than registration (4pm-8pm) and hopefully catching up with a few folk who have also arrived early.
In the evening I had the pleasure to meet many awesome people from the vCommunity.</description></item><item><title>Looking forward to #VMworld EMEA 2017</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/looking-forward-to-vmworld-emea-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 09:30:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/looking-forward-to-vmworld-emea-2017/</guid><description>Having missed last years VMworld I feel very ready for attending the EMEA VMworld in Barcelona.
I almost felt annoyed about missing last year as the big announcements really caused a stir in the community and wider afield. (VMware on AWS) The announcements from the US VMworld this year were equally exciting so I am very keen to hear what else VMware has planned to reveal in a Barcelona.
I have put a good deal of effort into planning what I will be doing and attending to maximise my time there without burnout (Veterans I hear you laughing)</description></item><item><title>Alexa, turn on my workload cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 15:05:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</guid><description>I already have a vRealize Orchestrator workflow to shutdown my workload cluster. What I want to do is trigger that by a voice command from Alexa.
Now, the correct and proper thing to do here would be to create a new Alexa skill, write the function in Lambda and connect that to my Orchestrator REST API and execute the workflow. That way I could control the “intents” and “utterances” and have verbal feedback.</description></item><item><title>Getting started with vRealize Log Insight 4.3 for vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/getting-started-with-vrealize-log-insight-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 12:09:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/getting-started-with-vrealize-log-insight-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>In this humble consultant&amp;rsquo;s opinion, Log Insight is one of the most useful tools in the administrator&amp;rsquo;s tool belt for troubleshooting vRealize Automation. I have lost count of the number of times I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to help troubleshoot an issue that, when asked, people don&amp;rsquo;t know which log they should be looking at. The simple fact is that vRealize Automation has a lot of log files. Correlating these log sources to provide an overall picture is a painful, manual process - unless you have Log Insight!</description></item><item><title>Adding a vCloud Air (PAYG/Gen2) instance to vRealize Orchestrator as a vCloud Director host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 13:26:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</guid><description>Big thanks to Jose Luis Gomez for this solution, his response to my tweet was spot on and invaluable!
I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to configure vCloud Air as a vCloud Director host in vRealize Orchestrator in order to create some custom resource actions for Day 2 operations in vRealize Automation. What I found was that there&amp;rsquo;s *very* little information out there on how to do this, and I ended up writing my own custom resource mapping for the virtual machines to VCAC:VirtualMachine objects - at least that way I could add my resource action.</description></item><item><title>What’s in my vRA7 EBS Payloads?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/whats-in-my-vra7-ebs-payloads/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 15:52:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/whats-in-my-vra7-ebs-payloads/</guid><description>&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-6186&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;vRA&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; - a properties object.
I wanted to create a workflow that I could enable to log all of the keys, values and types of the properties object for each stage of the vRA7 MachineProvisioning workflows, and create a reference for myself on the payload for each stage.
To do this I created a new workflow &amp;ldquo;debugProperties&amp;rdquo; and added an input variable called &amp;ldquo;payload&amp;rdquo;, type Properties.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7 XaaS blueprint form displays: Failed to retrieve form from provider</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-xaas-blueprint-form-displays-failed-to-retrieve-form-from-provider/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 13:47:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-xaas-blueprint-form-displays-failed-to-retrieve-form-from-provider/</guid><description>VMware KB2140539 where requesting an XaaS (vRealize Orchestrator) blueprint fails with:
Failed to retrieve form from provider
The KB describes it occuring when &amp;ldquo;more than one VMware vRealize Orchestrator instance is configured for different tenants&amp;rdquo;. The issue I faced is not the same - in my case, I had the system default tenant configured to use the embedded vRO, and the customer tenant configured to use the system default (which would be the embedded vRO!</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7 Custom Hostname with Event Broker (EB) Subscription</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-custom-hostname-with-event-broker-eb-subscription/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 17:54:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-custom-hostname-with-event-broker-eb-subscription/</guid><description>The new Event Broker service in vRA7 is one of the most exciting features of this latest release, the possibilities for extensibility are huge. At this point it time you can still use the old method of using workflow stubs to customise machine lifecycle events, but at some point in the future this will be deprecated and the Event Broker will be the only way to extend.
With this in mind, I wanted to use the Event Broker to do something that I am asked on almost every customer engagement - custom hostnames beyond what the Machine Prefixes mechanism can do.</description></item><item><title>MindMap: vRealize Automation Roles</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/mindmap-vrealize-automation-roles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 20:45:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/mindmap-vrealize-automation-roles/</guid><description>I use mind maps quite a lot for study, I find the visual representation of info makes it a lot easier for me to remember! Below is a mind map I created for learning the roles in vRealize Automation, which I used during my presentation for #vBrownBag on VCP6-CMA objective 2.
You can download a PDF version here: vRealize Automation Roles Mind Map</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: vRealize Automation 7 Briefing Notes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 08:20:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</guid><description>@vaficionado) – if that list of names doesn’t fill you with confidence for vRA.Next, then I suggest you follow them on twitter and trust me that it’s a crack team!
 So, my highlights:
Completely automated deployment…almost. The deployment of appliances and installation of IaaS components and pre-requisites will be wizard driven, the Window Servers will need to exist and have an agent installed, and the MSSQL server will also need to be installed.</description></item><item><title>Building a vRealize Automation NSX Lab on Ravello</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/building-a-vrealize-automation-nsx-lab-on-ravello/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 17:06:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/building-a-vrealize-automation-nsx-lab-on-ravello/</guid><description>As a vExpert, I am blessed to get 1000 CPU hours access to Ravello&amp;rsquo;s awesome platform and recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with the AutoLab deployments tailored for Ravello.
If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with Ravello&amp;rsquo;s offering (where have you been?!) then it&amp;rsquo;s basically a custom hypervisor (HVX) running on either AWS or Google Cloud that allows you to run nested environments on those platforms. I did say it&amp;rsquo;s awesome.
As an avid home-lab enthusiast Ravello initially felt weird, but having used it for a while I can definitely see the potential to augment, and in some cases completely replace the home lab.</description></item><item><title>Missing actions in vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/missing-actions-in-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 11:36:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/missing-actions-in-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>Recently the team I am working with came across an interesting bug/issue with actions missing from deployed VMs. We had checked and double checked the entitlements yet the actions that should be available to the end-user/customer were not listed.
Everything appeared to point to a permissions issue until one of the team members noticed something with regards to blueprints in the catalog.
Before I continue with what we observed and how we &amp;ldquo;fixed&amp;rdquo; it please bear in mind the blueprints were created programmatically.</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation instance – Configuring NetScaler Monitors</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-instance-configuring-netscaler-monitors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 09:24:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-instance-configuring-netscaler-monitors/</guid><description>Enter a name for the monitor, and leave the other parameters the same. Select the &amp;ldquo;Special Parameters&amp;rdquo; tab and configure the send string to the URL to monitor - e.g for the PSC SSO it&amp;rsquo;s going to be:
GET /websso/HealthStatus For the receive string, enter the expected response (&amp;ldquo;GREEN&amp;rdquo;). Click Create.
Assigning a NetScaler Monitor to a Service Assign the monitor to the PSC Services (or Service Groups) configured for PSC by opening the Configuration &amp;gt; Traffic Management &amp;gt; Load Balancing &amp;gt; Services page and selecting the PSC service for HTTPS/443 and clicking Edit.</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components – Part 2: Database, Web and Manager services</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-2-database-web-and-manager-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:40:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-2-database-web-and-manager-services/</guid><description>Now that the prerequisites for the IaaS layer have been completed, it&amp;rsquo;s time to move on to the actual installation of the IaaS components, starting with the database. We then move onto the first Web server, which also imports the ModelManagerData configuration to the database, populating the database with all of the info the IaaS layer needs out of the box. We then install the second Web server before moving on to the active Manager server.</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components – Part 1: Pre-requisites</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-1-pre-requisites/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:15:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-1-pre-requisites/</guid><description>One of the trickiest parts of deploying vRealize Automation is the IaaS layer - people sometimes look at me like I&amp;rsquo;m a crazy person when I say that, normally because they&amp;rsquo;ve deployed a PoC or small deployment with just a single IaaS server. Add in 5 more servers, some load balancers, certificates, a distributed setup and MSDTC to the mix and you have a huge potential for pain!
If you&amp;rsquo;ve followed my previous posts, you&amp;rsquo;ll see know that I&amp;rsquo;ve got a HA Platform Services Controller configured, and a HA vRealize Appliance cluster configured with Postgres replication - all good so far.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation Infrastructure Tab displays incorrect labels</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vrealize-automation-infrastructure-tab-displays-incorrect-labels/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 08:24:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vrealize-automation-infrastructure-tab-displays-incorrect-labels/</guid><description>Having just completed a particularly problem-prone distributed IaaS install, this was almost the straw that broke the camel&amp;rsquo;s back. Logging into vRealize Automation for the first time as an Infrastructure Admin displayed the infrastructure tab and all menu labels as big ugly references, and no functionality:
{com.cmware.cap.component.iaas.proxy.provider@csp.places.iaas.label}
Rebooting the IaaS web servers restored the functionality of the IaaS layer but still did not fix the label issue, it took a further reboot of both vRealize Automation appliances, then the IaaS web servers to finally view the correct labels.</description></item><item><title>Deploying vRealize Automation 6.2 Appliance Cluster with Postgres Replication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 19:57:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</guid><description>The recommendations for the vRealize Appliance have changed with 6.2, the published reference architecture now does not recommend using an external Postgres database (either vPostgres appliance, a 3rd party Postgres deployment or using a third vRealize Appliance as a stand-alone database installation). Instead the recommended layout is shown in the diagram below. One instance of postgres on the primary node becomes an active instance, replicating to the second node which is passive.</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 HA SSO (PSC) with NetScaler VPX Load Balancer for vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 15:40:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>vSphere 6 HA SSO (PSC) with NetScaler VPX Load Balancer for vRealize Automation Deploying vRealize Automation 6.2 Appliance Cluster with Postgres Replication Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components - Part 1: Pre-requisites Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components - Part 2: Database, Web and Manager services Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation instance - Configuring NetScaler Monitors Providing a highly available single sign on for vRealize Automation is a fundamental part of ensuring the availability of the platform.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation (vRA) Manager Service error</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-automation-vra-manager-service-error/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 10:07:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-automation-vra-manager-service-error/</guid><description>Recently when do a fresh install of vRealize Automation (vRA) 6.2 I came across the following error after configuring the first end point.
 Error log example
     DataBaseStatsService: ignoring exception: Error executing query usp_SelectAgent Inner Exception: Error executing query usp_SelectAgentCapabilities
and Error processing ping response Error executing query usp_SelectAgent Inner Exception: Error executing query usp_SelectAgentCapabilities First of all I checked to see if the end points were working which in this case they appeared to be, but I wanted to clear the error before continuing the install.</description></item></channel></rss>