<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Uncategorized on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/uncategorized/</link><description>Recent content in Uncategorized on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 10:24:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Real Man Cycling Challenge</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/08/the-real-man-cycling-challenge/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 10:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/08/the-real-man-cycling-challenge/</guid><description>*** Unfortunately the Real Man Cycling challenge has been cancelled for this year due to planning issues - I&amp;rsquo;m disappointed but I hope to do it again next year *** I&amp;rsquo;m doing the Real Man Cycling Challenge in London on the 14th September. It&amp;rsquo;s a 34km ride through london in aid of The Prostate Cancer Charity, which is a really worthwile cause. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to sponsor me, head on over to http://www.</description></item><item><title>Menus in MOSS (or WSS) open and disappear</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/menus-in-moss-or-wss-open-and-disappear/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 19:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/menus-in-moss-or-wss-open-and-disappear/</guid><description>We were integrating a 3rd party product&amp;rsquo;s web parts with MOSS the other day and came accross an interesting problem. In site editing mode, all the drop down menus would appear for a flash and then go blank. The actual admin pages we were trying to get to would work if you entered them into the browser directly, but that isn&amp;rsquo;t an easy way to manage the site!
The problem turned out to be that in the process of getting the 3rd party web parts to work, the support team had added a MIME type to the IIS installation.</description></item><item><title>Installing Windows XP without a CD drive</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/03/installing-windows-xp-without-a-cd-drive/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/03/installing-windows-xp-without-a-cd-drive/</guid><description>When the Dell engineer said “they’ve asked if you can reinstall the OS” my heart sank. Not because I felt like he was weasling out of work - unusually they were very helpful. Not because installing XP is a hard task, I’ve done it over 100 times on all sorts of hardware.
No, the reason I let out a sigh was because this particular laptop, the Latitude X1, has no internal CD/DVD drive.</description></item><item><title>Retrieving Your Exchange Server 2003 License Key</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/02/retrieving-your-exchange-server-2003-license-key/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/02/retrieving-your-exchange-server-2003-license-key/</guid><description>Recently I found the need to retrieve the key from an existing Exchange Server for a reinstall - the software is legally licensed but the key was somehow lost. A trawl through my registry revealed that the key is stored in an obscure place:
HKLM\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\Microsoft Integration\{GUID}\PID3.0 This was the case on a Windows Server 2000 install with Exchange Server 2003 installed, when I get the chance I will test this on Server 2003.</description></item><item><title>Office 2007 woes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/05/office-2007-woes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 20:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/05/office-2007-woes/</guid><description>Originally published Wednesday, May 30th, 2007 Wahey! I got published this week in IT Week, ok it was only a readers letter, but I got in! Here’s what I wrote: “New software always excites me, so I was enthusiastic as I installed Office 2007 on my laptop. The machine offers more than enough grunt for my media applications, but sadly not quite enough to install Office in less than 15 minutes, plus one restart.</description></item></channel></rss>