<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Certification on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/certification/</link><description>Recent content in Certification on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/certification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate (003) Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2025/10/hashicorp-certified-terraform-associate-003-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2025/10/hashicorp-certified-terraform-associate-003-exam-experience/</guid><description>My experience taking the HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate (003) exam — preparation, exam process, and thoughts on why certification still matters.</description></item><item><title>VCAP7-CMA Design Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/02/vcap7-cma-design-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 13:56:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/02/vcap7-cma-design-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For the last month I had been preparing for the VCAP7-CMA Design exam and I am very glad to say I passed on my first attempt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oddly I found it slightly easier than the VCP7-CMA but that I suspect is down to the fact I spend a lot of my time designing and implementing solutions for customers as opposed to day to day administration of any given solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what was the exam like?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>New Year, new things oh and a VCP7-CMA</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/01/new-year-new-things-oh-and-a-vcp7-cma/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 19:20:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/01/new-year-new-things-oh-and-a-vcp7-cma/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since I have had time to write a blog post, the last quarter of last year was pretty crazy from a work point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, it is now a New Year and my tech focus is turning very much on CMP related things particularly vRealize Automation. (I am also very much looking forward to learning more about VMware&amp;rsquo;s CaS which I saw demo&amp;rsquo;d at the UK VMUG late last year by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/grantorchard"&gt;Grant Orchard&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – VCAP6-DCA Deploy Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-vcap6-dca-deploy-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 22:44:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-vcap6-dca-deploy-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Greetings from Day 1 of VMworld US 2016!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year I try and make use of the VMworld discount at the exam centre, and this year was no exception I sat the VCAP6-DCV Deploy exam, and results are still pending! Overall it&amp;rsquo;s a good exam, there was very little of the spelling and grammatical errors I&amp;rsquo;ve complained about in the past, performance was OK and the level of difficulty was good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>MindMap: vRealize Automation Roles</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/mindmap-vrealize-automation-roles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 20:45:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/mindmap-vrealize-automation-roles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I use mind maps quite a lot for study, I find the visual representation of info makes it a lot easier for me to remember! Below is a mind map I created for learning the roles in vRealize Automation, which I used during my presentation for #vBrownBag on VCP6-CMA objective 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download a PDF version here: &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vRealize Automation Roles Mind Map&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VCDX-CMA 204</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vcdx-cma-204/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 11:51:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vcdx-cma-204/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apologies in advance if this is post is a jumbled nonsense, I&amp;rsquo;m still way too excited!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning I woke to the news that I have passed my VCDX-CMA!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my second attempt at VCDX and although the first failure was a painful experience, the lessons learned from it were invaluable to take into the defence the second time around. Failing doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be a negative experience - if there is one thing that I will take from the VCDX program it is that there is ALWAYS more I need to learn, and I can always do better. Learning has to be a way of life (in this industry especially!) and the minute you stop, you start falling back.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: VCIX-NV Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 16:58:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;For the last few years at VMworld I’ve taken advantage of the discounted exam price and booked a “have-a-go” exam – typically an exam I’ve been wanting to do but not necessarily had the time I wanted to study for it. Since I have been fairly immersed in the NSX world for the last week, sitting in an NSX design and deploy class and surrounded by some very smart networking guys, I changed my “have-a-go” exam from the VCP6-CMA to the VCIX-NV.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My VCAP5-DCD experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/my-vcap5-dcd-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 08:59:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/my-vcap5-dcd-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/08/VCAP-DCD-1.jpg" alt=""&gt;A few months ago I decided to tackle the VCAP5-DCD exam and when booking I gave myself 2 months to study before the date of the exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was keenly aware that at least in this calendar year the VCAP5-DCD exam and undergone some changes E.G. it no longer had multiple choice questions (think VCP5-DCV in terms of format)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a wealth of knowledge out there from people whom had either passed/failed or were currently studying so it didn&amp;rsquo;t take too long to get an understanding of what disciplines/knowledge VMware were looking for in the exam.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>