<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SMB on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/smb/</link><description>Recent content in SMB on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 15:30:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/smb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What about VSAN for SMB/SME?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/what-about-vsan-for-smbsme/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 15:30:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/what-about-vsan-for-smbsme/</guid><description>Unless you have been sleeping under a rock you will be aware that VSAN was launched last week and has gone GA today and from what I have seen so far I do think VSAN is a great product and I think VMware have done a superb job with it.
Aside from the -many- discussions on twitter and other channels regarding the then lack of licensing information and pricing I was eager to see if VMware would offer a &amp;ldquo;foundation&amp;rdquo; VSAN option for SMB/SME</description></item><item><title>vCHS – first impressions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vchs-first-impressions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:39:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vchs-first-impressions/</guid><description>In case you missed it VMware have now released vCHS (VMware vCloud Hybrid Service) in Europe! The first data center residing in Slough with more data centers planned across Europe in the near future.
Working in an SME that has several existing vSphere environments this was of real interest, as the need to scale out quickly from our Private clouds is rapidly becoming a requirement.
Having already spoken to VMware on the phone to get a rough idea on options and costs I decided to take a look at the Hands-on-labs to see how easy it really is to use and migrate VMs from an existing private cloud to vCHS.</description></item></channel></rss>