<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dns on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/dns/</link><description>Recent content in Dns on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/dns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automatically adding Kubernetes Service DNS records to Microsoft DNS using CoreDNS and k8s_gateway</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/12/automatically-adding-kubernetes-service-dns-records-to-microsoft-dns-using-coredns-and-k8s_gateway/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/12/automatically-adding-kubernetes-service-dns-records-to-microsoft-dns-using-coredns-and-k8s_gateway/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I deploy a new service into a namespace, I need to create a new DNS record that makes it available. I&amp;rsquo;ve previously talked about using CoreDNS to host my lab DNS zones, but this is something different. I want to make a Kubernetes Service available using an existing Microsoft DNS server - which is already used by all the clients who would need to access the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this I will create a delegated zone under my existing zone &lt;code&gt;cmbu.local&lt;/code&gt; that CoreDNS will be responsible for. Then I will use the &lt;code&gt;k8s_gateway&lt;/code&gt; plugin to automatically create records for Services provisioned within my zone.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Running CoreDNS for lab name resolution</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/running-coredns-for-lab-name-resolution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/running-coredns-for-lab-name-resolution/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Up until recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been running a Windows Server Core VM with Active Directory, DNS and Certificate Services deployed to provide some core features in my home lab. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve also been conscious that running a lab on old hardware doesn&amp;rsquo;t exactly have much in the way of green credentials. So, in an effort to reduce my carbon footprint (and electricity bill) I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for ways to shut down my lab when it&amp;rsquo;s not in use.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7.3 Distributed Install – Prerequisites</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrealize-automation-7-3-distributed-install-prerequisites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 13:33:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrealize-automation-7-3-distributed-install-prerequisites/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;As a consultant I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to design, install and configure dozens of production vRealize Automation deployments, from reasonably small Proof of Concept environments to globally-scaled multi-datacenter fully distributed behemoths. It&amp;rsquo;s fair to say, that I&amp;rsquo;ve made mistakes along the way - and learned a lot of lessons as to what makes a deployment a success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, pretty much everything comes down to getting the pre-requisites right. Nothing that I&amp;rsquo;ve written here is not already documented in the official documentation, and the installation wizard does a huge amount of the work for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 2: vPostgres</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-2-vpostgres/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 09:01:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-2-vpostgres/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This is the second article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diagram below shows the deployment at the end of this part, with vPostgres deployed and the vCAC Appliance running from the remote database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overview of the steps required are below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Issue and install certificates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure load balancing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install and configure additional IaaS server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="create-the-required-dns-records"&gt;Create the required DNS records &lt;a class="anchor" href="#create-the-required-dns-records"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;First of all, create DNS records for your vPostgres database server – you need both an A and PTR record. Most VMware appliances will check for a reverse DNS lookup when they boot and will set the hostname accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>