<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dns on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/dns/</link><description>Recent content in dns on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/dns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Running CoreDNS for lab name resolution</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/running-coredns-for-lab-name-resolution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/running-coredns-for-lab-name-resolution/</guid><description>Up until recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been running a Windows Server Core VM with Active Directory, DNS and Certificate Services deployed to provide some core features in my home lab. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve also been conscious that running a lab on old hardware doesn&amp;rsquo;t exactly have much in the way of green credentials. So, in an effort to reduce my carbon footprint (and electricity bill) I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for ways to shut down my lab when it&amp;rsquo;s not in use.</description></item><item><title>Running CoreDNS for lab name resolution</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/running-coredns-for-lab-name-resolution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/running-coredns-for-lab-name-resolution/</guid><description>Up until recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been running a Windows Server Core VM with Active Directory, DNS and Certificate Services deployed to provide some core features in my home lab. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve also been conscious that running a lab on old hardware doesn&amp;rsquo;t exactly have much in the way of green credentials. So, in an effort to reduce my carbon footprint (and electricity bill) I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for ways to shut down my lab when it&amp;rsquo;s not in use.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7.3 Distributed Install – Prerequisites</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrealize-automation-7-3-distributed-install-prerequisites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 13:33:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrealize-automation-7-3-distributed-install-prerequisites/</guid><description>As a consultant I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to design, install and configure dozens of production vRealize Automation deployments, from reasonably small Proof of Concept environments to globally-scaled multi-datacenter fully distributed behemoths. It&amp;rsquo;s fair to say, that I&amp;rsquo;ve made mistakes along the way - and learned a lot of lessons as to what makes a deployment a success.
In the end, pretty much everything comes down to getting the pre-requisites right. Nothing that I&amp;rsquo;ve written here is not already documented in the official documentation, and the installation wizard does a huge amount of the work for you.</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 2: vPostgres</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-2-vpostgres/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 09:01:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-2-vpostgres/</guid><description>This is the second article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
The diagram below shows the deployment at the end of this part, with vPostgres deployed and the vCAC Appliance running from the remote database.
vCAC deploymnent with vPostgres deployed An overview of the steps required are below:
Issue and install certificates Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database Configure load balancing Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering Install and configure additional IaaS server Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster Create the required DNS records First of all, create DNS records for your vPostgres database server – you need both an A and PTR record.</description></item></channel></rss>