<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud Native on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/cloud-native/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud Native on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/cloud-native/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMware Cloud Expert - Multi-Cloud Builder</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2022/11/vmware-cloud-expert-multi-cloud-builder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2022/11/vmware-cloud-expert-multi-cloud-builder/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I had the good fortune to be invited to attend a VMware Multi-Cloud course at VMware UK HQ in Staines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="multi-cloud-builder"&gt;Multi-Cloud Builder &lt;a class="anchor" href="#multi-cloud-builder"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The course took place over 4 days and was very well structured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initialy, we were given the VMware vision on Multi-Cloud and then we were straight into the &amp;ldquo;good stuff&amp;rdquo; hands-on-labs. This would be a consistent and well executed theme for the 4 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VMware now have an impressive global cloud presence utilising their partnerships with major hyperscalers such as AWS, Azure Google Cloud, Oracle Cloud, and several others. You can see from the list below VMware are serious about this Multi-Cloud journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware Aria - Unified Multi-Cloud Management</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2022/09/vmware-aria-unified-multi-cloud-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2022/09/vmware-aria-unified-multi-cloud-management/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;VMWorld, sorry VMware Explore has been and gone and seemed to go very smoothly, there were several announcements but the big one for me was Aria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vmware-aria-formerly-vrealize-cloud-management"&gt;VMware Aria (formerly vRealize Cloud Management) &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vmware-aria-formerly-vrealize-cloud-management"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Cloud management that unifies applications, infrastructure, and services across private, hybrid, and public clouds in a single platform with a common data model.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;With the VMware Aria launch, we are unifying VMware Cloud Management in four key respects:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/02/certified-kubernetes-administrator-cka-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/02/certified-kubernetes-administrator-cka-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Since I started learning Kubernetes the Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) exam has been a target for me, but it&amp;rsquo;s always seemed to be out of reach. The whole Kubernetes ecosystem is a vast and nebulous beast, with new projects rising to the fore all the time, and old projects fading from favour. The size and rapid development that make the field so interesting and powerful, are the same properties that make the learning curve so steep, and the entry bar so high.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Certified Kubernetes Security Specialist (CKS) Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/02/certified-kubernetes-security-specialist-cks-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/02/certified-kubernetes-security-specialist-cks-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had the Certified Kubernetes Security Specialist exam booked for a long time - so long in fact that the exam voucher was due to expire at the end of January 2022! I figured I&amp;rsquo;d give it a go right at the start of January, work out how far off the mark I was and then aim to do the free retake before it expired at the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lab Guide - Kubernetes and Storage with the vSphere Cloud Provider - Step by Step</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/06/lab-guide-kubernetes-and-storage-with-the-vsphere-cloud-provider-step-by-step/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/06/lab-guide-kubernetes-and-storage-with-the-vsphere-cloud-provider-step-by-step/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from me recent post &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/06/lab-guide-kubernetes-and-nsx-t-container-network-plugin-step-by-step/"&gt;deploying Kubernetes with the NSX-T
CNP&lt;/a&gt;,
I wanted to extend my environment to make use of the &lt;a href="https://vmware.github.io/vsphere-storage-for-kubernetes/documentation/index.html"&gt;vSphere Cloud
Provider&lt;/a&gt;
to enable Persistent Volumes backed by vSphere storage. This allows me to use
Storage Policy to create Persistent Volumes based on policy. For example, I’m
going to create two classes of storage, &lt;em&gt;Fast&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Slow&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;em&gt;Fast&lt;/em&gt; will be vSAN
based and &lt;em&gt;Slow&lt;/em&gt; will be NFS based.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>