<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linked Mode on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/linked-mode/</link><description>Recent content in Linked Mode on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 15:28:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/linked-mode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMware vCenter Linked Mode not supported through firewalls</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vmware-vcenter-linked-mode-not-supported-through-firewalls/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 15:28:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vmware-vcenter-linked-mode-not-supported-through-firewalls/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This article originally started off life as a record of how I managed to get this working, as a lot of my posts do, but this time it appears I am foiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I had 3 vCenter Servers that appeared to be happily talking to each other in Linked Mode sharing a singe Multi-site SSO domain without any real issues. I had a single-pane-of-glass view of all 3 and I could manage them all from the one client. The reason for the 3 vCenter servers was segregation of LAN and DMZ networks: vCenter001 was in the LAN, vCenter002 sat in DMZ1 and vCenter003 sat in DMZ2.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing VMware vSphere Single Sign On (SSO) in Multi-site Mode</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/installing-vmware-vsphere-single-sign-on-sso-in-multi-site-mode/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 19:33:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/installing-vmware-vsphere-single-sign-on-sso-in-multi-site-mode/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt; VMware vSphere Single Sign On (SSO) can be installed in Multi-site mode to support local sign-on to vCenters that you want to be part of the same single sign on domain - for example, if you want to install Linked-Mode and have the advantage of a single pane of glass view, but can&amp;rsquo;t risk using a single SSO instance across the WAN. In other words, from &lt;a href="http://blogs.vmware.com/vsphere/2012/09/vcenter-single-sign-on-part-1-what-is-vcenter-single-sign-on.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; VMware&amp;rsquo;s blog post
&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>