<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VRA 6.2 Deployment on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/series/vra-6.2-deployment/</link><description>Recent content in VRA 6.2 Deployment on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 09:24:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/series/vra-6.2-deployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation instance – Configuring NetScaler Monitors</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-instance-configuring-netscaler-monitors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 09:24:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-instance-configuring-netscaler-monitors/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter a name for the monitor, and leave the other parameters the same. Select the &amp;ldquo;Special Parameters&amp;rdquo; tab and configure the send string to the URL to monitor - e.g for the PSC SSO it&amp;rsquo;s going to be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the receive string, enter the expected response (&amp;ldquo;GREEN&amp;rdquo;). Click Create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/08/image_thumb40.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="assigning-a-netscaler-monitor-to-a-service"&gt;Assigning a NetScaler Monitor to a Service &lt;a class="anchor" href="#assigning-a-netscaler-monitor-to-a-service"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assign the monitor to the PSC Services (or Service Groups) configured for PSC by opening the Configuration &amp;gt; Traffic Management &amp;gt; Load Balancing &amp;gt; Services page and selecting the PSC service for HTTPS/443 and clicking Edit.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components – Part 2: Database, Web and Manager services</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-2-database-web-and-manager-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:40:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-2-database-web-and-manager-services/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png" alt=""&gt;Now that the prerequisites for the IaaS layer have been completed, it&amp;rsquo;s time to move on to the actual installation of the IaaS components, starting with the database. We then move onto the first Web server, which also imports the ModelManagerData configuration to the database, populating the database with all of the info the IaaS layer needs out of the box. We then install the second Web server before moving on to the active Manager server. The second Manager server is passive and the service should be disabled - I&amp;rsquo;ll cover installing DEM Orchestrators, Workers and the vSphere Agents in the next article.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components – Part 1: Pre-requisites</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-1-pre-requisites/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:15:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-1-pre-requisites/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One of the trickiest parts of deploying vRealize Automation is the IaaS layer - people sometimes look at me like I&amp;rsquo;m a crazy person when I say that, normally because they&amp;rsquo;ve deployed a PoC or small deployment with just a single IaaS server. Add in 5 more servers, some load balancers, certificates, a distributed setup and MSDTC to the mix and you have a huge potential for pain!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying vRealize Automation 6.2 Appliance Cluster with Postgres Replication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 19:57:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The recommendations for the vRealize Appliance have changed with 6.2, the published reference architecture now does not recommend using an external Postgres database (either vPostgres appliance, a 3rd party Postgres deployment or using a third vRealize Appliance as a stand-alone database installation). Instead the recommended layout is shown in the diagram below. One instance of postgres on the primary node becomes an active instance, replicating to the second node which is passive. In front of these a load balancer or DNS entry points to the active node only. Fail-over is still a manual task, but it does provide better protection than a single instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 HA SSO (PSC) with NetScaler VPX Load Balancer for vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 15:40:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Providing a highly available single sign on for vRealize Automation is a fundamental part of ensuring the availability of the platform. Traditionally, (vCAC) vRA uses the Identity Appliance and relies on vSphere HA to provide the availability of the SSO platform, but in a fully distributed HA environment that&amp;rsquo;s not really good enough. It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to use the vSphere 5.5 SSO install in a HA configuration - however, many companies are making the move to the latest version of vSphere and don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to maintain a 5.5 HA SSO instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0/6.1 build out to distributed model: Deploy the Identity Appliance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/vcac-6-06-1-build-out-to-distributed-model-deploy-the-identity-appliance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 14:55:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/vcac-6-06-1-build-out-to-distributed-model-deploy-the-identity-appliance/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;SSO is a fundamental requirement when deploying vCAC, whether for a distributed or simple installation. This walk through goes through the deployment and configuration of the vCAC Identity Appliance, which provides a stand alone SSO instance for vCAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the posts in this series are completed with vCAC 6.0.1, others will be with 6.1. Where there are differences I will aim to point them out!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>