<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tftp on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/tftp/</link><description>Recent content in Tftp on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/tftp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PXE Booting Raspberry Pi 4 with Synology and Ubiquiti EdgeRouter</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/pxe-booting-raspberry-pi-4-with-synology-and-ubiquiti-edgerouter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/pxe-booting-raspberry-pi-4-with-synology-and-ubiquiti-edgerouter/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I love Raspbery Pis - I have done since they first released them, all the way up to the present iteration, the Raspberry Pi 4. They&amp;rsquo;re phenominal little bits of kit, endlessly hackable and because of their really low price, they open up computing to a huge number of people who otherwise wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get the opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the irritating things, though, about running Raspberry Pis is that they typically boot from an SD card. SD cards are notorious for having high attrition rates, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re reading/writing to them regularly. Running a Kubernetes cluster on my Raspberry Pis is especially hard on the SD card because you&amp;rsquo;re not only running the system&amp;rsquo;s read and writes, but you&amp;rsquo;re also running containers and their I/O on the card.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Updating Cisco SG300 firmware the command line way</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/02/updating-cisco-sg300-firmware-the-command-line-way/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 15:14:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/02/updating-cisco-sg300-firmware-the-command-line-way/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright wp-image-5603 size-medium&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2015/02/cisco_SG300-20_1.png&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;Cisco SG300-20&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;180&amp;rdquo; of upgrading my lab switch, which is the excellent Cisco SG300-20, I&amp;rsquo;ve not had a chance to update the firmware since it was released 6 months ago because of the downtime. For some reason I prefer configuring the SG300 from the command line - a hangover from my old networking days I suppose, but somehow it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel right to me to use the GUI!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>