<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Exchange 2007 on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/exchange-2007/</link><description>Recent content in Exchange 2007 on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 12:29:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/exchange-2007/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overriding the OpsMgr Exchange 2007 Test MAPI Connectivity Monitor for Recovery Storage Groups</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/01/overriding-the-opsmgr-exchange-2007-test-mapi-connectivity-monitor-for-recovery-storage-groups/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 12:29:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/01/overriding-the-opsmgr-exchange-2007-test-mapi-connectivity-monitor-for-recovery-storage-groups/</guid><description>The Test MAPI Connectivity monitor for the Exchange 2007 management pack will automatically generate a critical error for any Recovery Storage Groups you have on monitored Exchange Mailbox Roles. As these are generally temporary Storage Groups created for a recovery and then removed, you don&amp;rsquo;t want an alert - but manually adding an override for every time is not a great use of your time either.
The State Change event details are as follows:</description></item><item><title>Testing access to your Exchange services with Microsoft Exchange Remote Connectivity Analyzer</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/07/testing-access-to-your-exchange-services-with-microsoft-exchange-remote-connectivity-analyzer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 09:27:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/07/testing-access-to-your-exchange-services-with-microsoft-exchange-remote-connectivity-analyzer/</guid><description>The Microsoft Exchange Remote Connectivity Analyzer is perhaps the best tool I’ve used in a long time for troubleshooting Exchange external access – it just works! On the forums and websites I read, it doesn’t seem to get the coverage that I’d expect, so I thought I’d give it a mention.</description></item><item><title>Useful commands for troubleshooting Exchange 2010 routing with Exchange 2003/2007</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/07/useful-commands-for-troubleshooting-exchange-2010-routing-with-exchange-20032007/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 17:05:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/07/useful-commands-for-troubleshooting-exchange-2010-routing-with-exchange-20032007/</guid><description>I’ve just fixed an issue with Routing for my mixed Exchange 2003/2007/2010 environment.
The environment is a single AD domain with 4 sites, Site1, Site2, Site3 and Site4. In Site1, Site2 and Site3 there are 3 Exchange 2003 servers, one per site. In Site4 there is an Exchange 2007 SP2 server (CAS, Mailbox, HT). All the connectors required worked as expected, and inter-site routing works as expected.
I introduced into the mix a 2010 Enterprise server (CAS, Mailbox, HT) to Site1 as a prelude to a full upgrade of the site to Exchange 2010.</description></item><item><title>Exchange ActiveSync fails on iPhone after upgrade to iOS4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/07/exchange-activesync-fails-on-iphone-after-upgrade-to-ios4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2010 15:55:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/07/exchange-activesync-fails-on-iphone-after-upgrade-to-ios4/</guid><description>I’ve spent a fair bit of time today trying to sort out my iPhone sync to my Exchange Server, failing miserably. It used to work, pre-upgrade to iOS4, but for some reason fails to sync.
Symptoms were:
iPhone fails to sync, generic timeout error (or is very slow) https://www.testexchangeconnectivity.com/ successfully tests the mailbox access The server was configured as per http://support.microsoft.com/kb/817379/en-us to allow OWA/ActiveSync with SSL on OWA.
The iPhone was configured to accept the SSL certificate on the Exchange Server.</description></item></channel></rss>