<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>london on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/london/</link><description>Recent content in london on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 09:44:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/london/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#LonVMUG 15th May &amp;ndash; another great VMUG!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/lonvmug-15th-may-another-great-vmug/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 09:44:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/lonvmug-15th-may-another-great-vmug/</guid><description>Yesterday saw another fantastic London VMUG with lots of quality sessions and opportunities to network with peers and friends. The committee seem to do a fantastic job every time and this one was no exception, so thanks to Alaric Davies, Jane Rimmer, Stuart Thompson and Simon Gallagher!
One of the best things for me about the VMUG is the chance to chat with some of the smartest and most influential people in the VMware world – a trip to the coffee table provided a great opportunity to “chew the vfat” with two of the VMUG&amp;rsquo;s biggest characters, Mike Laverick and Ricky El-Qasem – all before any sessions had started.</description></item><item><title>London VMUG &amp;ndash; July 2013</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/07/london-vmug-july-2013/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 12:54:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/07/london-vmug-july-2013/</guid><description>Yesterday I attended my second ever #LonVMUG and did my first ever VMUG presentation! Generally it was a great day, with loads of really good sessions and some really cool community and vendor content.
As ever it was great day for socialising and networking with people who you interact with on twitter. For me one of the major benefits of the VMUG is learning from other people’s experience. Twitter was alive with the hastag #LonVMUG and it definitely adds something to the day to be active</description></item></channel></rss>