<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Psc on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/psc/</link><description>Recent content in Psc on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 15:04:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/psc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automate changing the vSphere 6 Platform Services Controller IP address (and vRealize Automation)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/automate-changing-the-vsphere-6-platform-services-controller-ip-address/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 15:04:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/automate-changing-the-vsphere-6-platform-services-controller-ip-address/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Note: This falls under the “I don’t think this is supported” category – use this method at your own peril!&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;As part of some testing I’ve been doing for vRealize Automation DR scenarios, I wanted to test changing the IP address of a HA PSC pair using a script (think SRM failover to a new subnet).&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 HA SSO (PSC) with NetScaler VPX Load Balancer for vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 15:40:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Providing a highly available single sign on for vRealize Automation is a fundamental part of ensuring the availability of the platform. Traditionally, (vCAC) vRA uses the Identity Appliance and relies on vSphere HA to provide the availability of the SSO platform, but in a fully distributed HA environment that&amp;rsquo;s not really good enough. It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to use the vSphere 5.5 SSO install in a HA configuration - however, many companies are making the move to the latest version of vSphere and don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to maintain a 5.5 HA SSO instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unable to connect NSX to Lookup Service when using a vSphere 6 subordinate certificate authority (VMCA)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/06/unable-to-connect-nsx-to-lookup-service-when-using-a-vsphere-6-subordinate-certificate-authority-vmca/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 12:26:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/06/unable-to-connect-nsx-to-lookup-service-when-using-a-vsphere-6-subordinate-certificate-authority-vmca/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After deploying a new vSphere 6 vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) and configuring the Platform Services Controller (PSC) to act as a subordinate Certificate Authority (CS), I was unable to register the NSX Manager to the Lookup Service. Try saying that fast after a pint or two!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attempting to register NSX to the Lookup Service would result in the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSX Management Service operation failed.( Initialization of Admin Registration Service Provider failed. Root Cause: Error occurred while registration of lookup service, com.vmware.vim.vmomi.core.exception.CertificateValidationException: Server certificate chain not verified )&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>