<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VSAN on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vsan/</link><description>Recent content in VSAN on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vsan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lab Guide - Kubernetes and Storage with the vSphere Cloud Provider - Step by Step</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/06/lab-guide-kubernetes-and-storage-with-the-vsphere-cloud-provider-step-by-step/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/06/lab-guide-kubernetes-and-storage-with-the-vsphere-cloud-provider-step-by-step/</guid><description>Following on from me recent post deploying Kubernetes with the NSX-T CNP, I wanted to extend my environment to make use of the vSphere Cloud Provider to enable Persistent Volumes backed by vSphere storage. This allows me to use Storage Policy to create Persistent Volumes based on policy. For example, I’m going to create two classes of storage, Fast and Slow - Fast will be vSAN based and Slow will be NFS based.</description></item><item><title>One Node vSAN Lab Host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/12/one-node-vsan-lab-host/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 12:43:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/12/one-node-vsan-lab-host/</guid><description>A little while ago I replaced my three ageing Intel NUC hosts with a single (still ageing) Dell T7500 workstation. The workstation provides 24 processor cores and 96GB RAM for a really reasonable price, while still being quiet enough to sit in my home office. One of the driving factors in retiring the old NUCs was vSAN - I know in the newer generations of NUC you can get an M2 and a SATA SSD in, but my 1st gen.</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Sunday and Monday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-1-and-2-sunday-and-monday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 13:29:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-1-and-2-sunday-and-monday/</guid><description>Sunday Arriving in early on Sunday as the local flight choices are more limited from Bristol than perhaps a larger Airport, very fortunate to have a hotel so close to the VMworld venue, perhaps not so great for the evening activities but I am happy with it this way around.
Other than registration (4pm-8pm) and hopefully catching up with a few folk who have also arrived early.
In the evening I had the pleasure to meet many awesome people from the vCommunity.</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: vSAN Specialist and VMware {Code} Hackathon</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-vsan-specialist-and-vmware-code-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 10:41:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-vsan-specialist-and-vmware-code-hackathon/</guid><description>VMware vSAN 2017 Specialist Exam I always like to take a discounted exam at VMworld, this year I opted for the VMware vSAN 2017 Specialist exam, which was released a few weeks ago. Having delivered quite a few vSAN based solutions over the last few years, I was fairly confident in the blueprint. I am pleased to say that I passed the exam with a score of 422, way higher than I expected!</description></item><item><title>#vSAN Cache Performance Dashboard in #vROps</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/02/vsan-cache-performance-dashboard-in-vrops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 14:09:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/02/vsan-cache-performance-dashboard-in-vrops/</guid><description>I have recently been able to get vSAN properly up and running in my lab and took a look at the OOTB Dashboards that come with the MPSD (Management Pack for Storage Devices).
As I have a hybrid build (I know many have All Flash Arrays) I was interested in how hard my Flash Cache was working so I built a dashboard purely focused on this aspect of the vSAN product.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator Workflow: shutdownVSANCluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vro-shutdownvsancluster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 13:21:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vro-shutdownvsancluster/</guid><description>My vSphere lab is split into two halves - a low power management cluster, powered by 3 Intel NUCs, and a more hefty workload cluster powered by a Dell C6100 chassis with 3 nodes. The workload servers are noisy and power hungry so they tend to be powered off when I am not using them, and since they live in my garage, I power them on and off remotely.
To automate the process, I wanted to write an Orchestrator workflow (vRO sits on my management cluster and is therefore always on) that could safely and robustly shut down the workload cluster.</description></item><item><title>vSphere Web Client – VSAN is Turned Off – Edit button disappears</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/09/vsphere-web-client-vsan-is-turned-off-edit-button-disappears/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 16:10:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/09/vsphere-web-client-vsan-is-turned-off-edit-button-disappears/</guid><description>I ran into a strange one with my lab today where the previously working VSAN cluster couldn&amp;rsquo;t be enabled. Symptoms included:
The button to enable VSAN was missing from vSphere Web Client vsphere_client_virgo.log had the following error: [2016-09-16T14:49:03.473Z] [ERROR] http-bio-9090-exec-18 70001918 100023 200008 com.vmware.vise.data.query.impl.DataServiceImpl Error occurred while executing query:
QuerySpec
QueryName: dam-auto-generated: ConfigureVsanActionResolver:dr-57
ResourceSpec
Constraint: ObjectIdentityConstraint
TargetType: ClusterComputeResource</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 Lab Upgrade – VSAN</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-vsan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 11:16:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-vsan/</guid><description>I tested vSphere 6 quite intensively when it was in beta, but I didn’t ever upgrade my lab – basically because I need a stable environment to work on and I wasn’t sure that I could maintain that with the beta.
Now 6 has been GA a while and I have a little bit of time, I have begun the lab upgrade process. You can see a bit more about my lab hardware over on my lab page.</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 Lab Upgrade – Overview</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 19:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-overview/</guid><description>I tested vSphere 6 quite intensively when it was in beta, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t ever upgrade my lab - basically because I need a stable environment to work on and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure that I could maintain that with the beta.
Now 6 has been GA a while and I have a little bit of time, I have begun the lab upgrade process. You can see a bit more about my lab hardware over on my lab page.</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2014: Day Three and wrap-up</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-three-and-wrap-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 09:05:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-three-and-wrap-up/</guid><description>*This post was meant to be published on Friday, VMworld Sleep Deprivation meant I didn&amp;rsquo;t click the button!*
This is the last post and a bit of a wrap up on my VMworld 2014 series!
There isn&amp;rsquo;t a keynote on day three, and there&amp;rsquo;s definitely a &amp;ldquo;winding down&amp;rdquo; feel as people tend to arrive later (if at all) and many are…feeling the effects of the previous night shall we say! That said, every session I wanted to attend was still fully booked and it was a case of queuing for the spare seats.</description></item><item><title>VMware #vForum London and bloggers VSAN/vCHS lunch</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vmware-vforum-london-and-bloggers-vsanvchs-lunch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 15:35:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vmware-vforum-london-and-bloggers-vsanvchs-lunch/</guid><description>Fairly recently i attended the annual VMware vForum London 2014 at Wembley stadium!
If you have never been to a vForum i would certainly recommend it as it offers the chance to not only attend excellent and pertinent sessions but there is also the opportunity to network and visit the large vendor hall which as ever was a busy place!
 Keynote and sessions The opening keynote by @joebaguley (Joe Baguley) was excellent and as challenging as ever one aspect that stood out to me personally was the question &amp;ldquo;where are you on your journey?</description></item><item><title>What about VSAN for SMB/SME?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/what-about-vsan-for-smbsme/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 15:30:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/what-about-vsan-for-smbsme/</guid><description>Unless you have been sleeping under a rock you will be aware that VSAN was launched last week and has gone GA today and from what I have seen so far I do think VSAN is a great product and I think VMware have done a superb job with it.
Aside from the -many- discussions on twitter and other channels regarding the then lack of licensing information and pricing I was eager to see if VMware would offer a &amp;ldquo;foundation&amp;rdquo; VSAN option for SMB/SME</description></item></channel></rss>