<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows Server 2008 on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/windows-server-2008/</link><description>Recent content in Windows Server 2008 on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 12:27:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/windows-server-2008/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Requesting SCOM 2007 Gateway or Agent Certificates for Server 2008 from a Server 2003 Enterprise Certificate Authority</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/06/requesting-scom-2007-gateway-or-agent-certificates-for-server-2008-from-a-server-2003-enterprise-certificate-authority/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 12:27:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/06/requesting-scom-2007-gateway-or-agent-certificates-for-server-2008-from-a-server-2003-enterprise-certificate-authority/</guid><description>This is a pretty specific set of instructions for a specific environment:
If
you are using Microsoft System Center Operations Manager 2007
and
you have a Microsoft Certificate Services 2003 Certificate Authority on your domain
and
you have non-domain Windows Server 2008 servers you wish to monitor or set up as a gateway server.
 Getting a certificate for either a Gateway Server or remotely monitored Server can be a touch vexing.</description></item><item><title>Unable to access admin shares (c$, d$, ADMIN$, IPC$) on Windows Server 2008 in a Workgroup</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/06/unable-to-access-admin-shares-c-d-admin-ipc-on-windows-server-2008-in-a-workgroup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2010 10:07:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/06/unable-to-access-admin-shares-c-d-admin-ipc-on-windows-server-2008-in-a-workgroup/</guid><description>If you have a Windows Server 2008 box in a workgroup that you require access to one of the admin shares, it can be a little more complicated than with Server 2003. In my case, we had a SQL server on the back end which was trying to access the web server in the DMZ using PSExec.exe to remotely run a process. Executing PSExec and passing the correct credentials failed with “Access is Denied”.</description></item><item><title>Server 2008 – Reporting Services Error The permissions granted to user DOMAIN\USER are insufficient for performing this operation. (rsAccessDenied)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/04/server-2008-reporting-services-error-the-permissions-granted-to-user-domainuser-are-insufficient-for-performing-this-operation-rsaccessdenied/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 08:52:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/04/server-2008-reporting-services-error-the-permissions-granted-to-user-domainuser-are-insufficient-for-performing-this-operation-rsaccessdenied/</guid><description>If you install Reporting Services on Windows Server 2008 (RTM or R2) and attempt to verify the installation by opening the http://SERVER/ReportServer site, you may well see the following message:
Reporting Services Error -------------------------------------------------------------------------------- The permissions granted to user &amp;lsquo;MCGEOWN\Sam.McGeown&amp;rsquo; are insufficient for performing this operation. (rsAccessDenied) Get Online Help
SQL Server Reporting Services
Additionally, you may be able to access the http://SERVER/Reports site, but will have no permissions:</description></item><item><title>Configuring Server 2008 R2 Core Series: Installing and Managing IIS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-installing-and-managing-iis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 16:52:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-installing-and-managing-iis/</guid><description>So, you’ve installed a new server with Server 2008 R2 Core – what next? Logging on, you’re presented with a shiny command prompt, you can run notepad or regedit…but aside from that, where do you go from there? In the next few series of posts I’ll hopefully point out the basics, and some not so basics!
In this post, I’m covering Installing the IIS web server (and a few useful bits) and managing it from the IIS Management Snap-in.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Server 2008 R2 Core Series: Management Tasks</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-management-tasks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 15:41:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-management-tasks/</guid><description>So, you’ve installed a new server with Server 2008 R2 Core – what next? Logging on, you’re presented with a shiny command prompt, you can run notepad or regedit…but aside from that, where do you go from there? In the next few series of posts I’ll hopefully point out the basics, and some not so basics!
I’m going to look at some management tasks – the bread and butter of being a Windows admin.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Server 2008 R2 Core Series: Network Settings</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-network-settings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 14:22:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-network-settings/</guid><description>So, you’ve installed a new server with Server 2008 R2 Core – what next? Logging on, you’re presented with a shiny command prompt, you can run notepad or regedit…but aside from that, where do you go from there? In the next few series of posts I’ll hopefully point out the basics, and some not so basics!
Using the Server Configuration Tool The server configuration tool (sconfig.cmd) is provided in R2 for some of the basic setup tasks, so you can run that by issuing the “sconfig” command.</description></item><item><title>MCITP: Server Administrator and MCITP: Enterprise Administrator</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/mcitp-server-administrator-and-mcitp-enterprise-administrator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2010 10:35:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/mcitp-server-administrator-and-mcitp-enterprise-administrator/</guid><description>I’m pleased to say that yesterday I took and passed two Microsoft Certified IT Professional exams, the Server Administrator (70-646) and the Enterprise Administrator (70-647). Hopefully I can take a bit of a break from study and write a few more technical posts here now!</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Server 2008 RTM-SP2 to Server 2008 R2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/upgrading-server-2008-rtm-sp2-to-server-2008-r2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 15:06:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/upgrading-server-2008-rtm-sp2-to-server-2008-r2/</guid><description>If you read the Microsoft blurb for R2, the first thing you notice is that Server 2008 R2 is 64-bit only(!). It seems Microsoft are forcibly removing 32-bit server hardware from the data centre. I’ve not seen a decent upgrade guide online so far, so here’s my process.
I’m going to be upgrading a Server 2008 R2 x64 SP2 Standard Edition virtual server to R2. To see what editions can and can’t be upgraded, check out this Technet Article, but it’s safe to say that you can’t upgrade across architectures (32-bit to 64-bit) and you can’t downgrade SKUs (Enterprise to Standard).</description></item><item><title>Creating a Windows Server 2008 Microsoft Cluster Service SQL Active/Passive Cluster on a single ESXi 4.0 Server</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/01/creating-a-windows-server-2008-microsoft-cluster-service-sql-activepassive-cluster-on-a-single-esxi-4-0-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 14:52:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/01/creating-a-windows-server-2008-microsoft-cluster-service-sql-activepassive-cluster-on-a-single-esxi-4-0-server/</guid><description>Configuring the Virtual Environment and Virtual Machines Note – this configuration will work for ESXi 4 upwards due to the server 2008 MSCS requirement for persistent SCSI-3 reservations.
The first step is to create a new vSwitch for the host-only cluster heartbeat network, don’t assign any network adaptors to the switch as it’s going to be local only.
Create a new virtual machine with a single hard disk. For the purposes of this test, I’ve assigned 2 vProcessors, 1GB RAM, 30GB drive for the OS, 1 vNIC in the default vSwitch0.</description></item><item><title>Multi-homed Domain controller logs Event ID 1030 and 1058</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/multi-homed-domain-controller-logs-event-id-1030-and-1058/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/multi-homed-domain-controller-logs-event-id-1030-and-1058/</guid><description>I recently had an issue where a hosting environment was registering a lot of Netlogon Event 1030/1058 issues, being unable to find the Group Policy objects or download them. In this example, the server DC is the domain controller for DOMAIN.LCL.
_Event Type: Error
Event Source: Userenv
Event Category: None
Event ID: 1030
Date: 10/09/2009
Time: 06:24:29
User: NT AUTHORITY\SYSTEM</description></item><item><title>Windows Vista Local Area Network Connection “Authentication Failed”</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/01/windows-vista-local-area-network-connection-%E2%80%9Cauthentication-failed%E2%80%9D/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 13:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/01/windows-vista-local-area-network-connection-%E2%80%9Cauthentication-failed%E2%80%9D/</guid><description>If you’re getting a error on your LAN connection it’s possible that your network connection is attempting 802.11 authentication on your wired network. Unfortunately, it seems that Vista/Server 2008 both attempt it before reverting. As far as I can see, it’s not causing any issues, other than irritating me with a “failed” and a red question mark.
Fortunately, it’s pretty easy to fix! The authentication is handled by the Wired AutoConfig service, so it’s just a case of disabling it.</description></item></channel></rss>