<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vCSA on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcsa/</link><description>Recent content in vCSA on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 15:23:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcsa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vSphere 6 Lab Upgrade – vCenter Server Appliance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-vcenter-server-appliance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 15:23:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-vcenter-server-appliance/</guid><description>I tested vSphere 6 quite intensively when it was in beta, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t ever upgrade my lab - basically because I need a stable environment to work on and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure that I could maintain that with the beta.
Now 6 has been GA a while and I have a little bit of time, I have begun the lab upgrade process. You can see a bit more about my lab hardware over on my lab page.</description></item><item><title>Slow or failed logon to VCSA 5.5 with vCOps in the environment</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/slow-or-failed-logon-to-vcsa-5-5-with-vcops-in-the-environment/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 09:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/slow-or-failed-logon-to-vcsa-5-5-with-vcops-in-the-environment/</guid><description>Recently I encountered this problem in a customer site whereby the logon to VCSA 5.5 would either time out, or take 3-5 minutes to actually log on.
Running a netstat on the VCSA during the attempt to logon showed there was a SYN packet sent to the vCOps appliance on port 443 that never established a connection. Another check was attempting to connect using curl &amp;lt;https://&amp;gt; –k - this would time out.</description></item><item><title>VCSA 5.5 Web Client fails to log on with &amp;ldquo;SSL certificate verification failed&amp;rdquo;</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/vcsa-5-5-web-client-fails-to-log-on-with-ssl-certificate-verification-failed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 16:13:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/vcsa-5-5-web-client-fails-to-log-on-with-ssl-certificate-verification-failed/</guid><description>This had me scratching my head, what seemed to be a common problem wasn’t fixed by the common solution. It was actually my fault – too familiar with the product and setting things up too quickly to test.
I installed a VCSA 5.5 instance in my lab as a secondary site for some testing and during the process found I couldn’t log on to the web client – it failed with the error:</description></item><item><title>vCSA 5.5 won’t join AD Domain‏</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/vcsa-5-5-wont-join-ad-domain%E2%80%8F/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 15:44:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/vcsa-5-5-wont-join-ad-domain%E2%80%8F/</guid><description>Just a quick post on something that was not immediately obvious when it happened to me.
When deploying vCSA 5.5 and trying to add it to the domain, I was presented with the following error.
I immediately did all the all the usual checks, making sure it had a static IP and correct DNS servers etc..
The one thing missing however was a FQDN for the hostname (in the network tab).</description></item></channel></rss>