<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogging on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/blogging/</link><description>Recent content in Blogging on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using GitLab Pipelines to deploy Hugo sites to AWS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/using-gitlab-pipelines-to-deploy-hugo-sites-to-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/using-gitlab-pipelines-to-deploy-hugo-sites-to-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve posted previously about &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/"&gt;
 moving to Hugo as a publishing platform for this blog
&lt;/a&gt;, this post is a bit more about how I&amp;rsquo;m managing the publishing using GitLab&amp;rsquo;s CI/CD Pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I need to mention that I&amp;rsquo;m using three different repositories for my code base, and why. The three repositories are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;definit-hugo - this contains the hugo site configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;definit-content - this contains the site content - markdown files, images etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;definit-theme - this contains the VMware Clarity-based theme I use for my site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;definit-content&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;definit-theme&lt;/strong&gt; are git submodules in the &lt;strong&gt;definit-hugo&lt;/strong&gt; project, mapped into the /content and /themes folders respectively. This allows me to keep the configuration, content and theme separate, and to manage them as separate entities. The aim is that the theme will eventually be in a position to be released, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to extract it from my hugo code base later on.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Goodbye Wordpress, hello Hugo!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I started my blog back in May 2007 (12 years ago!) I was running Wordpress, then switched to DotNetNuke, then BlogEngine, then finally back to Wordpress - which I&amp;rsquo;ve used since 2010. Today I&amp;rsquo;ve cut over to a new architecture based on Hugo and hosted on AWS using a combination of Route53, Cloudfront and S3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-the-change-if-it-aint-broke"&gt;Why the change? If it ain&amp;rsquo;t broke&amp;hellip; &lt;a class="anchor" href="#why-the-change-if-it-aint-broke"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may well ask why I&amp;rsquo;ve made the move, or you may not&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you anyway&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware Clarity based WordPress Theme – v0.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/06/vmware-clarity-based-wordpress-theme-v0-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 21:12:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/06/vmware-clarity-based-wordpress-theme-v0-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago I saw a tweet from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/codydearkland" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Cody De Arkland
&lt;/a&gt; showing his new tweaked VMware Clarity based theme on his website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Staying up until 3am to get the brisket on, so what do I do? Work on tuning up &lt;a href="https://t.co/YDiFkGIKLY"&gt;https://t.co/YDiFkGIKLY&lt;/a&gt; with some better &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VMwareClarity?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@VMwareClarity&lt;/a&gt; styling! Check out the differences below! Subtle changes but I think it&amp;#39;s a lot better. Thoughts? &lt;a href="https://t.co/6sYnuBahwI"&gt;pic.twitter.com/6sYnuBahwI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Cody De Arkland (@Codydearkland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Codydearkland/status/1008269216049291264?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 17, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Cody has gone down the route of using Hugo and AWS, which I respect, but just seems like too much work for me at the moment! I am familiar with WordPress, and Simon is barely computer literate at the best of times, so I can&amp;rsquo;t ask him to start writing in markdown. But I did want some of this Clarity goodness - so I set about learning how to create a WordPress theme, and how to integrate Clarity with this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>GDPR, blogging and DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/05/gdpr-blogging-and-definit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 20:46:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/05/gdpr-blogging-and-definit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So…this is a frustrated sort of post. As you are most likely to already know, the new data protection laws (GDPR) are coming into effect on the 25th May 2018. I must emphasise that &lt;strong&gt;I am not an expert on GDPR&lt;/strong&gt;, this post is my layman’s conclusion for my specific circumstances. I run this blog as an exercise to help others, provide information and as a hobby. There is a lot of speculation around how this will affect bloggers, and a lot of panic and mis-information too. I’ve seen a few people this week simply shut down and delete their blogs - which is both upsetting and sad.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Heading to Las Vegas! #VMworld 2016</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/heading-to-vmworld-us-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 10:24:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/heading-to-vmworld-us-2016/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if I’ll take advantage of the cheap certifications this year - in previous years I’ve take &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vcix-nv-exam-experience/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; VCIX-NV
&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; VCP-NV
&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-day-2-vcap5-dcd-exam-experience/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; VCAP5-DCD
&lt;/a&gt; all with great results, so it’s something I’d consider, although at this point I’m not 100% sure what exam I’d take (I’ve done a lot of betas recently!)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>In response to @h0bbel: The "vCommunity"</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/in-response-to-h0bbel-the-vcommunity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 07:43:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/in-response-to-h0bbel-the-vcommunity/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is not my normal sort of post - don&amp;rsquo;t worry, normal service will resume shortly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Christian&amp;rsquo;s comments on the vCommunity&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; - or lack of it - yesterday and although some things resonate with me, and a lot of other people, I don&amp;rsquo;t quite agree. I want to be clear this is a response to Christian and not an argument, I respect Christian as someone who &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; contribute to the vCommunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Definit authors awarded vExpert 2014</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/definit-authors-awarded-vexpert-2014/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 22:19:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/definit-authors-awarded-vexpert-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2013/06/vExpert.jpg" alt=""&gt;It was with great honor both Sam and I were awarded vExpert 2014 (my first and Sam&amp;rsquo;s second award!) we are both proud to be listed alongside so many others in the vExpert programme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the announcement and the full list here - &lt;a href="http://blogs.vmware.com/vmtn/2014/04/vexpert-2014-announcement.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; http://blogs.vmware.com/vmtn/2014/04/vexpert-2014-announcement.html
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2014: what does the future look like?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/2014-what-does-the-future-look-like/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 09:46:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/2014-what-does-the-future-look-like/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After attending the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.vmwareemeablog.com/events-uk/hangout-with-joe-baguley-and-paul-saffo-to-hear-them-discuss-technology-past-present-and-future-1" title="Hangout with Joe Baguley and Paul Saffo to hear them discuss technology past, present and future" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Future of IT
&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; Google hangout in September, I was asked to give a quick summary on what 2014 may hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So without further ado..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I believe in 2014, we will see an increased demand for - and usage of - hybrid clouds, especially among SMEs who are trying to avoid large investment on private clouds to accommodate high demand, short term projects.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Welcome to DefinIT!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/02/welcome-to-definit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 11:27:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/02/welcome-to-definit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2011/02/wordpress_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;If you’ve been here before, you may have noticed a couple of changes – the theme and name of this blog for example, and hopefully you’ve been redirected to a new URL! There are a couple of reasons for the changes, all of which are aimed at increasing the presence and visitor numbers on this site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Branding. Whether I like it or not, “McGeown” is not easy to spell or remember so I wanted to move away from it as an identity. After some discussion with my friend and creative advisor &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Matt Hellyer&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, I picked DefinIT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’d like to add some more bloggers to the site – the number of visitors is directly in proportion to the number of posts, and I can’t post as much as I’d like to. I will introduce those bloggers as and when they arrive, but they will be people I know and trust – with real technical expertise. (That said, if you’re reading and are interested in writing for DefinIT, please contact me!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eventually I’d like to use McGeown.co.uk for a more personal site, aimed at family and friends. That’s what it was originally aimed at, and hopefully one of these days I’ll get the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to let me know what you think about the new theme, new name and new URL in the comments below. This blog will always be dedicated to providing high quality IT help on a broad range of subjects, as ever, I hope it helps!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Wordle word cloud of McGeown.co.uk</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/09/wordle-word-cloud-of-mcgeown-co-uk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 09:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/09/wordle-word-cloud-of-mcgeown-co-uk/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Wordle.net&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; is a great little site that’s been around for ages – but it gives quite a unique insight into the content of your blog – just shove the RSS feed in and out comes a nice word cloud. I found it interesting to compare this to the Tag cloud generated from how I tagged my posts – for example Exchange is the predominant word in the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Wordle.net&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;  cloud – but not in the tag cloud. Update and upgrade were some obvious ones, I expected install or installing to feature more heavily. There’s also a random Kevin in there!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why I&amp;rsquo;ve changed my blogging software from BlogEngine.Net to WordPress</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/07/why-ive-changed-my-bogging-software-from-blogengine-net-to-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 10:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/07/why-ive-changed-my-bogging-software-from-blogengine-net-to-wordpress/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/09/wordpress_thumb1.jpg" alt=""&gt; Up until now, I’ve been using BlogEngine.Net as my blogging platform, and up until now I’ve been relatively happy with using it. One of the major drivers for me as a “Microsoft” person was to use something that is based on Microsoft technology – &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;BlogEngine.Net&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; is based (as the name suggests) on the .Net framework. I’m much happier these days writing limited amounts of C#.Net than I am with PHP.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>