<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>opinion on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/opinion/</link><description>Recent content in opinion on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:58:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why do IT projects struggle or fail?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/why-do-it-projects-struggle-or-fail/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:58:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/why-do-it-projects-struggle-or-fail/</guid><description>Why do IT projects fail?
I am sure if you ask that question to ten people you will get 10 different answers, or at the very least a wide variety of reasons. The product chosen to deliver the solution was a poor match, the product was implemented incorrectly, the PM sucked, the Vendor gave no support, insufficient training material/resources, poor interoperability, the list goes on and on.
One issue I have observed from time to time on my travels is quite different from the above listed examples.</description></item><item><title>There is no one cloud solution to rule them all..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/there-is-no-one-cloud-solution-to-rule-them-all/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 17:01:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/there-is-no-one-cloud-solution-to-rule-them-all/</guid><description>I have been musing this a little while and decided to write this post/rant/opinion post, feel free to post your thoughts and opinions in the comments.
OK so here it is, one thing I have observed for a good while now is how much noise there is about how -you- should be in the cloud (Public) and if you are not you&amp;rsquo;re already dead.
I call Bull****!
Public, Hybrid and Private clouds are solutions not final destinations, regardless of whether you are a customer, partner, or any other third thing you should be purely focused on what is best for you or (if you provide IT services) your customer.</description></item><item><title>When everyones an Architect.. no one is..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/when-everyones-an-architect-no-one-is/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 10:34:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/when-everyones-an-architect-no-one-is/</guid><description>I think this is the first time I have written a &amp;ldquo;rant&amp;rdquo; post (for a while at least) so if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear me whine run away now!
In the past 12 months I think I have met more folk with Architect in their job title than I truly believe is valid. Now I will be clear this is not a slight on the individuals all of them have been exceptional (at least the ones I have had the pleasure to work with).</description></item></channel></rss>