<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows Vista on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/windows-vista/</link><description>Recent content in Windows Vista on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 11:58:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/windows-vista/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Trace cables the easy way with Cisco CDP on Windows</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/trace-cables-the-easy-way-with-cisco-cdp-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 11:58:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/trace-cables-the-easy-way-with-cisco-cdp-on-windows/</guid><description>No matter how good your network diagrams are, sometimes you need to verify the port your server/desktop is in. Cisco Discovery Protocol is a great tool for network admins when you need to quickly map routers and switches, and if you’ve got an ESX server connected you’ll see that it picks up CDP info too – but the vast majority of my managed systems are Windows.
Here’s how to use TCPDUMP by Micro Olap to extend that functionality to your Windows boxes.</description></item><item><title>How to force the removal of Folder Redirection from specific user accounts</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/04/how-to-force-the-removal-of-folder-redirection-from-specific-user-accounts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 11:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/04/how-to-force-the-removal-of-folder-redirection-from-specific-user-accounts/</guid><description>We have a folder redirection policy in place for all of our users in combination with a roaming profile policy - this policy is applied to the OU that contains our users. Unfortunately this policy was accidently linked to the root of our domain too, causing our Domain Admin users to be redirected too - something we do not want. When the mistake was discovered, the policy was unlinked, but the redirection remained (despite being set to revert when users fall out of scope).</description></item><item><title>Windows Vista Local Area Network Connection “Authentication Failed”</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/01/windows-vista-local-area-network-connection-%E2%80%9Cauthentication-failed%E2%80%9D/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 13:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/01/windows-vista-local-area-network-connection-%E2%80%9Cauthentication-failed%E2%80%9D/</guid><description>If you’re getting a error on your LAN connection it’s possible that your network connection is attempting 802.11 authentication on your wired network. Unfortunately, it seems that Vista/Server 2008 both attempt it before reverting. As far as I can see, it’s not causing any issues, other than irritating me with a “failed” and a red question mark.
Fortunately, it’s pretty easy to fix! The authentication is handled by the Wired AutoConfig service, so it’s just a case of disabling it.</description></item><item><title>Activating Microsoft Reader on a Windows Mobile 5 device under Vista</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/10/activating-microsoft-reader-on-a-windows-mobile-5-device-under-vista/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 14:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/10/activating-microsoft-reader-on-a-windows-mobile-5-device-under-vista/</guid><description>I recently tried to use Microsoft reader on my iMate K-Jam mobile, it&amp;rsquo;s Windows Mobile 5 powered, so according to Microsoft it&amp;rsquo;s fully supported. However, when I tried to activate, I got the following error:
&amp;ldquo;You have an older version of Pocket PC which does not support Activation&amp;rdquo;
Not true I cried, and after a lot of Google-ing and trying various different fixes that are posted on the net, I found the only one that actually worked for me!</description></item><item><title>Vista DVD/CDRW drive message "Prepare this blank disk"</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/10/vista-dvdcdrw-drive-message-prepare-this-blank-disk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 10:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/10/vista-dvdcdrw-drive-message-prepare-this-blank-disk/</guid><description>For a little while now I&amp;rsquo;ve had an irritating problem with my Vista laptop. Whenever I insert a DVD, CD of any kind, pops up the message asking me to prepare a blank disk:
It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to access the files on the disc and I don&amp;rsquo;t want Vista trying to &amp;ldquo;prepare&amp;rdquo; my data disc. Quite irritating, but not irritating enough to fix right away.
Microsoft have a KB article about it, which has worked in some cases, but not in most.</description></item><item><title>Vista .msu installer fails with error: Installer encountered an error: 0×80070422</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/09/vista-msu-installer-fails-with-error-installer-encountered-an-error-0x80070422/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 10:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/09/vista-msu-installer-fails-with-error-installer-encountered-an-error-0x80070422/</guid><description>I needed to use PowerShell for something today on my Vista laptop, but was unable to install the file. I had the normal UAC permission required when I ran it, but then it failed with this error
Installer encountered an error: 0x80070422
The service cannot be started, either because it is disabled or because it
has no enabled devices associated with it.
It turns out that you need to enable the Windows Update service in order to use an MSU file.</description></item><item><title>Create a 100Mb file for testing transfer speeds</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/create-a-100mb-file-for-testing-transfer-speeds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2008 10:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/create-a-100mb-file-for-testing-transfer-speeds/</guid><description>We have a Bonded ADSL solution for our servers to provide the necessary upstream transfer speeds for the applications we host. We have bonded ADSL because our exchange still doesn&amp;rsquo;t support SDSL, and a leased line is overkill. Theoretically, we should have 28.1 Mbps download and 3.2Mbps upload - what I am actually seeing is about 1.7Mbps down and 1.9Mbps up. I have tested this on various servers, over various times and file sizes, there is no doubt that the performance is POOR.</description></item><item><title>Outlook Web Access over SSL using Forms Based Authentication AND Integrated Authentication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/outlook-web-access-over-ssl-using-forms-based-authentication-and-integrated-authentication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/outlook-web-access-over-ssl-using-forms-based-authentication-and-integrated-authentication/</guid><description>Outlook Web access is a fantastic tool for our company, providing on-the-go
access to people&amp;rsquo;s mailboxes - which is of course secured by SSL and uses Forms
Based Authentication. Internally, we have an intranet portal that allows us to
access the various systems - one of which is OWA. One of the stipulations for
this internal portal is that it is all Single Sign On using NTLM authentication
integrated authentication. This is where the problem lies because enabling OWA with Forms Based Authentication over SSL disables Integrated Authentication.</description></item><item><title>Update your Windows Search or Windows Desktop Search</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/update-your-windows-search-or-windows-desktop-search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/update-your-windows-search-or-windows-desktop-search/</guid><description>I noticed a post over at David Overton&amp;rsquo;s blog today that highlights a new release of Windows Search. Normally not that exciting, but it is if you&amp;rsquo;re using Outlook to open up another users mailbox.
I have quite a few mailboxes that are opened for historical reasons, people leave a company and I need access to their email. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to bloat my mailbox with all their email, it&amp;rsquo;s hard enough to find my own emails!</description></item><item><title>Windows Vista shows black screen and the cursor before log in.</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/windows-vista-shows-black-screen-and-the-cursor-before-log-in/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2008 21:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/windows-vista-shows-black-screen-and-the-cursor-before-log-in/</guid><description>Had an interesting one yesterday, my bosses Vista laptop booted as per normal, making all the right pictures until just before the log in prompt popped up, then a black screen in what looked to be VGA graphics with the white default arrow cursor.
Corrupted graphics drivers, I thought. A quick boot into safe mode…but no, the same black screen and over-sized pointer.
No problem, Last Known Good Configuration will save my day…except that LKGC points are set when the OS manages a successful boot, and Vista had, in it&amp;rsquo;s own opinion, successfully booted.</description></item><item><title>Installing on Vista: Error 1327 invalid drive when using mapped drives</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/11/installing-on-vista-error-1327-invalid-drive-when-using-mapped-drives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2007 19:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/11/installing-on-vista-error-1327-invalid-drive-when-using-mapped-drives/</guid><description>Incredibly irritating error when you go to install under your user account when you’re using mapped drives for your documents. All our domain users have a userfolder on the server, it’s mapped as z:\ and there is a folder redirection set up. It’s pretty standard in a corporate/domain environment, so why does it cause so many Vista installations to fail?
&amp;nbsp; This is something I&amp;rsquo;ve run into time and time again and There are a couple of things you can try&amp;hellip;sometimes they work individually, sometimes not!</description></item><item><title>I’m qualified!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/10/i%E2%80%99m-qualified/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2007 19:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/10/i%E2%80%99m-qualified/</guid><description>It’s been a while since I’ve posted here, that’s for various reasons, one of which was that I have been preparing for, and taking, my MCSA exams. So here it is…
MCTS Windows Vista, Configuring (70-620)&amp;nbsp; MCP Managing and Maintaining a Windows Server 2003 Environment (70-290) MCP Implementing, Managing and Maintaining a Windows Server 2003 Network Infrastructure&amp;nbsp;(70-291) CompTIA Security+ (SYO-101) Which all add up to an MCSA Windows Server 2003 Security+.</description></item><item><title>iTunes crashes on startup under Vista</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/07/itunes-crashes-on-startup-under-vista/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2007 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/07/itunes-crashes-on-startup-under-vista/</guid><description>I had an odd problem today, I logged on to begin my day&amp;rsquo;s work and plugged in my iPod as per normal. iTunes crashes, Vista tries to recover. iTunes closes. iTunes opens. iTunes crashes. Vista tries to recover. As you can imagine that gets tiresome, so I tried repairing iTunes, reinstalling iTunes, installing older versions of iTunes, all to no avail. The solution in the end was to remove Quicktime and do a fresh install.</description></item><item><title>Installing Visual Studio 2003 SP1 on Vista</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/06/installing-visual-studio-2003-sp1-on-vista/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2007 19:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/06/installing-visual-studio-2003-sp1-on-vista/</guid><description>I’ve finally cracked the installation problems with VS 2003 SP1 on Vista. The problem seems to be that the SP must be installed under the same credentials that Visual Studio was installed. I.e. I installed Visual Studio under the domain administrator credentials, but I run my day-to-day under a standard user credential. When installing the SP1 I was elevating my standard user credential rather than running as the domain admin. I don’t know what difference that makes to anything, but it’s worked!</description></item><item><title>Windows Server 2003 Admin tools under Vista</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/06/windows-server-2003-admin-tools-under-vista/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 19:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/06/windows-server-2003-admin-tools-under-vista/</guid><description>If, like me, you want to administrate your Windows 2003 servers from your Vista workstation, you may find that you recieve an &amp;ldquo;MMC could not create snap in&amp;rdquo; error when you open one of the admin tools, it also manifests as&amp;nbsp;corrupted graphics within some MMC Add-ins. It appears that the dlls are not registered correctly, there&amp;rsquo;s a KB article from Microsoft&amp;nbsp;that contains a script to reregister the dlls. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple fix: Copy and paste the following script into a text document, save it as RegisterAdminPack.</description></item><item><title>Installing Visual Studio 2003 on Vista Enterprise</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/06/installing-visual-studio-2003-on-vista-enterprise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 19:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/06/installing-visual-studio-2003-on-vista-enterprise/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s not as easy as you might imagine if you&amp;rsquo;re going to be developing on a local machine. The pre-requisites include IIS and FrontPage Server Extensions which will need installing. Install IIS on Vista Go through Control Panel, Programs and Features, then select &amp;ldquo;Turn Windows features on or off&amp;rdquo; on the left hand menu. The basic installation of Vista from the control panel will not be sufficient for a VS install, you must add&amp;nbsp;IIS Metabase Compatibility (you&amp;rsquo;ll see why later),&amp;nbsp;.</description></item><item><title>Fixing your Windows Vista MBR</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/05/fixing-your-windows-vista-mbr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 19:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/05/fixing-your-windows-vista-mbr/</guid><description>I recently installed Vista as a dual boot with my old XP installation, while I transferred things over and made sure I could do all I need to do with my new Vista install. It came to the point when I needed to remove XP and solely rely on Vista. Some might say that&amp;rsquo;s brave, others foolish, others still insane. Whatever your opinion, I needed the HD space and was having no problems with Vista, so I bit the bullet.</description></item></channel></rss>