<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Authors on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/authors/</link><description>Recent content in Authors on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/authors/sam-mcgeown/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/authors/sam-mcgeown/</guid><description>Sam has been working in the IT industry for nearly 20 years now, and is currently working for VMware as a Senior Technical Marketing Manger in the Cloud Management Business Unit (CMBU) focussed on Automation. Previously, he has worked as consultant for VMware PSO, specializing in cloud automation and network virtualization. His technical experience includes design, development and implementation of cloud solutions, network function virtualisation and the software defined datacentre. Sam specialises in automation of network virtualisation for cloud infrastructure, enabling public cloud solutions for service providers and private or hybrid cloud solutions for the enterprise.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/authors/simon-eady/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/authors/simon-eady/</guid><description>An IT Professional with 20 years’ experience with broad technical and managerial experience, which has enabled him to deliver high quality, correctly scaled, easy to use IT solutions which are on budget and in line with business needs and requirements in any environment.
A leader of the Bristol and South West VMUG (VMware User Group)
Technology Specialities: vRealize Operations Manager (vROps), VMware vSphere, vRealize Automation (vRA), and not to shabby with the rest of the VMware stack.</description></item></channel></rss>