<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VRealize Operations on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/category/vrealize-operations/</link><description>Recent content in VRealize Operations on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/category/vrealize-operations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VMware Aria - Unified Multi-Cloud Management</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2022/09/vmware-aria-unified-multi-cloud-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2022/09/vmware-aria-unified-multi-cloud-management/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;VMWorld, sorry VMware Explore has been and gone and seemed to go very smoothly, there were several announcements but the big one for me was Aria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vmware-aria-formerly-vrealize-cloud-management"&gt;VMware Aria (formerly vRealize Cloud Management) &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vmware-aria-formerly-vrealize-cloud-management"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Cloud management that unifies applications, infrastructure, and services across private, hybrid, and public clouds in a single platform with a common data model.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;With the VMware Aria launch, we are unifying VMware Cloud Management in four key respects:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Operations 8.4 - What's New</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/04/vrealize-operations-8.4-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/04/vrealize-operations-8.4-whats-new/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There has been some really exciting things being announced/relased by VMware and their respective product teams recently so lets take a look at all the new goodness in vRealize Operations 8.4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vrealize-operations-84"&gt;vRealize Operations 8.4 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vrealize-operations-84"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vRealize Operations 8.4 delivers new and enhanced capabilities for self-driving operations to help customers optimize, plan, and scale VMware Cloud, which includes on-premises private cloud or VMware SDDC in multiple public clouds such as VMware Cloud on AWS, Azure VMware Solution (AVS), and Google Cloud VMware Engine (GCVE), while at the same time unifying multi-cloud monitoring, and supporting AWS, Azure Cloud, and Google Cloud platforms. Powered by artificial intelligence (AI), this release will provide a unified operations platform, deliver continuous performance optimization, efficient capacity and cost management, proactive planning, app-aware intelligent remediation, and integrated compliance.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using vRealize Orchestreator MP in vROps</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/using-vrealize-orchestreator-mp-in-vrops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/using-vrealize-orchestreator-mp-in-vrops/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="using-vrealize-orchestreator-mp-in-vrops"&gt;Using vRealize Orchestreator MP in vROps &lt;a class="anchor" href="#using-vrealize-orchestreator-mp-in-vrops"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="product-version---vrealize-operations-7x-and-8x"&gt;Product Version - vRealize Operations 7.x and 8.x &lt;a class="anchor" href="#product-version---vrealize-operations-7x-and-8x"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago VMware released the Orchestrator MP which is a superb way to directly call vRO workflows from vROps by way of alerts and actions. This opens the door to all manner of ideas for conditional automation using vROps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="the-limitation"&gt;The limitation &lt;a class="anchor" href="#the-limitation"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently for a customer we planned to use the vRO MP to assist a customer with a very unique/niche challenge. vRO was a key component to the challenge and we identified a possible solution using the vRO MP in vROPs which for all intents and purposes looked ideal.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vROps Remote Collectors - Design Considerations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/vrops-remote-collectors-design-considerations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/vrops-remote-collectors-design-considerations/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vrops-remote-collectors---design-considerations"&gt;vROps Remote Collectors - Design Considerations &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vrops-remote-collectors---design-considerations"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="product-version---vrealize-operations-7x-and-8x"&gt;Product Version - vRealize Operations 7.x and 8.x &lt;a class="anchor" href="#product-version---vrealize-operations-7x-and-8x"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of VMware Validated Designs tyically you would use Remote Collectors not just in different DCs but also local to the analytics cluster. However there are a circumstances where the rules &amp;ldquo;change&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="when-using-recoverpoint-or-site-recovery-manager"&gt;When using RecoverPoint or Site Recovery Manager &lt;a class="anchor" href="#when-using-recoverpoint-or-site-recovery-manager"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design Assumption - you have Remote Collectors on your Primary Site and on your Failover Site.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vROps Cluster without a Load Balancer (gotchas)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vrops-cluster-without-a-load-balancer-gotchas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vrops-cluster-without-a-load-balancer-gotchas/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vrops-cluster-without-a-load-balancer-gotchas"&gt;vROps Cluster without a Load Balancer (gotchas) &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vrops-cluster-without-a-load-balancer-gotchas"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="product-version---vrealize-operations-75"&gt;Product Version - vRealize Operations 7.5 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#product-version---vrealize-operations-75"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While it is far from recomended to deploy a vROps Cluster without a loadbalancer there are circumstances where this is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently helping a customer deploy a couple of simple issues cropped up that were not immediately obvious as to why they were issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="unable-to-connect-to-master-node-when-expanding-the-cluster"&gt;Unable to connect to Master Node when expanding the cluster &lt;a class="anchor" href="#unable-to-connect-to-master-node-when-expanding-the-cluster"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hit this issue and initialy it was a question mark moment there were no firewalls in the way and network connectivity was good end to end.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Operations 8.1 - What's New</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vrealize-operations-8.1-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vrealize-operations-8.1-whats-new/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;VMware have been very busy in the last few months across many of their products and Operations Management has not gone untouched. We saw glimpses of things to come late last year and now we see the Cloud Management Team in VMware really ramping things up with vRealize Operation 8.1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vrealize-operations-cloud"&gt;vRealize Operations Cloud &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vrealize-operations-cloud"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the bigger items to arrive very shortly is vRealize Operations Cloud (SaaS), this means you do not need to worry about standing vROps up in your environment to see what value it can bring to your infrastructure monitoring. It has the same feature set and UI as the on-premises offering.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Things we can look forward to seeing in #vROps 7.0</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/things-we-can-look-forward-to-seeing-in-vrops-7-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 11:51:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/things-we-can-look-forward-to-seeing-in-vrops-7-0/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I did a quick search online and could not find a collated list so, by way of a quick summary from all the VMworld 2018 announcements and comments my good friend and PM for vRealize Operations &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Sunny Dua
&lt;/a&gt; has made, I have collated a list of what we can expect to see in the next iteration of vROps (7.0). The list is in no order of interest or importance, some of the mentioned improvements have been long standing requests so enjoy and get hyped (I know I am).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.7 – Automate all the things..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrops-6-7-automate-all-the-things/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 12:24:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrops-6-7-automate-all-the-things/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;There are many improvements, changes and new additions to vROps in version 6.7 but one of the aspects that stands out to me personally is the direction VMware are taking with the product. Aside from the obvious addition of cloud costings and comparisons and a reworked capacity planning (from the ground up) and new hook in to  Wavefront (which I really like) there has been some real effort to improve how you can further automate things from vROps.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps data retention and the Cleaner</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrops-data-retention-and-the-cleaner/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 13:36:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrops-data-retention-and-the-cleaner/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Something that has come up with customers recently is why and when old data is cleaned up from your vROps instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will make the assumption that you have your data retention set to 6 months but the process is the same whether the value is less than or greater than 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When data reaches and or goes beyond the age threshold set in the global settings it will be cleaned away by a daily process &amp;ldquo;Old Data Cleaner&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2017 – Part 4 : Optimizing Workload Performance Using Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 10:17:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/03/logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;In this episode, Sunny gave us a deep dive into the WLP and WLB features of vROps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were also joined by a special guest, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/virtualjad" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Jad El-Zein
&lt;/a&gt; who gave us a great insight into how vRA utilises vROps for initial placement of freshly provisioned VMs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We would highly appreciate it if you could spend 30 seconds to fill up this quick and simple survey to provide us your feedback. You can also request topics of your choice through this survey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Tuesday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-3-tuesday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-3-tuesday/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/09/VMworld-2017.jpg" alt=""&gt;I managed to dodge the rainstorms in the morning before arriving, the hotel being just across the road from the Venue was a huge help (Thank you &lt;a href="https://xtravirt.com/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Xtravirt
&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main session was great particularly HCX announcement and the VR admin demo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then hit the solutions exchange as soon as it opened. There are all the usual suspects there -except- Cisco (anyone know why?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also great to see the guys from &lt;a href="https://bluemedora.com/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Blue Medora
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2017 – Announcing Part 4 : Optimizing Workload Performance Using Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-announcing-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 13:18:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-announcing-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/03/logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;In this coming episode, Sunny will DIVE DEEP into the interesting topic of introducing automation into operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we all know that, automating day to day operations tasks is becoming the choice of an IT organization, it is hard for them to find a solution which can completely understand their business policies and provide them the efficiency they need from automating simple operational tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on our research, we found that, one of the most time consuming activity done by an Virtual Infrastructure Administrator is to juggle resources between the changing business requirements and ensure that every VM which is being hosted in their environment is &lt;strong&gt;BEING SERVED WELL&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title> #vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 3 – What’s New with vROps 6.6</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 06:52:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;[&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vRealize Operations Manager 6.6&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, which was recently released by VMware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started with an overview of all the cool new stuff and then drill down into individual areas. We then jumped into a Live Demo as usual to see the new features in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We would highly appreciate if you could spend 30 seconds to fill up this quick and simple survey to provide us your feedback. You can also request topics of your choice through this survey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2017 – Announcing Part 3 : What’s New with #vROps 6.6</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-2017-announcing-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 07:13:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-2017-announcing-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/03/logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;Welcome to the next episode of vRealize Operations Manager Webinar Series. This time around we will talk about the latest release of vROps released in the month of June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this release, VMware has made drastic changes to the product and the initial reviews of the product have been great. Since I was a part of the team delivering this new release, I thought it would be a good topic to discuss in the next episode of the Webinar Series.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 2- Full Stack monitoring with vRealize Operations Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/05/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-2-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 07:18:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/05/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-2-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;[&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-8035&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2017/03/logo.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; which vROps can provide by using various extensibility solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discussed the following use cases and demonstrated them in live environments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Use Case 1 - Full-Stack vSphere Monitoring. From application to Infrastructure.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Use Case 2 - Amazon RDS Workloads. Monitoring public cloud workloads with vROps.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Use Case 3 - vROps Extensibility. Metrics, Logs and Costing come together along with other 3rd party extensibility options.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Can I monitor hardware OOTB with #vROps?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/05/can-i-monitor-hardware-ootb-with-vrops/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 11:42:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/05/can-i-monitor-hardware-ootb-with-vrops/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;So very recently i had a great question from a customer regarding ways to monitor things like the temperature of host systems. Would they need a management pack or is this something vROps can do out of the box?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short answer to this is yes, but it is not immediately obvious how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a great many metrics that come with a vanilla build of vROps but not all of them are enabled a good example of these are the sensor metrics.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Announcing Part 2 – #vROps Webinar series 2017 – “Full Stack” monitoring with vRealize Operations Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/announcing-part-2-vrops-webinar-series-2017-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 07:50:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/announcing-part-2-vrops-webinar-series-2017-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/03/logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;As promised, vROps Webinar Series 2017 is back with the second episode of the year. Last time around we looked closely into the features of vROps 6.5 and as stated during that webinar, we will now show you how you can unlock the full capabilities of vROps using the extensibility of the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have been following the Webinar Series, by now you have a complete visibility into the capabilities of vROps, when it comes to monitoring the vSphere infrastructure. While this infrastructure is important for the IaaS provider, what business cares about is Applications. The good news is that vROps provides you an extensible platform which can be leveraged to extend the product capability into any area where metrics exist. This could be at the layers of your Software Defined Datacenter such as Compute, Network &amp;amp; Storage, or in the Application Stack and it&amp;rsquo;s tiers such as App, Web and DB.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps hidden gem – XML Builder</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/vrops-hidden-gem-xml-builder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 08:06:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/vrops-hidden-gem-xml-builder/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;If you spend a good amount of time in vROps either at your place of work or with customers (like me) you will likely  have had to create some custom XML (metric configuration) for custom dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past you would either use the sample/examples to get them started and then go and find the specific metric names while, this was usually quite time consuming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent versions of vROps however, VMware have introduced a &amp;ldquo;builder&amp;rdquo; to help you properly format and slect the corect adapters/adapterkinds and metrics.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 1 – What’s New with vROps 6.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-with-vrops-6-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 09:02:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-with-vrops-6-5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/03/logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;Time to share the recording of the first episode of the vROps Webinar Series 2017. This time around, Sunny and I spoke about the latest release of vRealize Operations Manager. We spoke about almost all the new features which were introduced with this version and went into some of them in detail. Like always we rounded up the session with Live Demo of the new features for our audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduced a feedback form which can be used to provide your feedback in general and also request topics on which you would want us to focus this year.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Understanding #vROps High Availability</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/understanding-vrops-high-availability/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 19:32:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/understanding-vrops-high-availability/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;While there is a reasonable amount of information about how HA works in vROps I have found there is still some confusion as to how HA actually works with vROps or rather what are the benefits and perhaps more importantly the cost for enabling the feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HA is a great feature and in my opinion should be considered seriously with any deployment (where possible).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only does HA protect your Master node (which essentially behaves as an index for your vROps cluster and if lost will render your cluster dead unless you have a working backup of your cluster) it will also allow your cluster to tolerate a data node failure. So in short what is not to like!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.5 – Two new enhancements/features I really liked</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/vrops-6-5-two-new-enhancementsfeatures-i-really-liked/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 08:37:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/vrops-6-5-two-new-enhancementsfeatures-i-really-liked/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;So vROps 6.5 has been out for around a month now and I finally have a little while to write a post on what I personally really like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of great new enhancements and improvements added in 6.5 but for the sake of brevity I shall highlight two that I really liked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="flexibility-to-increase-ram-in-between-node-sizes"&gt;Flexibility to increase RAM in between node sizes &lt;a class="anchor" href="#flexibility-to-increase-ram-in-between-node-sizes"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So if you are familiar with vROps you will know that when you deploy it you have &amp;ldquo;T-Shirt&amp;rdquo; sizes to choose from, Small, Medium, Large and now Extra Large (6.5). However an additional extra in 6.5 is support to increase the memory allocation of your vROps nodes, you will not require additional CPU for the node until you hit the next node size bracket. If in doubt check the &lt;a href="https://kb.vmware.com/selfservice/microsites/search.do?language=en_US&amp;amp;cmd=displayKC&amp;amp;externalId=2093783" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; sizing guide spreadsheet
&lt;/a&gt; VMware has provided so you can be sure on what you can and cannot do.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Announcing #vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 1 – What’s new in 6.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/announcing-vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-in-6-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:58:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/announcing-vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-in-6-5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/03/logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;Welcome to the vRealize Operations Manager Webinar Series 2017. With the huge success of the series back in 2016, we wanted to take a break, enjoy the success and come back with full rigor for this series in 2017. We are here and we are charged up to give you some more dope on vRealize Operations manager in the year 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The delivery mechanism would be same as last year. We will start with talking about a topic and then jump into a live environment to see what happens when the rubber hits the road…&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vSAN Cache Performance Dashboard in #vROps</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/02/vsan-cache-performance-dashboard-in-vrops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 14:09:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/02/vsan-cache-performance-dashboard-in-vrops/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/02/vsan.jpg" alt=""&gt;I have recently been able to get vSAN properly up and running in my lab and took a look at the OOTB Dashboards that come with the MPSD (&lt;a href="https://solutionexchange.vmware.com/store/products/vrealize-operations-management-pack-for-storage-devices" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Management Pack for Storage Devices
&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I have a hybrid build (I know many have All Flash Arrays) I was interested in how hard my Flash Cache was working so I built a dashboard purely focused on this aspect of the vSAN product.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Part 12 : What’s New with vROps 6.4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 12:02:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;Time to publish the recording for the 12th episode of the vROps Webinar Series. This time we did a what’s new with vRealize Operations 6.4 and the changes made to vRealize Operations 6.4as you will see there has been a lot packed into this recent release!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been an awesome 12 months working with Sunny on this project and I am very glad to say we will be back next year (we will skip January and will return in February).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 12 : What’s New with vROps 6.4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 08:36:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the time of the month when I would like to invite you to join the next episode of our &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/?s=webinar" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; year long vROps Webinar Series
&lt;/a&gt;. As we move towards the closure of a fantastic year, we would like to take a zoom out view at the vRealize Operations Manager solution with a What&amp;rsquo;s New Episode. &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-6-3/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; We did a What&amp;rsquo;s new with vRealize Operations 6.3
&lt;/a&gt; a couple of months back, however looking at some awesome changes made to vRealize Operations 6.4 it absolutely makes sense to go over the new goodies.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series – Part 11 – Getting more out of #vROps with PowerCLI</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-part-11-getting-more-out-of-vrops-with-powercli-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 12:10:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-part-11-getting-more-out-of-vrops-with-powercli-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Time to publish the recording for the 11th episode of the vROps Webinar Series. This time we were joined by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vinithmenon28" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Vinith Menon
&lt;/a&gt; who spoke about getting more from your vROps builds with PowerCLI. Vinith demonstrated the many useful ways of leveraging PowerCLI to manage your vROps environments and also communicate with the vROps API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vinithmenon28" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Vinith Menon
&lt;/a&gt; for presenting this excellent session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So without further ado, here is the recording for this session:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series – Announcing Part 11 – Getting more out of #vROps with PowerCLI</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-part-11-getting-more-out-of-vrops-with-powercli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 13:05:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-part-11-getting-more-out-of-vrops-with-powercli/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;Another month has gone and Christmas is now looming large! It has been extremely busy but we still want to continue with the momentum of webinar series getting to the business end of the year. This time around we will talk about getting more out of vRealize Operations Manager using PowerCLI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session we will be joined by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vinithmenon28" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Vinith Menon
&lt;/a&gt; who will show us all kinds of PowerCLI goodness.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series Slide decks – available for download</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-slide-decks-available-for-download/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 23:27:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-slide-decks-available-for-download/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;If you have been following and enjoying the vROps Webinar series both &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Sunny
&lt;/a&gt; and I have been running this year you may find it useful to know &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Sunny
&lt;/a&gt; has put all the slide decks up and availble in one place for you to download and share if you so wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://app.box.com/s/pzarwjmf3m9wkwj628m9cmsi7bvprw4w" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; vROps Webinar Series Slide Decks
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy and share the knowledge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or comments just drop either Sunny or myself a comment on our respective blogs or contact us on twitter.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Adding and removing #vROps nodes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/adding-and-removing-vrops-nodes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 21:32:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/adding-and-removing-vrops-nodes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;I was asked recently if there were any materials I could direct people to with regards to expanding existing vROps deployments. I did a brief search on the web to see what material was &amp;ldquo;out there&amp;rdquo; on how to perform what is a straight forward task. To my surprise very little came up. So I have decided to create this guide with all the things you need to consider when you are going to either expand or need to remove a node from one of your active vROps deployments.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series 2016 – Part 10 – A Deep Dive into vROps API</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-2016-part-10-a-deep-dive-into-vrops-api/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 12:37:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-2016-part-10-a-deep-dive-into-vrops-api/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Time to publish the recording for the 10th episode of vROps Webinar Series. This time around we spoke about vRealize Operations Manager Resful API and how to use it. Post 20 minutes of slide-ware, I jumped into the lab and thanks to the demo god, we demonstrated a number of use cases and browsed through the documentation to make it easier for you to consume and use the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; @sunny_dua
&lt;/a&gt; for doing the session while I was MIA you are a legend buddy!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 10 : A Deep Dive into vROps API</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-10-a-deep-dive-into-vrops-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 11:57:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-10-a-deep-dive-into-vrops-api/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;The month has been extremely busy but we still want to continue with the momentum of webinar series getting to the business end of the year. This time around we will talk about vRealize Operations Manager API. API is your friend if you are trying to automate things which you would normally do on GUI. While GUI is a favourite of most, the geeks prefer the API since that helps them to programatically initiate tasks and go out for a coffee. By the time they are back from the LONG coffee break, the work is done 🙂&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series – Part 9 – What’s New with vRealize Operations 6.3</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-6-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 08:27:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-6-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;Here is the recording for the episode 9 vRealize Operations Manager Webinar Series 2016. During this episode we discussed about the new features and functionalities of vRealize Operations Manager 6.3. With this release of the product, we can clearly see that VMware is clearly working on enhancing the user experience and the user interface with some great new features and UI changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would encourage you to watch this session to understand the full potential of the product and how you can use the new features to meet your requirements and ease out operations in your Virtual / Cloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 9 : What’s New with vRealize Operations Manager 6.3</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/09/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-manager-6-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 12:42:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/09/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-manager-6-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the time of the month when we invite you to join the next episode of our year long vROps Webinar Series. As we move towards winter, we would like to take a zoom out view at the vRealize Operations Manager solution with a What&amp;rsquo;s New Episode. For the past 8 months, we have give pretty deep into most of the product features and we believe it is time when we review the product in it&amp;rsquo;s current form and shape. In my opinion, this could not be done better than sharing about the new features &amp;amp; functionalities available in the latest version of vRealize Operations Manager.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Part 8 : SDDC Operations with vROps Custom Dashboards</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-webinar-2016-part-8-sddc-operations-with-vrops-custom-dashboards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 14:52:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-webinar-2016-part-8-sddc-operations-with-vrops-custom-dashboards/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;With today, being the last day of the month, we wanted to make sure that we share this out with you folks out there to keep up with the practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iwan Rahabok, did a great job on this one, talking about the the concept of SDDC operations and I would recommend this session to anyone who wants a jump-start into transforming their operations for SDDC. Quickly want to thank Iwan here for spending his valuable time with us and giving back to the community through this Webinar Series, Blogs, Books etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.3 – SNMP filtering</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-6-3-snmp-filtering/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 09:42:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-6-3-snmp-filtering/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;So one of the most common questions I get from customers regarding vROps is alert filtering and up until very recently the only way to filter was either by email alerting or via the REST plugin. However 9/10 customers wanted to use SNMP and with vROps it was a question of switching on the fire-hose and pointing it to the receiver and let that end point or middle-ware handle the torrent of data. This was naturally not always well received and in some cases rendered that option as a dead end.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Whats new in #vROps 6.3 part 2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 21:16:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I will drill down to look at &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;some&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; of the enhancements, improvements and or new additions one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Home Dashboard&lt;/strong&gt; - as you can see this is a very useful and helpful way or presenting a high level set of data about your environment with also many ways to interact and interrogate the data you are being presented with. Among other items you can filter on (Health/Risk/Efficiency), alter the scope, see alerts relative to the objects you are interested in.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Whats new in #vROps 6.3</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 16:40:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;So the latest release of vROps has some cool new things and at a very high level below are the key stand out improvements and changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will do a more deep dive in the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get the &lt;a href="http://pubs.vmware.com/Release_Notes/en/vrops/63/vrops-63-release-notes.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; release notes here
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href="https://my.vmware.com/group/vmware/info?slug=infrastructure_operations_management/vmware_vrealize_operations/6_3" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; download it here
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New home dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved WLP and DRS integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Workload Dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wizard now available for policy creation or amendment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved visibility of Data collection status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many new Hardening policies (6.0, ESXi, vCenter, VMs, Network) and increased number of checks + reporting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New SDDC Health Dashboards (installed as a MP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Self services dashbaords (vROps)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved UI/UX Visuals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heatmap improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved dashboards (free widget layout)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Widget (recommended actions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Log insight integrations (3.6 vLI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 8 : SDDC Operations with vROps Custom Dashboards</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-8-sddc-operations-with-vrops-custom-dashboards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 08:30:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-8-sddc-operations-with-vrops-custom-dashboards/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;This time around Iwan Rahabok will lead the next session of the vROps Webinar Series while Sunny and myself will support him to deliver some awesome content which Iwan has developed over the past few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, this time around we will move our focus from vROps as a Product and related features to the concept of running your SDDC operations with vRealize Operations Dashboards. Just to clarify, this is not a session where we will teach you to create dashboards, but this is a session where we would share how a set of Customised Dashboards can help any organisation&amp;rsquo;s IT to get an insight into Storage, Network &amp;amp; Compute within your SDDC. While vROps is primarily a Performance Management and Capacity Planning tool, we will take you to the other important aspects as well such as Availability and Configuration.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Part 7 : Working with Alerts &amp; Symptoms</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vrops-webinar-2016-part-7-working-with-alerts-symptoms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 09:03:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vrops-webinar-2016-part-7-working-with-alerts-symptoms/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;Time to release the recording for the latest part of the vROps Webinar Series. We completed the 7th session of the series where we spoke about vRealize Operations Manager Alerts and Symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alerts as we all know would always remain the heart and soul for the operations teams to run the data centers, whether old school or the modern software defined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all cases you need alerts and more importantly you need meaningful and actionable alerts. In this part of the series, Simon and myself concentrated on making you aware of the alert constructs in vROps and as usual share experiences around how we help customers leverage the strong feature set of vROps to customize alerts and related symptoms, recommendations and actions to drastically reduce the Mean Time to Resolution of issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 7 : Working with Alerts &amp; Symptoms</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-7-working-with-alerts-symptoms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 17:54:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-7-working-with-alerts-symptoms/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;Time to announce the next part of the year long webinar series on vRealize Operations Manager. With the last part of the series, we started focusing on content withing vROps. We will continue the trend and talk about a major function of vROps a.k.a Alerts. Alerts is the most used and most ab-used part of vROps, and with this session we want to give you some insights on the entire life-cycle of the alerting function of vROps.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Part 6 : Understanding vROps SuperMetric &amp; Views</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/06/vrops-webinar-2016-part-6-understanding-vrops-supermetric-views/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 22:42:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/06/vrops-webinar-2016-part-6-understanding-vrops-supermetric-views/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/khBMWhr2aFg?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 6 : Understanding vROps SuperMetric &amp; Views</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/06/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-6-understanding-vrops-supermetric-views/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 09:31:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/06/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-6-understanding-vrops-supermetric-views/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;Time to announce the next part of the year long webinar series on vRealize Operations Manager. This time around, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Sunny
&lt;/a&gt; and I will take you to the world of Content within vROps. I will be honest in saying that this is an ocean in itself and we might not be able to touch upon all the aspects of developing content within vROps. During this effort we plan to start with giving you an overview of the various options available to develop content within vROps.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 5 : Design and Deployment considerations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-part-5-design-and-deployment-considerations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 13:25:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-part-5-design-and-deployment-considerations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;As promised, I am posting the recording for the 5th Session of vROps Webinar Series 2016. Both Sunny and I successfully delivered the session on Design and Deployment considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Session Details:-&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; In this instalment of the series, we discussed the steps and thought processes that should be used before and during the design and deployment of vRealize Operations Manager. During the session among other things we will cover the planning, core components, correct sizing, HA, clustering, DR and future growth**.**&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 5 : Design &amp; Deployment Considerations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-5-design-deployment-considerations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 06:52:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-5-design-deployment-considerations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;Time to announce the next part of the year long &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/starting-2016-with-a-bang-vrops-webinar-series/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; webinar series
&lt;/a&gt; on vRealize Operations Manager. This time around, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Sunny
&lt;/a&gt; and I thought about discussing Architecture of vROps. To some, it might sound strange as for smaller deployments you might not have to worry about Sizing and Architecture much since it is pretty simple to install and configure a small or a medium node for a small shop. However as your monitoring needs grow and you start adding solutions for monitoring data sources beyond vSphere, you would need to think about scaling up or scaling out. As your monitoring environment weaves into your incident ticketing system, you would start to see the need to HA of vROps and as you have a DR strategy for your workloads, you will start thinking about DR for your operations tools as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What if I want full metrics? in #vROps</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/what-if-i-want-full-metrics-in-vrops/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 16:06:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/what-if-i-want-full-metrics-in-vrops/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;If you have used vCOps (previous version of vROPs) you will likely remember the option in the admin panel where you could change the number of metrics being collected from &amp;ldquo;balanced&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;full&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many found, this option drop down was not present in vROps and there appeared to be no replacement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the good news, the ability to collect those metrics has not been removed rather it&amp;rsquo;s just a little more hidden (by design)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 4 – Contention Based Performance &amp; Capacity Management</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-webinar-2016-part-4-contention-based-performance-capacity-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 08:17:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-webinar-2016-part-4-contention-based-performance-capacity-management/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;As promised, I am posting the recording for the 4th Session of vROps Webinar Series 2016. We successfully delivered the session on Contention Based Performance &amp;amp; Capacity Management using vRealize Operations Manager!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Session Details:- &amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;With this instalment of the series, we have a new speaker &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/e1_ang&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Iwan Rahabok&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, who will entertain and educate us 🙂 He is no stranger to the world of vRealize Operations Manager and has written a couple of books on vROps as well.
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
 
 &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
 During this session we will help you understand a few basic concepts of using the right counters to monitor performance and capacity in your infrastructure. We will deep dive into the concept of the consumer and the provider layer and help you with solving issues which you might face as a provider of infrastructure to your business.
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
 
 &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;I also want to personally thank &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Sunny&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;amp; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/e1_ang&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Iwan&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/simoneady&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;for their continued support to this series.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
 
 &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Here is the recording for this session:::&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
 
 &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
 Note : It is recommended that you watch the video in HD quality for a great experience.
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
 
 &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;iframe width=&amp;quot;500&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;281&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mhXkiRWXEBg?feature=oembed&amp;quot; frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps what if I want to scale up?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-what-if-i-want-to-scale-up/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 21:42:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-what-if-i-want-to-scale-up/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;So a lot of noise is being made about vROps being able to scale out and rightly so it works -very- well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However what if you want to scale up your node or nodes, going from say small to medium?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reasons why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps your POC has proved so useful you want to move it into production?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have lots of really useful historical on your existing smaller build and you don&amp;rsquo;t want to redeploy (therefore losing your historical data)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have limitations where scaling out is simply not an option but you need vROps to take on more work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are likely other compelling reasons for you to want to scale up your vROps nodes so lets look at how we can do that.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 4 : Contention Based Performance &amp; Capacity Management</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-4-contention-based-performance-capacity-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 11:33:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-4-contention-based-performance-capacity-management/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;We hope you are having fun with the &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/starting-2016-with-a-bang-vrops-webinar-series/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; &lt;strong&gt;vROps Webinar Series&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; and learning in the process!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the next instalment of this series, we have a new speaker who will entertain us 🙂 He is no stranger to the world of vRealize Operations Manager and has written a couple of books on vROps as well. I am referring to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/e1_ang" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Iwan Rahabok
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; who has been my partner in crime on all the vROps related work which we do, inside VMware or with the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Hidden Gem – Automation Action Framework</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-hidden-gem-automation-action-framework/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 18:23:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-hidden-gem-automation-action-framework/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-7206&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2016/03/aaf-logo.png&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;aaf-logo&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; gems deep inside, vROps in this case is not without exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Automation Action Framework (AAF) is one of these, a really powerful vROps in-built automation tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now when I have discussed this capability with my peers and friends many ask why not use vRO etc? My reply is quite simple, &amp;ldquo;what if you do not have vRO or the in house skills to utilise it properly?&amp;rdquo; also &amp;ldquo;With the AAF you do -not- need any scripting knowledge or have to setup any workflows.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 3 – Capacity Planning De-Mystified!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 16:29:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Session Details:-&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capacity Planning Demystified!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capacity Planning is an integral part of vRealize Operations Manager and through this session we want to de-mystify the concepts of Capacity Planning in vROps using features such as projects and the out-of-box capacity views. We look at defining the capacity planning policies based on the business requirements of an organization&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A big thank you to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PunchingClouds" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Rawlinson Rivera
&lt;/a&gt; to provide all the lab equipment required for the live and thanks again to my Co-host &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Sunny
&lt;/a&gt; you&amp;rsquo;re a legend!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 3 : Capacity Planning De-Mystified!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 16:08:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capacity Planning Demystified!&lt;/strong&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description></item><item><title>Is there any #vROps reference architecture?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/is-there-any-vrops-reference-architecture/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 12:17:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/is-there-any-vrops-reference-architecture/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Given the flexibility in which you can choose to use and deploy vROps a question that frequently comes out is “is there a best practice?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While that phrase is getting pretty tired it is still valid if you are just starting a design for a new vROps build or trying to make the best of a bad implementation. Rather than me trying to tell you how you should use vROps in your place of work I would direct you to a very useful PDF VMware have produced vRealize Operations Manager &lt;a href="http://pubs.vmware.com/vrealizeoperationsmanager-62/index.jsp#com.vmware.vcom.core.doc/GUID-F683DD38-D960-48A8-B1AA-D60222C78F51.html?resultof=%2522%2572%2565%2566%2565%2572%2565%256e%2563%2565%2522%2520%2522%2572%2565%2566%2565%2572%2522%2520" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Reference Architecture
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Can I secure #vROps?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/can-i-secure-vrops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 13:42:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/can-i-secure-vrops/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Those of you used to using vSphere on a regular basis will already be aware of the hardening guide for ESXi and vSphere but what about vROps?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the vROps appliance needs to be hardened there is already a VMware provided guide and tool to accommodate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secure configuration guide - &lt;a href="http://pubs.vmware.com/vrealizeoperationsmanager-61/topic/com.vmware.ICbase/PDF/vrealize-operations-manager-61-secure-configuration-guide.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; http://pubs.vmware.com/vrealizeoperationsmanager-61/topic/com.vmware.ICbase/PDF/vrealize-operations-manager-61-secure-configuration-guide.pdf
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The documentation for Secure Configuration is intended to serve as a secure baseline for the deployment of vRealize Operations Manager.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 2 : Understanding vROps Policies</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-part-2-understanding-vrops-policies-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 10:31:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-part-2-understanding-vrops-policies-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;year long commitment&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; of providing quality content on vRealize Operations Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please remember that this is an introductory session to policies and we intend to go deeper into policies in the next session in the month of March, where we deep dive into more details around capacity planning with vRealize Operations Manager. You will hear more about that as we progress into the next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 2 : Understanding Policies.</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-2-understanding-policies-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 14:17:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-2-understanding-policies-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;vROps Webinar Series 2016 is back and as promised during &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrealize-operations-webinar-series-2015-part-1-building-self-healing-environments-with-vrops/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; the last session
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; we would now take you to the world of vRealize Operations Policies Policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a Policy??&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;A &lt;strong&gt;policy&lt;/strong&gt; is a deliberate system of principles to guide decisions and achieve rational outcomes. A &lt;strong&gt;policy&lt;/strong&gt; is a statement of intent, and is implemented as a procedure or protocol&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source - &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Policy" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Wikipedia
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the role of vRealize Operations Manager is to help you with Performance &amp;amp; Capacity Management of your Software Defined Datacenter (SDDC), it is important that you feed in the guiding principles of your Business Environment into vROps to get the rational outcomes. These outcomes span across Health, Risk &amp;amp; Efficiency of your SDDC environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.2 – upgrade and utilization dashboards</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-6-2upgrade-and-utilization-dashboards/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 08:25:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-6-2upgrade-and-utilization-dashboards/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;As you will see the upgrade is simple and even though its early days I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen anything that has been broken!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in seeing an example of the new utilization dashboard scroll to the bottom of this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="upgrading-from-61"&gt;Upgrading from 6.1 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#upgrading-from-61"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will be doing this upgrade on a VA so to begin with I will need the vRealize Operations Manager - Virtual Appliance Operating System upgrade .pak file (Realize_Operations_Manager-VA-OS-6.2.0.3445569.pak)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.2 what&amp;rsquo;s new?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-6-2-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 07:25:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-6-2-whats-new/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;vRealize Operations 6.2 was released last night and is now available for &lt;a href="https://my.vmware.com/group/vmware/details?downloadGroup=VROPS-620&amp;amp;productId=563&amp;amp;rPId=10016" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; download!
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at what’s new very quickly there are some good new enhancements but when you compare this to the 6.1 release it’s perhaps a little light, nevertheless there appears to be some new cool features and enhancements to be had in this version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There does not appear to be any sizing/scale increases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upgrading from existing 6.1 versions can be done via a .pak file.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps a new diva in the datacentre</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-a-new-diva-in-the-datacentre/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 16:06:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrops-a-new-diva-in-the-datacentre/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;For the last few months and certainly very recently (at the London VMUG meeting) I have had the chance to talk to peers and #vExperts and share “war stories” with regards to vRealize Operations Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What has become a consistent theme in all the stories is just how much compute resources vROps requires when you “go big” and not just what is clearly defined in the sizing spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example some of the large deployments I have either been involved in or heard about (to monitor upwards and beyond of 30000 VMs) required the deployment of Large vROps nodes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Operations Webinar Series : 2015 :Part 1 : Building Self Healing Environments with #vROps</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrealize-operations-webinar-series-2015-part-1-building-self-healing-environments-with-vrops/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 10:20:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrealize-operations-webinar-series-2015-part-1-building-self-healing-environments-with-vrops/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;A series of webcasts on vRealize Operations Manager 6.x, helping you learn about anything and everything about the solution. Some of the examples include, vROps Policies, Alert Definitions, Automated Action Framework, integration to third party etc. This would include power point and live demonstrations. The session would range anywhere between 60 to 90 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 100+ registrations and more than 70 live attendees, it was definitely a great start to this series. On popular demand of many who could not attend the session due to time-zone differences, we have recorded the session and you can watch the same right here. It is recommended that you watch the video in HD quality for a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Starting 2016 with a bang &amp;ndash; #vROps Webinar Series</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/starting-2016-with-a-bang-vrops-webinar-series/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 15:12:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/starting-2016-with-a-bang-vrops-webinar-series/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description></item><item><title>vROps multinode SNMP gotcha</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/vrops-multinode-snmp-gotcha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 20:43:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/vrops-multinode-snmp-gotcha/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;So if you are already familiar with vROps you will know you can now have multiple nodes in your cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 nodes if you are on versions 6.0.x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16 nodes if you are on version 6.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does this matter if you plan to use SNMP with your vROps cluster?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite simple really, what I discovered today is that even though you have a master node SNMP traps can and will be sent from all of the nodes to the destination you have configured.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vROps 6.1 – first glance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/vrops-6-1-first-glance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 15:04:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/vrops-6-1-first-glance/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware1.jpg" alt=""&gt;I must admit I have been quite keen to get a look at vROps 6.1 so I was quick to upgrade my lab from 6.0 to 6.1 (with not problems I might add) and have a good look at the new bits and pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bits I will cover briefly in this post are..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrading from 6.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EPO functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dashboards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated actions (ON?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="upgrading-from-60"&gt;Upgrading from 6.0 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#upgrading-from-60"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ensure you upgrade the OS of the appliance first (if you have one) - vRealize Operations Manager - Virtual Appliance Operating System upgrade (vRealize_Operations_Manager-VA-OS-6.1.0.3038037.pak )&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vROps 6.1 whats new?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/vrops-6-1-whats-new/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 21:12:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/vrops-6-1-whats-new/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware1.jpg" alt=""&gt;So vROps 6.1 has gone GA!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What have the guys at VMware added? I have listed what I consider the hi-lights below&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The maximum of 8 nodes has been doubled to 16!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSO integration has been added (requires vSphere 6.0)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Support for SRM has been added&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/09/srm1.jpg" alt=""&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vRealize Hyperic functionality has been added&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the addition of End Point Operations Management, the value of vRealize Hyperic functionality has been extended to the vRealize Operations Manager core product, without the need to deploy vRealize Hyperic&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The vROps HA conundrum</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/the-vrops-ha-conundrum/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 14:54:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/the-vrops-ha-conundrum/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware1.jpg" alt=""&gt;One of the great new features included in vROps is High Availability, however when you look a little closer at how it works careful thought needs to go into whether you want to use it or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have had several discussions with my colleagues on the subject about whether you should or should not enable it in any given deployment of a vROps cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the following are my thoughts and bullet points for you to consider when faced with same dilemma.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VCE Vision, vCOPs to vROps migration</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/vce-vision-vcops-to-vrops-migration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 22:26:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/vce-vision-vcops-to-vrops-migration/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/08/vce-logo-large.png" alt=""&gt;Recently I have been working with various products that compliment or are accessed by vCOPs/vROps via Management packs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As vROps is still fairly new in comparative terms to other products like vCOPs and VCE Vision, when planning migrations from vCOPs to vROps it is naturally important to check compatibility and what is required for a successful migration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are doing a greenfield deployment of vROps there is nothing to be concerned about, you simply need the VCE Vision appliance running version 2.6.1-2.6.5 and have the latest Management Pack installed on your vROps cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Automate the deployment of vROps (supporting vDS)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/05/automate-the-deployment-of-vrops-supporting-vds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 12:50:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/05/automate-the-deployment-of-vrops-supporting-vds/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/05/powercli-logo.png" alt=""&gt;Recently I have been looking at &lt;a href="http://www.virtuallyghetto.com/" title="VirutallyGhetto" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; William Lam
&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s excellent post on &lt;a href="http://www.virtuallyghetto.com/2014/12/automate-deployment-configuration-of-vrealize-operations-manager-6-0-part-1.html" title="Automate Deployment &amp;amp; Configuration of vRealize Operations Manager" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; automating
&lt;/a&gt; the deployment of vROps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having a play around with it, to suit my own needs, I made some modifications to the Powershell script so it would support distributed switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# William Lam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Edited by Simon Eady to support vDS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# &lt;a href="https://www.virtuallyghetto.com" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; www.virtuallyghetto.com
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Deployment of vRealize Operations Manager 6.0 (vROps)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vROps – first look – part 1 – installation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/vrops-first-look-part-1-installation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 11:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/vrops-first-look-part-1-installation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For several months now we have seen glimpses of vROps by way of limited blog posts and the HOL demo&amp;rsquo;s so it was great to see it finally released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is it like out of the box?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vmware.com/support/vrops/doc/vrops-60-release-notes.html" title="Release notes" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; vROps 6.0 Release notes
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first clear change is the move away from 2 VMs in a vAPP and consolidation down to 1 VM which is then easily scalable to more as you require.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCOPs resources (vCenter Operations Manager)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/vcops-resources-vcenter-operations-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 12:57:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/vcops-resources-vcenter-operations-manager/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="vcops-resources"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware1.jpg" alt=""&gt;vCOPs resources &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vcops-resources"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have spent time working with vCOPs you will be aware of the numerous and widespread resources out on the net to help you install and fine tune your deployment. Given there is a lot of content out there that is not always easy to fine immediately I wanted to collate a useful list for my own use and to share with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still a work in progress..&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Slow or failed logon to VCSA 5.5 with vCOps in the environment</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/slow-or-failed-logon-to-vcsa-5-5-with-vcops-in-the-environment/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 09:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/slow-or-failed-logon-to-vcsa-5-5-with-vcops-in-the-environment/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Recently I encountered this problem in a customer site whereby the logon to VCSA 5.5 would either time out, or take 3-5 minutes to actually log on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a netstat on the VCSA during the attempt to logon showed there was a SYN packet sent to the vCOps appliance on port 443 that never established a connection. Another check was attempting to connect using curl &amp;lt;https://&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&amp;gt; –k  - this would time out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing and configuring VMware Infrastructure Navigator 5.8</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/installing-and-configuring-vmware-infrastructure-navigator-5-8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 10:40:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/installing-and-configuring-vmware-infrastructure-navigator-5-8/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;According to VMware, Infrastructure Navigator is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…a component of the VMware vCenter Operations Management Suite. It automatically discovers application services, visualizes relationships and maps dependencies of applications on virtualized compute, storage and network resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effectively it takes a look at the network connections that are running between your VMs (and physical servers) and works out which applications and services are running on each, and the dependencies – both upstream and downstream – for each VM.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing vCOps 5.8 in the DefinIT Lab &amp;ndash; 4GB RAM and 2 vCPU</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/installing-vcops-5-8-in-the-definit-lab-4gb-ram-and-2-vcpu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 11:38:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/installing-vcops-5-8-in-the-definit-lab-4gb-ram-and-2-vcpu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;There’s no doubt that vCOps is a great product for proactively monitoring your vSphere environment, but it’s a hefty package for the lab. The minimum recommended RAM is a whopping 16GB – in my lab that’s the whole of my management host! I recently needed to do some testing so I wanted to get it running in the lab with the barest minimum I could get working, and it turns out you can get working with just 4GB and 2 CPU…albeit you wouldn’t want to monitor much! I also want to use vFlash Read Cache to accelerate I/O in the lab – this requires upgrading VMtools and the VM hardware to version 10.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>