<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>oracle on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/oracle/</link><description>Recent content in oracle on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/oracle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a free Arm-based Docker host in Oracle Cloud</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/06/building-a-free-arm-based-docker-host-in-oracle-cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/06/building-a-free-arm-based-docker-host-in-oracle-cloud/</guid><description>Most people have used AWS' free tier of resources for learning - and most people (including myself) have long since used the 12 months allowed free tier. It was recently brought to my attention that Oracle Cloud have a free tier offering (that they promise is always free) that includes two AMD-based compute VMs with 1/8th of an CPU and 1GB RAM (not much use to anyone) and (much more interestingly) a 4 Arm-based Ampere A1 cores and 24GB usable RAM as 1-4 VMs.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 2- Full Stack monitoring with vRealize Operations Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/05/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-2-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 07:18:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/05/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-2-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</guid><description>[&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-8035&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2017/03/logo.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; which vROps can provide by using various extensibility solutions.
We discussed the following use cases and demonstrated them in live environments:
Use Case 1 - Full-Stack vSphere Monitoring. From application to Infrastructure.
Use Case 2 - Amazon RDS Workloads. Monitoring public cloud workloads with vROps.
Use Case 3 - vROps Extensibility. Metrics, Logs and Costing come together along with other 3rd party extensibility options.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Part 2 – #vROps Webinar series 2017 – “Full Stack” monitoring with vRealize Operations Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/announcing-part-2-vrops-webinar-series-2017-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 07:50:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/announcing-part-2-vrops-webinar-series-2017-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</guid><description>As promised, vROps Webinar Series 2017 is back with the second episode of the year. Last time around we looked closely into the features of vROps 6.5 and as stated during that webinar, we will now show you how you can unlock the full capabilities of vROps using the extensibility of the platform.
If you have been following the Webinar Series, by now you have a complete visibility into the capabilities of vROps, when it comes to monitoring the vSphere infrastructure.</description></item></channel></rss>