<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ems on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/ems/</link><description>Recent content in Ems on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 11:21:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/ems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing a TMG Enterprise Management Server and Migrating and Existing Standalone Array: Part 1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/06/installing-a-tmg-enterprise-management-server-and-migrating-and-existing-standalone-array-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 11:21:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/06/installing-a-tmg-enterprise-management-server-and-migrating-and-existing-standalone-array-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2011/03/TMG2010.png" alt=""&gt;This is my current scenario: there are two existing servers in a stand-alone array - TMG01 and TMG02, and over in a DR site there is a new server (TMG03) that is in the process of being built. To comply with DR, all 3 servers must have their configurations up to date, however there is no direct communication allowed between the two DMZs, so simply adding to the new server as an array member is not possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Reporting all ActiveSync devices and their Users in Exchange 2010</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/02/reporting-all-activesync-devices-and-users-in-exchange-2010/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 14:28:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/02/reporting-all-activesync-devices-and-users-in-exchange-2010/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2011/02/Exchange-2010-Logo-748516_thumb.png" alt=""&gt;Recently I needed to report on the ActiveSync devices that were attached to our Exchange 2010 organisation, and which users they were accessing, and then export them to a CSV file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walking through the script it gets all the mailboxes from the server MBX01, gets an object containing the ActiveSync device name, type and user agent. It then adds a property to that object called “MailboxIdentity” and adds it to that object. That object is then added to an array of objects called ActiveSyncDevices, which is then exported to CSV.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>