<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>architecture on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/architecture/</link><description>Recent content in architecture on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VCF 4.4 Design Considerations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2022/03/vcf-4.4-design-considerations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2022/03/vcf-4.4-design-considerations/</guid><description>On the 10th February VCF 4.4 was released, this was quite a significant milestone as it removed a few things from the equation and also provided more flexbility.
Firstly and arguably the big change.
vRealize Suite vRealize Lifecycle Manager 8.6.2, upgrade and deployment of the vRealize Suite products is managed by vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager. You can upgrade vRealize Suite products as new versions become available in your vRealize Suite Lifecycle Manager.</description></item><item><title>VMware Validated Designs are discontinued - Long live VMware Validated Solutions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/11/vmware-validated-designs-are-discontinued-long-live-vmware-validated-solutions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/11/vmware-validated-designs-are-discontinued-long-live-vmware-validated-solutions/</guid><description>If you have spent any time designing IT soutions with VMware products you will very likely have come into contact with VMware Validated Designs (VVD)
VMware Validated Design is a family of solutions for data center designs that span compute, storage, networking, and management, serving as a blueprint for your Software-Defined Data Center (SDDC) implementation. The documentation of VMware Validated Design consists of succeeding deliverables for all stages of the SDDC life cycle.</description></item><item><title>vROps Remote Collectors - Design Considerations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/vrops-remote-collectors-design-considerations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/vrops-remote-collectors-design-considerations/</guid><description>vROps Remote Collectors - Design Considerations Product Version - vRealize Operations 7.x and 8.x As part of VMware Validated Designs tyically you would use Remote Collectors not just in different DCs but also local to the analytics cluster. However there are a circumstances where the rules &amp;ldquo;change&amp;rdquo;.
When using RecoverPoint or Site Recovery Manager Design Assumption - you have Remote Collectors on your Primary Site and on your Failover Site.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 5 : Design and Deployment considerations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-part-5-design-and-deployment-considerations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 13:25:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-part-5-design-and-deployment-considerations/</guid><description>As promised, I am posting the recording for the 5th Session of vROps Webinar Series 2016. Both Sunny and I successfully delivered the session on Design and Deployment considerations.
Session Details:- In this instalment of the series, we discussed the steps and thought processes that should be used before and during the design and deployment of vRealize Operations Manager. During the session among other things we will cover the planning, core components, correct sizing, HA, clustering, DR and future growth**.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 5 : Design &amp; Deployment Considerations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-5-design-deployment-considerations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 06:52:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-5-design-deployment-considerations/</guid><description>Time to announce the next part of the year long webinar series on vRealize Operations Manager. This time around, Sunny and I thought about discussing Architecture of vROps. To some, it might sound strange as for smaller deployments you might not have to worry about Sizing and Architecture much since it is pretty simple to install and configure a small or a medium node for a small shop. However as your monitoring needs grow and you start adding solutions for monitoring data sources beyond vSphere, you would need to think about scaling up or scaling out.</description></item><item><title>Is there any #vROps reference architecture?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/is-there-any-vrops-reference-architecture/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 12:17:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/is-there-any-vrops-reference-architecture/</guid><description>Given the flexibility in which you can choose to use and deploy vROps a question that frequently comes out is “is there a best practice?”
While that phrase is getting pretty tired it is still valid if you are just starting a design for a new vROps build or trying to make the best of a bad implementation. Rather than me trying to tell you how you should use vROps in your place of work I would direct you to a very useful PDF VMware have produced vRealize Operations Manager Reference Architecture.</description></item></channel></rss>