<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Password on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/password/</link><description>Recent content in Password on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 21:38:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/password/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3DES Password Based Encryption with vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/3des-password-based-encryption-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 21:38:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/3des-password-based-encryption-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A requirement that often arises in large, complex orchestration projects is the need to encrypt and decrypt information. One such requirement recently specified triple DES password based encryption as the standard, which led me through a lot of Google searches to &lt;a href="https://code.google.com/p/crypto-js/"&gt;CryptoJS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CryptoJS is a growing collection of standard and secure cryptographic algorithms implemented in JavaScript using best practices and patterns. They are fast, and they have a consistent and simple interface.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Generating a secure random password with vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/generating-a-secure-random-password-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 21:17:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/generating-a-secure-random-password-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly common requirement when creating a new user to assign a randomly generated password, so during a recent engagement I wrote a little password generator to do that. I wanted to be able to chose whether special characters were used, and the length of the password - typically if the password doesn&amp;rsquo;t used special characters I would increase the length significantly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Characters should be randomly picked from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a-z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A-Z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0-9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(optional) ASCII special characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="inputs"&gt;Inputs &lt;a class="anchor" href="#inputs"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;passwordLength - the length of the password to be generated (number)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;excludePunctuation - exclude the use of special characters if TRUE (boolean)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/01/image_thumb35.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Avoid SSO Admin lockout &amp;ndash; a.k.a. your first task after installing vSphere SSO</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/11/avoid-sso-admin-lockout-a-k-a-your-first-task-after-installing-vsphere-sso/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 12:55:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/11/avoid-sso-admin-lockout-a-k-a-your-first-task-after-installing-vsphere-sso/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In my post yesterday (&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vexpert.me/hS&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;) I talked about how to recover from an expired default SSO administrator password – this prompted a discussion on twitter with Anthony Spiteri (@anthonyspiteri) and Grant Orchard (@grantorchard) about the defaults for expiration and how to mitigate the risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first solution is to modify the password expiration policy for SSO. I’m not advocating this necessarily – I think that expiring passwords ensure that you change them regularly and increase the overall security of your SSO solution. However, I can envisage situations (similar to mine) when the SSO administrator account is not used for a long time and expired – that causes headaches.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Recover ESXi Root Password using AD Authentication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/recover-esxi-root-password-using-ad-authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 10:12:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/recover-esxi-root-password-using-ad-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;Losing a root password isn’t something that happens often, but when it does it’s normally a really irritating time. I have to rotate the password of all hosts once a month for compliance, but sometimes a host drops out of the loop and the root password gets lost. Fortunately, as the vpxuser is still valid I can manage the host via vCenter - this lends itself to this little recovery process:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>