<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vCHS on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vchs/</link><description>Recent content in vCHS on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 13:26:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vchs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adding a vCloud Air (PAYG/Gen2) instance to vRealize Orchestrator as a vCloud Director host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 13:26:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</guid><description>Big thanks to Jose Luis Gomez for this solution, his response to my tweet was spot on and invaluable!
I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to configure vCloud Air as a vCloud Director host in vRealize Orchestrator in order to create some custom resource actions for Day 2 operations in vRealize Automation. What I found was that there&amp;rsquo;s *very* little information out there on how to do this, and I ended up writing my own custom resource mapping for the virtual machines to VCAC:VirtualMachine objects - at least that way I could add my resource action.</description></item><item><title>VMware #vForum London and bloggers VSAN/vCHS lunch</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vmware-vforum-london-and-bloggers-vsanvchs-lunch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 15:35:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vmware-vforum-london-and-bloggers-vsanvchs-lunch/</guid><description>Fairly recently i attended the annual VMware vForum London 2014 at Wembley stadium!
If you have never been to a vForum i would certainly recommend it as it offers the chance to not only attend excellent and pertinent sessions but there is also the opportunity to network and visit the large vendor hall which as ever was a busy place!
 Keynote and sessions The opening keynote by @joebaguley (Joe Baguley) was excellent and as challenging as ever one aspect that stood out to me personally was the question &amp;ldquo;where are you on your journey?</description></item><item><title>Another fantastic South West UK VMUG</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/another-fantastic-south-west-uk-vmug/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 09:09:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/another-fantastic-south-west-uk-vmug/</guid><description>On the 3rd of June we had our second South West UK VMUG and I am pleased to say it went superbly well.
As before we held it at the Mshed facilities in Bristol.
We had a great day with many sessions from sponsors,vendors and community speakers alike!
Big thanks go to our speakers that day who were..
Justin Rohan - @justinrohan - Nimble Storage - Sponsor James Smith - @james55smith - PernixData - Sponsor Julian Regel - @jr_on_the_cloud - Community session on vCD Adam Bohle - @adambohle - VMware - vCAC session Jonathan Medd - @jonathanmedd - Community session on PowerCLI/Automation Richard Munro - @RikMunro - VMware - vCHS Session One of the South West UK VMUG leaders Barry Coombs took a fantastic time lapse video of the day which can be viewed on his blog site.</description></item><item><title>vCHS – first impressions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vchs-first-impressions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:39:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/02/vchs-first-impressions/</guid><description>In case you missed it VMware have now released vCHS (VMware vCloud Hybrid Service) in Europe! The first data center residing in Slough with more data centers planned across Europe in the near future.
Working in an SME that has several existing vSphere environments this was of real interest, as the need to scale out quickly from our Private clouds is rapidly becoming a requirement.
Having already spoken to VMware on the phone to get a rough idea on options and costs I decided to take a look at the Hands-on-labs to see how easy it really is to use and migrate VMs from an existing private cloud to vCHS.</description></item></channel></rss>