<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cpu on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/cpu/</link><description>Recent content in Cpu on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 08:37:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/cpu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#vROps 6.5 – Two new enhancements/features I really liked</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/vrops-6-5-two-new-enhancementsfeatures-i-really-liked/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 08:37:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/vrops-6-5-two-new-enhancementsfeatures-i-really-liked/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;So vROps 6.5 has been out for around a month now and I finally have a little while to write a post on what I personally really like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of great new enhancements and improvements added in 6.5 but for the sake of brevity I shall highlight two that I really liked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="flexibility-to-increase-ram-in-between-node-sizes"&gt;Flexibility to increase RAM in between node sizes &lt;a class="anchor" href="#flexibility-to-increase-ram-in-between-node-sizes"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So if you are familiar with vROps you will know that when you deploy it you have &amp;ldquo;T-Shirt&amp;rdquo; sizes to choose from, Small, Medium, Large and now Extra Large (6.5). However an additional extra in 6.5 is support to increase the memory allocation of your vROps nodes, you will not require additional CPU for the node until you hit the next node size bracket. If in doubt check the &lt;a href="https://kb.vmware.com/selfservice/microsites/search.do?language=en_US&amp;amp;cmd=displayKC&amp;amp;externalId=2093783"&gt;sizing guide spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt; VMware has provided so you can be sure on what you can and cannot do.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VM Power On fails with error: cpuid.coresPerSocket must be a number between 1 and 8</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vm-power-on-fails-with-error-cpuid-corespersocket-must-be-a-number-between-1-and-8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 11:10:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vm-power-on-fails-with-error-cpuid-corespersocket-must-be-a-number-between-1-and-8/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Had a strange one after deploying an XP VM from a template today - the VM would not power on and threw the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An error was received from the ESX host while powering on VM [VM name].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cpuid.coresPerSocket must be a number between 1 and 8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2013/02/2013-02-01-000.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digging around on google the error seemed to be related to over-allocating vCPUs (e.g. assigning 8 vCPUs on a VM with 4 physical CPU cores). This was a single vCPU machine on a 12 processor host, so not likely to be that! It did give me the idea that maybe the VMX had an error, so I edited the VM hardware and added an extra CPU and saved the config. I then edited it back to a single CPU and powered on the machine - it worked!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>