<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Digital music on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/digital-music/</link><description>Recent content in Digital music on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 14:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/digital-music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Activating Microsoft Reader on a Windows Mobile 5 device under Vista</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/10/activating-microsoft-reader-on-a-windows-mobile-5-device-under-vista/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 14:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/10/activating-microsoft-reader-on-a-windows-mobile-5-device-under-vista/</guid><description>I recently tried to use Microsoft reader on my iMate K-Jam mobile, it&amp;rsquo;s Windows Mobile 5 powered, so according to Microsoft it&amp;rsquo;s fully supported. However, when I tried to activate, I got the following error:
&amp;ldquo;You have an older version of Pocket PC which does not support Activation&amp;rdquo;
Not true I cried, and after a lot of Google-ing and trying various different fixes that are posted on the net, I found the only one that actually worked for me!</description></item><item><title>iTunes crashes on startup under Vista</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/07/itunes-crashes-on-startup-under-vista/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2007 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/07/itunes-crashes-on-startup-under-vista/</guid><description>I had an odd problem today, I logged on to begin my day&amp;rsquo;s work and plugged in my iPod as per normal. iTunes crashes, Vista tries to recover. iTunes closes. iTunes opens. iTunes crashes. Vista tries to recover. As you can imagine that gets tiresome, so I tried repairing iTunes, reinstalling iTunes, installing older versions of iTunes, all to no avail. The solution in the end was to remove Quicktime and do a fresh install.</description></item><item><title>DRM Free iTunes music with QTFairUse</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/06/drm-free-itunes-music-with-qtfairuse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2007 19:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/06/drm-free-itunes-music-with-qtfairuse/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into the rights and wrongs of DRM, I will say that I&amp;rsquo;m strongly against piracy and if your intention is to strip DRM for those kind of reasons, kindly go somewhere else for your info. If you&amp;rsquo;re wanting to strip DRM for a legitimate personal use, such as playing in another media player or an MP3 player&amp;nbsp;other than an iPod - read on! &amp;nbsp;QuickTimeFairUse is a great little application that takes your .</description></item></channel></rss>