<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Proxy on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/proxy/</link><description>Recent content in Proxy on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 16:46:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/proxy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator (vCO) Multi-node Plug-in use case: Remote Site Selection and Execution</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-operations-vco-multi-node-plug-in-use-case-remote-site-selection-and-execution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 16:46:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-operations-vco-multi-node-plug-in-use-case-remote-site-selection-and-execution/</guid><description>One of the use cases I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on with a customer is based on the vRO/vCO multi-node plug-in and involves the master vRO/vCO node calling proxy workflows based on a parameter - in this case the target site. As you can see from this very simple diagram, a Cloud Management System (CMS) calls a workflow on the Master node, which then executes a proxy workflow on the correct site. The trick is getting the Master Orchestrator node to pick the right proxy workflow.</description></item><item><title>Configuring and Using vRealize Orchestrator (vCO/vRO) Multi-node plugin</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/configuring-and-using-vrealize-orchestrator-vcovro-multi-node-plugin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 16:50:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/configuring-and-using-vrealize-orchestrator-vcovro-multi-node-plugin/</guid><description>To quote the release notes for the latest version of vCO/vRO Multi-node Plugin:
The VMware vCenter Orchestrator Multi-Node Plug-In allows organizations to manage environments with multiple vCenter Orchestrator server instances.
As organizations increase their level of automation, they often find the need to deploy multiple Orchestrator instances. With the VMware vCenter Orchestrator Multi-Node Plug-In, administrators have a more efficient way to manage multiple Orchestrator instances from a central point. The plug-in allows administrators to log in to a master Orchestrator server to view the inventories and workflows of remote Orchestrator servers, and to trigger workflows remotely.</description></item><item><title>In-depth: Installing and Configuring Threat Management Gateway 2010 in a Network Load Balanced Array</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/11/in-depth-installing-and-configuring-threat-management-gateway-2010-in-a-network-load-balanced-array/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 16:35:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/11/in-depth-installing-and-configuring-threat-management-gateway-2010-in-a-network-load-balanced-array/</guid><description>In this post I will be installing a TMG Array as a “back firewall” behind a hardware firewall. The Array will consist of two virtual servers, TMG01 and TMG02 which each have 3 NICs. One NIC will be dedicated to the LAN network, accessible internally. One NIC will be dedicated to the DMZ network, accessible to the outside world on a static mapped IP. The third NIC will be a dedicated intra-array communications NIC as per Microsoft’s recommendation.</description></item></channel></rss>