<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMUG on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vmug/</link><description>Recent content in VMUG on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vmug/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Looking forward to VMware Explore - the artist formerly known as VMworld</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2022/07/looking-forward-to-vmware-explore-the-artist-formerly-known-as-vmworld/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2022/07/looking-forward-to-vmware-explore-the-artist-formerly-known-as-vmworld/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe that my &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-arriving-and-day-1/"&gt;
 first VMworld
&lt;/a&gt; was almost 9 years ago! I feel very blessed to have attended in &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-one/"&gt;
 2014 (EU)
&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-pre-event-and-partner-day/"&gt;
 2015 (EU)
&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/heading-to-vmworld-us-2016/"&gt;
 2016 (US)
&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-before-i-go/"&gt;
 2017 (EU)
&lt;/a&gt;, 2018 (my first as an employee), 2019 (my first time as a speaker!), and virtually in 2020 and 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years VMworld has been hugely formative in my career, I&amp;rsquo;ve talked many times before about how the trajectory of my career really took off when I got involved with the London VMUG, and how that led to being awarded vExpert in 2013. Through the vExpert programme, I got my first blogger pass for VMworld, and from there the networking opportunities led to certification, career advances, and ultimately making the contacts (and friends) that got me in the door at VMware. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to overstate how much VMworld has helped over the years.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Am I the best I can be right now?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/03/am-i-the-best-i-can-be-right-now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 09:55:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/03/am-i-the-best-i-can-be-right-now/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a few years since I read (and lost) a great article on career progression and personal insight. That article helped me relax into who I am from a professional point of view, but it also challenged me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been in IT for over 20 years now and in truth the first 10 years were not so great (perhaps a story for another time) but it was when I stumbled upon the vCommunity by way of Twitter and then subsequently I attended my first VMUG (in London) which completely challenged and changed my way of thinking and approach to my career. Talking to and observing peers whom I respected gave me a lot of inspiration to re-evaluate what I was doing in my career, why I did what I was doing and perhaps most importantly of all was I really being the best I can be?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#UKVMUG &amp;ndash; Curry &amp;ndash; Beer &amp;ndash; Sessions &amp;ndash; Weddings</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-curry-beer-sessions-weddings-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 13:25:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-curry-beer-sessions-weddings-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vmug-usercon_thumb.png" alt=""&gt;This was my second UKVMUG and it was my first vCurry evening! so I was really looking forward to getting up to the event and seeing everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vCurry event was excellent and it was a great chance to enjoy good food in great company. Had the chance to meet with many people I would not normally get the chance to see, Frank &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fbuechsel" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; @fbuechsel
&lt;/a&gt; and Brad &lt;a href="mailto:V@VMUG_CEO"&gt;
 @VMUG_CEO
&lt;/a&gt; to name a couple! To top off a really great evening we (my table/team) won the vQuiz which was organised and conducted by Stuart &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virtual_Stu" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; @Virtual_Stu
&lt;/a&gt; (thanks Stuart!), a big thank you to Matt &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Twickersmatt" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; @Twickersmatt
&lt;/a&gt; for the beers (one of the prizes).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#UKVMUG Ravello Home Lab Winner!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-ravello-home-lab-winner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 11:11:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-ravello-home-lab-winner/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;First of all, thank you to everyone who came along to my session at the UKVMUG yesterday, it was great to see so many people at a round table discussion, sorry for those that had to stand! I hope that it was helpful and maybe a few of you will be building some awesome labs in the cloud!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ravello very kindly sponsored a free home lab, equivalent to the vExpert 1000 hours account as a prize for my session at the UKVMUG yesterday. Using a high tech random number generator and an Excel spread sheet the winner was picked, so without further ado, congratulations go to…&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015 – Days 3 and 4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-2015-days-3-and-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 21:09:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-2015-days-3-and-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="wednesday"&gt;Wednesday &lt;a class="anchor" href="#wednesday"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had lined up several sessions so I was quick to get along to my first session - Operational Remediation with vRealize Operations… Tying it All Together - #MGT5735. The session was excellent and gave a great overview and introduction to what is possible with remediation in vROps 6.1. Big thanks to Chima Njaka for this session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/10/CRRF3iyW8AA6yHx_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from a few other sessions I spent a lot of the afternoon in the VMUG lounge with my colleagues from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Xtravirt" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; @xtravirt
&lt;/a&gt; (see pic below) and meeting lots of other folk from the around the globe (this is what makes this conference so very great for me), putting faces to twitter handles for the first time and so on. Networking with your peers at an event such as this is incredibly valuable, educational and really enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015 – Day 2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-day-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 06:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-day-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The first full day of VMworld after PEX was a busy one.&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/10/vmworld2015-logo1.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the keynote (highlights were the docker announcements) I was on “booth babe” duty at the VMUG lounge. It was great to meet so many folk who were existing VMUG members and leaders as well as prospective new members. If you are at VMworld this year you should definitely stop by!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/10/IMAG0043_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt; &lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/10/IMAG0044_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch I hit the solutions exchange to catch up with a few vendors whom I had a few queries for also took the time to collect the #vExpert hoodie from @simplivity and the #vExpert tile from Tegile (thank you!) Suffice to say it was very busy and naturally noisy but judging by the many happy faces of people with various items of “swag” under their arms things were going well!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>In response to @h0bbel: The "vCommunity"</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/in-response-to-h0bbel-the-vcommunity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 07:43:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/in-response-to-h0bbel-the-vcommunity/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is not my normal sort of post - don&amp;rsquo;t worry, normal service will resume shortly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Christian&amp;rsquo;s comments on the vCommunity&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; - or lack of it - yesterday and although some things resonate with me, and a lot of other people, I don&amp;rsquo;t quite agree. I want to be clear this is a response to Christian and not an argument, I respect Christian as someone who &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; contribute to the vCommunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why should you go to a VMUG?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/why-should-you-go-to-a-vmug/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 15:37:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/why-should-you-go-to-a-vmug/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/06/vmw_vmug_logo_square_small.png" alt=""&gt;Having been a &lt;a href="http://www.vmug.com" title="VMUG Website" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; VMUG
&lt;/a&gt; member for several years and now a VMUG leader I have seen the value of being a VMUG member and attending the meetings/events/conferences continue to increase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="so-why-do-i-think-you-should-you-go"&gt;So why do I think you should you go? &lt;a class="anchor" href="#so-why-do-i-think-you-should-you-go"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are using VMware technologies/products in your workplace or you are regularly consulting on said VMware products, the VMUG events are in my opinion invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It simply doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what experience/knowledge you have of the products, whether you are very new to virtualization or an old hand I  guarantee you will come away from any VMUG meeting having learned something useful or dare I say been a great source/help to others whom you have met and networked with.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#UKVMUG 2014</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/11/ukvmug-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 12:27:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/11/ukvmug-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday (in case you missed it) was the fourth annual UK national VMUG at the National Motorcycle Museum in Birmingham. It was my second year attending and I continue to be blown away with the quality and value available at this event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a huge amount of content packed into this one-day event, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try and summarise my day…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vcurry-and-vquiz"&gt;vCurry and vQuiz &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vcurry-and-vquiz"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vCurry event was hosted on Monday night and is a great way to chill out after a long drive up to the midlands. It&amp;rsquo;s always well attended and there are always familiar faces from the London VMUG there. Also there is the now legendary vQuiz, hosted by Stuart Thompson (@virtual_stu) which is great for a laugh or two and makes a good ice breaker if you&amp;rsquo;re there on your own. Oh, and free curry and a free beer or two…what&amp;rsquo;s not to like?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My first VMworld..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/my-first-vmworld/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 12:38:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/my-first-vmworld/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/10/vmworld2014.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this was my first VMworld I am not ashamed to say I was really stoked about attending, many of my peers have attended in the past and were going to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I flew in on the Sunday evening so that I could register early on Monday for partner day, however I did miss the chance to attend what turned out to be a very popular and very full Rockstar event on the Sunday evening.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Another fantastic South West UK VMUG</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/another-fantastic-south-west-uk-vmug/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 09:09:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/another-fantastic-south-west-uk-vmug/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/06/vmug_logo.png" alt=""&gt;On the 3rd of June we had our second &lt;a href="http://www.vmug.com/index.php?mo=cm&amp;amp;op=ld&amp;amp;fid=217&amp;amp;gid=255" title="South West UK VMUG" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; South West UK VMUG
&lt;/a&gt; and I am pleased to say it went superbly well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As before we held it at the &lt;a href="http://mshed.org/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Mshed
&lt;/a&gt; facilities in Bristol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a great day with many sessions from sponsors,vendors and community speakers alike!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Big thanks&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; go to our speakers that day who were..&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#LonVMUG 15th May &amp;ndash; another great VMUG!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/lonvmug-15th-may-another-great-vmug/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 09:44:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/lonvmug-15th-may-another-great-vmug/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Yesterday saw another fantastic London VMUG with lots of quality sessions and opportunities to network with peers and friends. The committee seem to do a fantastic job every time and this one was no exception, so thanks to &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Alaric Davies&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jane Rimmer&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Stuart Thompson&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Simon Gallagher&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Online VMware Forum – my thoughts</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/online-vmware-forum-my-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 21:35:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/online-vmware-forum-my-thoughts/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/05/2014-05-08_130651.png" alt=""&gt;This was the second online event I have attended in the last few months, the first being the &lt;a href="www.vmug.com" title="VMware user group"&gt;
 VMUG
&lt;/a&gt; Virtual event back in January. One of the aspects I enjoyed the most about that event was being able to chat  to many well known and familiar faces from the wider community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this recent event there was a lot of focus on the various offerings from VMware  with a good deal of focus on VSAN, NSX, Horizon and vCHS but certainly not neglecting their other offerings.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>South West UK VMUG ready to launch! – 18th February</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/south-west-uk-vmug-ready-to-launch-18th-february/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 15:02:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/south-west-uk-vmug-ready-to-launch-18th-february/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="so-what-is-vmug"&gt;So what is VMUG?&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2013/09/vmug-logo.jpg" alt=""&gt; &lt;a class="anchor" href="#so-what-is-vmug"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The VMware User Group (VMUG) is an independent, global, customer-led organization, created to maximize members’ use of VMware and partner solutions through knowledge sharing, training, collaboration, and events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presently there are five VMUGs in the UK including the latest addition - South West UK VMUG - @swukvmug&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-am-i-involved-and-why-should-you-come-along"&gt;Why am I involved and why should you come along? &lt;a class="anchor" href="#why-am-i-involved-and-why-should-you-come-along"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had been using VMware products for over 3 years and after joining twitter it was very clear to me the VMware user community was very friendly and also very helpful, it was there I learned about &lt;a href="http://www.vmug.com/" title="VMware user group" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; VMUG
&lt;/a&gt; so the chance to meet and greet other users like myself and of course learn from the &amp;ldquo;rockstars&amp;rdquo; was to good an opportunity to pass up, after attending several meetings I was completely sold.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>New VMUG Launched – South West VMUG UK</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/new-vmug-launched-south-west-vmug-uk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 09:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/new-vmug-launched-south-west-vmug-uk/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The South West VMware User Group launches in the UK, bringing the best of VMware and the user community to The West, South West and South Wales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leadership team is pleased to announce the South West VMware User Group (VMUG). Meeting in Bristol at the crossroads to the South West, The West Country, South Wales and the Midlands, meetings will begin early in 2014, to bring together virtualization customers, end users and enthusiasts in an informal social setting for discussion, learning and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>London VMUG &amp;ndash; July 2013</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/07/london-vmug-july-2013/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 12:54:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/07/london-vmug-july-2013/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2013/07/20130705003.png" alt=""&gt;Yesterday I attended my second ever #LonVMUG and did my first ever VMUG presentation! Generally it was a great day, with loads of really good sessions and some really cool community and vendor content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As ever it was great day for socialising and networking with people who you interact with on twitter. For me one of the major benefits of the VMUG is learning from other people’s experience. Twitter was alive with the hastag #LonVMUG and it definitely adds something to the day to be active&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>