<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows XP on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/windows-xp/</link><description>Recent content in Windows XP on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 11:58:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/windows-xp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Trace cables the easy way with Cisco CDP on Windows</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/trace-cables-the-easy-way-with-cisco-cdp-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2010 11:58:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/trace-cables-the-easy-way-with-cisco-cdp-on-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;No matter how good your network diagrams are, sometimes you need to verify the port your server/desktop is in. Cisco Discovery Protocol is a great tool for network admins when you need to quickly map routers and switches, and if you’ve got an ESX server connected you’ll see that it picks up CDP info too – but the vast majority of my managed systems are Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how to use &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;TCPDUMP by Micro Olap&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; to extend that functionality to your Windows boxes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to force the removal of Folder Redirection from specific user accounts</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/04/how-to-force-the-removal-of-folder-redirection-from-specific-user-accounts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 11:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/04/how-to-force-the-removal-of-folder-redirection-from-specific-user-accounts/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We have a folder redirection policy in place for all of our users in combination with a roaming profile policy - this policy is applied to the OU that contains our users. Unfortunately this policy was accidently linked to the root of our domain too, causing our Domain Admin users to be redirected too - something we do not want. When the mistake was discovered, the policy was unlinked, but the redirection remained (despite being set to revert when users fall out of scope). I tried re-applying the policy, modifying the out of scope policy and then moving the Domain Admin user out of scope, but it failed to remove the folder redirection.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dell Latitude E6500 blue screen of death on XP install/downgrade/reinstall</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/01/dell-latitude-e6500-blue-screen-of-death-on-xp-installdowngradereinstall/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/01/dell-latitude-e6500-blue-screen-of-death-on-xp-installdowngradereinstall/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just had a frustrating few days trying to downgrade 4 Dell Latitude E6500 laptops to XP. The problem was, whenever you booted to the XP cd you would get to the point just before you agree to the license and then hit a blue screen with a SATA error code. It seems that the bundled driver for the SATA storage controller incorrectly identifies it and causes a fatal error as it&amp;rsquo;s loaded.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Create a 100Mb file for testing transfer speeds</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/create-a-100mb-file-for-testing-transfer-speeds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2008 10:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/create-a-100mb-file-for-testing-transfer-speeds/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We have a Bonded ADSL solution for our servers to provide the necessary upstream transfer speeds for the applications we host. We have bonded ADSL because our exchange still doesn&amp;rsquo;t support SDSL, and a leased line is overkill. Theoretically, we should have 28.1 Mbps download and 3.2Mbps upload - what I am actually seeing is about 1.7Mbps down and 1.9Mbps up. I have tested this on various servers, over various times and file sizes, there is no doubt that the performance is POOR.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fixing your Windows Vista MBR</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/05/fixing-your-windows-vista-mbr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 19:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/05/fixing-your-windows-vista-mbr/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>