<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vrealize operations on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vrealize-operations/</link><description>Recent content in vrealize operations on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vrealize-operations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Integrating vROps with vRA 8 using Workspace One Auth Source</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/03/integrating-vrops-with-vra-8-using-workspace-one-auth-source/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/03/integrating-vrops-with-vra-8-using-workspace-one-auth-source/</guid><description>Integrating vROps with vRA 8 using Workspace One Auth Source Product Version - vRealize Automation 8.x Why integrate vROps with vRA 8? vRealize Automation can work with vRealize Operations Manager to perform advanced workload placement, provide deployment health and virtual machine metrics, and display pricing.
So what is the problem? When configuring the integration, you will input the vROps URL and it will also ask you to input a username and password of the service account you wish to use.</description></item><item><title>Things we can look forward to seeing in #vROps 7.0</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/things-we-can-look-forward-to-seeing-in-vrops-7-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 11:51:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/things-we-can-look-forward-to-seeing-in-vrops-7-0/</guid><description>I did a quick search online and could not find a collated list so, by way of a quick summary from all the VMworld 2018 announcements and comments my good friend and PM for vRealize Operations Sunny Dua has made, I have collated a list of what we can expect to see in the next iteration of vROps (7.0). The list is in no order of interest or importance, some of the mentioned improvements have been long standing requests so enjoy and get hyped (I know I am).</description></item><item><title>#vROps data retention and the Cleaner</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrops-data-retention-and-the-cleaner/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 13:36:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrops-data-retention-and-the-cleaner/</guid><description>Something that has come up with customers recently is why and when old data is cleaned up from your vROps instance.
I will make the assumption that you have your data retention set to 6 months but the process is the same whether the value is less than or greater than 6 months.
When data reaches and or goes beyond the age threshold set in the global settings it will be cleaned away by a daily process &amp;ldquo;Old Data Cleaner&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title> #vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 3 – What’s New with vROps 6.6</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 06:52:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</guid><description>[vRealize Operations Manager 6.6, which was recently released by VMware.
We started with an overview of all the cool new stuff and then drill down into individual areas. We then jumped into a Live Demo as usual to see the new features in action.
We would highly appreciate if you could spend 30 seconds to fill up this quick and simple survey to provide us your feedback. You can also request topics of your choice through this survey.</description></item><item><title>Can I secure #vROps?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/can-i-secure-vrops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 13:42:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/can-i-secure-vrops/</guid><description>Those of you used to using vSphere on a regular basis will already be aware of the hardening guide for ESXi and vSphere but what about vROps?
If the vROps appliance needs to be hardened there is already a VMware provided guide and tool to accommodate.
Secure configuration guide - http://pubs.vmware.com/vrealizeoperationsmanager-61/topic/com.vmware.ICbase/PDF/vrealize-operations-manager-61-secure-configuration-guide.pdf
“The documentation for Secure Configuration is intended to serve as a secure baseline for the deployment of vRealize Operations Manager.</description></item><item><title>The vROps HA conundrum</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/the-vrops-ha-conundrum/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 14:54:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/the-vrops-ha-conundrum/</guid><description>One of the great new features included in vROps is High Availability, however when you look a little closer at how it works careful thought needs to go into whether you want to use it or not.
I have had several discussions with my colleagues on the subject about whether you should or should not enable it in any given deployment of a vROps cluster.
So the following are my thoughts and bullet points for you to consider when faced with same dilemma.</description></item></channel></rss>