<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VMware on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vmware/</link><description>Recent content in VMware on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Forwarding Tanzu Kubernetes Grid logs to vRealize Log Insight Cloud using the Fluent-bit Package</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/12/forwarding-tanzu-kubernetes-grid-logs-to-vrealize-log-insight-cloud-using-the-fluent-bit-package/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/12/forwarding-tanzu-kubernetes-grid-logs-to-vrealize-log-insight-cloud-using-the-fluent-bit-package/</guid><description>In my previous post I walked through configuring kubernetes ingress with automatically generated SSL certificates and DNS registration using Tanzu Kubernetes Grid&amp;rsquo;s Packages.</description></item><item><title>Ingress, SSL and DNS using TKG 1.4 Packages on TKGs Clusters</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/12/ingress-ssl-and-dns-using-tkg-1.4-packages-on-tkgs-clusters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/12/ingress-ssl-and-dns-using-tkg-1.4-packages-on-tkgs-clusters/</guid><description>So, you&amp;rsquo;ve set up your shiny new Workload Management on vSphere, created a Namespace and deployed a cluster&amp;hellip;now what?! When you deploy a workload cluster from Workload Management on vSphere 7, it comes with basic functionality, but in order to start running workloads you will inevitably need to install additional tools. That&amp;rsquo;s where Tanzu&amp;rsquo;s Packages come into play.
Tanzu&amp;rsquo;s User Managed Packages are based on a project called Carvel which:</description></item><item><title>VMware Validated Designs are discontinued - Long live VMware Validated Solutions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/11/vmware-validated-designs-are-discontinued-long-live-vmware-validated-solutions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/11/vmware-validated-designs-are-discontinued-long-live-vmware-validated-solutions/</guid><description>If you have spent any time designing IT soutions with VMware products you will very likely have come into contact with VMware Validated Designs (VVD)
VMware Validated Design is a family of solutions for data center designs that span compute, storage, networking, and management, serving as a blueprint for your Software-Defined Data Center (SDDC) implementation. The documentation of VMware Validated Design consists of succeeding deliverables for all stages of the SDDC life cycle.</description></item><item><title>Backing up Tanzu Kubernetes Grid (TKG) on vSphere Workloads to AWS with Velero</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/10/backing-up-tanzu-kubernetes-grid-tkg-on-vsphere-workloads-to-aws-with-velero/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/10/backing-up-tanzu-kubernetes-grid-tkg-on-vsphere-workloads-to-aws-with-velero/</guid><description>As more services go live on my Kubernetes clusters and more people start relying on them, I get nervous. For the most part, I try and keep my applications and configurations stateless - relying on ConfigMaps for example to store application configuration. This means with a handful of YAML files in my Git repository I can restore everything to working order. Sometimes though, there&amp;rsquo;s no choice but to use a PersistentVolume to provide some data persistance where you can&amp;rsquo;t capture it in a config file.</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2020 and VMware {Code} Connect!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/09/vmworld-2020-and-vmware-code-connect/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/09/vmworld-2020-and-vmware-code-connect/</guid><description>Where can you find me at VMworld 2020 VMworld 2020 - possible together VMworld 2020 is fast approaching (Sept 29th-October 1st), and in case you hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard, it online and free! If you struggle getting funding for tickets and flights normally, this could be a golden opportunity to get involved! Register for VMworld 2020 for FREE here! Please come and talk to me for my round table session, it will be awkward by myself!</description></item><item><title>Goodbye Wordpress, hello Hugo!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</guid><description>When I started my blog back in May 2007 (12 years ago!) I was running Wordpress, then switched to DotNetNuke, then BlogEngine, then finally back to Wordpress - which I&amp;rsquo;ve used since 2010. Today I&amp;rsquo;ve cut over to a new architecture based on Hugo and hosted on AWS using a combination of Route53, Cloudfront and S3.
Why the change? If it ain&amp;rsquo;t broke&amp;hellip; You may well ask why I&amp;rsquo;ve made the move, or you may not&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you anyway&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>VMware Clarity based WordPress Theme – v0.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/06/vmware-clarity-based-wordpress-theme-v0-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 21:12:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/06/vmware-clarity-based-wordpress-theme-v0-1/</guid><description>A couple of days ago I saw a tweet from Cody De Arkland showing his new tweaked VMware Clarity based theme on his website.
Staying up until 3am to get the brisket on, so what do I do? Work on tuning up https://t.co/YDiFkGIKLY with some better @VMwareClarity styling! Check out the differences below! Subtle changes but I think it&amp;#39;s a lot better. Thoughts? pic.twitter.com/6sYnuBahwI
&amp;mdash; Cody De Arkland (@Codydearkland) June 17, 2018 Cody has gone down the route of using Hugo and AWS, which I respect, but just seems like too much work for me at the moment!</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Network and Security keynote and NSX-T Architecture Deep Dive #NET1863BE</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-network-and-security-keynote-and-nsx-t-architecture-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 14:19:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-network-and-security-keynote-and-nsx-t-architecture-deep-dive/</guid><description>Transforming Networking and Security for the Digital Era Wednesday morning I attended the Network and Security keynote which, if I&amp;rsquo;m honest, I found to be a bit boring. To be fair, it was probably aimed at business leaders and maybe not those that are technical. There were three customer stories, but I would have liked to have heard much more about the problems that NSX solved for them specifically, rather than being datacenter transformation/cloud journey stories that included NSX.</description></item><item><title>The next big thing…</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/the-next-big-thing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 10:01:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/the-next-big-thing/</guid><description>Just under two months ago I left my role at Xtravirt and started life as a contractor. At that point I was content to live the contractor life for a year or so and see what opportunities came along. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect opportunity to come along so quickly!
TLDR; I&amp;rsquo;m joining VMware as part of the PSO NSX practice!
I&amp;rsquo;ve seen VMware as the place that I would end up working for a while now, having worked as a customer and a partner it seemed like a logical progression.</description></item><item><title> #vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 3 – What’s New with vROps 6.6</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 06:52:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-3-whats-new-with-vrops-6-6/</guid><description>[vRealize Operations Manager 6.6, which was recently released by VMware.
We started with an overview of all the cool new stuff and then drill down into individual areas. We then jumped into a Live Demo as usual to see the new features in action.
We would highly appreciate if you could spend 30 seconds to fill up this quick and simple survey to provide us your feedback. You can also request topics of your choice through this survey.</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7.3 Distributed Install – Prerequisites</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrealize-automation-7-3-distributed-install-prerequisites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 13:33:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrealize-automation-7-3-distributed-install-prerequisites/</guid><description>As a consultant I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to design, install and configure dozens of production vRealize Automation deployments, from reasonably small Proof of Concept environments to globally-scaled multi-datacenter fully distributed behemoths. It&amp;rsquo;s fair to say, that I&amp;rsquo;ve made mistakes along the way - and learned a lot of lessons as to what makes a deployment a success.
In the end, pretty much everything comes down to getting the pre-requisites right. Nothing that I&amp;rsquo;ve written here is not already documented in the official documentation, and the installation wizard does a huge amount of the work for you.</description></item><item><title>Announcing #vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 1 – What’s new in 6.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/announcing-vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-in-6-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:58:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/announcing-vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-in-6-5/</guid><description>Welcome to the vRealize Operations Manager Webinar Series 2017. With the huge success of the series back in 2016, we wanted to take a break, enjoy the success and come back with full rigor for this series in 2017. We are here and we are charged up to give you some more dope on vRealize Operations manager in the year 2017.
The delivery mechanism would be same as last year. We will start with talking about a topic and then jump into a live environment to see what happens when the rubber hits the road…</description></item><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – VCAP6-DCA Deploy Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-vcap6-dca-deploy-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 22:44:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-vcap6-dca-deploy-exam-experience/</guid><description>Greetings from Day 1 of VMworld US 2016!
 Every year I try and make use of the VMworld discount at the exam centre, and this year was no exception I sat the VCAP6-DCV Deploy exam, and results are still pending! Overall it&amp;rsquo;s a good exam, there was very little of the spelling and grammatical errors I&amp;rsquo;ve complained about in the past, performance was OK and the level of difficulty was good.</description></item><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – Day 0, #vmunderground opening acts, #beVCDX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-0-vmunderground-opening-acts-bevcdx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 17:18:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-0-vmunderground-opening-acts-bevcdx/</guid><description>I landed in Las Vegas about 9:30PM local time on Saturday evening, having not executed my plan to sleep on the flight! I had planned to sleep on the Toronto to Vegas leg, which would have meant I could head over to the Sips and Stogies pre-event, however a very rowdy hen do a couple of rows away meant that I didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep at all, so I grabbed a taxi down to my hotel, the Excalibur, and got myself checked in.</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2014: Day Three and wrap-up</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-three-and-wrap-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 09:05:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-day-three-and-wrap-up/</guid><description>*This post was meant to be published on Friday, VMworld Sleep Deprivation meant I didn&amp;rsquo;t click the button!*
This is the last post and a bit of a wrap up on my VMworld 2014 series!
There isn&amp;rsquo;t a keynote on day three, and there&amp;rsquo;s definitely a &amp;ldquo;winding down&amp;rdquo; feel as people tend to arrive later (if at all) and many are…feeling the effects of the previous night shall we say! That said, every session I wanted to attend was still fully booked and it was a case of queuing for the spare seats.</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 3.1: Configure Load Balancing with vCNS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 08:53:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</guid><description>This is the first part of the 3rd article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
By the end of this part, we will not have modified the vCAC deployment in any way, we’ll just have 3 configured load balanced URLs
vCAC simple configuration with vPostgres and Load Balancers prepared An overview of the steps required are below:
Issue and install certificates Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database Configure load balancing Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering Install and configure additional IaaS server Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster Deploy a vShield Edge appliance Log in to your vShield Manager and select your Datacenter, then the Network Virtualisation tab</description></item><item><title>VCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 1: Certificates</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-1-certificates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 11:43:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-1-certificates/</guid><description>This is the first article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
Simple vCAC deployment In a simple installation you have the Identity Appliance, the vCAC appliance (which includes a vPostgres DB and vCenter Orchestrator instance) and an IaaS server. The distributed model still has a single Identity Appliance but clusters 2 or more vCAC appliances behind a load balancer, backed by a separate vPostgres database appliance.</description></item><item><title>Book review: Networking for VMware Administrators</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/book-review-networking-for-vmware-administrators/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 09:34:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/book-review-networking-for-vmware-administrators/</guid><description>I recently got my hands on a copy* of Chris Wahl and Steve Pantol’s Networking for VMware Administrators and was very keen to read it – especially given the reputation of the authors. I came to the book as someone who is at CCNA level (although now expired) and someone who regularly designs complex VMware networks using standard and distributed switches. I would class myself as having a fairly decent understanding of networking, though not a networking specialist.</description></item><item><title>Definit authors awarded vExpert 2014</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/definit-authors-awarded-vexpert-2014/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 22:19:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/definit-authors-awarded-vexpert-2014/</guid><description>It was with great honor both Sam and I were awarded vExpert 2014 (my first and Sam&amp;rsquo;s second award!) we are both proud to be listed alongside so many others in the vExpert programme.
You can view the announcement and the full list here - http://blogs.vmware.com/vmtn/2014/04/vexpert-2014-announcement.html</description></item><item><title>Generating and Installing CA Signed Certificates for VMware SRM 5.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/generating-and-installing-ca-signed-certificates-for-vmware-srm-5-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 10:11:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/generating-and-installing-ca-signed-certificates-for-vmware-srm-5-5/</guid><description>I’m fairly new to SRM, but even so this one seemed like a real head-scratcher! If you happen to be using CA signed certificates on your “protected site” vCenter and “recovery site” vCenter servers, when you come to linking the two SRM sites you encounter SSLHandShake errors – basically SRM assumes you want to use certificates for authentication because you’re using signed certificates. If you use the default self-signed certificates, SRM will default to using password authentication (see SRM Authentication).</description></item><item><title>VCSA 5.5 Web Client fails to log on with &amp;ldquo;SSL certificate verification failed&amp;rdquo;</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/vcsa-5-5-web-client-fails-to-log-on-with-ssl-certificate-verification-failed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 16:13:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/vcsa-5-5-web-client-fails-to-log-on-with-ssl-certificate-verification-failed/</guid><description>This had me scratching my head, what seemed to be a common problem wasn’t fixed by the common solution. It was actually my fault – too familiar with the product and setting things up too quickly to test.
I installed a VCSA 5.5 instance in my lab as a secondary site for some testing and during the process found I couldn’t log on to the web client – it failed with the error:</description></item><item><title>VCP5-IaaS &amp;ndash; Exam experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/vcp5-iaas-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 16:01:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/vcp5-iaas-exam-experience/</guid><description>So this morning I took the VMware Infrastructure as a Service exam (VCPVCD510) to gain the VCP5-Cloud qualification. The IaaS exam is available for existing VCP5-DCV holders to take without any other pre-requisites. I am very pleased to say I finished the exam in good time and scored 466/500 – the pass mark is 300.
The Exam The exam itself is 85 multiple choice questions, and gives you 90 minutes to do them.</description></item><item><title>How to Virtualize Mac OS X using ESXi 5.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/how-to-virtualize-mac-os-x-using-esxi-5-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 15:02:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/how-to-virtualize-mac-os-x-using-esxi-5-1/</guid><description>As a proof of concept I recently tried to virtualize OS X (Mountain Lion) - It is important to note that VMware is now licensed to do so and you can read more here.
The following is an overview of the steps I followed to achieve my goal in some cases it was trial an error as I am not a regular Mac user.
The Hardware As OS X requires Apple hardware to run you will have to find yourself a Mac that will install and run ESXi.</description></item><item><title>Installing and configuring VMware Infrastructure Navigator 5.8</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/installing-and-configuring-vmware-infrastructure-navigator-5-8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 10:40:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/installing-and-configuring-vmware-infrastructure-navigator-5-8/</guid><description>According to VMware, Infrastructure Navigator is
…a component of the VMware vCenter Operations Management Suite. It automatically discovers application services, visualizes relationships and maps dependencies of applications on virtualized compute, storage and network resources.
Effectively it takes a look at the network connections that are running between your VMs (and physical servers) and works out which applications and services are running on each, and the dependencies – both upstream and downstream – for each VM.</description></item><item><title>vSphere Security: Advanced SSH Configurations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vsphere-security-advanced-ssh-configurations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 14:26:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vsphere-security-advanced-ssh-configurations/</guid><description>There are different schools of thought as to whether you should have SSH enabled on your hosts. VMware recommend it is disabled. With SSH disabled there is no possibility of attack, so that’s the “most secure” option. Of course in the real world there’s a balance between “most secure” and “usability” (e.g. the most secure host is powered off and physically isolated from the network, but you can’t run any workloads ).</description></item><item><title>VMworld Europe 2013 &amp;ndash; Day 2, VCAP5-DCD Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-day-2-vcap5-dcd-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 15:45:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-day-2-vcap5-dcd-exam-experience/</guid><description>Today was always going to be a bit of a funny day as I scheduled the VCAP5-DCD exam for 10am this morning. I am happy to say that I passed! I’m a bit light on VMworld to report today, so forgive my DCD experience to pad it out!
Preparation I have to confess my prep for this exam was light – I literally only watched the TrainSignal course by Scott Lowe (@scott_lowe) and just about finished that last night in the hotel!</description></item><item><title>What sort of lab would you build for $2000?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/what-sort-of-lab-would-you-build-for-2000/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 10:39:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/what-sort-of-lab-would-you-build-for-2000/</guid><description>John Troyer (@jtroyer) asked a question on Twitter last night about a CloudCred prize of $1000-2000:
@jtroyer a nice lab setup! — Sam McGeown (@sammcgeown) September 19, 2013 @jtroyer I guess a couple of hosts, storage and a switch, wouldn't get HCL certified for that but I'm sure it's doable! — Sam McGeown (@sammcgeown) September 19, 2013  That got me thinking – was it possible to create an entire 2 host lab with storage on a $2000 budget?</description></item><item><title>VCAP5-DCA &amp;ndash; Achievement Unlocked! And VMworld Europe</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vcap5-dca-achievement-unlocked-and-vmworld-europe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 15:47:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/09/vcap5-dca-achievement-unlocked-and-vmworld-europe/</guid><description>After my previous post about studying and the exam experience of the VCAP5-DCA exam (and 3 weeks of waking up to check my phone for the email all night) I am pleased to say that I received my Exam Score last week and it was a pass! I was really pleased to see that I passed with a very decent margin too, which was great! The rushed nature of the exam and long wait for the results leaves you going over the exam in your head convincing yourself how badly you’ve done, so it came as a huge relief and surprise.</description></item><item><title>Installing and Configuring vCenter Log Insight</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-and-configuring-vcenter-log-insight/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 13:32:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-and-configuring-vcenter-log-insight/</guid><description>With the release of vCenter Log Insight Public Beta (http://communities.vmware.com/community/vmtn/vcenter/vcenter-log-insight) I thought I’d strike while the iron is hot and run through the installation and configuration.
Deploying the OVF This is such a bread and butter task that it doesn’t require more than a few words – it’s definitely worth looking at the Sizing PDF before you deploy (VMware-vCenter-Log-Insight-1.0-Beta-Virtual-Appliance-Sizing.pdf) as it’s not small even for a test installation. If you’re using less than the recommended 8GB RAM there are additional steps to change the heap size for performance.</description></item><item><title>Installing VMware vSphere Update Manager Download Service and publishing via IIS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-vmware-vsphere-update-manager-download-service-and-publishing-via-iis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 15:30:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-vmware-vsphere-update-manager-download-service-and-publishing-via-iis/</guid><description>The vSphere UMDS provides a way to download patches for VMware servers that have an air-gap, or for some reason aren’t allowed to go out to the internet themselves – in my case a security policy prevented a DMZ vCenter Server from connecting to the internet directly. The solution is to use UMDS to download the updates to a 2nd server that was hosted in the DMZ and then update the vCenter Server from there.</description></item><item><title>VMware vCenter Linked Mode not supported through firewalls</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vmware-vcenter-linked-mode-not-supported-through-firewalls/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 15:28:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vmware-vcenter-linked-mode-not-supported-through-firewalls/</guid><description>This article originally started off life as a record of how I managed to get this working, as a lot of my posts do, but this time it appears I am foiled.
Last week, I had 3 vCenter Servers that appeared to be happily talking to each other in Linked Mode sharing a singe Multi-site SSO domain without any real issues. I had a single-pane-of-glass view of all 3 and I could manage them all from the one client.</description></item><item><title>VM Power On fails with error: cpuid.coresPerSocket must be a number between 1 and 8</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vm-power-on-fails-with-error-cpuid-corespersocket-must-be-a-number-between-1-and-8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 11:10:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/02/vm-power-on-fails-with-error-cpuid-corespersocket-must-be-a-number-between-1-and-8/</guid><description>Had a strange one after deploying an XP VM from a template today - the VM would not power on and threw the following error:
An error was received from the ESX host while powering on VM [VM name].
cpuid.coresPerSocket must be a number between 1 and 8
Digging around on google the error seemed to be related to over-allocating vCPUs (e.g. assigning 8 vCPUs on a VM with 4 physical CPU cores).</description></item><item><title>Installing the VMware Support Assistant</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/01/installing-the-vmware-support-assistant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 14:25:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/01/installing-the-vmware-support-assistant/</guid><description>So VMware&amp;rsquo;s Support Assistant is pretty awesome and it&amp;rsquo;s free! I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do a quick run through of the installation and set up for anyone who was interested, it&amp;rsquo;s fairly straightforward and if you raise a lot of calls or have multiple calls on the go it&amp;rsquo;s a time saver!
VMware&amp;rsquo;s official page for the Support Assistant is here - https://www.vmware.com/products/datacenter-virtualization/vcenter-support-assistant/overview.html
The OVF deploy is so simple I&amp;rsquo;ve just taken screenshots:</description></item><item><title>vCenter 5.1 Single Sign On Multi-Site error: User credentials are incorrect or empty</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/vcenter-5-1-single-sign-on-multi-site-error-user-credentials-are-incorrect-or-empty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 20:24:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/vcenter-5-1-single-sign-on-multi-site-error-user-credentials-are-incorrect-or-empty/</guid><description>While adding an additional vCenter Server to our Multi-Site Single Sign On instance I encountered a problem as I entered the details of the existing SSO.
The error thrown was:
User credentials are incorrect or empty. Provide correct credentials.
After a couple of hours online with VMware support I took a guess at the problem. On the existing Single Sign On Configuration I have added the Active Directory domain DefinIT and in order to enable integrated authentication from the vSphere Client I moved it to the top of the list - this meant that System-Domain is no longer the default authentication domain.</description></item><item><title>DataStore conflicts with an existing DataStore in the DataCenter – Manually disabling Storage I/O Control</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/datastore-conflicts-with-an-existing-datastore-in-the-datacenter-manually-disabling-storage-io-control/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 15:31:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/datastore-conflicts-with-an-existing-datastore-in-the-datacenter-manually-disabling-storage-io-control/</guid><description>I ran into this issue yesterday while reconnecting hosts in our vCenter Server following a complete reinstall - the reasons for which are a long story, but suffice to say that there were new certificates and the host passwords were encrypted with the old ones.
The LUNs had been unpresented at the hardware level by the storage team, but had not been unmounted or removed from vCenter. This is not the way to remove storage - let me re-iterate: remove storage properly.</description></item><item><title>vSphere HA agent for host [Host’s Name] has an error in [Cluster’s Name] in [Datacenter’s Name]: vSphere HA agent cannot be correctly installed or configured</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/vsphere-ha-agent-for-host-hosts-name-has-an-error-in-clusters-name-in-datacenters-name-vsphere-ha-agent-cannot-be-correctly-installed-or-configured/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 10:23:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/vsphere-ha-agent-for-host-hosts-name-has-an-error-in-clusters-name-in-datacenters-name-vsphere-ha-agent-cannot-be-correctly-installed-or-configured/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a lesson in checking the basics! I added new ESXi 5 host to a cluster today and spent a good couple of hours troubleshooting the error:
vSphere HA agent for host [Host&amp;rsquo;s Name] has an error in [Cluster&amp;rsquo;s Name] in [Datacenter&amp;rsquo;s Name]: vSphere HA agent cannot be correctly installed or configured
After a few basic checks, migrating the host in and out of the cluster and rebooting, I headed off to google and began troubleshooting.</description></item><item><title>vMA 5: Cannot initialize property ‘ vami.DNS0.vSphere_Management_Assistant_(vMA)’</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/vma-5-cannot-initialize-property-vami-dns0-vsphere_management_assistant_vma/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 17:25:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/vma-5-cannot-initialize-property-vami-dns0-vsphere_management_assistant_vma/</guid><description>Just a quick post regarding the vSphere Management Assistant 5 - when deploying the vMA with a static IP address, you might see the following error:
Power On virtual machine Cannot initialize property ' vami.DNS0.vSphere_Man- agement_Assistant_(vMA)' , since network &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo; has no associated IP pool configuration.
Edit the vMA virtual machine&amp;rsquo;s properties and go to Options, vApp Options and select disable. Acknowledge the warning and click OK to close the VM properties.</description></item><item><title>VMware ESXi Maximum paths includes local storage</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/vmware-esxi-maximum-paths-includes-local-storage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 09:45:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/vmware-esxi-maximum-paths-includes-local-storage/</guid><description>If you are close to the VMware ESXi storage path limit of 1024 paths per host, you may want to consider the following: local storage, including CD-ROMs, are counted in your total paths.
Simply because of the size and age of the environment, some of our production clusters have now reached the limit (including local paths) - you see this message in the logs
[2012-08-20 01:48:52.256 77C3DB90 info &amp;lsquo;ha-eventmgr&amp;rsquo;] Event 2003 : The maximum number of supported paths of 1024 has been reached.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading to ESXi 5.0 Update 1 using VMware Update Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/07/upgrading-to-esxi-5-0-update-1-using-vmware-update-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 15:34:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/07/upgrading-to-esxi-5-0-update-1-using-vmware-update-manager/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently updating a very small 4-host cluster built for a specific application within our datacentre, the hosts are IBM HS22 blades. Since we have the VMware Update Manager infrastructure in place already, I downloaded the IBM ESXi 5.0 Update 2 ISO and imported it into Update Manager, created a baseline and then applied it to the cluster. I scanned the cluster with the baseline and was issued this warning for each host:</description></item><item><title>VMware PowerCLI – Set Path Selection Policy on all LUNs for a host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/10/vmware-powercli-set-path-selection-policy-on-all-luns-for-a-host/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 11:08:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/10/vmware-powercli-set-path-selection-policy-on-all-luns-for-a-host/</guid><description>Just a quick script to set the Path Selection Policy on any LUNs on a host that do not have your target policy enabled. The script sets the server to Maintenance mode first, evacuating any VMs if you are in a full DRS automated environment. While this is not strictly necessary, it was required for my production environment just to be safe.
param( [string] $vCenterServer = $(Read-Host -prompt "Enter vCenter Server Name"</description></item><item><title>The case of the missing network adaptor: a.k.a Installing additional drivers on ESXi 4.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/the-case-of-the-missing-network-adaptor-a-k-a-installing-additional-drivers-on-esxi-4-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 14:15:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/the-case-of-the-missing-network-adaptor-a-k-a-installing-additional-drivers-on-esxi-4-1/</guid><description>Recently I installed and configured a client’s new ESXi host, they’re a small company and only require a single host. The host in question was an IBM x3650 M3, an excellent workhorse for virtualisation and one of 5 or 6 of the same model that I’ve installed in the last year. In addition to the onboard Broadcom Dual Gigabit NIC, we always install at least a second Intel PCIx Dual Gigabit card for resilience/redundancy/performance.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Software iSCSI multipathing on ESXi 4.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/11/configuring-software-iscsi-multipathing-on-esxi-4-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 16:40:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/11/configuring-software-iscsi-multipathing-on-esxi-4-1/</guid><description>Recently I had cause to configure iSCSI multipathing on a test ESXi server. The production environment servers use iSCSI HBAs to connect to the back end storage, so multipathing them is a straight-forward setup.
It’s good practice to separate VMotion, virtual machine and iSCSI traffic, it also helps you manage those logical and physical connections.
Connect to your ESXi server using the vSphere Client and select the host. Go to the configuration tab and click “Add Networking…”.</description></item><item><title>Managing ESXi 4.1 with vMA 4.1 on VMware Workstation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/10/managing-esxi-4-1-with-vma-4-1-on-vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 21:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/10/managing-esxi-4-1-with-vma-4-1-on-vmware-workstation/</guid><description>vMA is available as a Virtual Appliance (OVF) from VMware. To install it on VMware Workstation 7, open Workstation and select Import or Export to import a new OVF, the URL for the latest OVF for vMA is on the vMA download page
As per this article on virtualkenneth.com, you need to edit the VMX file to change the SCSI card and OS type, otherwise you’ll have a kernel panic on boot.</description></item><item><title>VMware vSphere – DRS only shows one host in cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/05/vmware-vsphere-drs-only-shows-one-host-in-cluster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 15:54:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/05/vmware-vsphere-drs-only-shows-one-host-in-cluster/</guid><description>I rebuilt an ESX host in my HA/DRS cluster today, following my build procedure to configure as per VMware best practices and internal guidelines. When the host was fully configured and up-to-date, I added it to the cluster and enabled HA and DRS. Then I went to generate some DRS recommendations to balance the load an ease off my overstretched host, but no recommendations were made.
I couldn’t manually migrate any VMs either – it was odd, because both hosts were added into the cluster, and could ping and vmkping each other from the console.</description></item><item><title>How to enable hot memory add on vSphere and ESX 4.0 after upgrade</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/how-to-enable-hot-memory-add-on-vsphere-and-esx-4-0-after-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 12:29:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/how-to-enable-hot-memory-add-on-vsphere-and-esx-4-0-after-upgrade/</guid><description>So you’ve upgraded your ESX 3.x servers to 4.0 and you’ve upgraded your vCenter server, now you want to access the shiny new hot-add feature to upgrade some running server’s memory. Except you can’t, the feature is no-where to be seen. Something to bear in mind though, your OS needs to support hot-add, so you’ll need a Windows Enterprise or Datacenter edition.
Here’s how to enable it:
Upgrade the VM’s tools, if you haven’t already.</description></item><item><title>Migrating VMware Virtual Infrastructure 3 HA Cluster to vSphere 4 – Stage 1: vCenter Upgrade</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/11/migrating-vmware-virtual-infrastructure-3-ha-cluster-to-vsphere-4-%E2%80%93-stage-1-vcenter-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/11/migrating-vmware-virtual-infrastructure-3-ha-cluster-to-vsphere-4-%E2%80%93-stage-1-vcenter-upgrade/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the process of migrating a 2-host High Availability cluster of ESX 3.5u4 servers to vSphere 4. This is going to come in 3 distinct stages: Stage 1 is to upgrade VirtualCenter Server 2.5 to vCenter 4, which I am going to cover today. Stage 2 is to upgrade each host, and will be covered as I do it. Stage 3 is the upgrade of the Virtual Machines to the latest VMware Tools and then the new VM hardware.</description></item><item><title>The requested Storage VMotion would move a virtual machine’s disks without assigning the virtual machine a new home, but such a move is not supported on the source host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/10/the-requested-storage-vmotion-would-move-a-virtual-machines-disks-without-assigning-the-virtual-machine-a-new-home-but-such-a-move-is-not-supported-on-the-source-host/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 14:04:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/10/the-requested-storage-vmotion-would-move-a-virtual-machines-disks-without-assigning-the-virtual-machine-a-new-home-but-such-a-move-is-not-supported-on-the-source-host/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m migrating some hosts off of an older storage LUN, but when I drag the disk to the new Datastore with the SVMotion plug-in the job fails with the following error:
The error occurs because the virtual disk cannot be moved without moving the source files, the .vmx, .vswap etc. Simply drag the entire VM, rather than the virtual disk to the new Datastore.
If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to move a 2nd, 3rd or nth disk and you get this error, drag the entire VM as per above over to the new Datastore, once that&amp;rsquo;s completed, go back in to SVMotion and drag the whole VM across again, only this time before you apply, drag the nth disk back to the new Datastore.</description></item><item><title>ESX 3.5 snapshots of disks on different storage are stored with the VM files</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/10/esx-3-5-snapshots-of-disks-on-different-storage-are-stored-with-the-vm-files/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2009 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/10/esx-3-5-snapshots-of-disks-on-different-storage-are-stored-with-the-vm-files/</guid><description>A.K.A Why not to use snapshots I ran into a slightly confusing problem today - our SQL servers are all created with 4 disks on 4 separate LUNs (System, Swap, SQL Data and SQL Logs). When viewing the server through Virtual Center I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see all of the LUNs, just the System LUN. It&amp;rsquo;s not a major problem as the VM can see the storage, but a little annoying when you have to remember what LUN the disks are on.</description></item><item><title>Teaming NICs with ESX 3.5 and Cisco Switches in an aggregate.</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/teaming-nics-with-esx-3-5-and-cisco-switches-in-an-aggregate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/teaming-nics-with-esx-3-5-and-cisco-switches-in-an-aggregate/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the setup. We have a core switch of 2 Cisco 3750s, connected together for fault tolerance as a single logical switch; we also have several ESX 3.5 hosts with 4 Gigabit Ethernet NICs installed each. The Virtual Machines will all be on VLAN 8 (reserved for internal servers) and the VMKernel will be on VLAN 107 (reserved for VMKernel traffic like VMotion). I want to create a load balanced, fault tolerant aggregate of these four NICs over the Core Switch.</description></item><item><title>VMWare Server: The VMware Host Agent service terminated with service-specific error 4294967295 (0xFFFFFFFF).</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/02/vmware-server-the-vmware-host-agent-service-terminated-with-service-specific-error-4294967295-0xffffffff/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2009 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/02/vmware-server-the-vmware-host-agent-service-terminated-with-service-specific-error-4294967295-0xffffffff/</guid><description>Having just rebooted my laptop, I clicked on the link to open VMWare Infrastructure Web Access in the my browser and was slightly puzzled by the &amp;ldquo;page cannot be displayed&amp;rdquo; error. I figured it was probably the VMWare Server Web Access service not starting for some reason, so I opened services.msc and checked it out. The Web Access service was actually running, but the Host Agent service was not, so I tried to start it - it failed.</description></item><item><title>SSH remote console to ESXi server</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/12/ssh-remote-console-to-esxi-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/12/ssh-remote-console-to-esxi-server/</guid><description>Having recently installed an ESXi server, I am getting to grips with the management and administration of it, one of the things that I wanted to be able to do was connect to the remote terminal through SSH.
I downloaded my SSH client of choice, PuTTY, and set about connecting, however the server refused the connection. It seems that SSH is not enabled out of the box for ESXi and you need to go through some steps to get there - I found some helpful hints here.</description></item><item><title>Utilising more than 4GB of RAM with Windows Server 2003 Standard Edition – Enabling /PAE /3GB</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/utilising-more-than-4gb-of-ram-with-windows-server-2003-standard-edition-enabling-pae-3gb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 11:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/utilising-more-than-4gb-of-ram-with-windows-server-2003-standard-edition-enabling-pae-3gb/</guid><description>We recently needed to upgrade one of our applications, and the new version requires an addition server instead of the application and SQL it requires a back end search, a front end web server and a SQL server. The specifications of the new server which are &amp;ldquo;required&amp;rdquo; to qualify for support are pretty high. The problem is that the actual processor usage is very light, and it is very hard to justify buying a whole new server that I know is going to be barely used.</description></item><item><title>VMWare Server 2 Beta fails to connect to virtual machine with “Error opening the remote virtual machine [machine] The host name could not be resolved.”</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/vmware-server-2-beta-fails-to-connect-to-virtual-machine-with-error-opening-the-remote-virtual-machine-machine-the-host-name-could-not-be-resolved/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 10:17:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/vmware-server-2-beta-fails-to-connect-to-virtual-machine-with-error-opening-the-remote-virtual-machine-machine-the-host-name-could-not-be-resolved/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just upgraded my VMWare Server install to the latest version of the VMWare Server beta, which I have to say, is looking pretty good! One slight niggle that I had was that when I opened the VMWare Remote Console it would tell me that I could not connect, with the error:
Error opening the remote virtual machine SM-00109:8333\16: The host name could not be resolved.
Clearly THAT&amp;rsquo;s a pain in the proverbial.</description></item><item><title>Moving and resizing a VMWare System Disk</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/06/moving-and-resizing-a-vmware-system-disk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2007 19:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/06/moving-and-resizing-a-vmware-system-disk/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently had to upgrade my VM Server due to an increase in load. I had 2 virtual servers running off of the same hard disk, with 768mb of RAM split between the lot. After jamming 2 new 1GB sticks of DDR in, and a new 120GB hard drive it was time to re-allocate some of these resources&amp;hellip;here&amp;rsquo;s how: WARNING! You should always perform a backup on a server you can&amp;rsquo;t afford to lose BEFORE any operation that could potentially destroy the disk (think what would happen if you had a power cut while resizing&amp;hellip;) Step 1 - Moving the Virtual Server.</description></item></channel></rss>