<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/category/community/</link><description>Recent content in Community on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/category/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate (003) Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2025/10/hashicorp-certified-terraform-associate-003-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2025/10/hashicorp-certified-terraform-associate-003-exam-experience/</guid><description>My experience taking the HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate (003) exam — preparation, exam process, and thoughts on why certification still matters.</description></item><item><title>DefinIT - A relaunch of sorts</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2025/05/definit-a-relaunch-of-sorts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2025/05/definit-a-relaunch-of-sorts/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s been a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked back and realised the last time I posted here was July 2022—almost three years ago! It’s hard to believe how quickly that time has flown. Consider this post a signal of intent: I’m planning to start publishing content here once again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="so-why-did-i-stop"&gt;So, why did I stop? &lt;a class="anchor" href="#so-why-did-i-stop"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a fair question. The truth is, I didn’t stop creating content—I just stopped publishing it here.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My VMworld 2021 Tips and Top Picks</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/08/my-vmworld-2021-tips-and-top-picks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/08/my-vmworld-2021-tips-and-top-picks/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I can tell from the ever-increasing urgency of emails from the events team that VMworld 2021 is just around the corner!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual conference event fatigue is real. I have attended and presented at many since the pandemic began, with varying levels of engagement. As an introvert, I can&amp;rsquo;t quite believe I&amp;rsquo;m saying this, but I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to get pack to meeting up with people in the real world!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value of a conference is super-charged by the mix of dedicated time, networking opportunities and quality live content. Unfortunately for me a virtual conference tends to be diluted by distractions on-screen (and off) and is missing the key ingredient of those haphazard incidental meetups in the conference center. And whether you prefer on-demand pre-recorded content or not, for me it loses some of it&amp;rsquo;s appeal when you know the mistakes are edited out. And yes, I edit out my mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2020 and VMware {Code} Connect!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/09/vmworld-2020-and-vmware-code-connect/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/09/vmworld-2020-and-vmware-code-connect/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="where-can-you-find-me-at-vmworld-2020"&gt;Where can you find me at VMworld 2020 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#where-can-you-find-me-at-vmworld-2020"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;




 


&lt;br clear="none"&gt;
&lt;div class="clr-content-image-wrap"&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href="2020-09-16-15-11-09.png" data-lightbox="2020-09-16-15-11-09.png" data-title="VMworld 2020 - possible together" class="lb"&gt;
 &lt;img class="lb" src="2020-09-16-15-11-09.png" alt="VMworld 2020 - possible together" /&gt;
 &lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;figcaption class="clr-caption"&gt;VMworld 2020 - possible together&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;VMworld 2020 is fast approaching (Sept 29th-October 1st), and in case you hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard, it online and free! If you struggle getting funding for tickets and flights normally, this could be a golden opportunity to get involved! &lt;a href="https://reg.rainfocus.com/flow/vmware/vmworld2020/reg/form/contactInfo?src=em_5f24f618aca08&amp;amp;cid=7012H000001xDgF"&gt;Register for VMworld 2020 for FREE here!&lt;/a&gt; Please come and talk to me for my round table session, it will be awkward by myself!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to become a vExpert - application tips</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/04/how-to-become-a-vexpert-application-tips/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/04/how-to-become-a-vexpert-application-tips/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the most recent round of vExpert sub-program applications, I was asked to help review applications for the vExpert Cloud Management track. As part of the CMBU and a long-standing vExpert it made sense for me to help out, and I was happy to do so. I reviewed ~60 of the applications that were in my area - automation. The experience was an eye-opener. What follows is a distillation of what (not) to do when you&amp;rsquo;re writing your application.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vExpert 2020 holographic sticker charity giveaway!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vexpert-2020-holographic-sticker-charity-giveaway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vexpert-2020-holographic-sticker-charity-giveaway/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; - the first 50 vExperts to sign up on &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/adfsWN29boZBhMDT6"&gt;this google sheet&lt;/a&gt; and then make a &lt;a href="https://uk.virginmoneygiving.com/SamMcGeown"&gt;donation to my fundraiser here&lt;/a&gt; or another charity of your choice will get a nice shiny new vExpert 2020 sticker!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I entered a &lt;a href="https://www.stickermule.com/"&gt;StickerMule&lt;/a&gt; tweet contest to get some free holographic sticker prints - and I won! While I was thinking about what to do with my newly donated sticker trove, I figured why not use it to bribe the vExpert community in exchange for some charitable giving?! And, given there were over 50 likes and 40 comments in response to my initial tweet, it seemed like vExperts were up for a little bit of paying it forward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using GitLab Pipelines to deploy Hugo sites to AWS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/using-gitlab-pipelines-to-deploy-hugo-sites-to-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/using-gitlab-pipelines-to-deploy-hugo-sites-to-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve posted previously about &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/"&gt;moving to Hugo as a publishing platform for this blog&lt;/a&gt;, this post is a bit more about how I&amp;rsquo;m managing the publishing using GitLab&amp;rsquo;s CI/CD Pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I need to mention that I&amp;rsquo;m using three different repositories for my code base, and why. The three repositories are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;definit-hugo - this contains the hugo site configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;definit-content - this contains the site content - markdown files, images etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;definit-theme - this contains the VMware Clarity-based theme I use for my site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;definit-content&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;definit-theme&lt;/strong&gt; are git submodules in the &lt;strong&gt;definit-hugo&lt;/strong&gt; project, mapped into the /content and /themes folders respectively. This allows me to keep the configuration, content and theme separate, and to manage them as separate entities. The aim is that the theme will eventually be in a position to be released, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to extract it from my hugo code base later on.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2020 - Simon's decade in review</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/2020-simons-decade-in-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/01/2020-simons-decade-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So it being 2020 now I thought it would be a pleasant exercise to quickly glance
over the previous ten years and reflect a little. Before I even begin I will say
I have never been happier in my career and work/life balance (which is always an
on going effort to keep appropriate)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to break it down in a yearly format and then summarize at the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Goodbye VMware PSO...</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/09/goodbye-vmware-pso.../</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/09/goodbye-vmware-pso.../</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Autumn seems to be a time for the winds of change to blow through our industry, and this year that&amp;rsquo;s true for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR - I&amp;rsquo;m leaving VMware PSO to join the Cloud Management Business Unit as a Technical Marketing Manager for Cloud Automation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a little over two years since I joined VMware as a Senior Conusltant in the EMEA NSX Practice, and in that time I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed some great opportunities, worked with some great people and technologies. And I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot since taking on my first NSX-T design just days after joining. But, as I &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/the-next-big-thing/"&gt;mentioned when I joined a couple of years ago&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve always said NSX comes alive when it&amp;rsquo;s automated by vRA. In fact, almost every engagement I&amp;rsquo;ve done over the past two years has had a strong vein of automation running through it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Goodbye Wordpress, hello Hugo!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/goodbye-wordpress-hello-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I started my blog back in May 2007 (12 years ago!) I was running Wordpress, then switched to DotNetNuke, then BlogEngine, then finally back to Wordpress - which I&amp;rsquo;ve used since 2010. Today I&amp;rsquo;ve cut over to a new architecture based on Hugo and hosted on AWS using a combination of Route53, Cloudfront and S3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-the-change-if-it-aint-broke"&gt;Why the change? If it ain&amp;rsquo;t broke&amp;hellip; &lt;a class="anchor" href="#why-the-change-if-it-aint-broke"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may well ask why I&amp;rsquo;ve made the move, or you may not&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you anyway&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Am I the best I can be right now?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/03/am-i-the-best-i-can-be-right-now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 09:55:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/03/am-i-the-best-i-can-be-right-now/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a few years since I read (and lost) a great article on career progression and personal insight. That article helped me relax into who I am from a professional point of view, but it also challenged me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been in IT for over 20 years now and in truth the first 10 years were not so great (perhaps a story for another time) but it was when I stumbled upon the vCommunity by way of Twitter and then subsequently I attended my first VMUG (in London) which completely challenged and changed my way of thinking and approach to my career. Talking to and observing peers whom I respected gave me a lot of inspiration to re-evaluate what I was doing in my career, why I did what I was doing and perhaps most importantly of all was I really being the best I can be?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Monitoring temperature and humidity with a Raspberry Pi 3, DHT22 sensor, InfluxDB and Grafana</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/monitoring-temperature-and-humidity-with-a-raspberry-pi-3-dht22-sensor-influxdb-and-grafana/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 13:52:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/monitoring-temperature-and-humidity-with-a-raspberry-pi-3-dht22-sensor-influxdb-and-grafana/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I recently started looking into ways of monitoring the temperature and humidity in my garage - for two reasons. Firstly, I have my lab workload cluster out there in the form of a Dell C6100, and I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed with the recent weather that the temperature in there gets…a bit warm. Secondly, I like to brew beer at home, and one of the keys to a good brew is consistent temperature!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware Clarity based WordPress Theme – v0.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/06/vmware-clarity-based-wordpress-theme-v0-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 21:12:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/06/vmware-clarity-based-wordpress-theme-v0-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago I saw a tweet from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/codydearkland"&gt;Cody De Arkland&lt;/a&gt; showing his new tweaked VMware Clarity based theme on his website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Staying up until 3am to get the brisket on, so what do I do? Work on tuning up &lt;a href="https://t.co/YDiFkGIKLY"&gt;https://t.co/YDiFkGIKLY&lt;/a&gt; with some better &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VMwareClarity?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@VMwareClarity&lt;/a&gt; styling! Check out the differences below! Subtle changes but I think it&amp;#39;s a lot better. Thoughts? &lt;a href="https://t.co/6sYnuBahwI"&gt;pic.twitter.com/6sYnuBahwI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Cody De Arkland (@Codydearkland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Codydearkland/status/1008269216049291264?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 17, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Cody has gone down the route of using Hugo and AWS, which I respect, but just seems like too much work for me at the moment! I am familiar with WordPress, and Simon is barely computer literate at the best of times, so I can&amp;rsquo;t ask him to start writing in markdown. But I did want some of this Clarity goodness - so I set about learning how to create a WordPress theme, and how to integrate Clarity with this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>GDPR, blogging and DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/05/gdpr-blogging-and-definit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 20:46:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/05/gdpr-blogging-and-definit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So…this is a frustrated sort of post. As you are most likely to already know, the new data protection laws (GDPR) are coming into effect on the 25th May 2018. I must emphasise that &lt;strong&gt;I am not an expert on GDPR&lt;/strong&gt;, this post is my layman’s conclusion for my specific circumstances. I run this blog as an exercise to help others, provide information and as a hobby. There is a lot of speculation around how this will affect bloggers, and a lot of panic and mis-information too. I’ve seen a few people this week simply shut down and delete their blogs - which is both upsetting and sad.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Looking back on 2017 and looking forward into 2018</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/looking-back-on-2017-and-looking-forward-into-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 09:59:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/looking-back-on-2017-and-looking-forward-into-2018/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Upon seeing others in the wider community making a blog post like this as a marker in the sand I thought I would follow suit as a way to see what I have learned and goals I would like to achieve in the coming year. 2017 was a good year and a very busy one at that, I got to see a lot of new places on my work travels and met some really amazing, clever and talented people.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Introduction to NSX APIs – vBrownBag</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/11/introduction-to-nsx-apis-vbrownbag/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 13:31:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/11/introduction-to-nsx-apis-vbrownbag/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday I had the privilege of presenting an introduction to the NSX APIs on vBrownBag EMEA - you can view the recording below or on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCaZf13iWhwnBdpIkrEmHLbA"&gt;vBrownBag&amp;rsquo;s youtube channel.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the presentation I showed a mind map of the API, which I&amp;rsquo;ve made&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sammcgeown/vBrownBagNSXAPI/blob/master/vBrownbag%20Introduction%20to%20NSX%20API.pdf"&gt;available on GitHub in PDF format&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/11/2017-11-24_13-22-20.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also published the &lt;a href="https://github.com/sammcgeown/vBrownBagNSXAPI"&gt;Postman collection and environment&lt;/a&gt; I used during the demonstration, which covers some basic configuration and deploy tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/11/2017-11-24_13-27-22.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Wednesday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-4-wednesday/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 17:30:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-4-wednesday/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/09/VMworld-2017.jpg" alt=""&gt;This was as I expected, the busiest day sessions wise for me. There was so much good stuff I had to be a little ruthless on what I wanted and or needed to attend while also wanting to get into the solutions exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also at the end of the day the customer appreciate party was scheduled so that was something I was looking forward to a great deal (Hint - Kaiser Chiefs)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Network and Security keynote and NSX-T Architecture Deep Dive #NET1863BE</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-network-and-security-keynote-and-nsx-t-architecture-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 14:19:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-network-and-security-keynote-and-nsx-t-architecture-deep-dive/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="transforming-networking-and-security-for-the-digital-era"&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Transforming Networking and Security for the Digital Era &lt;a class="anchor" href="#transforming-networking-and-security-for-the-digital-era"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wednesday morning I attended the Network and Security keynote which, if I&amp;rsquo;m honest, I found to be a bit boring. To be fair, it was probably aimed at business leaders and maybe not those that are technical. There were three customer stories, but I would have liked to have heard much more about the problems that NSX solved for them specifically, rather than being datacenter transformation/cloud journey stories that included NSX. For me, it felt like there was nothing new in the presentation that hadn&amp;rsquo;t been covered in the general sessions. I would have liked to have seen and heard a bit more what the NSBU&amp;rsquo;s leadership think is going to be big over the next 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Day Two General Session</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-day-two-general-session/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 13:09:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-day-two-general-session/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was honoured to be asked to be part of VMware&amp;rsquo;s CrowdChat for the general sessions this year, the idea being to live-tweet the General Session as it progressed. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to embed the session from CrowdChat itself below, but it might be blocked by your browser for running unsafe scripts. You can also see the commentary on the &lt;a href="https://www.crowdchat.net/VMworldDayTwo"&gt;Day Two General Session here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[http://www.via-cc.at/657sc]&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Tuesday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-3-tuesday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-3-tuesday/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/09/VMworld-2017.jpg" alt=""&gt;I managed to dodge the rainstorms in the morning before arriving, the hotel being just across the road from the Venue was a huge help (Thank you &lt;a href="https://xtravirt.com/"&gt;Xtravirt&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main session was great particularly HCX announcement and the VR admin demo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then hit the solutions exchange as soon as it opened. There are all the usual suspects there -except- Cisco (anyone know why?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also great to see the guys from &lt;a href="https://bluemedora.com/"&gt;Blue Medora&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Simon’s #VMworld 2017: Sunday and Monday</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-1-and-2-sunday-and-monday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 13:29:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/simons-vmworld-day-1-and-2-sunday-and-monday/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="sunday"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/09/VMworld-2017.jpg" alt=""&gt;Sunday &lt;a class="anchor" href="#sunday"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arriving in early on Sunday as the local flight choices are more limited from Bristol than perhaps a larger Airport, very fortunate to have a hotel so close to the VMworld venue, perhaps not so great for the evening activities but I am happy with it this way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than registration (4pm-8pm) and hopefully catching up with a few folk who have also arrived early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening I had the pleasure to meet many awesome people from the vCommunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Day One General Session</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-day-one-general-session/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 11:17:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-day-one-general-session/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was honoured to be asked to be part of VMware&amp;rsquo;s CrowdChat for the general sessions this year, the idea being to live-tweet the General Session as it progressed. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to embed the session from CrowdChat itself below, but it might be blocked by your browser for running unsafe scripts. You can also see the commentary on the &lt;a href="https://www.crowdchat.net/VMworldDayOne"&gt;Day One General Session here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[http://www.via-cc.at/057s1]&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: vSAN Specialist and VMware {Code} Hackathon</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-vsan-specialist-and-vmware-code-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 10:41:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-vsan-specialist-and-vmware-code-hackathon/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vmware-vsan-2017-specialist-exam"&gt;VMware vSAN 2017 Specialist Exam &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vmware-vsan-2017-specialist-exam"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I always like to take a discounted exam at VMworld, this year I opted for the VMware vSAN 2017 Specialist exam, which was released a few weeks ago. Having delivered quite a few vSAN based solutions over the last few years, I was fairly confident in the blueprint. I am pleased to say that I passed the exam with a score of 422, way higher than I expected! I thought the exam itself was fair, and covered and tested the basics of vSAN well. You definitely need to know the supported architectures and how storage policies effect and apply to the data on vSAN.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sam’s #VMworld 2017: Before I go…</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-before-i-go/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 13:35:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/sams-vmworld-2017-before-i-go/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;**&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;a non-VMware employee&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;! I am very much looking forward to meeting friends old and new during the week, so if you see me come say hi!&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where can you find me?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the day I&amp;rsquo;m likely to be found in the bloggers area, or hanging around the vBrownbag stage, when I&amp;rsquo;m not in a session. Monday evening I&amp;rsquo;ll be leading a fearless team of hackers for the VMware {Code} Hackathon, hoping to create something cool! Tuesday evening I will be at the vExpert party, and Wednesday is the VMworld Customer Appreciation Party (I&amp;rsquo;m pretty excited to see Kaiser Chiefs play!). This year I&amp;rsquo;ve opted to fly back on Thursday morning and see my wife and kids, so I won&amp;rsquo;t be about.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Looking forward to #VMworld EMEA 2017</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/looking-forward-to-vmworld-emea-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 09:30:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/looking-forward-to-vmworld-emea-2017/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/09/VMworld-2017.jpg" alt=""&gt;Having missed last years VMworld I feel very ready for attending the EMEA VMworld in Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I almost felt annoyed about missing last year as the big announcements really caused a stir in the community and wider afield. (VMware on AWS) The announcements from the US VMworld this year were equally exciting so I am very keen to hear what else VMware has planned to reveal in a Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have put a good deal of effort into planning what I will be doing and attending to maximise my time there without burnout (Veterans I hear you laughing)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>So long, and thanks for all the fish…</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/so-long-and-thanks-for-all-the-fish/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 16:06:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/so-long-and-thanks-for-all-the-fish/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working for Xtravirt for over 3 and a half years now, first as a Senior Consultant, and more recently as a Lead Consultant. During that time I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to work with some excellent people, some fantastic customers and some huge projects. I&amp;rsquo;ve developed and grown as a consultant and architect, achieved multiple VCP and VCAP qualifications, and VMware&amp;rsquo;s elite VCDX certification. For all of this, and for the opportunities and support they have provided, I am thankful to Xtravirt and to all of my colleagues who helped along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Book Review: VMware vSphere 6.5 Host Resources Deep Dive</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/book-review-vmware-vsphere-6-5-host-resources-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 14:36:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/book-review-vmware-vsphere-6-5-host-resources-deep-dive/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Host Resources Deep Dive book by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/frankdenneman"&gt;Frank Denneman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NHagoort"&gt;Niels Hagoort&lt;/a&gt; has been one of the most widely anticipated books in the VMware community - previous deep dive books by Frank (co-authored with Duncan Epping), tantalising blog posts and captivating presentations have whet the appetite for the last year or so. Having sat through some of these presentations at VMUGs and VMworld I can tell you the depth and understanding that the authors bring to the table is immense.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 2- Full Stack monitoring with vRealize Operations Manager</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/05/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-2-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 07:18:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/05/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-2-full-stack-monitoring-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;[&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-8035&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2017/03/logo.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; which vROps can provide by using various extensibility solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discussed the following use cases and demonstrated them in live environments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Use Case 1 - Full-Stack vSphere Monitoring. From application to Infrastructure.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Use Case 2 - Amazon RDS Workloads. Monitoring public cloud workloads with vROps.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Use Case 3 - vROps Extensibility. Metrics, Logs and Costing come together along with other 3rd party extensibility options.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Alexa, turn on my workload cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 15:05:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I already have a vRealize Orchestrator workflow to shutdown my workload cluster. What I want to do is trigger that by a voice command from Alexa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the correct and proper thing to do here would be to create a new Alexa skill, write the function in Lambda and connect that to my Orchestrator REST API and execute the workflow. That way I could control the “intents” and “utterances” and have verbal feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Speed of Change in IT Infrastructure (Opinion)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/02/the-speed-of-change-in-it-infrastructure-opinion/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 09:34:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/02/the-speed-of-change-in-it-infrastructure-opinion/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/02/The-Flash-FanPop.jpg" alt=""&gt;Over the past 6 months I have been dwelling more and more on the obvious speed of change and development in IT Infrastructure. What do I mean? Well each year there is the new hotness, the next thing/innovation you are told you need or should have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In most cases the innovations and new tech are ground breaking awesomeness and most certainly offer new opportunities for the infrastructure masses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am all for progress, if you are not moving forward and regularly looking for sensible ways to improve what you do and the infrastructure you use then I really do think you are in the wrong industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Security “fun” and embracing 2FA</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/security-fun-and-embracing-2fa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 10:47:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/security-fun-and-embracing-2fa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/11/Two-Factor_Image.png" alt=""&gt;So the other day my Skype account was briefly compromised, a successful login from Russia (after digging through activity logs) and this was after many attempts from IP addresses all around the world (China, Korea, Argentina the list goes on). You can see from the picture below the successful login attempt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/11/Capture.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My initial reaction was stress and panic, as I didn&amp;rsquo;t know precisely where I had been compromised I ran scans on my local machines while resetting passwords a plenty. Once I had calmed down a bit and reviewed where I had gone wrong I set about uping my game.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2016 – Day 2 workshops and sessions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-2-workshops-and-sessions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 16:50:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-2-workshops-and-sessions/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="vrealize-automation-vexperts-workshop"&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vRealize Automation vExperts Workshop &lt;a class="anchor" href="#vrealize-automation-vexperts-workshop"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I attended a workshop with Jad El Zein in Barcelona last year and it was one of the best sessions I attended, especially as it was just on the news of vRA7&amp;rsquo;s release. This workshop was this year&amp;rsquo;s equivelant, but because the session included a lot of people just getting started with vRA a lot of the time was taken to explain what vRA does, so there was no real time for the more in depth details on the new features that are coming (some already announced and in Tech Preview). I certainly don&amp;rsquo;t begrudge the guys just starting the chance to hear the basics from Jad, but I think a more expert session would also be good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – Day 1, #vBrownbag and VMware Code Hackathon</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-1-vbrownbag-and-vmware-code-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 16:55:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-1-vbrownbag-and-vmware-code-hackathon/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="day-1-keynote"&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Day 1 keynote &lt;a class="anchor" href="#day-1-keynote"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to lie, the start to the keynote was weird. There was drums and poetry. I will say no more. Another thing I&amp;rsquo;m not going to do (because many people do it far better than me - &lt;a href="http://www.wooditwork.com/2016/08/30/vmworld-us-2016-day-1-buzz/#more-6849"&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you Julian&lt;/a&gt;) is do a blow-by-blow account of the keynotes, for me the headlines are that VMware announced VMware Cloud Foundation and Cross Cloud Services.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – Day 0, #vmunderground opening acts, #beVCDX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-0-vmunderground-opening-acts-bevcdx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 17:18:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vmworld-2016-day-0-vmunderground-opening-acts-bevcdx/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I landed in Las Vegas about 9:30PM local time on Saturday evening, having not executed my plan to sleep on the flight! I had planned to sleep on the Toronto to Vegas leg, which would have meant I could head over to the Sips and Stogies pre-event, however a very rowdy hen do a couple of rows away meant that I didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep at all, so I grabbed a taxi down to my hotel, the Excalibur, and got myself checked in.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld 2016 – My session picks</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vmworld-2016-my-session-picks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 11:13:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vmworld-2016-my-session-picks/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In my post yesterday I promised to post my VMworld session picks, so here it is! I have filled my schedule, and even added some alternate picks when there were too many good sessions to go for. My session picks are focussing around:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vRealize Automation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NSX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VSAN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PowerCLI, APIs and automation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, before anyone tells me I&amp;rsquo;ve picked too many and I won&amp;rsquo;t make it to all of them - I know! I can guarantee I&amp;rsquo;ll get distracted/tired/hungry and won&amp;rsquo;t make all of them, but if I could…&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Heading to Las Vegas! #VMworld 2016</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/heading-to-vmworld-us-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 10:24:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/heading-to-vmworld-us-2016/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if I’ll take advantage of the cheap certifications this year - in previous years I’ve take &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vcix-nv-exam-experience/"&gt;VCIX-NV&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/"&gt;VCP-NV&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-day-2-vcap5-dcd-exam-experience/"&gt;VCAP5-DCD&lt;/a&gt; all with great results, so it’s something I’d consider, although at this point I’m not 100% sure what exam I’d take (I’ve done a lot of betas recently!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vRealize Automation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NSX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VSAN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PowerCLI, APIs and automation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus I’ll also be looking to pick up any sessions on emerging technologies like Cloud Native Applications, and some of the technology previews for upcoming feature releases. Hopefully there will be some sessions like last year’s excellent &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vExpert vRA7 briefing&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#UKVMUG &amp;ndash; Curry &amp;ndash; Beer &amp;ndash; Sessions &amp;ndash; Weddings</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-curry-beer-sessions-weddings-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 13:25:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-curry-beer-sessions-weddings-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vmug-usercon_thumb.png" alt=""&gt;This was my second UKVMUG and it was my first vCurry evening! so I was really looking forward to getting up to the event and seeing everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vCurry event was excellent and it was a great chance to enjoy good food in great company. Had the chance to meet with many people I would not normally get the chance to see, Frank &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fbuechsel"&gt;@fbuechsel&lt;/a&gt; and Brad &lt;a href="mailto:V@VMUG_CEO"&gt;@VMUG_CEO&lt;/a&gt; to name a couple! To top off a really great evening we (my table/team) won the vQuiz which was organised and conducted by Stuart &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virtual_Stu"&gt;@Virtual_Stu&lt;/a&gt; (thanks Stuart!), a big thank you to Matt &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Twickersmatt"&gt;@Twickersmatt&lt;/a&gt; for the beers (one of the prizes).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#UKVMUG Ravello Home Lab Winner!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-ravello-home-lab-winner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 11:11:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/ukvmug-ravello-home-lab-winner/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;First of all, thank you to everyone who came along to my session at the UKVMUG yesterday, it was great to see so many people at a round table discussion, sorry for those that had to stand! I hope that it was helpful and maybe a few of you will be building some awesome labs in the cloud!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ravello very kindly sponsored a free home lab, equivalent to the vExpert 1000 hours account as a prize for my session at the UKVMUG yesterday. Using a high tech random number generator and an Excel spread sheet the winner was picked, so without further ado, congratulations go to…&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>MindMap: vRealize Automation Roles</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/mindmap-vrealize-automation-roles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 20:45:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/mindmap-vrealize-automation-roles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I use mind maps quite a lot for study, I find the visual representation of info makes it a lot easier for me to remember! Below is a mind map I created for learning the roles in vRealize Automation, which I used during my presentation for #vBrownBag on VCP6-CMA objective 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download a PDF version here: &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vRealize Automation Roles Mind Map&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VCDX-CMA 204</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vcdx-cma-204/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 11:51:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vcdx-cma-204/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apologies in advance if this is post is a jumbled nonsense, I&amp;rsquo;m still way too excited!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning I woke to the news that I have passed my VCDX-CMA!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my second attempt at VCDX and although the first failure was a painful experience, the lessons learned from it were invaluable to take into the defence the second time around. Failing doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be a negative experience - if there is one thing that I will take from the VCDX program it is that there is ALWAYS more I need to learn, and I can always do better. Learning has to be a way of life (in this industry especially!) and the minute you stop, you start falling back.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015 – Day 2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-day-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 06:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld-day-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The first full day of VMworld after PEX was a busy one.&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/10/vmworld2015-logo1.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the keynote (highlights were the docker announcements) I was on “booth babe” duty at the VMUG lounge. It was great to meet so many folk who were existing VMUG members and leaders as well as prospective new members. If you are at VMworld this year you should definitely stop by!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/10/IMAG0043_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt; &lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/10/IMAG0044_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch I hit the solutions exchange to catch up with a few vendors whom I had a few queries for also took the time to collect the #vExpert hoodie from @simplivity and the #vExpert tile from Tegile (thank you!) Suffice to say it was very busy and naturally noisy but judging by the many happy faces of people with various items of “swag” under their arms things were going well!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: Pre-event and Partner Day</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-pre-event-and-partner-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 08:36:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-pre-event-and-partner-day/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;My trip started with a farcical attempt to fly – my 11:50am flight on Sunday didn’t leave ‘til 3:30pm, but in light of William Lam’s travel woes on the same day, I don’t think I’ll complain to heavily. After a quick stop off at the Fira to register and grab my VMworld bag and I headed off to meet DefinIT co-author Simon (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/simoneady"&gt;@simoneady&lt;/a&gt;) at our AirBnB apartment (which, by the way is awesome and a whole load cheaper than a hotel).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My #VCDX-CMA defense experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/06/my-vcdx-cma-defense-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 11:31:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/06/my-vcdx-cma-defense-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I received the dreaded email&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We regret to inform you that your attempt to achieve VCDX certification on June 09-11, 2015 in Frimley, UK was unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely unexpected, but somehow I still hoped my assessment of the defense was pessimistic and so it was nonetheless disappointing. It&amp;rsquo;s a big hit to not achieve something I have been focusing on for months and it is hard not to feel embarrassed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t make the grade. I am looking forward to receiving some feedback from the panelists and will be gearing up for another attempt in October.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>In response to @h0bbel: The "vCommunity"</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/in-response-to-h0bbel-the-vcommunity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 07:43:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/in-response-to-h0bbel-the-vcommunity/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is not my normal sort of post - don&amp;rsquo;t worry, normal service will resume shortly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Christian&amp;rsquo;s comments on the vCommunity&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; - or lack of it - yesterday and although some things resonate with me, and a lot of other people, I don&amp;rsquo;t quite agree. I want to be clear this is a response to Christian and not an argument, I respect Christian as someone who &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; contribute to the vCommunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Blogger briefing with Satyam Vaghani – PernixData</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/blogger-briefing-with-satyam-vaghani-pernixdata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 15:31:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/05/blogger-briefing-with-satyam-vaghani-pernixdata/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I had the good fortune to be invited along to a blogger briefing with Satyam Vaghani CTO and Co-founder of &lt;a href="http://www.pernixdata.com/" title="PernixData website"&gt;PernixData&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/05/satyamvaghani-304.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those of you not in the know Satyam already has quite the track record, more notably for authoring 50+ patents, Principle engineer and Storage CTO for VMware (10 years). So it is safe to say he knows a thing or two about storage and related technology!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nine of us (bloggers) were in attendance. (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dawoo"&gt;@dawoo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Archie_Hendryx"&gt;@Archie_Hendryx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Craig_Kilborn"&gt;@Craig_Kilborn&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GreggRobertson5"&gt;@GreggRobertson5&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dellock6"&gt;@dellock6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/egrigson"&gt;@egrigson&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/julian_wood"&gt;@julian_wood&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/simoneady"&gt;@simoneady&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/virtualisedgeek"&gt;@virtualisedgeek&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Book review: Networking for VMware Administrators</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/book-review-networking-for-vmware-administrators/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 09:34:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/04/book-review-networking-for-vmware-administrators/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I recently got my hands on a copy* of Chris Wahl and Steve Pantol’s Networking for VMware Administrators and was very keen to read it – especially given the reputation of the authors. I came to the book as someone who is at CCNA level (although now expired) and someone who regularly designs complex VMware networks using standard and distributed switches. I would class myself as having a fairly decent understanding of networking, though not a networking specialist.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>