<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Microsoft on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/category/microsoft/</link><description>Recent content in Microsoft on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 10:52:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/category/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing .NET core, PowerShell and PowerCLI on macOS Sierra</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/installing-net-core-powershell-and-powercli-on-macos-sierra/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 10:52:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/installing-net-core-powershell-and-powercli-on-macos-sierra/</guid><description>So, this is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting to write up for a while! PowerShell for macOS has been available for a while now, but what a lot of PowerCLI fans have been waiting for is to be able to use PowerCLI direct from their Mac.
Today, amidst all of the noise from VMWorld, PowerCLI Core dropped as a Fling! That means that although it&amp;rsquo;s not ready for production use yet, it is ready to start testing - and I&amp;rsquo;m way more excited than I should be!</description></item><item><title>VCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 1: Certificates</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-1-certificates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 11:43:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-1-certificates/</guid><description>This is the first article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
Simple vCAC deployment In a simple installation you have the Identity Appliance, the vCAC appliance (which includes a vPostgres DB and vCenter Orchestrator instance) and an IaaS server. The distributed model still has a single Identity Appliance but clusters 2 or more vCAC appliances behind a load balancer, backed by a separate vPostgres database appliance.</description></item><item><title>Generating and Installing CA Signed Certificates for VMware SRM 5.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/generating-and-installing-ca-signed-certificates-for-vmware-srm-5-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 10:11:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/03/generating-and-installing-ca-signed-certificates-for-vmware-srm-5-5/</guid><description>I’m fairly new to SRM, but even so this one seemed like a real head-scratcher! If you happen to be using CA signed certificates on your “protected site” vCenter and “recovery site” vCenter servers, when you come to linking the two SRM sites you encounter SSLHandShake errors – basically SRM assumes you want to use certificates for authentication because you’re using signed certificates. If you use the default self-signed certificates, SRM will default to using password authentication (see SRM Authentication).</description></item><item><title>PowerCLI Script to set RDM LUNs to Perennially Reserved – Fixes Slow Boot of ESXi 5.1 with MSCS RDMs</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/03/powercli-script-to-set-rdm-luns-to-perennially-reserved-fixes-slow-boot-of-esxi-5-1-with-mscs-rdms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 14:02:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/03/powercli-script-to-set-rdm-luns-to-perennially-reserved-fixes-slow-boot-of-esxi-5-1-with-mscs-rdms/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve previously posted around this topic as part of another problem but having had to figure out the process again I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth re-posting a proper script for this. VMware KB 1016106 is snappily titled &amp;ldquo;ESXi/ESX hosts with visibility to RDM LUNs being used by MSCS nodes with RDMs may take a long time to boot or during LUN rescan&amp;rdquo; and describes the situation where booting ESXi (5.1 in my case) takes a huge amount of time to boot because it&amp;rsquo;s attempting to gain a SCSI reservation on an RDM disk used by MS Clustering Services.</description></item><item><title>Installing a TMG Enterprise Management Server and Migrating and Existing Standalone Array: Part 1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/06/installing-a-tmg-enterprise-management-server-and-migrating-and-existing-standalone-array-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 11:21:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/06/installing-a-tmg-enterprise-management-server-and-migrating-and-existing-standalone-array-part-1/</guid><description>This is my current scenario: there are two existing servers in a stand-alone array - TMG01 and TMG02, and over in a DR site there is a new server (TMG03) that is in the process of being built. To comply with DR, all 3 servers must have their configurations up to date, however there is no direct communication allowed between the two DMZs, so simply adding to the new server as an array member is not possible.</description></item><item><title>SCOM 2007 R2: Daily Health Check Script v2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/05/scom-2007-r2-daily-health-check-script-v2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 13:57:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/05/scom-2007-r2-daily-health-check-script-v2/</guid><description>A couple of months ago I posted the first version of my SCOM 2007 R2 Daily Health Check Script - here is version 2. It&amp;rsquo;s more than a little motivated by some friendly competition with a Microsoft PFE for SCOM, hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ll agree it&amp;rsquo;s a big improvement on the last version.
Updated for this version
Formatting changed to make it more readable and more compatible Added &amp;ldquo;Report generated on &amp;rdquo; to the top of the report Management Server states reported as one section Default MP check moved to beneath the Management servers Agents in pending states moved to be with the Agent health states Clarified &amp;ldquo;Unresponsive Agents&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Agents reporting errors&amp;rdquo; Management server alerts streamlined Added top 10 alerts for the last 7 days, and added top alerters for each I&amp;rsquo;m planning to wrap in some SQL database size checks and some of the other recommendations later - I&amp;rsquo;ll post again here when that&amp;rsquo;s ready 🙂</description></item><item><title>PowerShell: Recursively taking ownership of files and folders and adding permissions without removing existing permissions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/02/powershell-recursively-taking-ownership-of-files-and-folders-and-adding-permissions-without-removing-existing-permissions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 14:59:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/02/powershell-recursively-taking-ownership-of-files-and-folders-and-adding-permissions-without-removing-existing-permissions/</guid><description>This is every file server admin&amp;rsquo;s nightmare: hundreds of shares, thousands of folders, hundreds of thousands of files - and custom or not inherited rights on many of them. Terabytes of data that need auditing - e.g. to find customer data, or credit card information. How do you go about accessing all the data in all the trees? What about backups failing because someone removed the System account? Of course you can seize control of the folder by taking ownership and pushing down from a top level - but how do you preserve the existing Access Control Lists?</description></item><item><title>SCOM 2007 R2: Daily Health Check Script</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/01/scom-2007-r2-daily-health-check-script/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 16:59:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/01/scom-2007-r2-daily-health-check-script/</guid><description>An updated version of this script has been released: https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/05/scom-2007-r2-daily-health-check-script-v2/
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with a Microsft SCOM PFE (Premier Field Engineer) for the last few months and part of the engagement is an environment health check for the SCOM setup. Based on this Microsoft recommend a series of health checks to for the environment that should be carried out every day. This is summarised as the following:
Check the health of all Management Servers and Gateways Check the RMS is not in maintenance mode Review Outstanding Alerts Review Agent&amp;rsquo;s Health Status Review Backup Status Review any Management Group Alerts Review the Pending Management status Review Database Sizes (Operations, Data warehouse, ACS) Review Volume of Alerts Review Alert Latency Document any changes From this, there are certain aspects that can&amp;rsquo;t be automated so easily, or shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be - e.</description></item><item><title>Overriding the OpsMgr Exchange 2007 Test MAPI Connectivity Monitor for Recovery Storage Groups</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/01/overriding-the-opsmgr-exchange-2007-test-mapi-connectivity-monitor-for-recovery-storage-groups/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 12:29:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/01/overriding-the-opsmgr-exchange-2007-test-mapi-connectivity-monitor-for-recovery-storage-groups/</guid><description>The Test MAPI Connectivity monitor for the Exchange 2007 management pack will automatically generate a critical error for any Recovery Storage Groups you have on monitored Exchange Mailbox Roles. As these are generally temporary Storage Groups created for a recovery and then removed, you don&amp;rsquo;t want an alert - but manually adding an override for every time is not a great use of your time either.
The State Change event details are as follows:</description></item><item><title>VMware PowerCLI – Set Path Selection Policy on all LUNs for a host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/10/vmware-powercli-set-path-selection-policy-on-all-luns-for-a-host/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 11:08:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/10/vmware-powercli-set-path-selection-policy-on-all-luns-for-a-host/</guid><description>Just a quick script to set the Path Selection Policy on any LUNs on a host that do not have your target policy enabled. The script sets the server to Maintenance mode first, evacuating any VMs if you are in a full DRS automated environment. While this is not strictly necessary, it was required for my production environment just to be safe.
param( [string] $vCenterServer = $(Read-Host -prompt "Enter vCenter Server Name"</description></item><item><title>More notes on Threat Management Gateway Arrays</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/08/more-notes-on-threat-management-gateway-arrays/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 19:57:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/08/more-notes-on-threat-management-gateway-arrays/</guid><description>It seems that despite my previous experiences with TMG 2010, I still stumble when creating a TMG array. Here are some &amp;ldquo;notes to self&amp;rdquo;, which will hopefully stop me making the same mistakes next time
Get the NICs right first In this case I came to a project after the initial installation of the array and there was no dedicated intra-array network installed. I added a new NIC to each VM and configured the IP addressing, VLANs and routing, but could not get the intra-array network to ping, let alone talk to each other.</description></item><item><title>Configuring a Guest wireless network with restricted access to Production VLANs</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/06/configuring-guest-wireless-network-restricted-access-production-vlans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 16:42:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/06/configuring-guest-wireless-network-restricted-access-production-vlans/</guid><description>It’s a fairly common requirement – setting up a guest WiFi network that is secure from the rest of your LAN. You need a secure WLAN access for the domain laptops which has full access to the Server and Client VLANs, but you also need a guest WLAN for visitors to the office which only allows internet access. Since the budget is limited, this must all be accomplished via a single Access Point – for this article, the access point is a Cisco WAP4410N.</description></item><item><title>Installing SharePoint Foundation 2010 with Remote BLOB support in SQL 2008 R2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/04/installing-sharepoint-foundation-2010-remote-blob-support-sql-2008-r2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 11:45:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/04/installing-sharepoint-foundation-2010-remote-blob-support-sql-2008-r2/</guid><description>Configuring WSS or SharePoint Services for a small client is a pretty effective way of getting a document management solution for a reasonable cost point. One of the limitations that caused headaches was that it used to have a maximum storage of 4GB, which was the database limit. If you wanted to go larger, you would need either a) multiple SPS installations, b) a full version of SQL server, or c) the full version of MOSS.</description></item><item><title>Configuring SSTP VPN connections to Threat Management Gateway 2010</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/configuring-sstp-vpn-connections-threat-management-gateway-2010/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 17:31:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/configuring-sstp-vpn-connections-threat-management-gateway-2010/</guid><description>SSTP or SSL VPN connections are great for people working on client sites or behind very restrictive firewalls – they only require HTTPS (port 443) to be open to be able to connect. Unfortunately, you need to be running Windows 7 or Server 2008 (or newer) in order to make use of them. Threat Management Gateway 2010 is one option for an SSL VPN endpoint.
SSTP VPN Requirements Clients must be Windows 7/Server 2008 or newer Certificate – either commercial or an internal Certificate Authority Published CRL – SSTP clients check for the Certificate Revocation List of the CA If you already have an SSL listener (e.</description></item><item><title>Keep it simple stupid!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/keep-it-simple-stupid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 10:57:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/keep-it-simple-stupid/</guid><description>I am a firm believer in trying to keep things simpler where ever possible (but not for the sake of it) In years gone by I have heard many admins lament about the complexities of deploying IIS to work alongside third party plugins such as PHP. I can remember numerous occasions where I have wrestled with the config and &amp;ldquo;best practice&amp;rdquo;.
I am however glad to say finally Microsoft have taken notice of this and produced a very simple and effective deployment toolkit.</description></item><item><title>Online Archiving with Exchange 2010? Can&amp;rsquo;t see your Online Archive in Outlook?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/online-archiving-with-exchange-2010-cant-see-your-online-archive-in-outlook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 12:37:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/online-archiving-with-exchange-2010-cant-see-your-online-archive-in-outlook/</guid><description>Having recently managed several Exchange 2010 migration projects, one of the best new features which really sells it to systems administrators is the Online Archive. “No more managing PST files? When can we have it installed by?”
The problem is, once they’ve purchased licensing for Exchange 2010 and installed and configured the server, migrated the users’ mailboxes and decommissioned the old Exchange 2003 server, the Online Archive feature is not available.</description></item><item><title>Exchange 2010 – CreateTestUser : Mailbox could not be created. Verify that OU ( Users ) exists and that password meets complexity requirements</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/exchange-2010-createtestuser-mailbox-could-not-be-created-verify-that-ou-users-exists-and-that-password-meets-complexity-requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 14:56:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/03/exchange-2010-createtestuser-mailbox-could-not-be-created-verify-that-ou-users-exists-and-that-password-meets-complexity-requirements/</guid><description>While using the New-TestCasConnectivityUser.ps1 script to create a test user for Exchange 2010’s connectivity testing, I ran into an issue:
CreateTestUser : Mailbox could not be created. Verify that OU ( Users ) exists and that password meets complexity requirements. At C:\Program Files\Microsoft\Exchange Server\V14\Scripts\new-TestCasConnectivityUser.ps1:255 char:27 + $result = CreateTestUser &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; $exchangeServer $mailboxServer $securePassword $OrganizationalUnit $UMDialPlan $UMExtension $Prompt + CategoryInfo : NotSpecified: (:) [Write-Error], WriteErrorException + FullyQualifiedErrorId : Microsoft.PowerShell.Commands.WriteErrorException,CreateTestUser Oddly enough, that OU does exist (as it will by default on any Windows Domain!</description></item><item><title>Remote Installation of SCOM 2007 R2 Agent on Threat Management Gateway Servers</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/01/remote-installation-of-scom-2007-r2-agent-on-threat-management-gateway-servers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 16:23:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/01/remote-installation-of-scom-2007-r2-agent-on-threat-management-gateway-servers/</guid><description>Getting a SCOM 2007 R2 SCOM agent on TMG is a useful way of monitoring TMG, especially with the SCOM TMG Management Pack – it’s not exactly “out-of-the-box” functionality though, with many sources I’ve read simply stating that it can’t be done. There are some half-working solutions I’ve seen, but nothing that worked for me.
The process involves simply opening the correct ports and protocols between the TMG servers and the SCOM management servers, which after a few attempts watching the live logs, I found.</description></item><item><title>Using PowerShell to add IP addresses to IIS7&amp;rsquo;s FTP IPv4 Address and Domain Restrictions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/11/using-powershell-to-add-ip-addresses-to-iis7s-ftp-ipv4-address-and-domain-restrictions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 10:55:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/11/using-powershell-to-add-ip-addresses-to-iis7s-ftp-ipv4-address-and-domain-restrictions/</guid><description>Today I was configuring a new FTP server based on IIS7 (well, 7.5 technically as it’s a Server 2008 R2 host), and I wanted an easy way to add and remove allowed IP addresses based on either an XML config file or a CSV import. Customers’ IP addresses are added or removed regularly, but I didn’t want to have to update their details twice, once on the server and once in the documents.</description></item><item><title>In-depth: Installing and Configuring Threat Management Gateway 2010 in a Network Load Balanced Array</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/11/in-depth-installing-and-configuring-threat-management-gateway-2010-in-a-network-load-balanced-array/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 16:35:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/11/in-depth-installing-and-configuring-threat-management-gateway-2010-in-a-network-load-balanced-array/</guid><description>In this post I will be installing a TMG Array as a “back firewall” behind a hardware firewall. The Array will consist of two virtual servers, TMG01 and TMG02 which each have 3 NICs. One NIC will be dedicated to the LAN network, accessible internally. One NIC will be dedicated to the DMZ network, accessible to the outside world on a static mapped IP. The third NIC will be a dedicated intra-array communications NIC as per Microsoft’s recommendation.</description></item><item><title>Creating/Enabling Exchange 2010 Personal Archives</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/09/creatingenabling-exchange-2010-personal-archives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 13:32:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/09/creatingenabling-exchange-2010-personal-archives/</guid><description>With the release of Exchange 2010 SP1, administrators can now use separate Mailbox Databases to store the Personal Archives of users – this is particularly useful if you have some larger, slower (and probably by virtue, older) storage that’s not really up to the I/O of your Exchange Server (that old SAN/NAS sitting in the corner of the server room?). It’s also useful if you just don’t have the capacity on your main storage.</description></item><item><title>Installing Exchange 2010 SP1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/09/installing-exchange-2010-sp1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2010 11:23:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/09/installing-exchange-2010-sp1/</guid><description>Exchange SP1 has now been released, so I thought I’d document the upgrade process for my small Exchange 2010 organisation, consisting of one CAS/Transport/Mailbox server, and an Edge Transport server.
References The starting point is always working out if you *need* to upgrade – what’s the business argument. For that you need to look at what’s new in Exchange 2010 SP1, the release notes and prerequisites. Finally, the installation instructions for upgrading from Exchange 2010 RTM to SP1.</description></item><item><title>Installing System Center Operations Manager 2007 R2 CU2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/09/installing-system-center-operations-manager-2007-r2-cu2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 15:28:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/09/installing-system-center-operations-manager-2007-r2-cu2/</guid><description>This should be a simple update of some hotfixes, but there were a few tripping points along the way that I had to stumble past. As reference I used the CU2 update page and I also a Kevin Holman technet article.
So, I’m going to assume that a) you’re installing the update for a reason, like one of the bugs it fixes and b) you have taken a backup of your OpsManager databases.</description></item><item><title>Testing throughput between two Windows Servers with NT Testing TCP Tool</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/08/testing-throughput-between-two-windows-servers-with-nt-testing-tcp-tool/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 10:22:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/08/testing-throughput-between-two-windows-servers-with-nt-testing-tcp-tool/</guid><description>The NT Testing TCP Tool is a handy little tool for testing the throughput between two servers – and it’s free! It’s available to download here: http://www.microsoft.com/whdc/device/network/TCP_tool.mspx
First, you need to install the MSI on both ends – for the sake of this, say SERVER1 and SERVER2. Once you’ve installed it on the server, navigate to \Program Files\Microsoft Corporation\NT Testing TCP Tool, you should see a few copies of the tool for different architectures.</description></item><item><title>Installing Exchange 2010 Edge Server with Forefront Protection for Exchange (FPE) and Threat Management Gateway (TMG) – Part 1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/08/installing-exchange-2010-edge-server-with-forefront-protection-for-exchange-fpe-and-threat-management-gateway-tmg-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 13:59:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/08/installing-exchange-2010-edge-server-with-forefront-protection-for-exchange-fpe-and-threat-management-gateway-tmg-part-1/</guid><description>I am mid-migration, in a co-existence setup with Exchange 2010, 2007 and 2003. So far the roles installed for Exchange 2010 are CAS, Hub and Mailbox on a single server. Into this mix I need to introduce an Edge Server, with message hygiene in the form of Forefront Protection for Exchange (FPE) and Threat Management Gateway (TMG) as a reverse proxy to publish OWA, ActiveSync et-al.
Since Edge, FPE and TMG can now all exist on a single 64-bit server, I will start with a clean installation of Windows Server 2008 R2, up to date with all the latest hot fixes.</description></item><item><title>Unable to access Outlook Web Access (OWA) after installing Update Rollup 1, 2, 3 or 4 – flogon.js errors</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/08/unable-to-access-outlook-web-access-owa-after-installing-update-rollup-1-2-3-or-4-flogon-js-errors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 11:02:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/08/unable-to-access-outlook-web-access-owa-after-installing-update-rollup-1-2-3-or-4-flogon-js-errors/</guid><description>If you’re having trouble accessing OWA after updating Exchange 2010 with any of the Rollup packages, try this:
Uninstall the update package from the Programs and Features control panel
Download the package file directly from Microsoft, don’t use Windows Update
Open a command prompt or PowerShell prompt as Administrator
Navigate to the location of the package (.msp) and run from the elevated command prompt.
Apparently when Windows update installs the package it doesn’t run it with the elevated privileges to write to the folder in the Exchange program files – why, I have no idea!</description></item><item><title>Passed Microsoft Exams 70-662 and 70-663 – Now officially MCITP: Enterprise Messaging Administrator</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/07/passed-microsoft-exams-70-662-and-70-663-now-officially-mcitp-enterprise-messaging-administrator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 09:49:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/07/passed-microsoft-exams-70-662-and-70-663-now-officially-mcitp-enterprise-messaging-administrator/</guid><description>On Monday I took the two Exchange 2010 exams, “70-662 TS: Microsoft Exchange Server 2010, Configuring” and “70-663 PRO: Deploying Messaging Solutions with Microsoft Exchange Server 2010” and I am pleased to say that I passed both of them, scoring an 812 on the 70-662 and 960 on the 70-663. I am especially pleased with the score on the PRO exam!
Overall, there’s quite a lot of overlap between the two exams, with the more heavily theory and design based PRO exam being a “high-level” of the more hands-on management and cmdlet based TS exam.</description></item><item><title>Requesting SCOM 2007 Gateway or Agent Certificates for Server 2008 from a Server 2003 Enterprise Certificate Authority</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/06/requesting-scom-2007-gateway-or-agent-certificates-for-server-2008-from-a-server-2003-enterprise-certificate-authority/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 12:27:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/06/requesting-scom-2007-gateway-or-agent-certificates-for-server-2008-from-a-server-2003-enterprise-certificate-authority/</guid><description>This is a pretty specific set of instructions for a specific environment:
If
you are using Microsoft System Center Operations Manager 2007
and
you have a Microsoft Certificate Services 2003 Certificate Authority on your domain
and
you have non-domain Windows Server 2008 servers you wish to monitor or set up as a gateway server.
Getting a certificate for either a Gateway Server or remotely monitored Server can be a touch vexing.</description></item><item><title>Exchange 2010 “New Local Move Request” and “New Remote Move Request” missing when you right-click a user’s MailBox</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/06/exchange-2010-%E2%80%9Cnew-local-move-request%E2%80%9D-and-%E2%80%9Cnew-remote-move-request%E2%80%9D-missing-when-you-right-click-a-user%E2%80%99s-mailbox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 12:14:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/06/exchange-2010-%E2%80%9Cnew-local-move-request%E2%80%9D-and-%E2%80%9Cnew-remote-move-request%E2%80%9D-missing-when-you-right-click-a-user%E2%80%99s-mailbox/</guid><description>I’m currently testing an Exchange 2010 server for the organisation prior to a migration project, specifically testing moving mailboxes backwards and forwards. Something that confused me slightly for a few minutes was this: if there is an existing Move Request (pending, in progress, failed or completed) you will not see the “New Local Move Request” or “New Remote Move Request” -
Fortunately this is very simple to counter – simply clear the old “Move Request” and the options will be back in the Mailbox options:</description></item><item><title>Unable to access admin shares (c$, d$, ADMIN$, IPC$) on Windows Server 2008 in a Workgroup</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/06/unable-to-access-admin-shares-c-d-admin-ipc-on-windows-server-2008-in-a-workgroup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2010 10:07:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/06/unable-to-access-admin-shares-c-d-admin-ipc-on-windows-server-2008-in-a-workgroup/</guid><description>If you have a Windows Server 2008 box in a workgroup that you require access to one of the admin shares, it can be a little more complicated than with Server 2003. In my case, we had a SQL server on the back end which was trying to access the web server in the DMZ using PSExec.exe to remotely run a process. Executing PSExec and passing the correct credentials failed with “Access is Denied”.</description></item><item><title>Certificate errors when connecting Gateway Server or non-domain Agent to System Center Operations Manager 2007 R2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/05/certificate-errors-when-connecting-gateway-server-or-non-domain-agent-to-system-center-operations-manager-2007-r2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2010 12:56:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/05/certificate-errors-when-connecting-gateway-server-or-non-domain-agent-to-system-center-operations-manager-2007-r2/</guid><description>This was a bit of an odd one. I was adding a Gateway Server to a newly rebuilt SCOM 2007 R2 Root Management Server when I kept encountering this error:
The certificate specified in the registry at HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\Microsoft Operations Manager\3.0\Machine Settings cannot be used for authentication. The error is The credentials supplied to the package were not recognized(0x8009030D).
I followed the Microsoft install and setup guides exactly, and it’s not my first time either – but I’d never seen that one before.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Forefront Client Security Setup Wizard fails on “Install Collection Server Component”</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/04/microsoft-forefront-client-security-setup-wizard-fails-on-%E2%80%9Cinstall-collection-server-component%E2%80%9D/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 10:54:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/04/microsoft-forefront-client-security-setup-wizard-fails-on-%E2%80%9Cinstall-collection-server-component%E2%80%9D/</guid><description>If you see the following cryptic errors when trying to install FCS, then the chances are you need to install the .Net Framework 1.1 AND SP1.
[06/04/2010 10:47:11] Task (Install Collection Server Component) The following process failed. Process: C:\Windows\system32\msiexec.exe Exit code: 1603 Number of tasks completed: [06/04/2010 10:47:12]</description></item><item><title>Server 2008 – Reporting Services Error The permissions granted to user DOMAIN\USER are insufficient for performing this operation. (rsAccessDenied)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/04/server-2008-reporting-services-error-the-permissions-granted-to-user-domainuser-are-insufficient-for-performing-this-operation-rsaccessdenied/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 08:52:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/04/server-2008-reporting-services-error-the-permissions-granted-to-user-domainuser-are-insufficient-for-performing-this-operation-rsaccessdenied/</guid><description>If you install Reporting Services on Windows Server 2008 (RTM or R2) and attempt to verify the installation by opening the http://SERVER/ReportServer site, you may well see the following message:
Reporting Services Error -------------------------------------------------------------------------------- The permissions granted to user &amp;lsquo;MCGEOWN\Sam.McGeown&amp;rsquo; are insufficient for performing this operation. (rsAccessDenied) Get Online Help
SQL Server Reporting Services
Additionally, you may be able to access the http://SERVER/Reports site, but will have no permissions:
You may also spend a good while checking DB permissions, IIS configurations, file permissions and so on.</description></item><item><title>Event IDs 1030 and 1058 on Server 2003 Domain Controller</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/event-ids-1030-and-1058-on-server-2003-domain-controller/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 10:30:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/event-ids-1030-and-1058-on-server-2003-domain-controller/</guid><description>I logged onto a production domain controller this morning and checked the event logs to be confronted with this:
Event ID 1030 and 1058 every 5 minutes, looking into the detail for these events I can see its a replication issue for one of the GPOs.
Event Type: Error Event Source: Userenv Event Category: None Event ID: 1030 Date: 29/03/2010 Time: 04:01:29 User: NT AUTHORITY\SYSTEM Computer: DC01 Description: Windows cannot query for the list of Group Policy objects.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Server 2008 R2 Core Series: Installing and Managing IIS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-installing-and-managing-iis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 16:52:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-installing-and-managing-iis/</guid><description>So, you’ve installed a new server with Server 2008 R2 Core – what next? Logging on, you’re presented with a shiny command prompt, you can run notepad or regedit…but aside from that, where do you go from there? In the next few series of posts I’ll hopefully point out the basics, and some not so basics!
In this post, I’m covering Installing the IIS web server (and a few useful bits) and managing it from the IIS Management Snap-in.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Server 2008 R2 Core Series: Management Tasks</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-management-tasks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 15:41:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-management-tasks/</guid><description>So, you’ve installed a new server with Server 2008 R2 Core – what next? Logging on, you’re presented with a shiny command prompt, you can run notepad or regedit…but aside from that, where do you go from there? In the next few series of posts I’ll hopefully point out the basics, and some not so basics!
I’m going to look at some management tasks – the bread and butter of being a Windows admin.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Server 2008 R2 Core Series: Network Settings</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-network-settings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 14:22:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/03/configuring-server-2008-r2-core-series-network-settings/</guid><description>So, you’ve installed a new server with Server 2008 R2 Core – what next? Logging on, you’re presented with a shiny command prompt, you can run notepad or regedit…but aside from that, where do you go from there? In the next few series of posts I’ll hopefully point out the basics, and some not so basics!
Using the Server Configuration Tool The server configuration tool (sconfig.cmd) is provided in R2 for some of the basic setup tasks, so you can run that by issuing the “sconfig” command.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Server 2008 RTM-SP2 to Server 2008 R2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/upgrading-server-2008-rtm-sp2-to-server-2008-r2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 15:06:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/02/upgrading-server-2008-rtm-sp2-to-server-2008-r2/</guid><description>If you read the Microsoft blurb for R2, the first thing you notice is that Server 2008 R2 is 64-bit only(!). It seems Microsoft are forcibly removing 32-bit server hardware from the data centre. I’ve not seen a decent upgrade guide online so far, so here’s my process.
I’m going to be upgrading a Server 2008 R2 x64 SP2 Standard Edition virtual server to R2. To see what editions can and can’t be upgraded, check out this Technet Article, but it’s safe to say that you can’t upgrade across architectures (32-bit to 64-bit) and you can’t downgrade SKUs (Enterprise to Standard).</description></item><item><title>Creating a Windows Server 2008 Microsoft Cluster Service SQL Active/Passive Cluster on a single ESXi 4.0 Server</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/01/creating-a-windows-server-2008-microsoft-cluster-service-sql-activepassive-cluster-on-a-single-esxi-4-0-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 14:52:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2010/01/creating-a-windows-server-2008-microsoft-cluster-service-sql-activepassive-cluster-on-a-single-esxi-4-0-server/</guid><description>Configuring the Virtual Environment and Virtual Machines Note – this configuration will work for ESXi 4 upwards due to the server 2008 MSCS requirement for persistent SCSI-3 reservations.
The first step is to create a new vSwitch for the host-only cluster heartbeat network, don’t assign any network adaptors to the switch as it’s going to be local only.
Create a new virtual machine with a single hard disk. For the purposes of this test, I’ve assigned 2 vProcessors, 1GB RAM, 30GB drive for the OS, 1 vNIC in the default vSwitch0.</description></item><item><title>MOSS 2007 – Alternate Access Mapping authentication fails</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/10/moss-2007-%E2%80%93-alternate-access-mapping-authentication-fails/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 14:58:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/10/moss-2007-%E2%80%93-alternate-access-mapping-authentication-fails/</guid><description>If you have an Alternate Access Mapping configured for a MOSS 2007 site with Integrated Authentication you might find that you get prompted for the DOMAIN\UserName and Password. After 3 attempts you get to a HTTP 401 error.
This can be resolved by following the steps in MS KB 896861
HTH,
Sam</description></item><item><title>DCDIAG /TEST:DNS fails with errors regarding root hint servers</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/dcdiag-testdns-fails-with-errors-regarding-root-hint-servers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 16:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/09/dcdiag-testdns-fails-with-errors-regarding-root-hint-servers/</guid><description>I recently resolved an ongoing DNS issue where the Active Directory Integrated DNS was loaded in both the Domain and the DomainDNSZones partition of AD - this is a separate issue and should be resolved differently. My problem when I tried to verify that the fixed DNS setup had propogated around my domain controllers, DC01 and DC02. DC01 kept failing &amp;ldquo;DCDIAG /TEST:DNS&amp;rdquo; with errors regarding the root hint servers. Googling about it was clear that a lot of people were suffering the same issue, but no article I read had correctly identified the solution.</description></item><item><title>Using AC97 audio with Windows 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/07/using-ac97-audio-with-windows-7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 08:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/07/using-ac97-audio-with-windows-7/</guid><description>Like thousands of other IT pros out there, I&amp;rsquo;m testing Windows 7 out on my laptop - since I don&amp;rsquo;t want to mess around with my main PC, it&amp;rsquo;s running on some older kit. The problem with that is that there aren&amp;rsquo;t many Vista drivers around for the hardware - why would there be, it&amp;rsquo;s not even supposed to be able to run Vista?! It does, however, run Windows 7 very admirably (just one of the many improvements).</description></item><item><title>How to force the removal of Folder Redirection from specific user accounts</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/04/how-to-force-the-removal-of-folder-redirection-from-specific-user-accounts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 11:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/04/how-to-force-the-removal-of-folder-redirection-from-specific-user-accounts/</guid><description>We have a folder redirection policy in place for all of our users in combination with a roaming profile policy - this policy is applied to the OU that contains our users. Unfortunately this policy was accidently linked to the root of our domain too, causing our Domain Admin users to be redirected too - something we do not want. When the mistake was discovered, the policy was unlinked, but the redirection remained (despite being set to revert when users fall out of scope).</description></item><item><title>Windows update or installer fails to install with error “You do not have permission to update Windows Server 2003. Please contact your system administrator.”</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/01/windows-update-or-installer-fails-to-install-with-error-you-do-not-have-permission-to-update-windows-server-2003-please-contact-your-system-administrator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 09:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/01/windows-update-or-installer-fails-to-install-with-error-you-do-not-have-permission-to-update-windows-server-2003-please-contact-your-system-administrator/</guid><description>I was just installing PowerShell on one of my Windows Server 2003 servers, when I encountered the error &amp;ldquo;You do not have permission to update Windows Server 2003. Please contact your system administrator.&amp;rdquo; Odd, especially considering that I was installing as the Domain Administrator, and that user should have more than enough permissions. A little bit of digging led me to MSKB 888791 which shows the permissions that are required in Group Policy to install the update.</description></item><item><title>Windows Vista Local Area Network Connection “Authentication Failed”</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/01/windows-vista-local-area-network-connection-%E2%80%9Cauthentication-failed%E2%80%9D/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 13:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2009/01/windows-vista-local-area-network-connection-%E2%80%9Cauthentication-failed%E2%80%9D/</guid><description>If you’re getting a error on your LAN connection it’s possible that your network connection is attempting 802.11 authentication on your wired network. Unfortunately, it seems that Vista/Server 2008 both attempt it before reverting. As far as I can see, it’s not causing any issues, other than irritating me with a “failed” and a red question mark.
Fortunately, it’s pretty easy to fix! The authentication is handled by the Wired AutoConfig service, so it’s just a case of disabling it.</description></item><item><title>Activating Microsoft Reader on a Windows Mobile 5 device under Vista</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/10/activating-microsoft-reader-on-a-windows-mobile-5-device-under-vista/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 14:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/10/activating-microsoft-reader-on-a-windows-mobile-5-device-under-vista/</guid><description>I recently tried to use Microsoft reader on my iMate K-Jam mobile, it&amp;rsquo;s Windows Mobile 5 powered, so according to Microsoft it&amp;rsquo;s fully supported. However, when I tried to activate, I got the following error:
&amp;ldquo;You have an older version of Pocket PC which does not support Activation&amp;rdquo;
Not true I cried, and after a lot of Google-ing and trying various different fixes that are posted on the net, I found the only one that actually worked for me!</description></item><item><title>How to configure Windows Server 2003 Enterprise and SQL 2005 to use more then 4GB RAM</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/10/how-to-configure-windows-server-2003-enterprise-and-sql-2005-to-use-more-then-4gb-ram/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 11:43:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/10/how-to-configure-windows-server-2003-enterprise-and-sql-2005-to-use-more-then-4gb-ram/</guid><description>32-bit processors have a limitation of only being able to directly address 4GB RAM - their architecture was never designed to address more. 64-bit processors get around that limitation by being able to us 64 bits to address RAM (potentially 16,777,216 GB), but what do you do if you have an application that won&amp;rsquo;t work on a 64-bit copy of Windows, but does need to utilise more than 4GB of RAM?</description></item><item><title>Vista DVD/CDRW drive message "Prepare this blank disk"</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/10/vista-dvdcdrw-drive-message-prepare-this-blank-disk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 10:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/10/vista-dvdcdrw-drive-message-prepare-this-blank-disk/</guid><description>For a little while now I&amp;rsquo;ve had an irritating problem with my Vista laptop. Whenever I insert a DVD, CD of any kind, pops up the message asking me to prepare a blank disk:
It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to access the files on the disc and I don&amp;rsquo;t want Vista trying to &amp;ldquo;prepare&amp;rdquo; my data disc. Quite irritating, but not irritating enough to fix right away.
Microsoft have a KB article about it, which has worked in some cases, but not in most.</description></item><item><title>Compiling a .Net DLL for a medium trust environment</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/09/compiling-a-net-dll-for-a-medium-trust-environment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/09/compiling-a-net-dll-for-a-medium-trust-environment/</guid><description>Recently I wrote a little utility for a client using the excellent Html Agility Pack to read and navigate through a HTML page, selecting the data that was needed and parsing it - basically a screen scrape. I downloaded the source, compiled it, added a reference to the dll in my project and tapped away for a few minutes and et voila, within a few minutes a working screen scrape. A fantastic library.</description></item><item><title>I’ve achieved my MCSE</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/09/ive-achieved-my-mcse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 09:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/09/ive-achieved-my-mcse/</guid><description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve been away with my friends at Firebrand again and guess what…MCSE Windows Server 2003!
70-293 Planning and Maintaining a Microsoft Windows Server 2003 Network Infrastructure 70-294 Planning, Implementing, and Maintaining a Microsoft Windows Server 2003 Active Directory Infrastructure 70-298 Designing Security for a Microsoft Windows Server 2003 Network</description></item><item><title>Create a 100Mb file for testing transfer speeds</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/create-a-100mb-file-for-testing-transfer-speeds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2008 10:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/create-a-100mb-file-for-testing-transfer-speeds/</guid><description>We have a Bonded ADSL solution for our servers to provide the necessary upstream transfer speeds for the applications we host. We have bonded ADSL because our exchange still doesn&amp;rsquo;t support SDSL, and a leased line is overkill. Theoretically, we should have 28.1 Mbps download and 3.2Mbps upload - what I am actually seeing is about 1.7Mbps down and 1.9Mbps up. I have tested this on various servers, over various times and file sizes, there is no doubt that the performance is POOR.</description></item><item><title>Outlook Web Access over SSL using Forms Based Authentication AND Integrated Authentication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/outlook-web-access-over-ssl-using-forms-based-authentication-and-integrated-authentication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/07/outlook-web-access-over-ssl-using-forms-based-authentication-and-integrated-authentication/</guid><description>Outlook Web access is a fantastic tool for our company, providing on-the-go
access to people&amp;rsquo;s mailboxes - which is of course secured by SSL and uses Forms
Based Authentication. Internally, we have an intranet portal that allows us to
access the various systems - one of which is OWA. One of the stipulations for
this internal portal is that it is all Single Sign On using NTLM authentication
integrated authentication. This is where the problem lies because enabling OWA with Forms Based Authentication over SSL disables Integrated Authentication.</description></item><item><title>Menus in MOSS (or WSS) open and disappear</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/menus-in-moss-or-wss-open-and-disappear/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2008 19:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/05/menus-in-moss-or-wss-open-and-disappear/</guid><description>We were integrating a 3rd party product&amp;rsquo;s web parts with MOSS the other day and came accross an interesting problem. In site editing mode, all the drop down menus would appear for a flash and then go blank. The actual admin pages we were trying to get to would work if you entered them into the browser directly, but that isn&amp;rsquo;t an easy way to manage the site!
The problem turned out to be that in the process of getting the 3rd party web parts to work, the support team had added a MIME type to the IIS installation.</description></item><item><title>Adding a Windows 2003 domain controller to your existing Windows 2000 domain</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/04/adding-a-windows-2003-domain-controller-to-your-existing-windows-2000-domain/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2008 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/04/adding-a-windows-2003-domain-controller-to-your-existing-windows-2000-domain/</guid><description>I was adding a shiny new domain controller to my server farm earlier today, we have just two Windows 2000 SP4 domain controllers on old kit and they&amp;nbsp;are due to retire. With the hardware selected, purchased&amp;nbsp;and a fresh copy of Windows Server 2003 R2 installed, I set to installing Active Directory. DCPromo.exe fires up and I go through the configuration steps until&amp;#8230; "The Active Directory Installation Wizard cannot continue because the forest is not prepared for installing Windows Server 2003.</description></item><item><title>Restoring the ASP.NET tab in IIS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/04/restoring-the-asp-net-tab-in-iis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2008 18:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/04/restoring-the-asp-net-tab-in-iis/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve logged onto the properties for your IIS install and found that the ASP.NET tab has mysteriously disappered, you can try a couple of things.
Firstly, try re-registering ASP.NET with IIS using the ASPNET_REGIIS.exe located in the .NET installation folder:
c:\WINDOWS\MICROSOFT.NET\framework\\aspnet_regiis -i &amp;nbsp; Chances are though, that it won't work, and that you can try and number of command using aspnet_regiis.exe or even uninstalling and reinstalling .NET and you won't actually fix the problem.</description></item><item><title>Installing Windows XP without a CD drive</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/03/installing-windows-xp-without-a-cd-drive/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/03/installing-windows-xp-without-a-cd-drive/</guid><description>When the Dell engineer said “they’ve asked if you can reinstall the OS” my heart sank. Not because I felt like he was weasling out of work - unusually they were very helpful. Not because installing XP is a hard task, I’ve done it over 100 times on all sorts of hardware.
No, the reason I let out a sigh was because this particular laptop, the Latitude X1, has no internal CD/DVD drive.</description></item><item><title>Retrieving Your Exchange Server 2003 License Key</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/02/retrieving-your-exchange-server-2003-license-key/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/02/retrieving-your-exchange-server-2003-license-key/</guid><description>Recently I found the need to retrieve the key from an existing Exchange Server for a reinstall - the software is legally licensed but the key was somehow lost. A trawl through my registry revealed that the key is stored in an obscure place:
HKLM\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\Microsoft Integration\{GUID}\PID3.0 This was the case on a Windows Server 2000 install with Exchange Server 2003 installed, when I get the chance I will test this on Server 2003.</description></item><item><title>Using NTDSUtil to transfer FSMO Roles by command line</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/01/using-ntdsutil-to-transfer-fsmo-roles-by-command-line/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2008 20:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2008/01/using-ntdsutil-to-transfer-fsmo-roles-by-command-line/</guid><description>I’ve just removed a domain controller (DC) from my root domain, the very first server not only in the domain, but the forest. The roles were migrating to a newer server, far more up to the job, but it isn’t a job to be taken lightly. If you mess up the root domain, you’ve potentially got problems all the way down your domain hierarchy.
&amp;nbsp; Let me explain; the primary domain controller in a domain (normally the first domain controller) hosts all the FSMO roles.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Project Location Not Trusted</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/06/visual-studio-project-location-not-trusted/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2007 19:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/06/visual-studio-project-location-not-trusted/</guid><description>Just a quick post today about trust levels for .NET assemblies that are hosted remotely. My current set up at work means that I am maintaining one version of our web site while working on developing a new one - not uncommon. I have 2 virtual servers running Server 2003, IIS and SQL Server, each an identical copy of our production server. Each solution and it&amp;rsquo;s projects are stored on each virtual server, with the project folders shared and mapped as drives on my laptop.</description></item><item><title>Office 2007 woes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/05/office-2007-woes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 20:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2007/05/office-2007-woes/</guid><description>Originally published Wednesday, May 30th, 2007 Wahey! I got published this week in IT Week, ok it was only a readers letter, but I got in! Here’s what I wrote: “New software always excites me, so I was enthusiastic as I installed Office 2007 on my laptop. The machine offers more than enough grunt for my media applications, but sadly not quite enough to install Office in less than 15 minutes, plus one restart.</description></item></channel></rss>