<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ha on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/ha/</link><description>Recent content in ha on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 19:32:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/ha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding #vROps High Availability</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/understanding-vrops-high-availability/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 19:32:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/understanding-vrops-high-availability/</guid><description>While there is a reasonable amount of information about how HA works in vROps I have found there is still some confusion as to how HA actually works with vROps or rather what are the benefits and perhaps more importantly the cost for enabling the feature.
HA is a great feature and in my opinion should be considered seriously with any deployment (where possible).
Not only does HA protect your Master node (which essentially behaves as an index for your vROps cluster and if lost will render your cluster dead unless you have a working backup of your cluster) it will also allow your cluster to tolerate a data node failure.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 5 : Design and Deployment considerations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-part-5-design-and-deployment-considerations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 13:25:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-part-5-design-and-deployment-considerations/</guid><description>As promised, I am posting the recording for the 5th Session of vROps Webinar Series 2016. Both Sunny and I successfully delivered the session on Design and Deployment considerations.
Session Details:- In this instalment of the series, we discussed the steps and thought processes that should be used before and during the design and deployment of vRealize Operations Manager. During the session among other things we will cover the planning, core components, correct sizing, HA, clustering, DR and future growth**.</description></item><item><title>The vROps HA conundrum</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/the-vrops-ha-conundrum/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 14:54:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/the-vrops-ha-conundrum/</guid><description>One of the great new features included in vROps is High Availability, however when you look a little closer at how it works careful thought needs to go into whether you want to use it or not.
I have had several discussions with my colleagues on the subject about whether you should or should not enable it in any given deployment of a vROps cluster.
So the following are my thoughts and bullet points for you to consider when faced with same dilemma.</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 HA SSO (PSC) with NetScaler VPX Load Balancer for vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 15:40:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>vSphere 6 HA SSO (PSC) with NetScaler VPX Load Balancer for vRealize Automation Deploying vRealize Automation 6.2 Appliance Cluster with Postgres Replication Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components - Part 1: Pre-requisites Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components - Part 2: Database, Web and Manager services Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation instance - Configuring NetScaler Monitors Providing a highly available single sign on for vRealize Automation is a fundamental part of ensuring the availability of the platform.</description></item><item><title>vSphere HA agent for host [Host’s Name] has an error in [Cluster’s Name] in [Datacenter’s Name]: vSphere HA agent cannot be correctly installed or configured</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/vsphere-ha-agent-for-host-hosts-name-has-an-error-in-clusters-name-in-datacenters-name-vsphere-ha-agent-cannot-be-correctly-installed-or-configured/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 10:23:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/08/vsphere-ha-agent-for-host-hosts-name-has-an-error-in-clusters-name-in-datacenters-name-vsphere-ha-agent-cannot-be-correctly-installed-or-configured/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a lesson in checking the basics! I added new ESXi 5 host to a cluster today and spent a good couple of hours troubleshooting the error:
vSphere HA agent for host [Host&amp;rsquo;s Name] has an error in [Cluster&amp;rsquo;s Name] in [Datacenter&amp;rsquo;s Name]: vSphere HA agent cannot be correctly installed or configured After a few basic checks, migrating the host in and out of the cluster and rebooting, I headed off to google and began troubleshooting.</description></item></channel></rss>