<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vrealize automation 7 on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vrealize-automation-7/</link><description>Recent content in vrealize automation 7 on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 22:38:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vrealize-automation-7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating an AWS Hardware VPN Connection with Ubiquiti EdgeRouterX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/creating-an-aws-hardware-vpn-connection-with-ubiquiti-edgerouterx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 22:38:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/creating-an-aws-hardware-vpn-connection-with-ubiquiti-edgerouterx/</guid><description>When you&amp;rsquo;re working with Amazon and vRealize Automation Software Components, one of the requirements is for the Guest Agent (gugent) to talk back to the vRealize Automation APIs - the gugent polls the API for tasks it should perform, downloads them from the API and executes them, then updates the tasks with a status.
This means that Virtual Machines deployed as EC2 instances in an AWS VPC require the ability to talk back to internal corporate networks - not something you&amp;rsquo;d want to publish on the internet!</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: vRealize Automation 7 Briefing Notes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 08:20:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</guid><description>@vaficionado) – if that list of names doesn’t fill you with confidence for vRA.Next, then I suggest you follow them on twitter and trust me that it’s a crack team!
So, my highlights:
Completely automated deployment…almost. The deployment of appliances and installation of IaaS components and pre-requisites will be wizard driven, the Window Servers will need to exist and have an agent installed, and the MSSQL server will also need to be installed.</description></item></channel></rss>