<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/category/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/category/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a free Arm-based Docker host in Oracle Cloud</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/06/building-a-free-arm-based-docker-host-in-oracle-cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/06/building-a-free-arm-based-docker-host-in-oracle-cloud/</guid><description>Most people have used AWS' free tier of resources for learning - and most people (including myself) have long since used the 12 months allowed free tier. It was recently brought to my attention that Oracle Cloud have a free tier offering (that they promise is always free) that includes two AMD-based compute VMs with 1/8th of an CPU and 1GB RAM (not much use to anyone) and (much more interestingly) a 4 Arm-based Ampere A1 cores and 24GB usable RAM as 1-4 VMs.</description></item><item><title>Lab Notes – vCloud Director 9.1 for Service Providers – Part 1: Pre-requisites</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/02/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9.1-for-service-providers-part-1-pre-requisites/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 17:09:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/02/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9.1-for-service-providers-part-1-pre-requisites/</guid><description>This series was originally going to be a more polished endeavour, but unfortunately time got in the way. A prod from James Kilby (@jameskilbynet) has convinced me to publish as is, as a series of lab notes. Maybe one day I&amp;rsquo;ll loop back and finish them…
Requirements Routing Because I’m backing my vCloud Director installation with NSX-T, I will be using my existing Tier-0 router, which interfaces with my physical router via BGP.</description></item><item><title>Lab Notes – vCloud Director 9.1 for Service Providers – Part 5: vRealize Orchestrator Cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9-1-for-service-providers-part-5-vrealize-orchestrator-cluster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 16:07:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9-1-for-service-providers-part-5-vrealize-orchestrator-cluster/</guid><description>This series was originally going to be a more polished endeavour, but unfortunately time got in the way. A prod from James Kilby (@jameskilbynet) has convinced me to publish as is, as a series of lab notes. Maybe one day I&amp;rsquo;ll loop back and finish them…
Prerequisites PostgreSQL server deployed and configured
Two vRO 7.4 appliances deployed
Before powering them on, add an additional network card on the vcd-sql network</description></item><item><title>Lab Notes – vCloud Director 9.1 for Service Providers – Part 2: PostgreSQL Installation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9-1-for-service-providers-part-2-postgresql-installation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 14:18:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/07/lab-notes-vcloud-director-9-1-for-service-providers-part-2-postgresql-installation/</guid><description>This series was originally going to be a more polished endeavour, but unfortunately time got in the way. A prod from James Kilby (@jameskilbynet) has convinced me to publish as is, as a series of lab notes. Maybe one day I&amp;rsquo;ll loop back and finish them…
Installing PostgreSQL 10 Server The base OS for the PostgreSQL server is CentOS7, deployed from the same template and with the same preparation as detailed in the prerequisites post.</description></item><item><title>Alexa, turn on my workload cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 15:05:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</guid><description>I already have a vRealize Orchestrator workflow to shutdown my workload cluster. What I want to do is trigger that by a voice command from Alexa.
Now, the correct and proper thing to do here would be to create a new Alexa skill, write the function in Lambda and connect that to my Orchestrator REST API and execute the workflow. That way I could control the “intents” and “utterances” and have verbal feedback.</description></item><item><title>Deploying to AWS with Software Components on vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/deploying-to-aws-with-software-components-on-vrealize-automation-7/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 17:09:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/deploying-to-aws-with-software-components-on-vrealize-automation-7/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on some ideas in my lab to leverage the AWS endpoint on vRealize Automation. One of the things I needed to get working was getting Software Components working on my AWS deployed instances.
The diagram to the right shows my end-stage network - the instance deployed by vRA into AWS should be in a private subnet in my VPC, and should use my local lab DNS server and be able to access my vRA instance.</description></item><item><title>Creating an AWS Hardware VPN Connection with Ubiquiti EdgeRouterX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/creating-an-aws-hardware-vpn-connection-with-ubiquiti-edgerouterx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 22:38:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/creating-an-aws-hardware-vpn-connection-with-ubiquiti-edgerouterx/</guid><description>When you&amp;rsquo;re working with Amazon and vRealize Automation Software Components, one of the requirements is for the Guest Agent (gugent) to talk back to the vRealize Automation APIs - the gugent polls the API for tasks it should perform, downloads them from the API and executes them, then updates the tasks with a status.
This means that Virtual Machines deployed as EC2 instances in an AWS VPC require the ability to talk back to internal corporate networks - not something you&amp;rsquo;d want to publish on the internet!</description></item><item><title>There is no one cloud solution to rule them all..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/there-is-no-one-cloud-solution-to-rule-them-all/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 17:01:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/there-is-no-one-cloud-solution-to-rule-them-all/</guid><description>I have been musing this a little while and decided to write this post/rant/opinion post, feel free to post your thoughts and opinions in the comments.
OK so here it is, one thing I have observed for a good while now is how much noise there is about how -you- should be in the cloud (Public) and if you are not you&amp;rsquo;re already dead.
I call Bull****!
Public, Hybrid and Private clouds are solutions not final destinations, regardless of whether you are a customer, partner, or any other third thing you should be purely focused on what is best for you or (if you provide IT services) your customer.</description></item><item><title>Adding an AWS endpoint to vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/adding-an-amazon-web-services-endpoint-to-vrealize-automation-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 09:46:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/adding-an-amazon-web-services-endpoint-to-vrealize-automation-7/</guid><description>Although it&amp;rsquo;s fairly limited, you can add AWS as an endpoint for vRealize Automation 7 and consume EC2 AMIs as part of a blueprint. You can even add the deployed instances to an existing Elastic Load Balancer at deploy time. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll run through the basics to get up and running and deploy your first highly available (multiple Availability Zone, load balanced) blueprint.
Preparing AWS for use as a vRA endpoint There are some obvious pre-requisites for attaching an AWS endpoint - for example, you need to have a VPC configured.</description></item></channel></rss>