<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vro on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vro/</link><description>Recent content in Vro on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workaround: Adding an external vRealize Orchestrator 8.x instance to Code Stream</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/06/workaround-adding-an-external-vrealize-orchestrator-8.x-instance-to-code-stream/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/06/workaround-adding-an-external-vrealize-orchestrator-8.x-instance-to-code-stream/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was doing some testing with adding an external vRealize Orchestrator 8.4 endpoint to vRealize Automation Code Stream 8.4, and it turns out there&amp;rsquo;s a redirect that happens with the vRO 8.4 appliance that makes the endpoint validation fail. When you enter the URL and click ACCEPT CERTIFICATE the UI will throw an error:
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Server error on getting certificates.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Http failure response for https://&amp;lt;vRA FQDN&amp;gt;/codestream/api/endpoint-certificate?url=https://&amp;lt;vRO FQDN&amp;gt;: 400 Bad Request&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Foundation - Deployment Observations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/07/vmware-cloud-foundation-deployment-observations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/07/vmware-cloud-foundation-deployment-observations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working with VMware Cloud Foundation recently and while for the most part things went well there were occasions where challenges were encountered which made the delivery to the customer all the more trickier than expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is a list of observations and things to most definitely check or watch out for when delivering a VCF project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were working with VCF version 3.7.2 (yes I am aware 3.8 has arrived but that was too late for the delivery in this project)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Enable vCenter High Availability with vRealize Orchestrator</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/enable-vcenter-high-availability-with-vrealize-orchestrator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 11:45:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/enable-vcenter-high-availability-with-vrealize-orchestrator/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick post today to cover a new vRO action and workflow I’ve uploaded to GitHub that configures vCenter High Availability in the basic mode. This is based on &lt;a href="https://www.virtuallyghetto.com/2016/12/vcenter-server-high-availability-vcha-powercli-6-5-community-module.html" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; William Lam’s excellent PowerShell module
&lt;/a&gt; that does the same, but using vRO. I also hope to release a version for the advanced mode based on my &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/06/powershell-deploying-vcenter-high-availability-in-advanced-mode/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; PowerShell script
&lt;/a&gt; in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR - &lt;a href="https://github.com/sammcgeown/org.definit.vcha" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; package is availabile on GitHub
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps 6.7 – Automate all the things..</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrops-6-7-automate-all-the-things/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 12:24:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/04/vrops-6-7-automate-all-the-things/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;There are many improvements, changes and new additions to vROps in version 6.7 but one of the aspects that stands out to me personally is the direction VMware are taking with the product. Aside from the obvious addition of cloud costings and comparisons and a reworked capacity planning (from the ground up) and new hook in to  Wavefront (which I really like) there has been some real effort to improve how you can further automate things from vROps.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Alexa, turn on my workload cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 15:05:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I already have a vRealize Orchestrator workflow to shutdown my workload cluster. What I want to do is trigger that by a voice command from Alexa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the correct and proper thing to do here would be to create a new Alexa skill, write the function in Lambda and connect that to my Orchestrator REST API and execute the workflow. That way I could control the “intents” and “utterances” and have verbal feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Getting started with vRealize Log Insight 4.3 for vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/getting-started-with-vrealize-log-insight-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 12:09:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/getting-started-with-vrealize-log-insight-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In this humble consultant&amp;rsquo;s opinion, Log Insight is one of the most useful tools in the administrator&amp;rsquo;s tool belt for troubleshooting vRealize Automation. I have lost count of the number of times I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to help troubleshoot an issue that, when asked, people don&amp;rsquo;t know which log they should be looking at. The simple fact is that vRealize Automation has a lot of log files. Correlating these log sources to provide an overall picture is a painful, manual process - unless you have Log Insight!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator Workflow: shutdownVSANCluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vro-shutdownvsancluster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 13:21:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vro-shutdownvsancluster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;My vSphere lab is split into two halves - a low power management cluster, powered by 3 Intel NUCs, and a more hefty workload cluster powered by a Dell C6100 chassis with 3 nodes. The workload servers are noisy and power hungry so they tend to be powered off when I am not using them, and since they live in my garage, I power them on and off remotely.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Increasing the Java Heap size for vRealize Orchestrator Client (7.x)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/increasing-the-java-heap-size-for-vrealize-orchestrator-client-7-x/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 11:05:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/increasing-the-java-heap-size-for-vrealize-orchestrator-client-7-x/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Back in January 2015 I wrote an article on &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/performance-tweak-increasing-max-heap-size-for-the-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-client/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; how to modify the Java heap settings for the vCenter Orchestrator client
&lt;/a&gt; when working with very large workflows. Since vRealize Orchestrator 7.x has been released, we no longer have an installable client, just a Java WebStart file (.jnlp) that you run, or a package that you can download - but nothing that installs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Note that none of this is official or supported by VMware as far as I know - it&amp;rsquo;s the results of my experimentation which has shown some performance improvement by increasing the configured memory pool. Use it at your own risk!&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Adding a vCloud Air (PAYG/Gen2) instance to vRealize Orchestrator as a vCloud Director host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 13:26:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Big thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pipoe2h" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Jose Luis Gomez
&lt;/a&gt; for this solution, his response to my tweet was spot on and invaluable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to configure vCloud Air as a vCloud Director host in vRealize Orchestrator in order to create some custom resource actions for Day 2 operations in vRealize Automation. What I found was that there&amp;rsquo;s *very* little information out there on how to do this, and I ended up writing my own custom resource mapping for the virtual machines to VCAC:VirtualMachine objects - at least that way I could add my resource action. But this still didn&amp;rsquo;t expose the vCloud Director functionality for those machines. To do this I needed vCloud Air added as a vCloud Director host.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7 XaaS blueprint form displays: Failed to retrieve form from provider</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-xaas-blueprint-form-displays-failed-to-retrieve-form-from-provider/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 13:47:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-xaas-blueprint-form-displays-failed-to-retrieve-form-from-provider/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;VMware KB2140539&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; where requesting an XaaS (vRealize Orchestrator) blueprint fails with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Failed to retrieve form from provider&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The KB describes it occuring when &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;more than one VMware vRealize Orchestrator instance is configured for different tenants&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. The issue I faced is not the same - in my case, I had the system default tenant configured to use the embedded vRO, and the customer tenant configured to use the system default (which would be the embedded vRO!)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator REST API – "Connection pool shut down"</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/12/vrealize-orchestrator-rest-api-connection-pool-shut-down/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 17:29:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/12/vrealize-orchestrator-rest-api-connection-pool-shut-down/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you use the in-built vRealize Orchestrator instance shipped with the vRealize Automation appliance then you might run into this issue when working with the REST client:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connection pool shut down (Workflow:Get-IdentityToken / Scripting (item3)#14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/12/image_thumb.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vRA appliance version I have (6.2 - note to self, need to update lab!) includes the plugin version 1.0.4 for REST. According to the release notes, this was fixed in 1.0.5 - typical!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: vRealize Automation 7 Briefing Notes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 08:20:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;@vaficionado&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;) – if that list of names doesn’t fill you with confidence for vRA.Next, then I suggest you follow them on twitter and trust me that it’s a crack team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, my highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completely automated deployment…almost. The deployment of appliances and installation of IaaS components and pre-requisites will be wizard driven, the Window Servers will need to exist and have an agent installed, and the MSSQL server will also need to be installed. Anyone who’s done a distributed vRA install will know that this is a massive improvement over the current state of affairs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The vRealize Automation appliances will be clustered automatically for core services such as identity, cafe (portal), vPostgres and embedded vRealize Orchestrator (Embedded vRO is now recommended for production).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new identity service. No more vSphere SSO or PSC – VMware Identity Management (vIDM) is a new, highly scalable and performing federated identity platform. Any SAML identity source, and more than 3m users supported per source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An initial setup wizard that creates your first tenant, configuring things like fabric groups, business groups and vSphere endpoints automatically. It will even import your existing vSphere templates as clone blueprints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The old CDK is gone! Instead you can use any event within vRA that is pushed through the RabbitMQ message bus to trigger extensibility through workflow subscriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vRealize Orchestrator has a new HTML5 Control Center which is your single admin point for plugin configuration as well as adding metrics and monitoring for all workflows being executed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s no need for unique tenant URLs – the new vIDM platform allows a single logon interface for all tenants. (Though you can keep your URLs if you want!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vIDM can also be used to control authentication from IP source, e.g. to restrict logon to a specific subnet regardless of whether the credentials are valid or not. This has some cool ramifications for having the web layer in a DMZ, for example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality is slowly being migrated from the old IaaS/DynamicOps layer to the appliance – this is fantastic news. The migrated portions (such as vSphere Endpoint configuration) are now accessible through the vRA API, as well as gaining the speed and stability that the appliances provide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new blueprint designer is awesome. Added to that what was AppD is now called App Services and allows you to take a base blueprint (e.g. a CentOS VM) and drag and drop software components that you’ve scripted on top (e.g. Apache, then PHP). You can also drag and drop XaaS (vRO workflows) onto the blueprint, as well as existing blueprints to create nested blueprints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much fuller integration between NSX and vRA. There’s a whole raft of improvements in the integration between vRA and NSX – e.g. you can drag a new routed network onto a blueprint and it will automatically create a new Logical Switch and Distributed Logical Router to attach the Logical Switch to. Similarly load balancing applications is a drag and drop operation, as is applying existing security groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All blueprints can be imported and exported in YAML, which opens up exciting possibilities for storing versioned blueprints and retrieving programmatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are over 60 lifecycle events out of the box on which you can trigger Orchestrator workflows, but you can create custom filters based on properties and events to extend functionality – the only limitation is what you can imagine!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still several months of development to go between now and the GA of vRA 7 and the development seems to be moving at a great pace. Between beta 1 and beta 2 there was a huge amount of change, and even the version demoed today had new features and UI.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO) – Troubleshooting SOAP operations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-troubleshooting-soap-operations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 12:09:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-troubleshooting-soap-operations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a bit of a SOAP baptism of fire - the project I am working on makes hundreds of SOAP calls to multiple SOAP APIs on multiple hosts. During this time I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered some common and rare problems and troubleshooting them seems to be a bit of a black art, if the number of results in Google is any measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate some of these troubleshooting methods I will use a global weather SOAP service, &lt;a href="http://www.webservicex.com/globalweather.asmx?WSDL" title="http://www.webservicex.com/globalweather.asmx?WSDL" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; http://www.webservicex.com/globalweather.asmx?WSDL
&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve added the web service to vRO using the &amp;ldquo;Add a SOAP host&amp;rdquo; workflow, and then used the &amp;ldquo;Generate a new workflow from a SOAP operation&amp;rdquo; workflow to create a new workflow: GetWeather. This simple workflow runs successfully:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO) and vCloud Director – fixing bugs in "Add a vDC"</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-and-vcloud-director-fixing-bugs-in-add-a-vdc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 10:53:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-and-vcloud-director-fixing-bugs-in-add-a-vdc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;When you are using a VMware orchestration platform with an official VMware plugin to manage a VMware product, you don&amp;rsquo;t really expect to have to fix the out-of-the-box workflows. However, during some testing of some workflows with a client the other day we ran into a couple of issues with the vCloud Director plugin workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software versions used&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vCloud Director 5.5.1 (appliance for development) and 5.5.2 (production deployment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vRealize Orchestrator Appliance 5.5.2.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vCloud Director plugin 5.5.1.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="cpu-allocations-are-incorrect-for-both-add-a-vdc"&gt;CPU allocations are incorrect for both &amp;ldquo;Add a VDC&amp;rdquo; &lt;a class="anchor" href="#cpu-allocations-are-incorrect-for-both-add-a-vdc"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you provide the CPU allocation model properties for the Allocation Pool model the first problem is decrypting the naming - it doesn&amp;rsquo;t match the names in the vCloud Director interface!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Performance tweak – increasing Max Heap Size for the vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO) Client</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/performance-tweak-increasing-max-heap-size-for-the-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-client/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 20:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/performance-tweak-increasing-max-heap-size-for-the-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-client/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;[Update Dec 2016: &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/increasing-the-java-heap-size-for-vrealize-orchestrator-client-7-x/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; An updated article for vRO 7.x is available here
&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m developing some very large, very complicated workflows for vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO), and as it&amp;rsquo;s a Java based application it will probably come as no surprise to many that the performance of the client drops off sharply as the client&amp;rsquo;s RAM usage creeps up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When working on some of the larger workflows, or after long sessions and heavy clipboard use, the client would become (even more) sluggish and in some cases would freeze entirely. This is particularly annoying because the vRO client has a habit of forcing itself on top of other applications - for instance Task Manager.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>3DES Password Based Encryption with vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/3des-password-based-encryption-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 21:38:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/3des-password-based-encryption-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A requirement that often arises in large, complex orchestration projects is the need to encrypt and decrypt information. One such requirement recently specified triple DES password based encryption as the standard, which led me through a lot of Google searches to &lt;a href="https://code.google.com/p/crypto-js/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; CryptoJS
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CryptoJS is a growing collection of standard and secure cryptographic algorithms implemented in JavaScript using best practices and patterns. They are fast, and they have a consistent and simple interface.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Generating a secure random password with vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/generating-a-secure-random-password-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 21:17:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/generating-a-secure-random-password-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly common requirement when creating a new user to assign a randomly generated password, so during a recent engagement I wrote a little password generator to do that. I wanted to be able to chose whether special characters were used, and the length of the password - typically if the password doesn&amp;rsquo;t used special characters I would increase the length significantly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Characters should be randomly picked from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a-z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A-Z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0-9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(optional) ASCII special characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="inputs"&gt;Inputs &lt;a class="anchor" href="#inputs"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;passwordLength - the length of the password to be generated (number)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;excludePunctuation - exclude the use of special characters if TRUE (boolean)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/01/image_thumb35.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator (vCO) Multi-node Plug-in use case: Remote Site Selection and Execution</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-operations-vco-multi-node-plug-in-use-case-remote-site-selection-and-execution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 16:46:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-operations-vco-multi-node-plug-in-use-case-remote-site-selection-and-execution/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One of the use cases I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on with a customer is based on the vRO/vCO multi-node plug-in and involves the master vRO/vCO node calling proxy workflows based on a parameter - in this case the target site. As you can see from this very simple diagram, a Cloud Management System (CMS) calls a workflow on the Master node, which then executes a proxy workflow on the correct site. The trick is getting the Master Orchestrator node to pick the right proxy workflow.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Configuring and Using vRealize Orchestrator (vCO/vRO) Multi-node plugin</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/configuring-and-using-vrealize-orchestrator-vcovro-multi-node-plugin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 16:50:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/configuring-and-using-vrealize-orchestrator-vcovro-multi-node-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;To quote the release notes for the latest version of vCO/vRO Multi-node Plugin:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VMware vCenter Orchestrator Multi-Node Plug-In allows organizations to manage environments with multiple vCenter Orchestrator server instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As organizations increase their level of automation, they often find the need to deploy multiple Orchestrator instances. With the VMware vCenter Orchestrator Multi-Node Plug-In, administrators have a more efficient way to manage multiple Orchestrator instances from a central point. The plug-in allows administrators to log in to a master Orchestrator server to view the inventories and workflows of remote Orchestrator servers, and to trigger workflows remotely.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Configuring a vRO/vCAC PowerShell host with Basic Authentication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/configuring-a-vrovcac-powershell-host-with-basic-authentication/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 15:50:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/12/configuring-a-vrovcac-powershell-host-with-basic-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/03/20140313-043.png" alt=""&gt;To add a Windows Server 2012 R2 PowerShell host using Basic Authentication only, follow these steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure that the Windows Firewall service is running (it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if the firewall is enabled or disabled, it should always be running! That&amp;rsquo;s a general rule, not just for this).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the PowerShell host open a command prompt (*NOT* PowerShell console) as administrator and run the quickconfig command - you can re-run it if it&amp;rsquo;s already been run - but make sure it has.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>