<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VRealize Automation on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/category/vrealize-automation/</link><description>Recent content in VRealize Automation on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/category/vrealize-automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workaround: Adding an external vRealize Orchestrator 8.x instance to Code Stream</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/06/workaround-adding-an-external-vrealize-orchestrator-8.x-instance-to-code-stream/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/06/workaround-adding-an-external-vrealize-orchestrator-8.x-instance-to-code-stream/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was doing some testing with adding an external vRealize Orchestrator 8.4 endpoint to vRealize Automation Code Stream 8.4, and it turns out there&amp;rsquo;s a redirect that happens with the vRO 8.4 appliance that makes the endpoint validation fail. When you enter the URL and click ACCEPT CERTIFICATE the UI will throw an error:
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Server error on getting certificates.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Http failure response for https://&amp;lt;vRA FQDN&amp;gt;/codestream/api/endpoint-certificate?url=https://&amp;lt;vRO FQDN&amp;gt;: 400 Bad Request&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Integrating vROps with vRA 8 using Workspace One Auth Source</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/03/integrating-vrops-with-vra-8-using-workspace-one-auth-source/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/03/integrating-vrops-with-vra-8-using-workspace-one-auth-source/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="integrating-vrops-with-vra-8-using-workspace-one-auth-source"&gt;Integrating vROps with vRA 8 using Workspace One Auth Source &lt;a class="anchor" href="#integrating-vrops-with-vra-8-using-workspace-one-auth-source"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="product-version---vrealize-automation-8x"&gt;Product Version - vRealize Automation 8.x &lt;a class="anchor" href="#product-version---vrealize-automation-8x"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id="why-integrate-vrops-with-vra-8"&gt;Why integrate vROps with vRA 8? &lt;a class="anchor" href="#why-integrate-vrops-with-vra-8"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vRealize Automation can work with vRealize Operations Manager to perform advanced workload placement, provide deployment health and virtual machine metrics, and display pricing.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="so-what-is-the-problem"&gt;So what is the problem? &lt;a class="anchor" href="#so-what-is-the-problem"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When configuring the integration, you will input the vROps URL and it will also ask you to input a username and password of the service account you wish to use. This is no problem if the accouint is a locally created account in vROps itself but most enterprises will want to use AD created service accounts which are then imported into vROps via WorkSpace One (vIDM)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why use Content Libraries with vRA 8</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/why-use-content-libraries-with-vra-8/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/02/why-use-content-libraries-with-vra-8/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="why-use-content-libraries-with-vra-8"&gt;Why use Content Libraries with vRA 8 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#why-use-content-libraries-with-vra-8"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="product-version---vrealize-automation-8x"&gt;Product Version - vRealize Automation 8.x &lt;a class="anchor" href="#product-version---vrealize-automation-8x"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id="what-are-vsphere-content-libraries"&gt;What are vSphere Content Libraries? &lt;a class="anchor" href="#what-are-vsphere-content-libraries"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;A content library stores and manages content in the form of library items. A single library item can consist of one file or multiple files. For example, the OVF template is a set of files (.ovf, .vmdk, and .mf). When you upload an OVF template to the library, you upload the entire set of files, but the result is a single library item of the OVF Template type.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Code Stream - Custom Integration - Generate Basic Authentication Header</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/11/code-stream-custom-integration-generate-basic-authentication-header/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/11/code-stream-custom-integration-generate-basic-authentication-header/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To generate a basic authentication header from a username and password in Code Stream you could use a CI task and execute &lt;code&gt;echo -n username:password | base64&lt;/code&gt; in the shell then export the result for use later on. A more repeatable way is to create a Custom Integration that takes the two inputs, and returns the encoded header as an output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create the Custom Integration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new Custom Integration named &amp;ldquo;Create Basic Authentication Header&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the Runtime - the examples below are &lt;code&gt;shell&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;python3&lt;/code&gt; respectively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace the placeholder code with the example from below&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save and version the Custom Integration, ensuring you eanble the &amp;ldquo;Release Version&amp;rdquo; toggle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;





 


&lt;br clear="none"&gt;
&lt;div class="clr-content-image-wrap"&gt;
 &lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href="2020-11-04-11-28-23.png" data-lightbox="2020-11-04-11-28-23.png" data-title="Creating the Custom Integration" class="lb"&gt;
 &lt;img class="lb" src="2020-11-04-11-28-23.png" alt="Creating the Custom Integration" /&gt;
 &lt;/a&gt;
 
 &lt;figcaption class="clr-caption"&gt;Creating the Custom Integration&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To use the Custom Integration in a pipeline:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VMware Cloud Foundation - Deployment Observations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/07/vmware-cloud-foundation-deployment-observations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/07/vmware-cloud-foundation-deployment-observations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working with VMware Cloud Foundation recently and while for the most part things went well there were occasions where challenges were encountered which made the delivery to the customer all the more trickier than expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is a list of observations and things to most definitely check or watch out for when delivering a VCF project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were working with VCF version 3.7.2 (yes I am aware 3.8 has arrived but that was too late for the delivery in this project)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Upgrading vRA withvRLCM and JAVA versions</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/upgrading-vra-withvrlcm-and-java-versions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2019/04/upgrading-vra-withvrlcm-and-java-versions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently upgraded an instance of vRA from 7.2 to 7.5 and rather than do it the manual way I used VMware’s vRealize LifeCycle Manager (version 2.0 update 3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything was going great and according to plan, the vRLCM pre-requisites checker made short work of all of the checks you need to do before you start an upgrade of vRA. You can see below vRLCM does a great job of keeping you informed of the current progress and in a really elegant way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Three Tier App for vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/03/three-tier-app-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/03/three-tier-app-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One question I’m asked quite a lot is what I use for a 3-tier application when I’m testing things like NSX micro-segmentation with vRealize Automation. The simple answer is that I used to make something up as I went along, deploying components by hand and generally repeating myself a lot. I had some cut/paste commands in my note application that sped things up a little, but nothing that developed. I’ve been meaning to rectify this for a while, and this is the result!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Retrieve Blueprint or Virtual Machine Custom Properties using the vRealize Automation API</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/02/retrieve-blueprint-or-virtual-machine-custom-properties-using-the-vrealize-automation-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 14:11:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/02/retrieve-blueprint-or-virtual-machine-custom-properties-using-the-vrealize-automation-api/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Just a quick post today, as I was working with a customer recently and we were trying to retrieve the Custom Properties assigned to a vRealize Automation 7.3 deployed Virtual Machine, similar to the one in the image below. It’s not as intuitive as you’d like it to be because of the split between IaaS APIs and Cafe APIs. Below you can see I’ve deployed a simple CentOS blueprint with a custom property at the Blueprint level (called “BlueprintLevel” with a value of “CustomProperty”) and a custom property at the VM level (called “CustomProperty” and a value of “Test123”).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7.3 and NSX – Micro-segmentation strategies</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrealize-automation-7-3-and-nsx-micro-segmentation-strategies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 17:40:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/01/vrealize-automation-7-3-and-nsx-micro-segmentation-strategies/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2018/01/Firewall.jpg" alt=""&gt;vRealize Automation and NSX integration has introduced the ability to deploy multi-tiered applications with network services included. The current integration also enables a method to deploy micro-segmentation out of the box, based on dynamic Security Group membership and the Service Composer. This method does have some limitations, and can be inflexible for the on-going management of deployed applications. It requires in-depth knowledge and understanding of NSX and the Distributed Firewall, as well as access to the Networking and Security manager that is hosted by vCenter Server.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2017 – Part 4 : Optimizing Workload Performance Using Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 10:17:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/03/logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;In this episode, Sunny gave us a deep dive into the WLP and WLB features of vROps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were also joined by a special guest, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/virtualjad" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Jad El-Zein
&lt;/a&gt; who gave us a great insight into how vRA utilises vROps for initial placement of freshly provisioned VMs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We would highly appreciate it if you could spend 30 seconds to fill up this quick and simple survey to provide us your feedback. You can also request topics of your choice through this survey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7.3 Distributed Install – Prerequisites</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrealize-automation-7-3-distributed-install-prerequisites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 13:33:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/07/vrealize-automation-7-3-distributed-install-prerequisites/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;As a consultant I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to design, install and configure dozens of production vRealize Automation deployments, from reasonably small Proof of Concept environments to globally-scaled multi-datacenter fully distributed behemoths. It&amp;rsquo;s fair to say, that I&amp;rsquo;ve made mistakes along the way - and learned a lot of lessons as to what makes a deployment a success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, pretty much everything comes down to getting the pre-requisites right. Nothing that I&amp;rsquo;ve written here is not already documented in the official documentation, and the installation wizard does a huge amount of the work for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Alexa, turn on my workload cluster</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 15:05:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/alexa-turn-on-my-workload-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I already have a vRealize Orchestrator workflow to shutdown my workload cluster. What I want to do is trigger that by a voice command from Alexa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the correct and proper thing to do here would be to create a new Alexa skill, write the function in Lambda and connect that to my Orchestrator REST API and execute the workflow. That way I could control the “intents” and “utterances” and have verbal feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRA7.2 and vSphere Integrated Containers</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vra7-2-and-vsphere-integrated-containers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 15:28:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vra7-2-and-vsphere-integrated-containers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One of the cool new features released with vRealize Automation 7.2 was the integration of VMware Admiral (container management) into the product, and recently VMware made version 1 of vSphere Integrated Containers generally available (GA), so I thought it was time I started playing around with the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover deploying VIC to my vSphere environment and then adding that host to the vRA 7.2 container management.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying to AWS with Software Components on vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/deploying-to-aws-with-software-components-on-vrealize-automation-7/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 17:09:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/deploying-to-aws-with-software-components-on-vrealize-automation-7/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id=""&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/11/AWS-vRA.png" alt=""&gt; &lt;a class="anchor" href="#"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on some ideas in my lab to leverage the AWS endpoint on vRealize Automation. One of the things I needed to get working was getting Software Components working on my AWS deployed instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diagram to the right shows my end-stage network - the instance deployed by vRA into AWS should be in a private subnet in my VPC, and should use my local lab DNS server and be able to access my vRA instance. This allows me to make use of the vRA guest agent for software components on the deployed VMs. I also wanted to have the deployed VMs use their local NAT gateway for internet traffic, rather than paying for the data over my VPN connection.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Creating an AWS Hardware VPN Connection with Ubiquiti EdgeRouterX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/creating-an-aws-hardware-vpn-connection-with-ubiquiti-edgerouterx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 22:38:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/creating-an-aws-hardware-vpn-connection-with-ubiquiti-edgerouterx/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/11/Multiple_VPN_Tunnels_diagram.png" alt=""&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re working with Amazon and vRealize Automation Software Components, one of the requirements is for the Guest Agent (gugent) to talk back to the vRealize Automation APIs - the gugent polls the API for tasks it should perform, downloads them from the API and executes them, then updates the tasks with a status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that Virtual Machines deployed as EC2 instances in an AWS VPC require the ability to talk back to internal corporate networks - not something you&amp;rsquo;d want to publish on the internet! That&amp;rsquo;s where AWS&amp;rsquo;s VPN connections come in - you can create several types of VPN that allow such communication over a secure (encrypted) virtual private network.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Adding an AWS endpoint to vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/adding-an-amazon-web-services-endpoint-to-vrealize-automation-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 09:46:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/adding-an-amazon-web-services-endpoint-to-vrealize-automation-7/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Although it&amp;rsquo;s fairly limited, you can add AWS as an endpoint for vRealize Automation 7  and consume EC2 AMIs as part of a blueprint. You can even add the deployed instances to an existing Elastic Load Balancer at deploy time. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll run through the basics to get up and running and deploy your first highly available (multiple Availability Zone, load balanced) blueprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="preparing-aws-for-use-as-a-vra-endpoint"&gt;Preparing AWS for use as a vRA endpoint &lt;a class="anchor" href="#preparing-aws-for-use-as-a-vra-endpoint"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are some obvious pre-requisites for attaching an AWS endpoint - for example, you need to have a VPC configured. There are plenty of resources out there for creating a VPC, so I won&amp;rsquo;t extend this post by replicating them. This is what I&amp;rsquo;m using:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Adding a vCloud Air (PAYG/Gen2) instance to vRealize Orchestrator as a vCloud Director host</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 13:26:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/adding-a-vcloud-air-payggen2-instance-to-vrealize-orchestrator-as-a-vcloud-director-host/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Big thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pipoe2h" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Jose Luis Gomez
&lt;/a&gt; for this solution, his response to my tweet was spot on and invaluable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to configure vCloud Air as a vCloud Director host in vRealize Orchestrator in order to create some custom resource actions for Day 2 operations in vRealize Automation. What I found was that there&amp;rsquo;s *very* little information out there on how to do this, and I ended up writing my own custom resource mapping for the virtual machines to VCAC:VirtualMachine objects - at least that way I could add my resource action. But this still didn&amp;rsquo;t expose the vCloud Director functionality for those machines. To do this I needed vCloud Air added as a vCloud Director host.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What’s in my vRA7 EBS Payloads?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/whats-in-my-vra7-ebs-payloads/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 15:52:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/whats-in-my-vra7-ebs-payloads/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;img class=&amp;ldquo;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-6186&amp;rdquo; src=&amp;quot;/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;vRA&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo; - a properties object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to create a workflow that I could enable to log all of the keys, values and types of the properties object for each stage of the vRA7 MachineProvisioning workflows, and create a reference for myself on the payload for each stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this I created a new workflow &amp;ldquo;debugProperties&amp;rdquo; and added an input variable called &amp;ldquo;payload&amp;rdquo;, type Properties. Next I added a single scriptable task and cycled through the properties. Some of the properties&amp;rsquo; values are actually other properties objects, so there&amp;rsquo;s a function to test the type and iterate through if required.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7 XaaS blueprint form displays: Failed to retrieve form from provider</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-xaas-blueprint-form-displays-failed-to-retrieve-form-from-provider/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 13:47:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-xaas-blueprint-form-displays-failed-to-retrieve-form-from-provider/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;VMware KB2140539&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; where requesting an XaaS (vRealize Orchestrator) blueprint fails with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Failed to retrieve form from provider&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The KB describes it occuring when &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;more than one VMware vRealize Orchestrator instance is configured for different tenants&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. The issue I faced is not the same - in my case, I had the system default tenant configured to use the embedded vRO, and the customer tenant configured to use the system default (which would be the embedded vRO!)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation 7 Custom Hostname with Event Broker (EB) Subscription</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-custom-hostname-with-event-broker-eb-subscription/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 17:54:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrealize-automation-7-custom-hostname-with-event-broker-eb-subscription/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The new Event Broker service in vRA7 is one of the most exciting features of this latest release, the possibilities for extensibility are huge. At this point it time you can still use the old method of using workflow stubs to customise machine lifecycle events, but at some point in the future this will be deprecated and the Event Broker will be the only way to extend.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Running Platypus in Docker on Photon with AppCatalyst</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/platypusindockeronphotonwithappcatalyst/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 08:09:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/platypusindockeronphotonwithappcatalyst/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick little post this morning! Anyone who works with the vRealize Automation APIs should definitely check out Grant Orchard and Roman Tarnavski’s awesome little side project, &lt;a href="http://grantorchard.com/uncategorized/platypus-vra7-api-documentation/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Platypus
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It only took me a couple of minutes to get it running on my MacBook - here’s how!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download and install &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;AppCatalyst&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open a new terminal window&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a new VM called “photon&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>MindMap: vRealize Automation Roles</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/mindmap-vrealize-automation-roles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 20:45:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/11/mindmap-vrealize-automation-roles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I use mind maps quite a lot for study, I find the visual representation of info makes it a lot easier for me to remember! Below is a mind map I created for learning the roles in vRealize Automation, which I used during my presentation for #vBrownBag on VCP6-CMA objective 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download a PDF version here: &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;vRealize Automation Roles Mind Map&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: vRealize Automation 7 Briefing Notes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 08:20:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;@vaficionado&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;) – if that list of names doesn’t fill you with confidence for vRA.Next, then I suggest you follow them on twitter and trust me that it’s a crack team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, my highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completely automated deployment…almost. The deployment of appliances and installation of IaaS components and pre-requisites will be wizard driven, the Window Servers will need to exist and have an agent installed, and the MSSQL server will also need to be installed. Anyone who’s done a distributed vRA install will know that this is a massive improvement over the current state of affairs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The vRealize Automation appliances will be clustered automatically for core services such as identity, cafe (portal), vPostgres and embedded vRealize Orchestrator (Embedded vRO is now recommended for production).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new identity service. No more vSphere SSO or PSC – VMware Identity Management (vIDM) is a new, highly scalable and performing federated identity platform. Any SAML identity source, and more than 3m users supported per source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An initial setup wizard that creates your first tenant, configuring things like fabric groups, business groups and vSphere endpoints automatically. It will even import your existing vSphere templates as clone blueprints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The old CDK is gone! Instead you can use any event within vRA that is pushed through the RabbitMQ message bus to trigger extensibility through workflow subscriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vRealize Orchestrator has a new HTML5 Control Center which is your single admin point for plugin configuration as well as adding metrics and monitoring for all workflows being executed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s no need for unique tenant URLs – the new vIDM platform allows a single logon interface for all tenants. (Though you can keep your URLs if you want!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vIDM can also be used to control authentication from IP source, e.g. to restrict logon to a specific subnet regardless of whether the credentials are valid or not. This has some cool ramifications for having the web layer in a DMZ, for example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality is slowly being migrated from the old IaaS/DynamicOps layer to the appliance – this is fantastic news. The migrated portions (such as vSphere Endpoint configuration) are now accessible through the vRA API, as well as gaining the speed and stability that the appliances provide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new blueprint designer is awesome. Added to that what was AppD is now called App Services and allows you to take a base blueprint (e.g. a CentOS VM) and drag and drop software components that you’ve scripted on top (e.g. Apache, then PHP). You can also drag and drop XaaS (vRO workflows) onto the blueprint, as well as existing blueprints to create nested blueprints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much fuller integration between NSX and vRA. There’s a whole raft of improvements in the integration between vRA and NSX – e.g. you can drag a new routed network onto a blueprint and it will automatically create a new Logical Switch and Distributed Logical Router to attach the Logical Switch to. Similarly load balancing applications is a drag and drop operation, as is applying existing security groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All blueprints can be imported and exported in YAML, which opens up exciting possibilities for storing versioned blueprints and retrieving programmatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are over 60 lifecycle events out of the box on which you can trigger Orchestrator workflows, but you can create custom filters based on properties and events to extend functionality – the only limitation is what you can imagine!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still several months of development to go between now and the GA of vRA 7 and the development seems to be moving at a great pace. Between beta 1 and beta 2 there was a huge amount of change, and even the version demoed today had new features and UI.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building a vRealize Automation NSX Lab on Ravello</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/building-a-vrealize-automation-nsx-lab-on-ravello/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 17:06:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/building-a-vrealize-automation-nsx-lab-on-ravello/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/09/image_thumb22.png" alt=""&gt;As a vExpert, I am blessed to get 1000 CPU hours access to Ravello&amp;rsquo;s awesome platform and recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with the AutoLab deployments tailored for Ravello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Ravello&amp;rsquo;s offering&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; (where have you been?!) then it&amp;rsquo;s basically a custom hypervisor (HVX) running on either AWS or Google Cloud that allows you to run nested environments on those platforms. I did say it&amp;rsquo;s awesome.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Missing actions in vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/missing-actions-in-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 11:36:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/missing-actions-in-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png" alt=""&gt;Recently the team I am working with came across an interesting bug/issue with actions missing from deployed VMs. We had checked and double checked the entitlements yet the actions that should be available to the end-user/customer were not listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything appeared to point to a permissions issue until one of the team members noticed something with regards to blueprints in the catalog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I continue with what we observed and how we &amp;ldquo;fixed&amp;rdquo; it &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;please bear in mind the blueprints were created programmatically&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. (&lt;a href="http://automate-it.today/automating-vra-iaas-blueprint-creation-with-vro/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; Automating vRA IaaS Blueprint creation with vRO
&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation instance – Configuring NetScaler Monitors</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-instance-configuring-netscaler-monitors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 09:24:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-instance-configuring-netscaler-monitors/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter a name for the monitor, and leave the other parameters the same. Select the &amp;ldquo;Special Parameters&amp;rdquo; tab and configure the send string to the URL to monitor - e.g for the PSC SSO it&amp;rsquo;s going to be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the receive string, enter the expected response (&amp;ldquo;GREEN&amp;rdquo;). Click Create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/08/image_thumb40.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="assigning-a-netscaler-monitor-to-a-service"&gt;Assigning a NetScaler Monitor to a Service &lt;a class="anchor" href="#assigning-a-netscaler-monitor-to-a-service"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assign the monitor to the PSC Services (or Service Groups) configured for PSC by opening the Configuration &amp;gt; Traffic Management &amp;gt; Load Balancing &amp;gt; Services page and selecting the PSC service for HTTPS/443 and clicking Edit.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components – Part 2: Database, Web and Manager services</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-2-database-web-and-manager-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:40:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-2-database-web-and-manager-services/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png" alt=""&gt;Now that the prerequisites for the IaaS layer have been completed, it&amp;rsquo;s time to move on to the actual installation of the IaaS components, starting with the database. We then move onto the first Web server, which also imports the ModelManagerData configuration to the database, populating the database with all of the info the IaaS layer needs out of the box. We then install the second Web server before moving on to the active Manager server. The second Manager server is passive and the service should be disabled - I&amp;rsquo;ll cover installing DEM Orchestrators, Workers and the vSphere Agents in the next article.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying fully distributed vRealize Automation IaaS components – Part 1: Pre-requisites</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-1-pre-requisites/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 14:15:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/08/deploying-fully-distributed-vrealize-automation-iaas-components-part-1-pre-requisites/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One of the trickiest parts of deploying vRealize Automation is the IaaS layer - people sometimes look at me like I&amp;rsquo;m a crazy person when I say that, normally because they&amp;rsquo;ve deployed a PoC or small deployment with just a single IaaS server. Add in 5 more servers, some load balancers, certificates, a distributed setup and MSDTC to the mix and you have a huge potential for pain!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation Infrastructure Tab displays incorrect labels</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vrealize-automation-infrastructure-tab-displays-incorrect-labels/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 08:24:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vrealize-automation-infrastructure-tab-displays-incorrect-labels/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/vRA-Product-Icon-Mac_0.png" alt=""&gt;Having just completed a particularly problem-prone distributed IaaS install, this was almost the straw that broke the camel&amp;rsquo;s back. Logging into vRealize Automation for the first time as an Infrastructure Admin displayed the infrastructure tab and all menu labels as big ugly references, and no functionality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:%7bcom.cmware.cap.component.iaas.proxy.provider@csp.places.iaas.label"&gt;
 {com.cmware.cap.component.iaas.proxy.provider@csp.places.iaas.label
&lt;/a&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/07/clip_image002_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebooting the IaaS web servers restored the functionality of the IaaS layer but still did not fix the label issue, it took a further reboot of both vRealize Automation appliances, then the IaaS web servers to finally view the correct labels.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deploying vRealize Automation 6.2 Appliance Cluster with Postgres Replication</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 19:57:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/deploying-vrealize-automation-6-2-appliance-cluster-with-postgres-replication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The recommendations for the vRealize Appliance have changed with 6.2, the published reference architecture now does not recommend using an external Postgres database (either vPostgres appliance, a 3rd party Postgres deployment or using a third vRealize Appliance as a stand-alone database installation). Instead the recommended layout is shown in the diagram below. One instance of postgres on the primary node becomes an active instance, replicating to the second node which is passive. In front of these a load balancer or DNS entry points to the active node only. Fail-over is still a manual task, but it does provide better protection than a single instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 HA SSO (PSC) with NetScaler VPX Load Balancer for vRealize Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 15:40:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/07/vsphere-6-ha-sso-psc-with-netscaler-vpx-load-balancer-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Providing a highly available single sign on for vRealize Automation is a fundamental part of ensuring the availability of the platform. Traditionally, (vCAC) vRA uses the Identity Appliance and relies on vSphere HA to provide the availability of the SSO platform, but in a fully distributed HA environment that&amp;rsquo;s not really good enough. It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to use the vSphere 5.5 SSO install in a HA configuration - however, many companies are making the move to the latest version of vSphere and don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to maintain a 5.5 HA SSO instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vSphere 6 Lab Upgrade – Overview</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 19:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/04/vsphere-6-lab-upgrade-overview/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/07/vSphereLogo.png" alt=""&gt;I tested vSphere 6 quite intensively when it was in beta, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t ever upgrade my lab - basically because I need a stable environment to work on and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure that I could maintain that with the beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be upgrading&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vCenter Server Appliance - currently 5.5 update 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vSphere Update Manager - currently 5.5 update 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 HP N54L resource hosts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Intel NUC management host&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my lab I run various VMware software suites listed below, although I typically run them in nested environments to keep my lab install relatively clean.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Automation (vRA) Manager Service error</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-automation-vra-manager-service-error/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 10:07:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-automation-vra-manager-service-error/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently when do a fresh install of vRealize Automation (vRA) 6.2 I came across the following error after configuring the first end point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Error log example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/01/msdtc-error.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DataBaseStatsService: ignoring exception: Error executing query usp_SelectAgent Inner Exception: Error executing query usp_SelectAgentCapabilities&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all I checked to see if the end points were working which in this case they appeared to be, but I wanted to clear the error before continuing the install.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.1 – Creating a user selectable network dropdown that sets Network and Network Profile correctly</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vcac-6-1-creating-a-user-selectable-network-dropdown-that-sets-network-and-network-profile-correctly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 11:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vcac-6-1-creating-a-user-selectable-network-dropdown-that-sets-network-and-network-profile-correctly/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I am aware that that&amp;rsquo;s not a catchy blog post title. In fact, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even really describe the problem or solution very well - for that I need to go into a little bit more depth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose I have configured a Reservation with two Networks ticked (&amp;ldquo;192.168.1.0-VLAN1&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;192.168.10.0-VLAN10&amp;rdquo;). As you can see in the screenshot below, each of the networks has a Network Profile created and assigned with a network pool to provide IP addressing for the VMs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0/6.1 build out to distributed model: Deploy the Identity Appliance</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/vcac-6-06-1-build-out-to-distributed-model-deploy-the-identity-appliance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 14:55:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/vcac-6-06-1-build-out-to-distributed-model-deploy-the-identity-appliance/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;SSO is a fundamental requirement when deploying vCAC, whether for a distributed or simple installation. This walk through goes through the deployment and configuration of the vCAC Identity Appliance, which provides a stand alone SSO instance for vCAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the posts in this series are completed with vCAC 6.0.1, others will be with 6.1. Where there are differences I will aim to point them out!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>HTTP Error 500 installing vCAC IaaS Model Manager Data</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/http-error-500-installing-vcac-iaas-model-manager-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 16:16:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/http-error-500-installing-vcac-iaas-model-manager-data/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This was a fun little error, whilst installing the distributed IaaS roles I couldn’t seem to get the IaaS components to install – when I got the Website and Model Manager Data install it would fail with the following message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2014/07/image_thumb.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve pasted it in here because I couldn’t find anything through google that referred to my error messages – hopefully if you’re reading this you’ve found it because you’re looking for it!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 3.1: Configure Load Balancing with vCNS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 08:53:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This is the first part of the 3rd article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this part, we will not have modified the vCAC deployment in any way, we’ll just have 3 configured load balanced URLs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overview of the steps required are below:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 2: vPostgres</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-2-vpostgres/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 09:01:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-2-vpostgres/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This is the second article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diagram below shows the deployment at the end of this part, with vPostgres deployed and the vCAC Appliance running from the remote database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overview of the steps required are below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Issue and install certificates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure load balancing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install and configure additional IaaS server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="create-the-required-dns-records"&gt;Create the required DNS records &lt;a class="anchor" href="#create-the-required-dns-records"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;First of all, create DNS records for your vPostgres database server – you need both an A and PTR record. Most VMware appliances will check for a reverse DNS lookup when they boot and will set the hostname accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 1: Certificates</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-1-certificates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 11:43:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-1-certificates/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This is the first article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a simple installation you have the Identity Appliance, the vCAC appliance (which includes a vPostgres DB and vCenter Orchestrator instance) and an IaaS server. The distributed model still has a single Identity Appliance but clusters 2 or more vCAC appliances behind a load balancer, backed by a separate vPostgres database appliance. The IaaS components are installed on 2 or more IaaS Windows servers and are load balanced, backed by an external MSSQL database. Additionally, the vCenter Orchestrator appliance is used in a failover cluster, backed by the external vPostgres database appliance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VCP5-IaaS &amp;ndash; Exam experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/vcp5-iaas-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 16:01:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/vcp5-iaas-exam-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;So this morning I took the VMware Infrastructure as a Service exam (VCPVCD510) to gain the VCP5-Cloud qualification. The IaaS exam is available for existing VCP5-DCV holders to take without any other pre-requisites. I am very pleased to say I finished the exam in good time and scored 466/500 – the pass mark is 300.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://mylearn.vmware.com/lcms/web/portals/certification/PathDiagrams/VCP-Cloud.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-exam"&gt;The Exam &lt;a class="anchor" href="#the-exam"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The exam itself is 85 multiple choice questions, and gives you 90 minutes to do them. The last two exams I’ve sat were VCAPs, which require you to move very quickly through the questions, so I am in the habit of answering quickly: I finished with over an hour to spare! The questions and answers are not particularly wordy but it is important to read carefully and pick out the important information.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>