<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Charity on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/charity/</link><description>Recent content in Charity on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/charity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vExpert 2020 holographic sticker charity giveaway!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vexpert-2020-holographic-sticker-charity-giveaway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/vexpert-2020-holographic-sticker-charity-giveaway/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; - the first 50 vExperts to sign up on &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/adfsWN29boZBhMDT6"&gt;this google sheet&lt;/a&gt; and then make a &lt;a href="https://uk.virginmoneygiving.com/SamMcGeown"&gt;donation to my fundraiser here&lt;/a&gt; or another charity of your choice will get a nice shiny new vExpert 2020 sticker!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I entered a &lt;a href="https://www.stickermule.com/"&gt;StickerMule&lt;/a&gt; tweet contest to get some free holographic sticker prints - and I won! While I was thinking about what to do with my newly donated sticker trove, I figured why not use it to bribe the vExpert community in exchange for some charitable giving?! And, given there were over 50 likes and 40 comments in response to my initial tweet, it seemed like vExperts were up for a little bit of paying it forward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I’m running the Virgin London Marathon 2012 for The Lighthouse Group</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/01/im-running-the-virgin-london-marathon-2012-for-the-lighthouse-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 12:46:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/01/im-running-the-virgin-london-marathon-2012-for-the-lighthouse-group/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2012/01/vlm-logo.gif" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is nothing more than a shameless request for sponsorship! As the title suggests, I am running the London marathon this year (in 96 days!) for the charity &amp;ldquo;The Lighthouse Group&amp;rdquo;. Check out &lt;a href="http://www.tlg.org.uk/about.aspx"&gt;the TLG site&lt;/a&gt; for more detail on what they do, but in a nutshell they are a charity that works with young people who have been excluded from school, at risk of exclusion or are at crisis point in their education. It&amp;rsquo;s a really worthwhile cause and my father-in-law has just been involved in opening a TLG center based in Normanton, Yorkshire&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>