<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NSX/vCNS on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/nsx/vcns/</link><description>Recent content in NSX/vCNS on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/nsx/vcns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#VMworld2015: vRealize Automation 7 Briefing Notes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 08:20:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vrealize-automation-7-briefing-notes/</guid><description>@vaficionado) – if that list of names doesn’t fill you with confidence for vRA.Next, then I suggest you follow them on twitter and trust me that it’s a crack team!
 So, my highlights:
Completely automated deployment…almost. The deployment of appliances and installation of IaaS components and pre-requisites will be wizard driven, the Window Servers will need to exist and have an agent installed, and the MSSQL server will also need to be installed.</description></item><item><title>#VMworld2015: VCIX-NV Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 16:58:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/10/vmworld2015-vcix-nv-exam-experience/</guid><description>For the last few years at VMworld I’ve taken advantage of the discounted exam price and booked a “have-a-go” exam – typically an exam I’ve been wanting to do but not necessarily had the time I wanted to study for it. Since I have been fairly immersed in the NSX world for the last week, sitting in an NSX design and deploy class and surrounded by some very smart networking guys, I changed my “have-a-go” exam from the VCP6-CMA to the VCIX-NV.</description></item><item><title>Building a vRealize Automation NSX Lab on Ravello</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/building-a-vrealize-automation-nsx-lab-on-ravello/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 17:06:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/09/building-a-vrealize-automation-nsx-lab-on-ravello/</guid><description>As a vExpert, I am blessed to get 1000 CPU hours access to Ravello&amp;rsquo;s awesome platform and recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with the AutoLab deployments tailored for Ravello.
If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with Ravello&amp;rsquo;s offering (where have you been?!) then it&amp;rsquo;s basically a custom hypervisor (HVX) running on either AWS or Google Cloud that allows you to run nested environments on those platforms. I did say it&amp;rsquo;s awesome.
As an avid home-lab enthusiast Ravello initially felt weird, but having used it for a while I can definitely see the potential to augment, and in some cases completely replace the home lab.</description></item><item><title>Unable to connect NSX to Lookup Service when using a vSphere 6 subordinate certificate authority (VMCA)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/06/unable-to-connect-nsx-to-lookup-service-when-using-a-vsphere-6-subordinate-certificate-authority-vmca/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 12:26:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/06/unable-to-connect-nsx-to-lookup-service-when-using-a-vsphere-6-subordinate-certificate-authority-vmca/</guid><description>After deploying a new vSphere 6 vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) and configuring the Platform Services Controller (PSC) to act as a subordinate Certificate Authority (CS), I was unable to register the NSX Manager to the Lookup Service. Try saying that fast after a pint or two!?
Attempting to register NSX to the Lookup Service would result in the following error:
NSX Management Service operation failed.( Initialization of Admin Registration Service Provider failed.</description></item><item><title>VMworld 2014: VCP NV Exam Experience</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 11:56:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/10/vmworld-2014-vcp-nv-exam-experience/</guid><description>It is with great relief that I can announce I have passed my VCP NV (Network Virtualisation) having been caught out by the difficulty of the exam and failing previously.
Exam Preparation I was fortunate to attend a VMware internal bootcamp (roughly equivalent to the ICM course) for NSX and have had experience deploying production NSX environments, so that is by far the best preparation. As always, the exam blueprint is crucial, you *have* to know all areas covered there.</description></item><item><title>Configuring a remote access SSL VPN with VMware NSX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/configuring-a-remote-access-ssl-vpn-with-vmware-nsx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 12:35:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/09/configuring-a-remote-access-ssl-vpn-with-vmware-nsx/</guid><description>The NSX Edge Gateway comes pre-armed with the ability to provide an SSL VPN for remote access into your network. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a new feature (SSL VPN was available in vCloud Networking and Security), but it&amp;rsquo;s worth a run through. I&amp;rsquo;m configuring remote access to my Lab, since it&amp;rsquo;s often useful to access it when on a client site, but traditional VPN connections are often blocked on corporate networks where HTTPS isn&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 3.2: Configure load balancing with NSX</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-2-configure-load-balancing-with-nsx/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-2-configure-load-balancing-with-nsx/</guid><description>This is the second part of the 3rd article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
By the end of this part, we will not have modified the vCAC deployment in any way, we’ll just have 3 configured load balanced URLs
vCAC Simple Install with vPostgres deployed and load balancers prepared An overview of the steps required are below:</description></item><item><title>vCAC 6.0 build-out to distributed model &amp;ndash; Part 3.1: Configure Load Balancing with vCNS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 08:53:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/06/vcac-6-0-build-out-to-distributed-model-part-3-1-configure-load-balancing-with-vcns/</guid><description>This is the first part of the 3rd article in a series about how to build-out a simple vCAC 6 installation to a distributed model.
By the end of this part, we will not have modified the vCAC deployment in any way, we’ll just have 3 configured load balanced URLs
vCAC simple configuration with vPostgres and Load Balancers prepared An overview of the steps required are below:
Issue and install certificates Deploy an external vPostgres appliance and migrate the vCAC database Configure load balancing Deploy a second vCAC appliance and configure clustering Install and configure additional IaaS server Deploy vCenter Orchestrator Appliance cluster Deploy a vShield Edge appliance Log in to your vShield Manager and select your Datacenter, then the Network Virtualisation tab</description></item><item><title>VMworld Europe 2013 – Day 1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-arriving-and-day-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 15:22:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/10/vmworld-europe-2013-arriving-and-day-1/</guid><description>I flew from Gatwick to Barcelona last night to my very first VMworld!
I&amp;rsquo;m staying in a hotel that is actually quite far from the conference, it&amp;rsquo;s a metro, train and bus journey away from the conference center and it takes about 40 minutes to get here. On the plus side I was only 5 minutes away from the VMUG party last night so I went over there for an hour or so.</description></item></channel></rss>