<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vcenter on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcenter/</link><description>Recent content in Vcenter on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 11:45:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcenter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enable vCenter High Availability with vRealize Orchestrator</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/enable-vcenter-high-availability-with-vrealize-orchestrator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 11:45:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2018/09/enable-vcenter-high-availability-with-vrealize-orchestrator/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick post today to cover a new vRO action and workflow I’ve uploaded to GitHub that configures vCenter High Availability in the basic mode. This is based on &lt;a href="https://www.virtuallyghetto.com/2016/12/vcenter-server-high-availability-vcha-powercli-6-5-community-module.html"&gt;William Lam’s excellent PowerShell module&lt;/a&gt; that does the same, but using vRO. I also hope to release a version for the advanced mode based on my &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/06/powershell-deploying-vcenter-high-availability-in-advanced-mode/"&gt;PowerShell script&lt;/a&gt; in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR - &lt;a href="https://github.com/sammcgeown/org.definit.vcha"&gt;package is availabile on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workflow itself is pretty self explanatory, with my deployment action, which returns a VC:Task, and the standard “wait for a task to end” action.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Slow or failed logon to VCSA 5.5 with vCOps in the environment</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/slow-or-failed-logon-to-vcsa-5-5-with-vcops-in-the-environment/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 09:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/07/slow-or-failed-logon-to-vcsa-5-5-with-vcops-in-the-environment/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Recently I encountered this problem in a customer site whereby the logon to VCSA 5.5 would either time out, or take 3-5 minutes to actually log on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a netstat on the VCSA during the attempt to logon showed there was a SYN packet sent to the vCOps appliance on port 443 that never established a connection. Another check was attempting to connect using curl &amp;lt;https://&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&amp;gt; –k  - this would time out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing vCOps 5.8 in the DefinIT Lab &amp;ndash; 4GB RAM and 2 vCPU</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/installing-vcops-5-8-in-the-definit-lab-4gb-ram-and-2-vcpu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 11:38:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2014/01/installing-vcops-5-8-in-the-definit-lab-4gb-ram-and-2-vcpu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;There’s no doubt that vCOps is a great product for proactively monitoring your vSphere environment, but it’s a hefty package for the lab. The minimum recommended RAM is a whopping 16GB – in my lab that’s the whole of my management host! I recently needed to do some testing so I wanted to get it running in the lab with the barest minimum I could get working, and it turns out you can get working with just 4GB and 2 CPU…albeit you wouldn’t want to monitor much! I also want to use vFlash Read Cache to accelerate I/O in the lab – this requires upgrading VMtools and the VM hardware to version 10.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Installing VMware vSphere Update Manager Download Service and publishing via IIS</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-vmware-vsphere-update-manager-download-service-and-publishing-via-iis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 15:30:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-vmware-vsphere-update-manager-download-service-and-publishing-via-iis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The vSphere UMDS provides a way to download patches for VMware servers that have an air-gap, or for some reason aren’t allowed to go out to the internet themselves – in my case a security policy prevented a DMZ vCenter Server from connecting to the internet directly. The solution is to use UMDS to download the updates to a 2nd server that was hosted in the DMZ and then update the vCenter Server from there. It also can save on bandwidth if you’re running multiple vCenter Servers, which again was the case (though bandwidth isn’t really a constraint).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Powershell – Generate Microsoft CA signed SSL certificates with vSphere 5.1</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/powershell-generate-microsoft-ca-signed-ssl-certificates-with-vsphere-5-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 16:59:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/powershell-generate-microsoft-ca-signed-ssl-certificates-with-vsphere-5-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2010/11/VMware3.jpg" alt=""&gt;The process of requesting certificates for vSphere 5.1 is a fairly grim, manual process. It&amp;rsquo;s repetitive and easy to make a mistake on any step of the way. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve got to do this for quite a few VirtualCenter Servers, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d script the certificate generation if nothing else. I am following the excellent documentation provided in &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Implementing CA signed SSL certificates with vSphere 5.1&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; and more specifically in &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Creating certificate requests and certificates for vCenter Server 5.1 components&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>