<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Webinar on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/webinar/</link><description>Recent content in Webinar on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 10:17:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/webinar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2017 – Part 4 : Optimizing Workload Performance Using Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 10:17:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/03/logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;In this episode, Sunny gave us a deep dive into the WLP and WLB features of vROps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were also joined by a special guest, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/virtualjad"&gt;Jad El-Zein&lt;/a&gt; who gave us a great insight into how vRA utilises vROps for initial placement of freshly provisioned VMs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We would highly appreciate it if you could spend 30 seconds to fill up this quick and simple survey to provide us your feedback. You can also request topics of your choice through this survey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2017 – Announcing Part 4 : Optimizing Workload Performance Using Automation</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-announcing-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 13:18:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/09/vrops-webinar-2017-announcing-part-4-optimizing-workload-performance-using-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/03/logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;In this coming episode, Sunny will DIVE DEEP into the interesting topic of introducing automation into operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we all know that, automating day to day operations tasks is becoming the choice of an IT organization, it is hard for them to find a solution which can completely understand their business policies and provide them the efficiency they need from automating simple operational tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on our research, we found that, one of the most time consuming activity done by an Virtual Infrastructure Administrator is to juggle resources between the changing business requirements and ensure that every VM which is being hosted in their environment is &lt;strong&gt;BEING SERVED WELL&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 1 – What’s New with vROps 6.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-with-vrops-6-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 09:02:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/04/vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-with-vrops-6-5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/03/logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;Time to share the recording of the first episode of the vROps Webinar Series 2017. This time around, Sunny and I spoke about the latest release of vRealize Operations Manager. We spoke about almost all the new features which were introduced with this version and went into some of them in detail. Like always we rounded up the session with Live Demo of the new features for our audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduced a feedback form which can be used to provide your feedback in general and also request topics on which you would want us to focus this year.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Announcing #vROps Webinar Series 2017 – Part 1 – What’s new in 6.5</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/announcing-vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-in-6-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 10:58:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/announcing-vrops-webinar-series-2017-part-1-whats-new-in-6-5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2017/03/logo.jpg" alt=""&gt;Welcome to the vRealize Operations Manager Webinar Series 2017. With the huge success of the series back in 2016, we wanted to take a break, enjoy the success and come back with full rigor for this series in 2017. We are here and we are charged up to give you some more dope on vRealize Operations manager in the year 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The delivery mechanism would be same as last year. We will start with talking about a topic and then jump into a live environment to see what happens when the rubber hits the road…&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Part 12 : What’s New with vROps 6.4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 12:02:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;Time to publish the recording for the 12th episode of the vROps Webinar Series. This time we did a what’s new with vRealize Operations 6.4 and the changes made to vRealize Operations 6.4as you will see there has been a lot packed into this recent release!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been an awesome 12 months working with Sunny on this project and I am very glad to say we will be back next year (we will skip January and will return in February).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 12 : What’s New with vROps 6.4</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 08:36:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-12-whats-new-with-vrops-6-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the time of the month when I would like to invite you to join the next episode of our &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/?s=webinar"&gt;year long vROps Webinar Series&lt;/a&gt;. As we move towards the closure of a fantastic year, we would like to take a zoom out view at the vRealize Operations Manager solution with a What&amp;rsquo;s New Episode. &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-6-3/"&gt;We did a What&amp;rsquo;s new with vRealize Operations 6.3&lt;/a&gt; a couple of months back, however looking at some awesome changes made to vRealize Operations 6.4 it absolutely makes sense to go over the new goodies.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series – Part 11 – Getting more out of #vROps with PowerCLI</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-part-11-getting-more-out-of-vrops-with-powercli-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 12:10:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-part-11-getting-more-out-of-vrops-with-powercli-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Time to publish the recording for the 11th episode of the vROps Webinar Series. This time we were joined by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vinithmenon28"&gt;Vinith Menon&lt;/a&gt; who spoke about getting more from your vROps builds with PowerCLI. Vinith demonstrated the many useful ways of leveraging PowerCLI to manage your vROps environments and also communicate with the vROps API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vinithmenon28"&gt;Vinith Menon&lt;/a&gt; for presenting this excellent session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So without further ado, here is the recording for this session:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series – Announcing Part 11 – Getting more out of #vROps with PowerCLI</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-part-11-getting-more-out-of-vrops-with-powercli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 13:05:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-part-11-getting-more-out-of-vrops-with-powercli/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;Another month has gone and Christmas is now looming large! It has been extremely busy but we still want to continue with the momentum of webinar series getting to the business end of the year. This time around we will talk about getting more out of vRealize Operations Manager using PowerCLI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session we will be joined by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/vinithmenon28"&gt;Vinith Menon&lt;/a&gt; who will show us all kinds of PowerCLI goodness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So without further a do, save the date in your calendars and join use for the next episode of vRealize Operations Webinar Series 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series Slide decks – available for download</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-slide-decks-available-for-download/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 23:27:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/11/vrops-webinar-series-slide-decks-available-for-download/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;If you have been following and enjoying the vROps Webinar series both &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua"&gt;Sunny&lt;/a&gt; and I have been running this year you may find it useful to know &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua"&gt;Sunny&lt;/a&gt; has put all the slide decks up and availble in one place for you to download and share if you so wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://app.box.com/s/pzarwjmf3m9wkwj628m9cmsi7bvprw4w"&gt;vROps Webinar Series Slide Decks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy and share the knowledge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or comments just drop either Sunny or myself a comment on our respective blogs or contact us on twitter.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series 2016 – Part 10 – A Deep Dive into vROps API</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-2016-part-10-a-deep-dive-into-vrops-api/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 12:37:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-2016-part-10-a-deep-dive-into-vrops-api/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Time to publish the recording for the 10th episode of vROps Webinar Series. This time around we spoke about vRealize Operations Manager Resful API and how to use it. Post 20 minutes of slide-ware, I jumped into the lab and thanks to the demo god, we demonstrated a number of use cases and browsed through the documentation to make it easier for you to consume and use the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua"&gt;@sunny_dua&lt;/a&gt; for doing the session while I was MIA you are a legend buddy!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 10 : A Deep Dive into vROps API</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-10-a-deep-dive-into-vrops-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 11:57:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-10-a-deep-dive-into-vrops-api/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;The month has been extremely busy but we still want to continue with the momentum of webinar series getting to the business end of the year. This time around we will talk about vRealize Operations Manager API. API is your friend if you are trying to automate things which you would normally do on GUI. While GUI is a favourite of most, the geeks prefer the API since that helps them to programatically initiate tasks and go out for a coffee. By the time they are back from the LONG coffee break, the work is done 🙂&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar Series – Part 9 – What’s New with vRealize Operations 6.3</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-6-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 08:27:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/vrops-webinar-series-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-6-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;Here is the recording for the episode 9 vRealize Operations Manager Webinar Series 2016. During this episode we discussed about the new features and functionalities of vRealize Operations Manager 6.3. With this release of the product, we can clearly see that VMware is clearly working on enhancing the user experience and the user interface with some great new features and UI changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would encourage you to watch this session to understand the full potential of the product and how you can use the new features to meet your requirements and ease out operations in your Virtual / Cloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 9 : What’s New with vRealize Operations Manager 6.3</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/09/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-manager-6-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 12:42:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/09/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-9-whats-new-with-vrealize-operations-manager-6-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the time of the month when we invite you to join the next episode of our year long vROps Webinar Series. As we move towards winter, we would like to take a zoom out view at the vRealize Operations Manager solution with a What&amp;rsquo;s New Episode. For the past 8 months, we have give pretty deep into most of the product features and we believe it is time when we review the product in it&amp;rsquo;s current form and shape. In my opinion, this could not be done better than sharing about the new features &amp;amp; functionalities available in the latest version of vRealize Operations Manager.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Part 8 : SDDC Operations with vROps Custom Dashboards</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-webinar-2016-part-8-sddc-operations-with-vrops-custom-dashboards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 14:52:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-webinar-2016-part-8-sddc-operations-with-vrops-custom-dashboards/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/11/vRealize-Operations-Manager-Logo_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;With today, being the last day of the month, we wanted to make sure that we share this out with you folks out there to keep up with the practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iwan Rahabok, did a great job on this one, talking about the the concept of SDDC operations and I would recommend this session to anyone who wants a jump-start into transforming their operations for SDDC. Quickly want to thank Iwan here for spending his valuable time with us and giving back to the community through this Webinar Series, Blogs, Books etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 8 : SDDC Operations with vROps Custom Dashboards</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-8-sddc-operations-with-vrops-custom-dashboards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 08:30:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-8-sddc-operations-with-vrops-custom-dashboards/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;This time around Iwan Rahabok will lead the next session of the vROps Webinar Series while Sunny and myself will support him to deliver some awesome content which Iwan has developed over the past few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, this time around we will move our focus from vROps as a Product and related features to the concept of running your SDDC operations with vRealize Operations Dashboards. Just to clarify, this is not a session where we will teach you to create dashboards, but this is a session where we would share how a set of Customised Dashboards can help any organisation&amp;rsquo;s IT to get an insight into Storage, Network &amp;amp; Compute within your SDDC. While vROps is primarily a Performance Management and Capacity Planning tool, we will take you to the other important aspects as well such as Availability and Configuration.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Part 7 : Working with Alerts &amp; Symptoms</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vrops-webinar-2016-part-7-working-with-alerts-symptoms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 09:03:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vrops-webinar-2016-part-7-working-with-alerts-symptoms/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;Time to release the recording for the latest part of the vROps Webinar Series. We completed the 7th session of the series where we spoke about vRealize Operations Manager Alerts and Symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alerts as we all know would always remain the heart and soul for the operations teams to run the data centers, whether old school or the modern software defined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all cases you need alerts and more importantly you need meaningful and actionable alerts. In this part of the series, Simon and myself concentrated on making you aware of the alert constructs in vROps and as usual share experiences around how we help customers leverage the strong feature set of vROps to customize alerts and related symptoms, recommendations and actions to drastically reduce the Mean Time to Resolution of issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 7 : Working with Alerts &amp; Symptoms</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-7-working-with-alerts-symptoms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 17:54:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/07/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-7-working-with-alerts-symptoms/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;Time to announce the next part of the year long webinar series on vRealize Operations Manager. With the last part of the series, we started focusing on content withing vROps. We will continue the trend and talk about a major function of vROps a.k.a Alerts. Alerts is the most used and most ab-used part of vROps, and with this session we want to give you some insights on the entire life-cycle of the alerting function of vROps.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Part 6 : Understanding vROps SuperMetric &amp; Views</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/06/vrops-webinar-2016-part-6-understanding-vrops-supermetric-views/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 22:42:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/06/vrops-webinar-2016-part-6-understanding-vrops-supermetric-views/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/khBMWhr2aFg?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 6 : Understanding vROps SuperMetric &amp; Views</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/06/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-6-understanding-vrops-supermetric-views/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 09:31:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/06/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-6-understanding-vrops-supermetric-views/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;Time to announce the next part of the year long webinar series on vRealize Operations Manager. This time around, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua"&gt;Sunny&lt;/a&gt; and I will take you to the world of Content within vROps. I will be honest in saying that this is an ocean in itself and we might not be able to touch upon all the aspects of developing content within vROps. During this effort we plan to start with giving you an overview of the various options available to develop content within vROps.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 5 : Design and Deployment considerations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-part-5-design-and-deployment-considerations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 13:25:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-part-5-design-and-deployment-considerations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;As promised, I am posting the recording for the 5th Session of vROps Webinar Series 2016. Both Sunny and I successfully delivered the session on Design and Deployment considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Session Details:-&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; In this instalment of the series, we discussed the steps and thought processes that should be used before and during the design and deployment of vRealize Operations Manager. During the session among other things we will cover the planning, core components, correct sizing, HA, clustering, DR and future growth**.**&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 5 : Design &amp; Deployment Considerations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-5-design-deployment-considerations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 06:52:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/05/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-5-design-deployment-considerations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;Time to announce the next part of the year long &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/starting-2016-with-a-bang-vrops-webinar-series/"&gt;webinar series&lt;/a&gt; on vRealize Operations Manager. This time around, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua"&gt;Sunny&lt;/a&gt; and I thought about discussing Architecture of vROps. To some, it might sound strange as for smaller deployments you might not have to worry about Sizing and Architecture much since it is pretty simple to install and configure a small or a medium node for a small shop. However as your monitoring needs grow and you start adding solutions for monitoring data sources beyond vSphere, you would need to think about scaling up or scaling out. As your monitoring environment weaves into your incident ticketing system, you would start to see the need to HA of vROps and as you have a DR strategy for your workloads, you will start thinking about DR for your operations tools as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 4 – Contention Based Performance &amp; Capacity Management</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-webinar-2016-part-4-contention-based-performance-capacity-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 08:17:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-webinar-2016-part-4-contention-based-performance-capacity-management/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;As promised, I am posting the recording for the 4th Session of vROps Webinar Series 2016. We successfully delivered the session on Contention Based Performance &amp;amp; Capacity Management using vRealize Operations Manager!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Session Details:- &amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;With this instalment of the series, we have a new speaker &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/e1_ang&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Iwan Rahabok&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, who will entertain and educate us 🙂 He is no stranger to the world of vRealize Operations Manager and has written a couple of books on vROps as well.
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
 
 &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
 During this session we will help you understand a few basic concepts of using the right counters to monitor performance and capacity in your infrastructure. We will deep dive into the concept of the consumer and the provider layer and help you with solving issues which you might face as a provider of infrastructure to your business.
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
 
 &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;I also want to personally thank &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Sunny&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;amp; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/e1_ang&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Iwan&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/simoneady&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;for their continued support to this series.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
 
 &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Here is the recording for this session:::&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
 
 &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
 Note : It is recommended that you watch the video in HD quality for a great experience.
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
 
 &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;iframe width=&amp;quot;500&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;281&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mhXkiRWXEBg?feature=oembed&amp;quot; frameborder=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 4 : Contention Based Performance &amp; Capacity Management</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-4-contention-based-performance-capacity-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 11:33:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-4-contention-based-performance-capacity-management/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;We hope you are having fun with the &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/starting-2016-with-a-bang-vrops-webinar-series/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vROps Webinar Series&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and learning in the process!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the next instalment of this series, we have a new speaker who will entertain us 🙂 He is no stranger to the world of vRealize Operations Manager and has written a couple of books on vROps as well. I am referring to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/e1_ang"&gt;Iwan Rahabok&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; who has been my partner in crime on all the vROps related work which we do, inside VMware or with the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 3 – Capacity Planning De-Mystified!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 16:29:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Session Details:-&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capacity Planning Demystified!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capacity Planning is an integral part of vRealize Operations Manager and through this session we want to de-mystify the concepts of Capacity Planning in vROps using features such as projects and the out-of-box capacity views. We look at defining the capacity planning policies based on the business requirements of an organization&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A big thank you to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PunchingClouds"&gt;Rawlinson Rivera&lt;/a&gt; to provide all the lab equipment required for the live and thanks again to my Co-host &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sunny_Dua"&gt;Sunny&lt;/a&gt; you&amp;rsquo;re a legend!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 3 : Capacity Planning De-Mystified!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 16:08:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capacity Planning Demystified!&lt;/strong&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 2 : Understanding vROps Policies</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-part-2-understanding-vrops-policies-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 10:31:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-part-2-understanding-vrops-policies-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;year long commitment&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; of providing quality content on vRealize Operations Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please remember that this is an introductory session to policies and we intend to go deeper into policies in the next session in the month of March, where we deep dive into more details around capacity planning with vRealize Operations Manager. You will hear more about that as we progress into the next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 2 : Understanding Policies.</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-2-understanding-policies-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 14:17:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/02/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-2-understanding-policies-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;vROps Webinar Series 2016 is back and as promised during &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrealize-operations-webinar-series-2015-part-1-building-self-healing-environments-with-vrops/"&gt;the last session&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; we would now take you to the world of vRealize Operations Policies Policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a Policy??&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;A &lt;strong&gt;policy&lt;/strong&gt; is a deliberate system of principles to guide decisions and achieve rational outcomes. A &lt;strong&gt;policy&lt;/strong&gt; is a statement of intent, and is implemented as a procedure or protocol&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source - &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Policy"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the role of vRealize Operations Manager is to help you with Performance &amp;amp; Capacity Management of your Software Defined Datacenter (SDDC), it is important that you feed in the guiding principles of your Business Environment into vROps to get the rational outcomes. These outcomes span across Health, Risk &amp;amp; Efficiency of your SDDC environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Operations Webinar Series : 2015 :Part 1 : Building Self Healing Environments with #vROps</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrealize-operations-webinar-series-2015-part-1-building-self-healing-environments-with-vrops/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 10:20:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/vrealize-operations-webinar-series-2015-part-1-building-self-healing-environments-with-vrops/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2016/01/CZFR4nKUsAADI5G.png" alt=""&gt;A series of webcasts on vRealize Operations Manager 6.x, helping you learn about anything and everything about the solution. Some of the examples include, vROps Policies, Alert Definitions, Automated Action Framework, integration to third party etc. This would include power point and live demonstrations. The session would range anywhere between 60 to 90 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 100+ registrations and more than 70 live attendees, it was definitely a great start to this series. On popular demand of many who could not attend the session due to time-zone differences, we have recorded the session and you can watch the same right here. It is recommended that you watch the video in HD quality for a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Starting 2016 with a bang &amp;ndash; #vROps Webinar Series</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/starting-2016-with-a-bang-vrops-webinar-series/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 15:12:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/01/starting-2016-with-a-bang-vrops-webinar-series/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>