<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>logging on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/logging/</link><description>Recent content in logging on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/logging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Forwarding Tanzu Kubernetes Grid logs to vRealize Log Insight Cloud using the Fluent-bit Package</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/12/forwarding-tanzu-kubernetes-grid-logs-to-vrealize-log-insight-cloud-using-the-fluent-bit-package/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2021/12/forwarding-tanzu-kubernetes-grid-logs-to-vrealize-log-insight-cloud-using-the-fluent-bit-package/</guid><description>In my previous post I walked through configuring kubernetes ingress with automatically generated SSL certificates and DNS registration using Tanzu Kubernetes Grid&amp;rsquo;s Packages.</description></item><item><title>Getting started with vRealize Log Insight 4.3 for vRealize Automation 7</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/getting-started-with-vrealize-log-insight-for-vrealize-automation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 12:09:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2017/03/getting-started-with-vrealize-log-insight-for-vrealize-automation/</guid><description>In this humble consultant&amp;rsquo;s opinion, Log Insight is one of the most useful tools in the administrator&amp;rsquo;s tool belt for troubleshooting vRealize Automation. I have lost count of the number of times I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to help troubleshoot an issue that, when asked, people don&amp;rsquo;t know which log they should be looking at. The simple fact is that vRealize Automation has a lot of log files. Correlating these log sources to provide an overall picture is a painful, manual process - unless you have Log Insight!</description></item><item><title>Installing and Configuring vCenter Log Insight</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-and-configuring-vcenter-log-insight/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 13:32:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2013/06/installing-and-configuring-vcenter-log-insight/</guid><description>With the release of vCenter Log Insight Public Beta (http://communities.vmware.com/community/vmtn/vcenter/vcenter-log-insight) I thought I’d strike while the iron is hot and run through the installation and configuration.
Deploying the OVF This is such a bread and butter task that it doesn’t require more than a few words – it’s definitely worth looking at the Sizing PDF before you deploy (VMware-vCenter-Log-Insight-1.0-Beta-Virtual-Appliance-Sizing.pdf) as it’s not small even for a test installation. If you’re using less than the recommended 8GB RAM there are additional steps to change the heap size for performance.</description></item></channel></rss>