<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>McGeown on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/mcgeown/</link><description>Recent content in McGeown on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 11:27:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/mcgeown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Welcome to DefinIT!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/02/welcome-to-definit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 11:27:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2011/02/welcome-to-definit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2011/02/wordpress_thumb.jpg" alt=""&gt;If you’ve been here before, you may have noticed a couple of changes – the theme and name of this blog for example, and hopefully you’ve been redirected to a new URL! There are a couple of reasons for the changes, all of which are aimed at increasing the presence and visitor numbers on this site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Branding. Whether I like it or not, “McGeown” is not easy to spell or remember so I wanted to move away from it as an identity. After some discussion with my friend and creative advisor &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Matt Hellyer&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, I picked DefinIT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’d like to add some more bloggers to the site – the number of visitors is directly in proportion to the number of posts, and I can’t post as much as I’d like to. I will introduce those bloggers as and when they arrive, but they will be people I know and trust – with real technical expertise. (That said, if you’re reading and are interested in writing for DefinIT, please contact me!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eventually I’d like to use McGeown.co.uk for a more personal site, aimed at family and friends. That’s what it was originally aimed at, and hopefully one of these days I’ll get the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to let me know what you think about the new theme, new name and new URL in the comments below. This blog will always be dedicated to providing high quality IT help on a broad range of subjects, as ever, I hope it helps!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>