<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VCenter Orchestrator on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcenter-orchestrator/</link><description>Recent content in VCenter Orchestrator on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 12:09:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vcenter-orchestrator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO) – Troubleshooting SOAP operations</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-troubleshooting-soap-operations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 12:09:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-troubleshooting-soap-operations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a bit of a SOAP baptism of fire - the project I am working on makes hundreds of SOAP calls to multiple SOAP APIs on multiple hosts. During this time I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered some common and rare problems and troubleshooting them seems to be a bit of a black art, if the number of results in Google is any measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate some of these troubleshooting methods I will use a global weather SOAP service, &lt;a href="http://www.webservicex.com/globalweather.asmx?WSDL" title="http://www.webservicex.com/globalweather.asmx?WSDL" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; http://www.webservicex.com/globalweather.asmx?WSDL
&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve added the web service to vRO using the &amp;ldquo;Add a SOAP host&amp;rdquo; workflow, and then used the &amp;ldquo;Generate a new workflow from a SOAP operation&amp;rdquo; workflow to create a new workflow: GetWeather. This simple workflow runs successfully:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO) and vCloud Director – fixing bugs in "Add a vDC"</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-and-vcloud-director-fixing-bugs-in-add-a-vdc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 10:53:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-and-vcloud-director-fixing-bugs-in-add-a-vdc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;When you are using a VMware orchestration platform with an official VMware plugin to manage a VMware product, you don&amp;rsquo;t really expect to have to fix the out-of-the-box workflows. However, during some testing of some workflows with a client the other day we ran into a couple of issues with the vCloud Director plugin workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software versions used&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vCloud Director 5.5.1 (appliance for development) and 5.5.2 (production deployment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vRealize Orchestrator Appliance 5.5.2.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vCloud Director plugin 5.5.1.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="cpu-allocations-are-incorrect-for-both-add-a-vdc"&gt;CPU allocations are incorrect for both &amp;ldquo;Add a VDC&amp;rdquo; &lt;a class="anchor" href="#cpu-allocations-are-incorrect-for-both-add-a-vdc"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you provide the CPU allocation model properties for the Allocation Pool model the first problem is decrypting the naming - it doesn&amp;rsquo;t match the names in the vCloud Director interface!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Performance tweak – increasing Max Heap Size for the vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO) Client</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/performance-tweak-increasing-max-heap-size-for-the-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-client/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 20:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/performance-tweak-increasing-max-heap-size-for-the-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco-client/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;[Update Dec 2016: &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/12/increasing-the-java-heap-size-for-vrealize-orchestrator-client-7-x/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; An updated article for vRO 7.x is available here
&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m developing some very large, very complicated workflows for vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO), and as it&amp;rsquo;s a Java based application it will probably come as no surprise to many that the performance of the client drops off sharply as the client&amp;rsquo;s RAM usage creeps up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When working on some of the larger workflows, or after long sessions and heavy clipboard use, the client would become (even more) sluggish and in some cases would freeze entirely. This is particularly annoying because the vRO client has a habit of forcing itself on top of other applications - for instance Task Manager.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>3DES Password Based Encryption with vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/3des-password-based-encryption-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 21:38:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/3des-password-based-encryption-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A requirement that often arises in large, complex orchestration projects is the need to encrypt and decrypt information. One such requirement recently specified triple DES password based encryption as the standard, which led me through a lot of Google searches to &lt;a href="https://code.google.com/p/crypto-js/" target="_blank"&gt;
 &lt;clr-icon shape="pop-out" size="12"&gt;&lt;/clr-icon&gt; CryptoJS
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CryptoJS is a growing collection of standard and secure cryptographic algorithms implemented in JavaScript using best practices and patterns. They are fast, and they have a consistent and simple interface.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Generating a secure random password with vRealize Orchestrator (vRO/vCO)</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/generating-a-secure-random-password-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 21:17:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/generating-a-secure-random-password-with-vrealize-orchestrator-vrovco/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly common requirement when creating a new user to assign a randomly generated password, so during a recent engagement I wrote a little password generator to do that. I wanted to be able to chose whether special characters were used, and the length of the password - typically if the password doesn&amp;rsquo;t used special characters I would increase the length significantly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Characters should be randomly picked from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a-z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A-Z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0-9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(optional) ASCII special characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="inputs"&gt;Inputs &lt;a class="anchor" href="#inputs"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;passwordLength - the length of the password to be generated (number)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;excludePunctuation - exclude the use of special characters if TRUE (boolean)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.definit.co.uk/images/2015/01/image_thumb35.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>vRealize Orchestrator (vCO) Multi-node Plug-in use case: Remote Site Selection and Execution</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-operations-vco-multi-node-plug-in-use-case-remote-site-selection-and-execution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 16:46:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/vrealize-operations-vco-multi-node-plug-in-use-case-remote-site-selection-and-execution/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;One of the use cases I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on with a customer is based on the vRO/vCO multi-node plug-in and involves the master vRO/vCO node calling proxy workflows based on a parameter - in this case the target site. As you can see from this very simple diagram, a Cloud Management System (CMS) calls a workflow on the Master node, which then executes a proxy workflow on the correct site. The trick is getting the Master Orchestrator node to pick the right proxy workflow.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Configuring and Using vRealize Orchestrator (vCO/vRO) Multi-node plugin</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/configuring-and-using-vrealize-orchestrator-vcovro-multi-node-plugin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 16:50:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2015/01/configuring-and-using-vrealize-orchestrator-vcovro-multi-node-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;To quote the release notes for the latest version of vCO/vRO Multi-node Plugin:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VMware vCenter Orchestrator Multi-Node Plug-In allows organizations to manage environments with multiple vCenter Orchestrator server instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As organizations increase their level of automation, they often find the need to deploy multiple Orchestrator instances. With the VMware vCenter Orchestrator Multi-Node Plug-In, administrators have a more efficient way to manage multiple Orchestrator instances from a central point. The plug-in allows administrators to log in to a master Orchestrator server to view the inventories and workflows of remote Orchestrator servers, and to trigger workflows remotely.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>