<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Raspberrypi on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/raspberrypi/</link><description>Recent content in Raspberrypi on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/raspberrypi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What's in your Kubernetes Home Lab?</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/09/whats-in-your-kubernetes-home-lab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/09/whats-in-your-kubernetes-home-lab/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, your home lab is constantly changing, evolving, breaking, rebuilding. For the last year or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been running all my home kubernetes workloads on a Raspberry Pi cluster - and it&amp;rsquo;s been working really well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been through several iterations - for example firstly running on SD cards (tl;dr - it&amp;rsquo;s bad, they wear out really fast with Kubernetes on board!), then &lt;a href="https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/pxe-booting-raspberry-pi-4-with-synology-and-ubiquiti-edgerouter/"&gt;
 PxE booting them from my Synology
&lt;/a&gt; to it&amp;rsquo;s now current state of booting directly from SSDs. I&amp;rsquo;ve also moved from Raspberry Pi 3s to 4s, I&amp;rsquo;ve played around with stacking cluster cases before landing on the current rack-mount format.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PXE Booting Raspberry Pi 4 with Synology and Ubiquiti EdgeRouter</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/pxe-booting-raspberry-pi-4-with-synology-and-ubiquiti-edgerouter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2020/03/pxe-booting-raspberry-pi-4-with-synology-and-ubiquiti-edgerouter/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I love Raspbery Pis - I have done since they first released them, all the way up to the present iteration, the Raspberry Pi 4. They&amp;rsquo;re phenominal little bits of kit, endlessly hackable and because of their really low price, they open up computing to a huge number of people who otherwise wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get the opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the irritating things, though, about running Raspberry Pis is that they typically boot from an SD card. SD cards are notorious for having high attrition rates, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re reading/writing to them regularly. Running a Kubernetes cluster on my Raspberry Pis is especially hard on the SD card because you&amp;rsquo;re not only running the system&amp;rsquo;s read and writes, but you&amp;rsquo;re also running containers and their I/O on the card.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>