<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>capacity on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/capacity/</link><description>Recent content in capacity on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 11:33:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/capacity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 4 : Contention Based Performance &amp; Capacity Management</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-4-contention-based-performance-capacity-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 11:33:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/04/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-4-contention-based-performance-capacity-management/</guid><description>We hope you are having fun with the vROps Webinar Series and learning in the process!
With the next instalment of this series, we have a new speaker who will entertain us 🙂 He is no stranger to the world of vRealize Operations Manager and has written a couple of books on vROps as well. I am referring to Iwan Rahabok who has been my partner in crime on all the vROps related work which we do, inside VMware or with the community.</description></item><item><title>#vROps Webinar 2016 : Part 3 – Capacity Planning De-Mystified!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 16:29:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</guid><description>Sunny and myself delivered the session on vROps Capacity Planning with some demo scenarios which will help you define your capacity monitoring goals. Session Details:-
Capacity Planning Demystified!
Capacity Planning is an integral part of vRealize Operations Manager and through this session we want to de-mystify the concepts of Capacity Planning in vROps using features such as projects and the out-of-box capacity views. We look at defining the capacity planning policies based on the business requirements of an organization</description></item><item><title>vROps Webinar 2016 – Announcing Part 3 : Capacity Planning De-Mystified!</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 16:08:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/03/vrops-webinar-2016-announcing-part-3-capacity-planning-de-mystified/</guid><description>we will now deep-dive into vRealize Operations Manager Policies, specifically around the area of Capacity Planning. Capacity Planning Demystified!**
**
Capacity Planning is an integral part of vRealize Operations Manager and through this session we want to de-mystify the concepts of Capacity Planning in vROps using features such as projects and the out-of-box capacity views. We will also look at defining the capacity planning policies based on the business requirements of an organization &amp; yeah this would be all done through LIVE DEMOS 🙂 Day &amp; Date : Thursday, 24th Mar 2016</description></item></channel></rss>