<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>remove on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/remove/</link><description>Recent content in remove on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 21:32:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/remove/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adding and removing #vROps nodes</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/adding-and-removing-vrops-nodes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 21:32:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/10/adding-and-removing-vrops-nodes/</guid><description>I was asked recently if there were any materials I could direct people to with regards to expanding existing vROps deployments. I did a brief search on the web to see what material was &amp;ldquo;out there&amp;rdquo; on how to perform what is a straight forward task. To my surprise very little came up. So I have decided to create this guide with all the things you need to consider when you are going to either expand or need to remove a node from one of your active vROps deployments.</description></item><item><title>DataStore conflicts with an existing DataStore in the DataCenter – Manually disabling Storage I/O Control</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/datastore-conflicts-with-an-existing-datastore-in-the-datacenter-manually-disabling-storage-io-control/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 15:31:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/datastore-conflicts-with-an-existing-datastore-in-the-datacenter-manually-disabling-storage-io-control/</guid><description>I ran into this issue yesterday while reconnecting hosts in our vCenter Server following a complete reinstall - the reasons for which are a long story, but suffice to say that there were new certificates and the host passwords were encrypted with the old ones.
The LUNs had been unpresented at the hardware level by the storage team, but had not been unmounted or removed from vCenter. This is not the way to remove storage - let me re-iterate: remove storage properly.</description></item></channel></rss>