<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vROps 6.3 on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vrops-6.3/</link><description>Recent content in vROps 6.3 on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 09:42:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/vrops-6.3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#vROps 6.3 – SNMP filtering</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-6-3-snmp-filtering/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 09:42:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/vrops-6-3-snmp-filtering/</guid><description>So one of the most common questions I get from customers regarding vROps is alert filtering and up until very recently the only way to filter was either by email alerting or via the REST plugin. However 9/10 customers wanted to use SNMP and with vROps it was a question of switching on the fire-hose and pointing it to the receiver and let that end point or middle-ware handle the torrent of data.</description></item><item><title>Whats new in #vROps 6.3 part 2</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 21:16:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3-part-2/</guid><description>In this post I will drill down to look at some of the enhancements, improvements and or new additions one by one.
New Home Dashboard - as you can see this is a very useful and helpful way or presenting a high level set of data about your environment with also many ways to interact and interrogate the data you are being presented with. Among other items you can filter on (Health/Risk/Efficiency), alter the scope, see alerts relative to the objects you are interested in.</description></item><item><title>Whats new in #vROps 6.3</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 16:40:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2016/08/whats-new-in-vrops-6-3/</guid><description>So the latest release of vROps has some cool new things and at a very high level below are the key stand out improvements and changes.
I will do a more deep dive in the next few days.
You can get the release notes here.
You can download it here.
New home dashboard Improved WLP and DRS integration Improved Workload Dashboard Wizard now available for policy creation or amendment Improved visibility of Data collection status Many new Hardening policies (6.</description></item></channel></rss>