<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>multisite on DefinIT</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/multisite/</link><description>Recent content in multisite on DefinIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 20:24:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.definit.co.uk/tag/multisite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>vCenter 5.1 Single Sign On Multi-Site error: User credentials are incorrect or empty</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/vcenter-5-1-single-sign-on-multi-site-error-user-credentials-are-incorrect-or-empty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 20:24:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/11/vcenter-5-1-single-sign-on-multi-site-error-user-credentials-are-incorrect-or-empty/</guid><description>While adding an additional vCenter Server to our Multi-Site Single Sign On instance I encountered a problem as I entered the details of the existing SSO.
The error thrown was:
User credentials are incorrect or empty. Provide correct credentials.
After a couple of hours online with VMware support I took a guess at the problem. On the existing Single Sign On Configuration I have added the Active Directory domain DefinIT and in order to enable integrated authentication from the vSphere Client I moved it to the top of the list - this meant that System-Domain is no longer the default authentication domain.</description></item><item><title>Installing VMware vSphere Single Sign On (SSO) in Multi-site Mode</title><link>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/installing-vmware-vsphere-single-sign-on-sso-in-multi-site-mode/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 19:33:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.definit.co.uk/2012/10/installing-vmware-vsphere-single-sign-on-sso-in-multi-site-mode/</guid><description>VMware vSphere Single Sign On (SSO) can be installed in Multi-site mode to support local sign-on to vCenters that you want to be part of the same single sign on domain - for example, if you want to install Linked-Mode and have the advantage of a single pane of glass view, but can&amp;rsquo;t risk using a single SSO instance across the WAN. In other words, from VMware&amp;rsquo;s blog post:</description></item></channel></rss>